<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00116</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(3) Reduction in the availability of highly productive</textblock>
    <textblock>brackish-water habitat,</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Urban and agricultural pollution,</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Introduction of exotic species, and</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Exacerbation of the effects of these factors as a result of 6</textblock>
    <textblock>years of drought.</textblock>
    <textblock>The causes of splittail decline in the Estuary are multiple and</textblock>
    <textblock>synergistically threaten this species. The individual threats include:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Reduced river outflows, primarily in the Sacramento and San</textblock>
    <textblock>Joaquin Rivers and their tributaries;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Loss of shallow-water habitat;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Mortality caused by diversion into State and Federal water</textblock>
    <textblock>projects and privately-operated agricultural in-Delta water diversions;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Human and natural perturbations of the food web;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Presence of toxic substances in the aquatic habitat (e.g.,</textblock>
    <textblock>agricultural and industrial chemicals and heavy metals); and</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Introduction of non-native species.</textblock>
    <textblock>Previous Service Action</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service included the Sacramento splittail as a category 2</textblock>
    <textblock>candidate species for possible future listing as endangered or</textblock>
    <textblock>threatened in the January 6, 1989 (54 FR 554), Animal Notice of Review.</textblock>
    <textblock>Category 2 includes species for which information contained in Service</textblock>
    <textblock>files indicates that proposing to list is possibly appropriate but</textblock>
    <textblock>additional data is needed to support a listing proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>On November 5, 1992, the Service received a petition from Mr.</textblock>
    <textblock>Gregory A. Thomas of the Natural Heritage Institute to add the splittail</textblock>
    <textblock>to the List of Endangered and Threatened Wildlife and to designate</textblock>
    <textblock>critical habitat for this species in the Sacramento and San Joaquin</textblock>
    <textblock>Rivers and those estuaries. In his letter, Mr. Thomas identified the</textblock>
    <textblock>following eight organizations as co-petitioners: American Fisheries</textblock>
    <textblock>Society, Bay Institute of San Francisco, Natural Heritage Institute,</textblock>
    <textblock>Planning and Conservation League, Save San Francisco Bay Association,</textblock>
    <textblock>Friends of the River, San Francisco Baykeeper, and the Sierra Club. On</textblock>
    <textblock>June 24, 1993, the Service issued a 90-day finding, notice of which was</textblock>
    <textblock>published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on July 6, 1993 (58 FR 36184), that</textblock>
    <textblock>the petition presented substantial information indicating that the</textblock>
    <textblock>requested action may be warranted. The Service initiated a status</textblock>
    <textblock>review and analyzed available data on this species (Meng 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional sources of information describing the human factors and</textblock>
    <textblock>projects that may affect this species include expert testimonies</textblock>
    <textblock>presented to the California State Water Resources Control Board's 1987</textblock>
    <textblock>Water Quality/Water Rights Proceeding on the San Francisco Bay and</textblock>
    <textblock>Sacramento-San Joaquin River Delta and 1992 Water Rights Phase of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bay-Delta Estuary Proceedings. This proposal constitutes the final</textblock>
    <textblock>finding on the petition to list the Sacramento splittail.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
