<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00009</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>DOC has submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for clearance the following proposal for collection of information under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. chapter 35).</textblock>
    <textblock>Agency:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of the Census.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Quarterly Survey of the Finances of Public-Employee Retirement Systems.</textblock>
    <textblock>Form Number(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>F-10.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agency Approval Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>0607-0143.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Request:</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension of the expiration date of a currently approved collection without any change in the substance or in the method of collection.</textblock>
    <textblock>Burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>416 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>104.</textblock>
    <textblock>Avg Hours Per Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>1 hour.</textblock>
    <textblock>Needs and Uses:</textblock>
    <textblock>This survey provides, on a quarterly basis, nationwide data on the receipts, expenditures, and cash and security holdings of the 104 largest public-employee retirement systems. These 104 systems control billions of asset dollars and represent 90 percent of the total assets of all public employee retirement systems. Census conducts this survey at the request of the Council of Economic Advisors and the Federal Reserve Board. Economists from these agencies, the Department of Treasury, the Bureau of Economic Analysis, and others use these data to monitor and analyze investment trends and to formulate governmental economic policies and investment decisions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Affected Public:</textblock>
    <textblock>State or local governments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency:</textblock>
    <textblock>Quarterly.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondent's Obligation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Voluntary.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB Desk Officer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Maria Gonzalez, (202) 395-7313.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the above information collection proposal can be obtained by calling or writing Edward Michals, DOC Forms Clearance Officer, (202) 482-3271, Department of Commerce, room 5312, 14th and Constitution Avenue, NW, Washington, DC 20230.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments and recommendations for the proposed information collection should be sent to Maria Gonzalez, OMB Desk Officer, room 3208, New Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Agency Form Under Review by the Office of Management and Budget</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Edward Michals,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Departmental Forms Clearance Officer, Office of Management and Organization.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-283 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-07-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
