<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00122</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00069</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>TENNESSEE VALLEY AUTHORITY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Information Collection Under Review by the Office of Management and Budget</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Tennessee Valley Authority.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information collections under review by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB).</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) has sent to OMB the following proposal for the collection of information under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. chapter 35), as amended by Public Law 99-591.</textblock>
    <textblock>Requests for information, including copies of the information collection proposed and supporting documentation, should be directed to the Agency Clearance Officer whose name, address, and telephone number appear below. Questions or comments should be made within 30 days directly to the Agency Clearance Officer and also to the Desk Officer for the Tennessee Valley Authority, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503; Telephone: (202) 395-3084.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agency Clearance Officer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mark R. Winter, Tennessee Valley Authority, 1101 Market Street (BR 6B), Chattanooga, TN 37402-2801; (615) 751-2523.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Request:</textblock>
    <textblock>Regular submission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title of Information Collection:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comparison of Factors Influencing Minority and Nonminority Representation in State and Federal Natural Resource Professions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Use:</textblock>
    <textblock>On occasion.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Affected Public:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals or households, state or local governments, Federal agencies or employees.</textblock>
    <textblock>Small Businesses or Organizations Affected:</textblock>
    <textblock>No.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Budget Functional Category Code:</textblock>
    <textblock>452.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Number of Annual Responses.</textblock>
    <textblock>2,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Total Annual Burden Hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>500.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Average Burden Hours Per Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>.25.</textblock>
    <textblock>Need For and Use of Information:</textblock>
    <textblock>TVA is cooperating with 22 other Federal and state agencies to investigate selected factors which may influence minority and nonminority representation in state and Federal agency natural resource professions. A survey of natural resource professions in the Southeastern United States will be conducted to determine (1) the diversity in the workforce and job responsibilities, (2) factors that promote or preclude job satisfaction, (3) educational backgrounds attained and needed by inservice professionals, and (4) conceptual framework for career selection by and retention of minorities in natural resource professions. Results of the study may provide strategies for state and Federal agencies to refine minority recruitment and retention programs, personnel planning, and career counseling.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William S. Moore,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Information Support Services.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-297 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8120-08-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
