<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00070</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>E. Sablefish and the DTS Complex (Dover Sole, Thornyheads, and Trawl-Caught Sablefish</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>1994 Management Goal.</textblock>
    <textblock>The sablefish fishery will be managed to achieve the 7,000 mt harvest guideline in 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington Coastal Tribal Fisheries.</textblock>
    <textblock>An estimate will be made of the catch to the end of 1994 for the Washington coastal treaty tribes. It is anticipated that these tribes will regulate their fisheries so as not to exceed their estimated catch. There will be no Federally imposed tribal allocation or quota. In 1994, the estimated tribal catch is 300 mt, the same as in 1991, 1992, and 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Limited-entry Fishery.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Gear Allocations.</textblock>
    <textblock>After subtracting the tribal-imposed catch limit and the open-access allocation from the harvest guideline, the remainder will be allocated 58 percent to the trawl fishery and 42 percent to the nontrawl fishery.</textblock>
    <textblock>[</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>The 1994 harvest guideline for sablefish is 7,000 mt. The 300-mt tribal-imposed catch limit is subtracted, and the limited-entry and open-access allocations are based on the remaining 6,700 mt. The limited-entry allocation for 1994 of 6,070 mt is allocated 3,520 mt (58 percent) to the trawl fishery and 2,550 mt (42 percent) to the nontrawl fishery. The trawl and nontrawl gear allocations are harvest guidelines in 1994, which means the fishery will be managed so that the harvest guidelines are not exceeded, but will not necessarily be closed if they are reached.]</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Trip and Size Limits for the DTS Complex (Thornyheads, Dover Sole, and Trawl-caught Sablefish).</textblock>
    <textblock>These provisions apply to thornyheads and Dover sole caught with any limited-entry gear and sablefish caught with limited-entry trawl gear.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) ``DTS complex'' (formerly called the ``deepwater complex'') means Dover sole (</textblock>
    <textblock>Microstomus pacificus</textblock>
    <textblock>), thornyheads (</textblock>
    <textblock>Sebastolobus</textblock>
    <textblock>spp.), and trawl-caught sablefish (</textblock>
    <textblock>Anoplopoma fimbria</textblock>
    <textblock>). Sablefish also are called blackcod. Thornyheads also are called idiots, channel rockfish, or hardheads.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Trip limits.</textblock>
    <textblock>Coastwide, no more than 50,000 pounds (22,680 kg) cumulative of the DTS complex may be taken and retained, possessed, or landed per vessel per month. Within this 50,000 pounds (22,680 kg), no more than 30,000 pounds (13,608 kg) cumulative may be thornyheads, and no more than 12,000 pounds (5,443 kg) cumulative may be trawl-caught sablefish. In any landing of the DTS complex, the trip limit for trawl-caught sablefish is the greater of 1,000 pounds (454 kg), or 25 percent of the DTS complex. In any landing, no more than 5,000 pounds (2,268 kg) of sablefish may be smaller than 22 inches (56 cm) (total length).</textblock>
    <textblock>[</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>Twenty-five percent of the DTS complex (including sablefish) is equivalent to 33.333 percent of the legal thornyheads and Dover sole.]</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Nontrawl trip and size limits.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The daily trip limit for sablefish in the Vancouver, Columbia, Eureka and Monterey subareas (the U.S.-Canada border to 36</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>’00</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N. latitude) is 250 pounds (113 kg), and in the Conception subarea (36</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>’00</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N. latitude to the U.S.-Mexico border) is 350 pounds (159 kg). These daily trip limits, which apply to sablefish of any size, remain in effect until the regular season begins, as specified at 50 CFR 663.23(b)(2).</textblock>
    <textblock>[</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>In 1994, the daily trip limits will be in effect from 0001 hours January 1 through 2400 hours May 11; the first 72-hour closure will occur from 0001 hours May 12 through 2400 hours May 14; and the regular season will start at 0001 hours May 15.]</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) During the ``regular'' season, the only trip limit in effect applies to sablefish smaller than 22 inches (56 cm) (total length) which may comprise no more than 1,500 pounds (680 kg) or 3 percent of all legal sablefish on board, whichever is greater.</textblock>
    <textblock>(See paragraph (d) regarding length measurement.)</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Following the regular season, on a date to be announced in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register,</textblock>
    <textblock>the daily trip limits will be reimposed for sablefish (of any size) caught with nontrawl gear.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Length measurement.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Total length is measured from the tip of the snout (mouth closed) to the tip of the tail (pinched together) without mutilation of the fish or the use of additional force to extend the length of the fish.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
