<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00073</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00036</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Proposed Funding Priority for FY 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>It is proposed that a funding priority be given to applicants based on their level of accomplishment in relation to the outcome</textblock>
    <textblock>or</textblock>
    <textblock>process measures cited below:</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicants May Only Receive Priority Points in One of the Above Six Categories</textblock>
    <textblock>Information Requirements Provision in Statute</textblock>
    <textblock>Under section 791(b) of the Act, the Secretary may make an award under the Grants for the Establishment of Departments of Family Medicine program only if the applicant for the award submits to the Secretary the following information:</textblock>
    <textblock>l. A description of rotations or preceptorships for students, or clinical training programs for residents, that have the</textblock>
    <textblock>principal focus of providing health care to medically underserved communities.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The number of faculty on admissions committees who have a clinical practice in community-based ambulatory settings in</textblock>
    <textblock>medically underserved communities.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. With respect to individuals who are from disadvantaged backgrounds, or from medically underserved communities, the number of such individuals who are recruited for academic programs of the applicant, the number of such individuals who are admitted to such programs, and the number of such individuals who graduate from such programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. If applicable, the number of recent graduates who have chosen careers in primary health care.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. The number of recent graduates whose practices are serving medically underserved communities.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. A description of whether and to what extent the applicant is able to operate without Federal assistance under this title.</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional details concerning the implementation of this information requirement have been published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>at 58 FR 43642, August 17, 1993, and will be provided in the application materials.</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional Information</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to comment on the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>minimum percentages for ``high rate'' and ``significant increase in the rate'' for implementation of the general statutory funding preference, and funding priority. All comments received on or before February 7, 1994 will be considered before the final minimum percentages for ``high rate'' and ``significant increase in the rate'' for implementation of the general statutory funding preference, and funding priority are established.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments should be addressed to: Marc L. Rivo, M.D., M.P.H.</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, Division of Medicine, Bureau of Health Professions, Health Resources and Services Administration, 5600 Fishers Lane, Parklawn Building, room 4C-25,</textblock>
    <textblock>Rockville, Maryland 20857.</textblock>
    <textblock>All comments received will be available for public inspection and copying at the Division of Medicine, Bureau of Health Professions, at the above address, weekdays (Federal holidays excepted) between the hours of 8:30 a.m. and 5 p.m.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Outcome measures</textblock>
    <textblock>1Points</textblock>
    <textblock>1Process measures</textblock>
    <textblock>_25% of students who graduated in 1991, 1992 and 1993 entered family practice residencies</textblock>
    <textblock>100</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>_20% of students who graduated in 1991, 1992 and 1993 entered family practice residencies</textblock>
    <textblock>75</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>_15% of students who graduated in 1991, 1992 and 1993 entered family practice residencies</textblock>
    <textblock>50</textblock>
    <textblock>_Required 3rd Year Clerkship* (of at least 4 weeks duration).</textblock>
    <textblock>_12% of students who graduated in 1991, 1992 and 1993 entered family practice residencies</textblock>
    <textblock>35</textblock>
    <textblock>_Required primary care preceptorship/mentorship program* in preclinical years.</textblock>
    <textblock>*Curricular elements must be in place at the time of application or the applicant must provide satisfactory evidence (including commitments from institutional officials) that the clerkship or preceptorship will be operational by the beginning of the third year of the grant.</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
