<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00040</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00024</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Petition for Permanent Filing Exemption; Petition of Totem Ocean Trailer Express, Inc.; Filing of Petition</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given of the filing of a petition by Totem Ocean Trailer Express, Inc. pursuant to 46 CFR 514.8(a), for permanent exemption of its Local Freight Tariff No. 3-C, FMC-F No. 4, ICC TOTE 201, from the electronic tariff filing requirements of the Commission's ATFI System, on the grounds that the tariff is jointly filed with the Interstate Commerce Commission and the Federal Maritime Commission, and is therefore not compatible with the ATFI filing requirements. Alternatively, petitioner seeks complete exemption from filing the tariff in paper or electronic form.</textblock>
    <textblock>To facilitate through consideration of the petition, interested persons are requested to reply to the petition no later than January 18, 1994. Replies shall be directed to the Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, Washington, DC 20573-0001, shall consist of an original and 15 copies, and shall be served on Counsel for petitioner, Mr. Michael D. Duppenthaler, Registered Practitioner, Interstate Commerce Commission, 1100 Olive Way, suite 1150, Seattle, Washington 98101-1839.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the petition are available for examination at the Washington, DC office of the Secretary of the Commission, 800 N. Capitol Street, NW., room 1046.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL MARITIME COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Petition No. P108-93]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Joseph C. Polking,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-111 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6730-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
