<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00034</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>PART 100_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 100 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>33 U.S.C. 1233; 49 CFR 1.46 and 33 CFR 100.35.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. A temporary ยง100.35-T02-035 is added, to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง100.35-T02-035</textblock>
    <textblock>Ohio River, Fort Knox, Kentucky.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulated area.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ohio River from mile 630.0 to 636.5.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Special local regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Except for participants in the Operation Anzio Reenactment no person or vessel may enter or remain in the regulated area without permission of the Patrol Commander.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The Coast Guard Patrol Commander will be a commissioned or petty officer designated by the Commanding Officer, Marine Safety Office Louisville, Kentucky and may be contacted, during the event, on channel 16 (156.8 MHZ) by the call sign ``Coast Guard Patrol Commander.'' The Patrol Commander may:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Direct the anchoring, mooring, or movement of any vessel within the regulated area,</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Restrict vessel operation within the regulated area to vessels having particular operating characteristics,</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Terminate the marine event or the operation of any vessel when necessary for the protection of life and property, and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Allow vessels to transit the regulated area whenever an event is not being conducted and the transit can be completed before another event begins.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Coast Guard commissioned or petty officers will patrol the event on board patrol vessels which display the Coast Guard Ensign. If radio or other voice communications are not available to communicate with a vessel, they will use a series of sharp, short blasts by whistle or horn to signal the operator of any vessel in the vicinity of the regulated area to stop. When signaled, the operator of any vessel in the immediate vicinity of the regulated area shall stop the vessel immediately and shall proceed as directed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Vessels desiring to transit the regulated area may do so only with the prior approval and direction of the Patrol Commander.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) The Patrol Commander will terminate enforcement of the regulations at the conclusion of the marine event if earlier than the announced termination time.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective dates.</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulation becomes effective daily from 12 p.m. to 3 p.m. local time on January 20-22, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Paul M. Blayney,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Rear Admiral, U.S. Coast Guard, Commander, Second Coast Guard District.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-268 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-14-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
