<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00091</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>ETA estimates that 1,400 facilities per year will be submitting attestations. The public reporting burden for this collection of information is estimated to average 8-10 hours for searching existing information/data sources and gathering and compiling the data at the facility the first year that a facility submits an attestation. In the second, and subsequent years, the reporting burden, based on operating experience, will average 2-3 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Impact and Administrative Procedure</textblock>
    <textblock>E.O. 12866</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with Executive Order 12866, the Department of Labor has determined that this is not a significant regulatory action as defined in section 3(f) of the Order.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>At the time the proposed rule was published, the Department of Labor notified the Chief Counsel for Advocacy, Small Business Administration, and made the certification pursuant to the Regulatory Flexibility Act at 5 U.S.C. 605(b), that the rule does not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Number</textblock>
    <textblock>This program is not yet listed in the Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects</textblock>
    <textblock>20 CFR Part 621</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedure, Aliens, Employment, Guam, Labor, Wages.</textblock>
    <textblock>20 CFR Part 655</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative and practice procedure, Agriculture, Aliens, Crewmembers, Employment, Enforcement, Forest and forest products, Guam, Health professions, Immigration, Labor, Longshore work, Migrant labor, Nurse, Penalties, Registered nurse, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Specialty occupation, Students, Wages.</textblock>
    <textblock>29 CFR Part 504</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedures, Aliens, Employment, Enforcement, Health professions, Immigration, Labor, Nurse, Penalties, Registered nurse, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Wages.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
