<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00044</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00028</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The organization listed in this notice has applied under  225.23(a) or (f) of the Board's Regulation Y (12 CFR 225.23(a) or (f)) for the Board's approval under section 4(c)(8) of the Bank Holding Company Act (12 U.S.C. 1843(c)(8)) and  225.21(a) of Regulation Y (12 CFR 225.21(a)) to acquire or control voting securities or assets of a company engaged in a nonbanking activity. Unless otherwise noted, such activities will be conducted throughout the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>The application is available for immediate inspection at the Federal Reserve Bank indicated. Once the application has been accepted for processing, it will also be available for inspection at the offices of the Board of Governors. Interested persons may express their views in writing on the question whether consummation of the proposal can ``reasonably be expected to produce benefits to the public, such as greater convenience, increased competition, or gains in efficiency, that outweigh possible adverse effects, such as undue concentration of resources, decreased or unfair competition, conflicts of interests, or unsound banking practices.'' Any request for a hearing on this question must be accompanied by a statement of the reasons a written presentation would not suffice in lieu of a hearing, identifying specifically any questions of fact that are in dispute, summarizing the evidence that would be presented at a hearing, and indicating how the party commenting would be aggrieved by approval of the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments regarding the application must be received at the Reserve Bank indicated or the offices of the Board of Governors not later than January 31, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis</textblock>
    <textblock>(James M. Lyon, Vice President) 250 Marquette Avenue, Minneapolis, Minnesota 55480:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Norwest Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>, Minneapolis, Minnesota, and Norwest Investment Services, Inc., Minneapolis, Minnesota; to acquire FN Investment Center, Phoenix, Arizona, and thereby engage in securities brokerage activities pursuant to  225.25(b)(15) of the Board's Regulation Y, including private placement, limited underwriting, precious metal brokerage, riskless pincipal and leasing activities pursuant to</textblock>
    <textblock>Norwest Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>, 76 Federal Reserve Bulletin 79 (1990).</textblock>
    <textblock>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, December 30, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Norwest Corporation; Acquisition of Company Engaged in Nonbanking Activities</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jennifer J. Johnson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Secretary of the Board.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-216 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6210-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
