<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00115</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In recent times, dams and diversions have increasingly prevented</textblock>
    <textblock>upstream access to large rivers, and the species is now restricted to a</textblock>
    <textblock>small portion of its former range (Moyle and Yoshiyama 1992). Splittail</textblock>
    <textblock>enter the lower reaches of the Feather (Jones and Stokes 1993) and</textblock>
    <textblock>American Rivers (Charles Hanson, State Water Contractors Association,</textblock>
    <textblock>in</textblock>
    <textblock>litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993) on occasion; however, the species now largely is confined</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Delta, Suisun Bay, Suisun Marsh, and Napa Marsh.</textblock>
    <textblock>Splittail are relatively long-lived, frequently reaching 5 to 7</textblock>
    <textblock>years of age. Females are highly fecund and produce over 100,000 eggs</textblock>
    <textblock>each year. Populations fluctuate annually depending on spawning</textblock>
    <textblock>success, which is highly correlated with freshwater outflow and the</textblock>
    <textblock>availability of shallow-water habitat with submerged vegetation (Daniels</textblock>
    <textblock>and Moyle 1983). Fish usually reach sexual maturity by the end of their</textblock>
    <textblock>second year. Some variability in the period of reproduction exists</textblock>
    <textblock>because older individuals reproduce first, followed by younger</textblock>
    <textblock>individuals (Caywood 1974). The onset of spawning is associated with</textblock>
    <textblock>rising temperature, and peak spawning occurs from the months of March</textblock>
    <textblock>through May, although records of spawning exist for late January to</textblock>
    <textblock>early July (Wang 1986). Spawning occurs over flooded vegetation in</textblock>
    <textblock>tidal freshwater and euryhaline habitats of estuarine marshes and</textblock>
    <textblock>sloughs and slow-moving reaches of large rivers. Larvae remain in</textblock>
    <textblock>shallow, weedy areas close to spawning sites and move into deeper water</textblock>
    <textblock>as they mature (Wang 1986).</textblock>
    <textblock>Splittail are benthic foragers that feed on opossum shrimp (</textblock>
    <textblock>Neomysis</textblock>
    <textblock>mercedis</textblock>
    <textblock>), although detrital material makes up a large percentage of</textblock>
    <textblock>their stomach content (Daniels and Moyle 1983). Earthworms, clams,</textblock>
    <textblock>insect larvae, and other invertebrates also are found in the diet.</textblock>
    <textblock>Predators include striped bass and other piscivores.</textblock>
    <textblock>Although primarily a freshwater species, the splittail can tolerate</textblock>
    <textblock>salinities as high as 10 to 18 parts per thousand (ppt) (Moyle 1976,</textblock>
    <textblock>Moyle and Yoshiyama 1992). In recent years, this fish has been found</textblock>
    <textblock>most often in slow-moving sections of rivers and sloughs and dead-end</textblock>
    <textblock>sloughs (Moyle</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1982, Daniels and Moyle 1983). Reports from the</textblock>
    <textblock>1950s, however, mention Sacramento River spawning migrations and catches</textblock>
    <textblock>of splittail during fast tides in Suisun Bay (Caywood 1974). Because</textblock>
    <textblock>they require flooded vegetation for spawning and rearing, splittail are</textblock>
    <textblock>frequently found in areas subject to flooding, such as the major flood</textblock>
    <textblock>basins distributed throughout the Sacramento and San Joaquin Valleys.</textblock>
    <textblock>California Department of Fish and Game (CDFG) survey data from the last</textblock>
    <textblock>15 years indicate that the highest catches occurred in shallow areas of</textblock>
    <textblock>Suisun and Grizzly Bays.</textblock>
    <textblock>The decline in splittail abundance has taken place during increased</textblock>
    <textblock>human-induced changes to seasonal estuary hydrology and freshwater</textblock>
    <textblock>exports and the accompanying changes in the temporal, spatial, and</textblock>
    <textblock>relative ratios of water diversions. These deleterious hydrological</textblock>
    <textblock>effects, coupled with severe drought years, introduced aquatic species,</textblock>
    <textblock>and loss of shallow-water habitat to reclamation, seem to have reduced</textblock>
    <textblock>the species' capacity to recover from natural seasonal fluctuations in</textblock>
    <textblock>hydrology for which it was adapted.</textblock>
    <textblock>Analyses of survey data collected since 1967 (Meng 1993) by Service,</textblock>
    <textblock>CDFG, and University of California, Davis, biologists from several</textblock>
    <textblock>different studies indicate the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) On average, splittail have declined in abundance by 62 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>since 1984. Percent decline varied among studies, dependent upon</textblock>
    <textblock>location of sampling effort. The greatest declines (over 80 percent)</textblock>
    <textblock>were found from studies that sampled the shallow Suisun Bay area, the</textblock>
    <textblock>center of the species' range. A study that began in 1980 at the lower</textblock>
    <textblock>Estuary, the outermost edge of splittail range, found the lowest percent</textblock>
    <textblock>decline (34 percent). The number of splittail young taken at State and</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal pumping facilities (per acre-foot of water pumped) has declined</textblock>
    <textblock>64 percent since 1984;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Successful reproduction in splittail is highly correlated with</textblock>
    <textblock>wet years, but within these wet years, young-of-the-year taken per unit</textblock>
    <textblock>effort has declined steadily from a high of 12.3 in 1978 to 0.3 in 1993;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) A strong relationship exists between young-of-the-year abundance</textblock>
    <textblock>and outflow (i.e., river outflow into San Francisco Bay after water</textblock>
    <textblock>exports are removed). As outflow increases, annual abundance of</textblock>
    <textblock>splittail young increases. Changes in outflow explain 73 percent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>changes seen in splittail young abundance;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) When young-of-the-year abundance is predicted using unimpaired</textblock>
    <textblock>outflow (i.e., river outflow without water exports removed), abundance</textblock>
    <textblock>is higher than expected in dry years, indicating that water exports</textblock>
    <textblock>affect young-of-the-year abundance in dry years. In dry years when river</textblock>
    <textblock>outflow is reduced, high proportions of outflow are diverted, resulting</textblock>
    <textblock>in lower than expected splittail young numbers;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Lower than expected numbers of splittail young persisted</textblock>
    <textblock>throughout the recent 6-year drought in California. This prolonged</textblock>
    <textblock>period of poor reproductive success may affect the stock's ability to</textblock>
    <textblock>recover;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Splittail are most abundant in shallow areas of Suisun and</textblock>
    <textblock>Grizzly Bays and are vulnerable to increased salinities. Salinities</textblock>
    <textblock>increase when, as a result of water exports and drought conditions, the</textblock>
    <textblock>entrapment zone (mixing zone at the freshwater-saltwater interface) is</textblock>
    <textblock>moved upstream. Concentration of splittail in shallow areas suggests</textblock>
    <textblock>that they are particularly vulnerable to reclamation activities, such as</textblock>
    <textblock>dredging and the diking and filling of wetlands; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Splittail distribution has shifted upstream into the lower</textblock>
    <textblock>Sacramento River and South Delta since 1983. Ninety-one percent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>splittail captured in San Pablo and lower Suisun Bays from 1967 to 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>were taken before 1983, and 77 percent of the splittail captured in the</textblock>
    <textblock>lower Sacramento River and South Delta were taken after 1983. Because</textblock>
    <textblock>State and Federal water project pumps are located near the lower</textblock>
    <textblock>Sacramento River and South Delta, this upstream shift in splittail</textblock>
    <textblock>distribution increases splittail mortality at the pumps. In 1993, the</textblock>
    <textblock>number of splittail young taken at the Federal pumping facility was four</textblock>
    <textblock>times higher than in previous years.</textblock>
    <textblock>A variety of factors affects the estuarine ecosystems and has led to</textblock>
    <textblock>the decline of Sacramento splittail. Principal among these factors</textblock>
    <textblock>specific to the Estuary are the altered hydraulics and reduced outflow</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Delta caused by export of freshwater from the Sacramento and San</textblock>
    <textblock>Joaquin Rivers through State and Federal water diversion projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional threats to this species include:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Loss at pumping plants and in-Delta diversion sites,</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Loss of spawning and nursery habitat as a consequence of</textblock>
    <textblock>draining and diking for agriculture,</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
