<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00035</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Appendix_Text of Oil and Gas Order No. 5</textblock>
    <textblock>Note.</textblock>
    <textblock>_This appendix will not appear in the Code of Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Onshore Oil and Gas Order No. 5</textblock>
    <textblock>Measurement of Gas</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Introduction</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Authority</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Purpose</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Scope</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Definitions</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Required Recordkeeping</textblock>
    <textblock>B. General</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Primary Element_Orifice Meters</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Secondary Element</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Other Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Gas Measurement by Other Methods or at Other Locations</textblock>
    <textblock>Acceptable to the Authorized Officer</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Variances from Minimum Standards</textblock>
    <textblock>Attachment</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Sections from 43 CFR Subparts 3163 and 3165</textblock>
    <textblock>Onshore Oil and Gas Order No. 5</textblock>
    <textblock>Measurement of Gas on Federal and Indian Oil and Gas Leases</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Introduction</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Authority</textblock>
    <textblock>This Order is established pursuant to the authority granted to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary of the Interior under various Federal and Indian</textblock>
    <textblock>mineral leasing statutes and the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty</textblock>
    <textblock>Management Act of 1982. This authority has been delegated to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management and is implemented by the onshore oil</textblock>
    <textblock>and gas operating regulations contained in 43 CFR part 3160.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 3164.1 thereof specifically authorizes the Director to</textblock>
    <textblock>issue Onshore Oil and Gas Orders when necessary to implement or</textblock>
    <textblock>supplement the operating regulations and provides that all such</textblock>
    <textblock>Orders shall be binding on the lessees and operators of Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>and restricted Indian oil and gas leases which have been, or may</textblock>
    <textblock>hereafter, be issued.</textblock>
    <textblock>Specific authority for the provisions contained in this Order</textblock>
    <textblock>is found at: section 3162.4-1, Well records and reports; section</textblock>
    <textblock>3162.4-2, Samples, tests, and surveys; section 3162.7-1,</textblock>
    <textblock>Disposition of production; section 3162.7-3, Measurement of gas;</textblock>
    <textblock>and subpart 3163, Noncompliance, Assessments, and Penalties.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Purpose</textblock>
    <textblock>One purpose of this Order is to establish requirements and</textblock>
    <textblock>minimum standards for the accurate measurement of gas by the</textblock>
    <textblock>methods authorized in 43 CFR 3162.7-3, i.e., measurement by</textblock>
    <textblock>orifice meter or other methods acceptable to the authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>officer. Accurate gas measurement ensures that the Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Government, the general public, State Governments that share in</textblock>
    <textblock>the proceeds, and Indian mineral owners receive the royalties</textblock>
    <textblock>due, as specified in the governing oil and gas leases.</textblock>
    <textblock>Another purpose of this Order is to establish abatement</textblock>
    <textblock>periods for corrective action when noncompliance with the minimum</textblock>
    <textblock>standards is detected.</textblock>
    <textblock>This Order also serves as notice to any party cited for</textblock>
    <textblock>noncompliance that it may request from the authorized officer an</textblock>
    <textblock>extension of the abatement period for any violation, provided</textblock>
    <textblock>that the request for extension is applied for and granted prior</textblock>
    <textblock>to the expiration of the abatement period previously allowed.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Scope</textblock>
    <textblock>This Order is applicable to all Federal and Indian (except</textblock>
    <textblock>Osage) oil and gas leases. In addition, this Order is also</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable to all wells and facilities on State or privately</textblock>
    <textblock>owned mineral lands committed to a unit or communitization</textblock>
    <textblock>agreement that affects Federal or Indian interests, notwithstanding any provision of a unit or communitization agreement to</textblock>
    <textblock>the contrary.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Definitions</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
