<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00046</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Thursday</textblock>
    <textblock>January 6, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part II</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency</textblock>
    <textblock>40 CFR Part 131</textblock>
    <textblock>Sacramento River, San Joaquin River, and San Francisco Bay and Delta, CA; Water Quality Standards for Surface Water; Proposed Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Interior</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service</textblock>
    <textblock>50 CFR Part 17</textblock>
    <textblock>Endangered and Threatened Wildlife and Plants: Delta Smelt, Sacramento Splittail, and Longfin Smelt; Proposed Rules</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 4␣/␣Thursday, January 6, 1994␣/␣Proposed Rules</textblock>
    <textblock>[OW-FRL-4783-6]</textblock>
    <textblock>Water Quality Standards for Surface Waters of the Sacramento River, San Joaquin River, and San Francisco Bay and Delta of the State of California</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>40 CFR Part 131</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>On September 3, 1991, the Regional Administrator for Region IX of the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency disapproved certain water quality criteria contained in the Water Quality Control Plan for Salinity for the San Francisco Bay/Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta Estuary, that was adopted by the California State Water Resources Control Board on May 1, 1991. These criteria were disapproved because they failed to protect the Estuarine Habitat and other designated fish and wildlife uses of the estuary. Under the authority of section 303 of the Clean Water Act, this document proposes a rule establishing three sets of federal criteria to protect the designated uses of the estuary: salinity criteria protecting the Estuarine Habitat and other designated fish and wildlife uses, a second set of salinity criteria (measured in electrical conductivity) to protect the Fish Spawning (Striped Bass) designated use in the lower San Joaquin River, and a set of salmon smolt survival index criteria to protect the Fish Migration and Cold Fresh-Water Habitat designated uses in the estuary.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>All written comments received on or before March 11, 1994, will be considered in the preparation of the final rule. Public Hearings will be held during the week of February 21, 1994, in Fresno, Sacramento, and San Francisco, California.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments should be addressed to Patrick Wright, Bay/Delta Program Manager, Water Quality Standards Branch, W-3, Water Management Division, Environmental Protection Agency, 75 Hawthorne Street, San Francisco, California 94105.</textblock>
    <textblock>Both oral and written comments will be accepted at the hearings. EPA reserves the right to fix reasonable limits on the time allowed for oral presentations. Written comments are encouraged.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contact Lois Grunwald, Public Affairs Office, Environmental Protection Agency, 75 Hawthorne Street, San Francisco, California 94105, 415/744-1588, for further information on hearings.</textblock>
  </address>
</doc>
