<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00035</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00019</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>December 30, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Northern Electric Power Co., L.P. (``Northern Electric'') filed with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission an application on December 30, 1993 for determination of exempt wholesale generator status pursuant to part 365 of the Commission's Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Northern Electric is a New York limited partnership formed to own a hydroelectric generating facility located on the Hudson River in Saratoga and Washington Counties, New York.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to be heard concerning the application for exempt wholesale generator status should file a motion to intervene or comments with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with sections 385.211 and 385.214 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure. The Commission will limit its consideration of comments to those that concern the adequacy or accuracy of the application. All such motions and comments must be filed on or before January 10, 1994 and must be served on the applicant. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. EG94-12-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Northern Electric Power Co., L.P.; Application for Commission Determination of Exempt Wholesale Generator Status</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-230 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
