<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00112</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Goldman, C.R., and A.J. Horne. 1983. Limnology. McGraw-Hill Book</textblock>
    <textblock>Company, New York, New York.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monroe, M.W., and J. Kelly. 1992. State of the estuary: A report on</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions and problems in the San Francisco Bay/Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta Estuary. San Francisco Estuary Project, Oakland, California.</textblock>
    <textblock>Moyle, P.B. 1976. Inland Fishes of California. University of</textblock>
    <textblock>California Press, Berkeley, California.</textblock>
    <textblock>Moyle, P.B., B. Herbold, D.E. Stevens, and L.W. Miller. 1992. Life history and status of delta smelt in the Sacramento-San Joaquin Estuary, California. Trans. Amer. Fish. Soc. 121:67-77.</textblock>
    <textblock>Nichols, F.H., J.E. Cloern, S.N. Luoma, and D.H. Peterson. 1986.</textblock>
    <textblock>The modification of an estuary. Science 231:567-573.</textblock>
    <textblock>Radtke, L.D. 1966. Distribution of smelt, juvenile sturgeon, and</textblock>
    <textblock>starry flounder in the Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta with observations on food of sturgeon. Pages 115-129</textblock>
    <textblock>in</textblock>
    <textblock>J.L. Turner and D.W. Kelley, editors. Ecological studies of the Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta, Part 2. Calif. Dept. Fish and Game, Fish Bulletin 136.</textblock>
    <textblock>Stevens, D.E., L.W. Miller, and B.C. Bolster. 1990. Report to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and Game Commission: A status review of the delta smelt</textblock>
    <textblock>(Hypomesus transpacificus)</textblock>
    <textblock>in California. Calif. Dept. Fish and Game Candidate Species Status Report 90-2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sweetnam, D.A., and D.E. Stevens. 1993. Report to the Fish and Game</textblock>
    <textblock>Commission: A status review of the delta smelt</textblock>
    <textblock>(Hypomesus transpacificus)</textblock>
    <textblock>in California. Calif. Dept. Fish and Game Candidate Species Status Report 93-DS.</textblock>
    <textblock>Wang, J.C.S. 1986. Fishes of the Sacramento-San Joaquin estuary and adjacent waters, California: A guide to the early life histories. Interagency Ecological Study Program for the Sacramento-San Joaquin Estuary. Tech. Rept. 9.</textblock>
    <textblock>Wang, J.C.S. 1991. Early life stages and early life history of the</textblock>
    <textblock>delta smelt,</textblock>
    <textblock>Hypomesus transpacificus,</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Sacramento-San Joaquin estuary, with comparison of early life stages of the longfin smelt,</textblock>
    <textblock>Spirinchus thaleichthys.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interagency Ecological Studies Program for the Sacramento-San Joaquin Estuary. Tech. Rept. 28.</textblock>
    <textblock>Author</textblock>
    <textblock>The primary author of this proposed rule is Nadine R. Kanim, Sacramento Field Office (see</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>section).</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 50 CFR Part 17</textblock>
    <textblock>Endangered and threatened species, Exports, Imports, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Transportation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Regulations Promulgation</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, the Service hereby proposes to amend part 17, subchapter B of chapter I, title 50 of the Code of Federal Regulations, as set forth below:</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
