<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00030</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>COMPETITIVENESS POLICY COUNCIL</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of forthcoming meetings.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act, Public Law 92-463, as amended, the Competitiveness Policy Council announces several forthcoming meetings.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 13, 1994; 9:30 a.m. to 4:00 p.m.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Third Floor, 1726 M Street, NW., suite 300, Washington, DC 20036.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Howard Rosen, Executive Director, Competitiveness Policy Council, suite 300, 1726 M Street, NW., Washington, DC 20036, (202) 632-1307.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Competitiveness Policy Council (CPC) was established by the Competitiveness Policy Council Act, as contained in the Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1988, Public Law 100-418, sections 5201-5210, as amended by the Customs and Trade Act of 1990, Public Law 101-382, section 133. The CPC is composed of 12 members and is to advise the President and Congress on matters concerning competitiveness of the US economy. The Council's chairman, Dr. C. Fred Bergsten, will chair each meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be open to the public subject to the seating capacity of the room. Visitors will be requested to sign a visitor's register.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Meeting: Open.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agenda: The Council will discuss the Administration's Workforce Investment Strategy, the impact of regulation on US competitiveness, and a mechanism to finance public infrastructure expenditures. The Council will also consider additional business as suggested by its members.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 30, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Dr. C. Fred Bergsten,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, Competitiveness Policy Council.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-193 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4739-54-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
