<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00118</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Splittail are adapted for life in the entrapment zone. Estuaries</textblock>
    <textblock>are ecosystems where the entrapment zone and salinity levels are</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by the interaction of river outflow and tidal action.</textblock>
    <textblock>Splittail are most abundant in the shallow waters of Suisun Bay, which</textblock>
    <textblock>is historically associated with the entrapment zone. The young of this</textblock>
    <textblock>species require high zooplankton densities produced by the entrapment</textblock>
    <textblock>zone environment. The best survival and growth of splittail occurs when</textblock>
    <textblock>the entrapment zone occupies a large geographic area with extensive</textblock>
    <textblock>shoal regions within the euphotic zone (depths less than 4 meters).</textblock>
    <textblock>Fall mid-water trawl survey data collected by CDFG indicate that 76</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of the splittail captured from 1967 to 1992 in the Delta were</textblock>
    <textblock>taken in the shallow areas of Suisun and Grizzly Bays (Meng 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>During periods of drought and increased water diversions, the</textblock>
    <textblock>entrapment zone and associated fish populations are shifted farther</textblock>
    <textblock>upstream in the Estuary. During years prior to 1984, the entrapment</textblock>
    <textblock>zone was located in Suisun Bay from October through March (except in</textblock>
    <textblock>months with exceptionally high outflows or during years of extreme</textblock>
    <textblock>drought). From April through September, the entrapment zone usually was</textblock>
    <textblock>found upstream in the river channels. Since 1984, with the exception of</textblock>
    <textblock>the record 1986 flood outflows, the entrapment zone has been located</textblock>
    <textblock>primarily in the river channels during the entire year because of</textblock>
    <textblock>drought and increased water exports and diversions. When located</textblock>
    <textblock>upstream, the entrapment zone is confined to deep river channels where</textblock>
    <textblock>the total surface area is smaller, fewer shoal areas of suitable</textblock>
    <textblock>spawning substrate exist, water currents are swifter and more turbulent,</textblock>
    <textblock>and zooplankton productivity is low. In all respects, the upstream</textblock>
    <textblock>river channels are much less favorable for spawning and rearing of</textblock>
    <textblock>splittail. Splittail declines since 1984 have been concurrent with an</textblock>
    <textblock>increasing amount and proportion of freshwater diversions that confine</textblock>
    <textblock>the entrapment zone to the narrow, deep, and less productive channels in</textblock>
    <textblock>the lower rivers.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Overutilization for Commercial, Recreational, Scientific, or</textblock>
    <textblock>Educational Purposes</textblock>
    <textblock>This factor is not known to be applicable. Some</textblock>
    <textblock>scientific collecting is conducted for splittail, but these activities</textblock>
    <textblock>do not adversely affect this species. Little or no recreational harvest</textblock>
    <textblock>of splittail is likely occurring because the population has dramatically</textblock>
    <textblock>declined, and it is not a desirable game species. No recent records of</textblock>
    <textblock>splittail harvest exist, probably because little or no harvest occurs,</textblock>
    <textblock>and the identification of this species is often confused with other</textblock>
    <textblock>nongame species. No other recreational or educational uses of this</textblock>
    <textblock>species exist that may affect its abundance.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Disease or Predation</textblock>
    <textblock>This factor is not known to be</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable. However, if the non-native striped bass populations</textblock>
    <textblock>increase, all size classes of splittail could be under greater threat of</textblock>
    <textblock>predation. An effort by CDFG is under way to compensate for striped</textblock>
    <textblock>bass population mortalities caused by water export projects. The 1991</textblock>
    <textblock>striped bass stock was low relative to the population in the 1960s.</textblock>
    <textblock>Previously, the striped bass compensation program annually released 1 to</textblock>
    <textblock>2 million juvenile, hatchery-reared striped bass in the Estuary in an</textblock>
    <textblock>effort to rebuild the population. However, for the last 2 years, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Director of CDFG has foregone release of striped bass because of the</textblock>
    <textblock>potential harm they would cause to the federally-threatened Sacramento</textblock>
    <textblock>River winter-run chinook salmon and delta smelt.</textblock>
    <textblock>D. The Inadequacy of Existing Regulatory Mechanisms</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory mechanisms currently in effect do not provide adequate protection for the splittail or its habitat. This species is not listed by the State of California.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
