<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00072</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00036</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>It is not required that applicants request consideration for a funding factor. Applications which do not request consideration for funding factors will be reviewed and given full consideration for funding.</textblock>
    <textblock>General Statutory Funding Preference</textblock>
    <textblock>As provided in section 791(a) of the PHS Act, preference will be given to any qualified applicant that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Has a high rate for placing graduates in practice</textblock>
    <textblock>settings having the principal focus of serving</textblock>
    <textblock>residents of medically underserved communities; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) During the 2-year period preceding the fiscal year for</textblock>
    <textblock>which an award is sought, has achieved a significant</textblock>
    <textblock>increase in the rate of placing graduates in such</textblock>
    <textblock>settings. This preference will only be applied to</textblock>
    <textblock>applications that rank above the 20th percentile that</textblock>
    <textblock>have been recommended for approval by the peer review</textblock>
    <textblock>group.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Minimum Percentages for ``High Rate'' and ``Significant Increase in the Rate''</textblock>
    <textblock>``High rate'' means that 20 percent of all graduates of the medical school in 1989 or 1990, whichever is greater, are spending at least 50 percent of their work time in clinical practice in the specified settings.</textblock>
    <textblock>``Significant increase in the rate'' means that, between academic years 1991-92 and 1992-93, the rate of placing 1989 or 1990 graduates in the specified settings has increased by at least 50 percent and that not less than 15 percent of graduates from the most recent year (1990) are working in these settings.</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional information concerning the implementation of this preference has been published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>at 58 FR 40659, dated July 29, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Establishment and Expansion</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Law 102-408 has amended section 747(b), (previously section 780) to include the following statutory funding preference for this program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 747(b)(2) provides that preference shall be given to any qualified applicant that agrees to expend the award for one of the following purposes:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Establishing an academic administrative unit (defined as a department, division, or other unit), for programs in family medicine; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Substantially expanding the programs of such a unit.</textblock>
    <textblock>A program will meet the definition of ``substantial expansion'' if it has developed an acceptable plan for a 50 percent increase in a sufficient number of the following areas to qualify for 70 points. The expansion must be completed within 3 years.</textblock>
    <textblock>More detail on each of these areas will be provided in the</textblock>
    <textblock>program application materials.</textblock>
    <textblock>Established Funding Priority for FY 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>The following funding priority was established in FY 1993, after public comment at 58 FR 35019, June 30, 1993, and is being continued in FY 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>A funding priority will be given to applicants that demonstrate either substantial progress over the last 3 years or a significant experience of 10 or more years in influencing graduates from those minority or low-income populations identified as at-risk of poor health outcomes to enter family medicine residency training.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Points</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Required 3rd Year Clerkship</textblock>
    <textblock>30</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Required Preceptorship</textblock>
    <textblock>20</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Family Medicine Research</textblock>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Expansion of Faculty</textblock>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Faculty Development Program for Community Based Faculty</textblock>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Family Medicine Faculty Represented on Medical School Standing Committees of Admissions or Curriculum</textblock>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Family Medicine Faculty Represented on Dean's Executive Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>that determines Tenure</textblock>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
