<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00037</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>All future sales and allocation facilities and sales or</textblock>
    <textblock>allocation facilities in existence on the effective date of this</textblock>
    <textblock>Order, unless covered by a valid variance, shall meet the minimum</textblock>
    <textblock>standards prescribed in this Order; provided, however, that all gas</textblock>
    <textblock>produced from or allocated to Federal and Indian (except Osage) oil</textblock>
    <textblock>and gas leases wherein the gas is measured through sales or</textblock>
    <textblock>allocation meters handling 100 thousand cubic feet (Mcf) per day or</textblock>
    <textblock>less on a monthly basis are exempt from the standards in section</textblock>
    <textblock>III. C.1., C.2., D.10.a., D.10.b., and D.11.c. of this Order. The</textblock>
    <textblock>authorized officer may, where appropriate and necessary for proper</textblock>
    <textblock>measurement, work with the operators in designating consolidated</textblock>
    <textblock>gas sales and/or allocation meter stations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Meter installations constructed in accordance with the AGA</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee Report No. 3 standards in effect at that time shall not</textblock>
    <textblock>automatically be required to retrofit if the standards are</textblock>
    <textblock>revised. The Bureau will review any revised standards and, when</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary, will amend the Order through the rulemaking process.</textblock>
    <textblock>The intent of these minimum standards is to ensure that when</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment malfunctions occur that could result in inaccurate</textblock>
    <textblock>measurement, proper corrective actions are taken, the authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>officer is notified, and a report is submitted.</textblock>
    <textblock>Failure to comply with these minimum standards will be</textblock>
    <textblock>considered noncompliance and an incident of noncompliance (INC)</textblock>
    <textblock>will be issued. Operators who discover noncompliance with these</textblock>
    <textblock>minimum standards and take immediate corrective action will not</textblock>
    <textblock>be issued an INC. If the authorized officer or his</textblock>
    <textblock>representative is present when an operator discovers a</textblock>
    <textblock>malfunction or uses incorrect procedures as specified in this</textblock>
    <textblock>Order, an INC will be issued unless immediate corrective action</textblock>
    <textblock>is taken. Failure of equipment will not be considered a</textblock>
    <textblock>violation. However, the incidents of noncompliance which may</textblock>
    <textblock>result from equipment failure are considered violations. A</textblock>
    <textblock>partial list of such incidents follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Failure to install equipment properly.</textblock>
    <textblock>Failure to repair or correct equipment malfunction properly or</textblock>
    <textblock>in a timely manner.</textblock>
    <textblock>Failure to submit report of alternate method of sales.</textblock>
    <textblock>Failure to submit required reports in a timely manner.</textblock>
    <textblock>Failure to adhere to the minimum standard procedures specified</textblock>
    <textblock>in this Order.</textblock>
    <textblock>The use of improper equipment, when discovered, will be</textblock>
    <textblock>considered a violation and a formal INC will be issued.</textblock>
    <textblock>The use of improper procedures will be considered a violation</textblock>
    <textblock>and when witnessed by the authorized officer or his</textblock>
    <textblock>representative, immediate corrective action will be required. In</textblock>
    <textblock>the event that proper procedures are then used as required by</textblock>
    <textblock>this Order, and prior to completing the operation, calibration,</textblock>
    <textblock>or proving, the violation will be considered as properly</textblock>
    <textblock>corrected. In this case, although the violation will be</textblock>
    <textblock>documented in the agency files, no INC will be issued.</textblock>
    <textblock>The failure to take timely corrective action as required to</textblock>
    <textblock>meet any standard in this article will be considered either a</textblock>
    <textblock>major or minor violation in accordance with the classification</textblock>
    <textblock>set out below for each standard, unless an applicable variance</textblock>
    <textblock>has been granted or the standards have been otherwise modified in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with Article IV.</textblock>
    <textblock>A major violation, as defined in this Order, will generally</textblock>
    <textblock>require an immediate shut-in of the metering device. However,</textblock>
    <textblock>where the non-recoupable loss is not significant or where damage</textblock>
    <textblock>to the resource is likely to occur if a shut-in is required, an</textblock>
    <textblock>abatement period of 24 hours may be granted by the authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>officer or his representative.</textblock>
    <textblock>Where abatement is required ``prior to sales or removal,''</textblock>
    <textblock>action is required to be taken so that no gas can be removed</textblock>
    <textblock>beyond the measurement point until properly measured.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Primary Element_Orifice Meters</textblock>
    <textblock>The following are minimum standards for the measurement of</textblock>
    <textblock>natural gas using orifice meters.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. For meters measuring more than 100 Mcf per day on a monthly</textblock>
    <textblock>basis, the orifice to pipe diameter ratio (d/D), or the beta</textblock>
    <textblock>ratio, with meters using ``flange taps,'' shall be between 0.15 and</textblock>
    <textblock>0.70.</textblock>
    <textblock>Violation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Major.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
