<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00047</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>A number of the commenters believe that</textblock>
    <textblock>certain of our proposed changes at §§421.124 and 421.203</textblock>
    <textblock>are unnecessary. Those changes would allow the Secretary to</textblock>
    <textblock>take adverse action if an intermediary or carrier exceeds</textblock>
    <textblock>the amount the Secretary finds to be reasonable and adequate</textblock>
    <textblock>to meet the costs which must be incurred by an efficiently</textblock>
    <textblock>and economically operated intermediary or carrier,</textblock>
    <textblock>notwithstanding whether the intermediary or carrier meets</textblock>
    <textblock>the published criteria and standards. Both the intermediary</textblock>
    <textblock>and carrier contracts currently have a provision to allow</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary to request a committee of the contractors to</textblock>
    <textblock>assist in efforts to effect improvements in the high cost</textblock>
    <textblock>contractor's performance. In addition, the current</textblock>
    <textblock>Contractor Performance Evaluation Program (CPEP) contains</textblock>
    <textblock>measures on contractor costs. If a contractor fails to meet</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicable criteria, its CPEP score is reduced</textblock>
    <textblock>accordingly.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>We do not agree that the proposed changes</textblock>
    <textblock>are unnecessary. This section of the regulation would</textblock>
    <textblock>authorize us to take adverse action for deficient</textblock>
    <textblock>performance of a function not specifically evaluated by</textblock>
    <textblock>CPEP. Currently, CPEP only measures contractor performance</textblock>
    <textblock>in meeting the approved budget and the contractor's relative</textblock>
    <textblock>standing among similar contractors. Moreover, beginning in</textblock>
    <textblock>FY 1993, CPEP eliminated the concept of passing/failing the</textblock>
    <textblock>overall evaluation. Passing/failing now is determined on a</textblock>
    <textblock>standard by standard basis. For example, if a contractor</textblock>
    <textblock>fails to meet the approved budget, it will fail one standard</textblock>
    <textblock>in CPEP, not the entire CPEP. Thus, despite CPEP, the</textblock>
    <textblock>authority to take adverse contract action against high cost</textblock>
    <textblock>intermediaries and carriers is necessary. As the commenters</textblock>
    <textblock>note, current contracts allow the Secretary to request a</textblock>
    <textblock>committee of the contractors to assist in efforts to effect</textblock>
    <textblock>improvements in the high cost contractor's performance. The</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulatory change allows us to take the next</textblock>
    <textblock>logical step in the event efforts to effect improvement have</textblock>
    <textblock>failed. We will have authority to take adverse action based</textblock>
    <textblock>on continued high cost performance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>Several commenters stressed that the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§421.124 and §421.203 were vague. They asked that HCFA</textblock>
    <textblock>further define ``reasonable'' amount, and how and when high</textblock>
    <textblock>cost would be calculated.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>We believe that the provisions at §421.124</textblock>
    <textblock>and §421.203 are clear and straightforward. It is our</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility to consider the funding levels that are</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonable and adequate to meet the costs incurred by an</textblock>
    <textblock>efficiently and economically operated contractor. To</textblock>
    <textblock>address this responsibility, we develop unit cost targets</textblock>
    <textblock>for each contractor prior to the start of every fiscal year.</textblock>
    <textblock>These unit cost targets are forwarded to the HCFA regional</textblock>
    <textblock>offices as part of the Budget and Performance Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>(BPRs) package and represent the benchmark for the</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiations between the regional offices and the</textblock>
    <textblock>contractors.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
