<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00064</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00035</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>[BPD-795-NC]</textblock>
    <textblock>RIN: 0938-AG56</textblock>
    <textblock>Medicare Program; Schedule of Limits for Skilled Nursing</textblock>
    <textblock>Facility Inpatient Routine Service Costs</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock/>
  <rindock/>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Health Care Financing Administration (HCFA), HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final notice with comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This final notice with comment period provides that there will be no changes in the skilled nursing facility (SNF) cost limits for cost reporting periods beginning during Federal fiscal years 1994 and 1995 and that the add-on for administrative and general costs of hospital-based SNFs is eliminated. This notice announces provisions of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993 that affect the schedule of limits on SNF routine service costs for which payment may be made under the Medicare program and explains the effects of these provisions on the methodology used in calculating the SNF cost limits.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective date:</textblock>
    <textblock>The provisions set forth in this notice are effective for cost reporting periods beginning on or after October 1, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments will be considered if we receive them at the appropriate address, as provided below, no later than 5 p.m. on [March 7, 1994].</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mail written comments (1 original and 3 copies) to the following address:</textblock>
    <textblock>Health Care Financing Administration</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Health and Human Services</textblock>
    <textblock>Attention: BPD-795-NC, P.O. Box 7571,</textblock>
    <textblock>Baltimore Maryland 21207-0517.</textblock>
    <textblock>If you prefer, you may deliver your comments to</textblock>
    <textblock>one of the following addresses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 309-G, Hubert H. Humphrey Building,</textblock>
    <textblock>200 Independence Ave. SW.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington DC 20201, or</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 132, East High Rise Building</textblock>
    <textblock>6325 Security Boulevard</textblock>
    <textblock>Baltimore Maryland 21207.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because of staffing and resource limitations, we cannot accept comments by facsimile (FAX) transmission. In commenting, please refer to file code BPD-795-NC. Comments received timely will be available for public inspection as they are received, beginning approximately three weeks after publication of a document, in room 309-G of the Department's offices at 200 Independence Avenue SW., Washington DC, on Monday through Friday of each week from 8:30 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. (Phone: 202-690-7890).</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies:</textblock>
    <textblock>To order copies of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>containing this document, send your request to: New Orders,</textblock>
    <textblock>Superintendent of Documents, P.O. Box 371954, Pittsburgh, PA 15250-7954. Specify the date of the issue requested and enclose a check or money order payable to the Superintendent of Documents, or enclose your Visa or MasterCard number and expiration date. Credit card orders can also be placed by calling the order desk at (202) 783-3238 or by faxing to (202) 275-6802. The cost for each copy (in paper or microfiche form) is $4.50. As an alternative, you can view and photocopy the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>document at most libraries designated as U.S. Government Depository Libraries and at many other public and academic libraries throughout the country that receive the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Laurence Wilson, (410) 966-4603</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Background</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 1861(v)(1)(A) and 1888 of the Social Security Act (the Act) authorize the Secretary to set limits on allowable costs incurred by a provider of services for which payment may be made under Medicare. These limits are based on estimates of the costs necessary for the efficient delivery of needed health services. Implementing regulations appear at 42 CFR 413.30. Section 1888 of the Act directs the Secretary to set limits on per diem inpatient routine service costs for hospital-based and freestanding skilled nursing facilities (SNFs) by urban or rural area location. Section 4008(e)(2) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 (Pub. L. 101-508) amended section 1888(a) of the Act to require the Secretary to update the per diem SNF cost limits for cost reporting periods beginning on or after October 1, 1992, and every 2 years thereafter.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the authority of section 1888 of the Act, we published a final notice on October 7, 1992 (57 FR 46177) announcing a schedule of limits for freestanding and hospital-based SNFs effective for cost reporting periods beginning on or after October 1, 1992. The limits were computed using data from cost reporting periods ending on or after June 30, 1989, through May 31, 1990, for freestanding SNFs and from cost reporting periods ending on or after October 31, 1988, through September 30, 1989, for hospital-based SNFs.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
