<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00039</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00023</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>December 30, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Communications Commission has submitted the following information collection requirements to OMB for review and clearance under the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. 3507).</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of these submissions may be purchased from the Commission's copy contractor, International Transcription Service, Inc., 2100 M Street NW., suite 140, Washington, DC 20037, (202) 857-3800. For further information on these submissions contact Judy Boley, Federal Communications Commission, (202) 632-0276. Persons wishing to comment on these information collections should contact Timothy Fain, Office of Management and Budget, room 3235 NEOB, Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-3561.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>3060-0176.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 73.1510, Experimental Authorizations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension of a currently approved collection.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Businesses or other for-profit (including small businesses).</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>On occasion reporting requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Annual Burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>25 responses; 2.96 hours average burden per response; 74 hours total annual burden.</textblock>
    <textblock>Needs and Uses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 73.1510 requires that a licensee of an AM, FM and TV broadcast station file an informal application with the FCC to request an experimental authorization to conduct technical experimentation directed toward improvement of the technical phases of operation and service. This request shall describe the nature and purpose of experimentation to be conducted, the nature of the experimental signal to be transmitted, and the proposed schedule of hours and duration of the experimentation. The data is used by FCC staff to maintain complete technical information about a broadcast station and to ensure that such experimentation will not cause interference to other stations.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>3060-0181.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 73.1615, Operation During Modification of Facilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension of a currently approved collection.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Businesses or other for-profit (including small businesses).</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>On occasion reporting requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Annual Burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>160 responses; 0.69 hour average burden per response; 110 hours total annual burden.</textblock>
    <textblock>Needs and Uses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 73.1615 requires notification to the FCC by a licensee of an AM, FM or TV station when it is in the process of modifying existing facilities as authorized by a construction permit and it becomes necessary to either discontinue operation or to operate with temporary facilities. If such licensee needs to discontinue operations or operate with temporary facilities for more than 30 days, then an informal letter request must be sent to the FCC prior to the 30th day. The data is used by FCC staff to maintain complete technical records and to ensure that interference will not be caused to other licensed broadcast facilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL COMMUNICATIONS COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Public Information Collection Requirements Submitted to Office of Management and Budget for Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William F. Caton,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-212 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
