<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00121</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Service has carefully assessed the best scientific and</textblock>
    <textblock>commercial information available regarding the past, present, and future</textblock>
    <textblock>threats faced by this species in determining to propose this rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sacramento splittail have declined by 62 percent over the last 15 years.</textblock>
    <textblock>This species has been extirpated from portions of its range. In the</textblock>
    <textblock>Estuary during the past 2 decades, the entrapment zone, associated with</textblock>
    <textblock>the important nurseries for splittail, has been more frequently shifted</textblock>
    <textblock>upstream to a confined area of greater depth as a result of drought</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions, water management schedules, and the continual and increasing</textblock>
    <textblock>demand for water exports and diversions. These factors will continue to</textblock>
    <textblock>adversely affect all life stages of splittail.</textblock>
    <textblock>Threatened status is proposed for the Sacramento splittail because</textblock>
    <textblock>of several factors. The population has declined by 62 percent within 15</textblock>
    <textblock>years. The historical and current range of the species is constricted.</textblock>
    <textblock>Changes in water salinity and the reverse flow of water has shifted the</textblock>
    <textblock>distribution of individuals upstream and has caused the fish to be</textblock>
    <textblock>vulnerable to State and Federal pumping plants. The death of these fish</textblock>
    <textblock>due to pumping continues at present and is likely to continue in the</textblock>
    <textblock>future. Water exports also threaten the quality and quantity of habitat</textblock>
    <textblock>at present and for the future. Because Sacramento splittail are long-lived, their decline has been gradual, and extinction is not imminent,</textblock>
    <textblock>listing the splittail as endangered would not be appropriate. Although</textblock>
    <textblock>this species is not in imminent danger of extinction at this time, it is</textblock>
    <textblock>likely to become endangered in the foreseeable future.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, based on the evaluation of all available information on</textblock>
    <textblock>abundance, present distribution, and threats to this species, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Service has determined that proposing to list the Sacramento splittail</textblock>
    <textblock>as threatened is appropriate at this time. Critical habitat is not</textblock>
    <textblock>determinable for reasons discussed in the ``Critical Habitat'' section of</textblock>
    <textblock>this rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Critical Habitat</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 4(a)(3) of the Act requires that, to the maximum extent</textblock>
    <textblock>prudent and determinable, the Secretary propose critical habitat</textblock>
    <textblock>concurrently with proposing a species to be endangered or threatened.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service finds that designation of critical habitat for the</textblock>
    <textblock>Sacramento splittail is not determinable at this time. Regulations at</textblock>
    <textblock>50 CFR 424.12(a)(2) state that critical habitat is not determinable if</textblock>
    <textblock>information sufficient to perform required analyses of the impacts of</textblock>
    <textblock>the designation is lacking or if the biological needs of the species are</textblock>
    <textblock>not sufficiently known to permit identification of an area of critical</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat. The Service's efforts to gather information on the potential</textblock>
    <textblock>benefits of designating critical habitat for splittail may lead to the</textblock>
    <textblock>conclusion that designation of critical habitat is not prudent.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations at 50 CFR 424.12(a)(1) state that a designation of critical</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat is not prudent when the species is threatened by taking or other</textblock>
    <textblock>human activity, and identification of critical habitat can be expected</textblock>
    <textblock>to increase the degree of such threat to the species, or when such</textblock>
    <textblock>designation would not be beneficial to the species.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
