<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00002</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Special Conditions; Pratt &amp; Whitney Model(s) PW4073 and PW4084 Turbofan Engines</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 33</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93-ANE-66; Notice No. 33-ANE-05]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of proposed special conditions.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice proposes special conditions for the Pratt &amp; Whitney (PW) Model(s) PW4073 and PW4048 turbofan engines. The applicable regulations do not contain adequate or appropriate safety standards for the protection of these systems from medium and large bird ingestion. This notice proposes the additional safety standards which the Administrator considers necessary to establish a level of safety equivalent to that established by the airworthiness standards for aircraft engines of the Federal Aviation Regulations (FAR).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be submitted on or before February 22, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this proposal may be submitted in triplicate to: Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), New England Region, Office of the Assistant Chief Counsel, Attn: Rules Docket No. 93-ANE-66, 12 New England Executive Park, Burlington, Massachusetts 01803-5299. Comments must be marked: Docket No. 93-ANE-66. Comments may be inspected at this location between 8 a.m. and 4:30 p.m., Monday through Friday, except Federal holidays.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>John Golinski, Engine and Propeller Standards Staff, ANE-110, Engine and Propeller Directorate, Aircraft Certificate Service, FAA, New England Region, 12 New England Executive Park, Burlington, Massachusetts 01803-5229; telephone (617) 238-7119; fax (617) 238-7199.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments Invited</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to participate in the making of the proposed special conditions by submitting such written data, views, or arguments as they may desire. Communications should identify the Rules Docket number and be submitted in triplicate to the address specified under ``ADDRESSES.</textblock>
    <textblock>'' All communications received on or before the closing date for comments, specified under ``</textblock>
    <textblock>DATES</textblock>
    <textblock>,'' will be considered by the Administrator before taking action on the proposal. The proposal contained in this notice may be changed in light of the comments received.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments are specifically invited on the overall regulatory, economic environmental, and energy aspects of the proposed special conditions. All comment submitted will be available in the Rules Docket for examination by interested persons, both before and after the closing date for comments. A report summarizing each substantive public contact with FAA personnel concerning this proposal will be filed in the docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Commenters wishing the FAA to acknowledge receipt of their comments submitted in response to this notice must submit with those comments a self-addressed, stamped postcard on which the following statement is made: ``Comments to Docket No. 93-ANE-66.'' The postcard will be date stamped and returned to the commenter.</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 10, 1990, Pratt &amp; Whitney applied for type certification of PW Model(s) PW4073 and PW4084 turbofan engines. The FAA has determined that the current foreign object ingestion requirements of §33.77(a) for four pound birds; and §33.77(b) for one and one-half pound flocking birds, do not adequately represent the bird threat encountered in service. A study of in-service bird ingestion events has indicated a need to modify the bird ingestion requirements of this section to ensure design integrity and demonstrate an adequate level of safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA has concluded that additional safety standards must be applied to Pratt &amp; Whitney Model(s) PW4073 and PW4048 turbofan engines to demonstrate that they are capable of acceptable operation after medium and large bird ingestion. The applicable airworthiness requirements do not contain adequate or appropriate safety standards for type certification with respect to the new design criteria. This new design criteria assumes the actual bird threat encountered in service.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Certification Basis</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the provisions of §21.101 of the FAR, Pratt &amp; Whitney must show that the PW Model(s) PW4073 and PW4084 turbofan engines meet the requirements of the applicable regulations in effect on the date of the application. Those Federal Aviation Regulations are §21.21 and part 33, effective February 1, 1965, as amended through August 10, 1990, Amendment 33-14.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Administrator finds that the applicable airworthiness regulations in part 33, as amended, do not contain adequate or appropriate safety standards for the PW Model(s) PW4073 and PW4084 turbofan engines because of its unique design criteria. Therefore, the Administrator proposes these special conditions under the provisions of §21.16 to establish a level of safety equivalent to that established in the regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Special conditions, as appropriate, are issued in accordance with §11.49 of the FAR after public notice and opportunity for comment, as required by §§11.28 and 11.29(b), and become part of the type certification basis in accordance with §21.101(b)(2).</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
