<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00117</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00066</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>OFFICE OF MANAGEMENT AND BUDGET</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Rescission of OMB Circular A-120, Guidelines for the Use of Advisory and Assistance Services; Correction</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Management and Budget (OMB), Executive Office of the President.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Correction.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document contains a correction to the notice of rescission of OMB Circular No. A-120, Guidelines for the Use of Advisory and Assistance Services, which was published Thursday, December 2, 1993 (58 FR 63593). The Transmittal Memorandum No. 1 was inadvertently left out of the document submitted for publication. The test of Transmittal Memorandum No. 1 follows.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Linda G. Williams, Deputy Associate Administrator, (202) 395-3502. To obtain a copy of Transmittal Memorandum No. 1, please call the Executive Office of the President's Publications Office at (202) 395-7332.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 28, 1993.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John B. Arthur,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Director for Administration.</textblock>
    <textblock>November 19, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Circular No. A-120</textblock>
    <textblock>Transmittal Memorandum No. 1</textblock>
    <textblock>To the Heads of Executive Departments and Establishments</textblock>
    <textblock>Subject: Guidelines for the Use of Advisory and Assistance Services</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Circular No. A-120, ``Guidelines for the Use of Advisory and Assistance Services,'' dated January 4, 1988, is hereby rescinded. Executive departments and agencies are no longer required to comply with the management controls and reporting requirements of the Circular.</textblock>
    <textblock>Guidance contained in the Circular has been revised and incorporated into other policy documents, as appropriate. Those documents include: (1) Office of Federal Procurement Policy (OFPP) Policy Letter 93-1 on ``Management Oversight of Service Contracting,'' (2) OFPP Policy Letter 92-1 on ``Inherently Governmental Functions,'' (3) OFPP Policy Letter 91-2 on ``Service Contracting,'' (4) OFPP Policy Letter 89-1 on ``Conflicts of Interest Applicable to Consultants,'' (5) OMB Circular A-76 on ``Performance of Commercial Activities,'' and (6) OFPP's Guidance on Contract Administration. To obtain a copy of these documents, please call the Executive Office of the President's Publication Office at (202) 395-7332.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Leon E. Panetta,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-110 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3110-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
