<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00005</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Special Conditions; Rolls-Royce Model(s) RB211-Trent-875-17/-877-17/-884-17 Turbofan Engines</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 33</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93-ANE-67; Notice No. 33-ANE-06]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of proposed special conditions.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice proposes special conditions for the Rolls-Royce Aircraft Engines Model(s) RB211-Trent-875-17/-877-17/-884-17 Turbofan Engines. The applicable regulations do not contain adequate or appropriate safety standards for the protection of these systems from water and hail ingestion. This notice proposes the additional safety standards which the Administrator considers necessary to establish a level of safety equivalent to that established by the airworthiness standards of part 33 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (FAR).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be submitted on or before February 22, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this proposal may be submitted in triplicate to: Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), New England Region, Office of the Assistant Chief Counsel, Attn: Rules Docket No. 93-ANE-67, 12 New England Executive Park, Burlington, Massachusetts 01803-5299. Comments must be marked: Docket No. 93-ANE-67. Comments may be inspected at this location between 8 a.m. and 4:30 p.m., Monday through Friday, except Federal holidays.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Thomas Boudreau, Engine and Propeller Standards Staff, ANE-110, Engine and Propeller Directorate, Aircraft Certification Service, FAA, New England Region, 12 New England Executive Park, Burlington, Massachusetts 01803-5229; telephone (617) 238-7117; fax (617) 238-7199.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments Invited</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to participate in the making of the proposed special conditions by submitting such written data, views, or arguments as they may desire. Communications should identify the Rules Docket number and be submitted in triplicate to the address specified under ADDRESSES.</textblock>
    <textblock>All communications received on or before the closing date for comments, specified under</textblock>
    <textblock>DATES,</textblock>
    <textblock>will be considered by the Administrator before taking action on the proposal. The proposal contained in this notice may be changed in light of the comments received.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments are specifically invited on the overall regulatory, economic, environmental, and energy aspects of the proposed special conditions. All comments submitted will be available in the Rules Docket for examination by interested persons, both before and after the closing date for comments. A report summarizing each substantive public contact with FAA personnel concerning this proposal will be filed in the docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Commenters wishing the FAA to acknowledge receipt of their comments submitted in response to this notice must submit with those comments a self-addressed, stamped postcard on which the following statement is made: ``Comments to Docket No. 93-ANE-67.'' The postcard will be date stamped and returned to the commenter.</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On August 4, 1992, Rolls-Royce applied for type certification of Model(s) RB211-Trent-870-17/-877-17/-884-17 turbofan engines. The application for type certification of the Model RB211-Trent-870-17 turbofan engine was withdrawn and a new application for type certification of the Model RB211-Trent-875-17 was made on April 6, 1993. The FAA has determined that the current water and hail ingestion requirements of §33.77(c) of the FAR do not represent the inclement weather threat encountered in service.</textblock>
    <textblock>A study of in-service inclement weather events has indicated a need to modify the water and hail ingestion requirements of this section to ensure design integrity and demonstrate an adequate level of safety. This study indicated that a potential flight safety threat existed for engines when operating in severe weather environments. Although current requirements provide adequate validation of the engine's resistance to mechanical damage due to hail impact and case contractions from water ingestion, the study showed that the current standards did not adequately address engine power loss anomalies, such as rollback and flameout at lower than take off rated power settings.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA has concluded that additional safety standards must be applied to Rolls-Royce Model(s) RB211-Trent-875-17/-877-17/-884-17 turbofan engines to demonstrate that they are capable of acceptable operation in severe weather environments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type Certification Basis</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the provisions of §21.101 of the FAR, Rolls-Royce must show that Model(s) RB211-Trent-875-17/-877-17/-884-17 turbofan engines meet the requirements of the applicable regulations in effect on the date of the application. Those Federal Aviation Regulations are §21.21 and Part 33, effective February 1, 1965, as amended through August 10, 1990, Amendment 33-14.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Administrator finds that the applicable airworthiness regulations in part 33, as amended, do not contain adequate or appropriate safety standards for Rolls-Royce Model(s) RB211-Trent-875-17/-877-17/-884-17 turbofan engines because of unique design criteria. Therefore, the Administrator proposes these special conditions under the provisions of §21.16 to establish a level of safety equivalent to that established in the regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Special conditions, as appropriate, are issued in accordance with §11.49 of the FAR after public notice and opportunity for comment, as required by §§11.28 and 11.29(b), and become part of the type certification basis in accordance with §21.101(b)(2).</textblock>
    <textblock>Conclusion</textblock>
    <textblock>This action affects only Rolls-Royce Model(s) RB211-Trent-875-17/-877-17/-884-17 turbofan engines. It is not a rule of general applicability and affects only the manufacturer who applied to the FAA for approval of these new design criteria on the engine.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 14 CFR Part 33</textblock>
    <textblock>Air transportation, Aircraft, Aviation safety, Safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>The authority citation for these special conditions continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>49 U.S.C. App. 1354(a), 1421, 1423; and 49 U.S.C. 106(g).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Proposed Special Conditions</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) proposes the following special conditions as part of the type certification basis for the Rolls-Royce Model(s) RB211-Trent-875-17/-877-17/-884-17 turbofan engines.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
