<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00069</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(11) It is unlawful for any person to take and retain, possess, or land groundfish in excess of the landing limit for the open-access fishery without having a valid limited-entry permit for the vessel affixed with a gear endorsement for the gear used to catch the fish. (50 CFR 663.7(t))</textblock>
    <textblock>(12) The following provisions that are not covered under the headings ``limited-entry'' or ``open-access'' apply to all vessels that take and retain groundfish unless otherwise stated.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Widow Rockfish</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Limited-entry Fishery.</textblock>
    <textblock>No more than 30,000 pounds (13,608 kg) cumulative of widow rockfish may be taken and retained, possessed, or landed per vessel per month. (Widow rockfish are also called brownies.)</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Open-access Fishery.</textblock>
    <textblock>See section G. Of the 40,000 pound (18,144 kg) monthly cumulative trip limit for rockfish taken in the open-access fishery, no more than 30,000 pounds (13,608 kg) may be widow rockfish.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Sebastes Complex (Including Yellowtail and Bocaccio Rockfish)</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>General.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Sebastes</textblock>
    <textblock>complex means all rockfish managed by the FMP except Pacific ocean perch (</textblock>
    <textblock>Sebastes alutus</textblock>
    <textblock>), widow rockfish (</textblock>
    <textblock>S. entomelas</textblock>
    <textblock>), shortbelly rockfish (</textblock>
    <textblock>S. jordani</textblock>
    <textblock>), and</textblock>
    <textblock>Sebastolobus</textblock>
    <textblock>spp. (also called thornyheads, idiot, or channel rockfish). Yellowtail rockfish (</textblock>
    <textblock>S. flavidus</textblock>
    <textblock>) are commonly called greenies. Bocaccio (</textblock>
    <textblock>S. paucispinis</textblock>
    <textblock>) are commonly called rock salmon.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Cape Lookout means 45</textblock>
    <textblock>○20</textblock>
    <textblock>’15</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N. latitude.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Cape Mendocino means 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>’00</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N. latitude.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Limited-entry fishery.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Cumulative trip limits.</textblock>
    <textblock>Coastwide, no more than 80,000 pounds (36,287 kg) cumulative of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Sebastes</textblock>
    <textblock>complex may be taken and retained, possessed or landed per vessel per month. Within this 80,000 pounds (36,287 kg), no more then 14,000 pounds (6,350 kg) cumulative may be yellowtail rockfish taken and retained north of Cape Lookout; no more than 30,000 pounds (13,608 kg) cumulative may be yellowtail rockfish taken and retained south of Cape Lookout; and no more than 30,000 pounds (13,608 kg) cumulative may be bocaccio taken and retained south of Cape Mendocino.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The provisions of this paragraph (b) apply unless declarations are made according to paragraph (c) below. If any vessel transits through or fishes in the area north of Cape Lookout during a month, then that vessel is subject to the trip limit for yellowtail rockfish taken and retained north of Cape Lookout, no matter where the fish are possessed or landed. Similarly, if a vessel takes and retains yellowtail rockfish south of Cape Lookout and possesses or lands yellowtail rockfish north of Cape Lookout during a month, that vessel is subject to the northern trip limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>State declarations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The States of Oregon and Washington are implementing declaration procedures that enable a vessel that fishes or transits both north and south of Cape Lookout during a month to retain the 30,000 pound (13,608 kg) cumulative limit for yellowtail rockfish south of Cape Lookout. For any vessel that takes and retains or lands yellowtail rockfish during the month, a declaration must be filed for each fishing trip that crosses the line at Cape Lookout during that month, must be made before leaving port on the fishing trip, and may not be changed once the vessel has left port. Declarations must be made, according to State law, to the state where the fish will be landed. To make a declaration or for further information, contact: Washington Department of Fisheries, Montesano, WA, at 206-249-4628; or Oregon Department of Fish and Wildlife, Newport, OR, at 503-867-4741.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) A vessel under a northern trip declaration may not exceed the northern limit during a single trip, nor may the cumulative catch of all northern declared trips exceed the northern cumulative limit. The total cumulative catch for the month may not exceed the southern limit, no matter where the fish are caught.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A vessel under a southern trip declaration may not fish for any groundfish north of Cape Lookout during the fishing trip for which the declaration is made; otherwise, the northern trip limit would apply. A vessel under a southern trip declaration may not exceed the southern trip limit during a single trip, nor may the cumulative catch of all southern declared trips exceed the southern cumulative limit. The total cumulative catch for the month may not exceed the southern limit, no matter where the fish are caught.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) If any vessel is used to fish south of Cape Mendocino during the month, then the vessel is subject to the trip limit for bocaccio taken and retained south of Cape Mendocino, no matter where the fish are possessed or landed. Similarly, if a vessel is used to take and retain bocaccio north of Cape Mendocino and possesses or lands bocaccio south of Cape Mendocino, that vessel is subject to the southern trip limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Open-access Fishery.</textblock>
    <textblock>See section G. Of the 40,000 pound (18,144 kg) monthly cumulative trip limit for rockfish taken in the open-access fishery, no more than 14,000 pounds (6,350 kg) cumulative may be yellowtail rockfish caught north of Cape Lookout, no more than 30,000 pounds (13,608 kg) cumulative may be yellowtail rockfish caught south of Cape Lookout, and no more than 30,000 pounds (13,608 kg) cumulative may be bocaccio caught south of Cape Mendocino. The State declaration procedures apply to all vessels, whether in the limited-entry or open-access fishery.</textblock>
    <textblock>D.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pacific Ocean Perch (POP)</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Limited-entry Fishery.</textblock>
    <textblock>The trip limit for Pacific ocean perch coastwide is 3,000 pounds (1,361 kg) or 20 percent of all legal fish on board, whichever is less. If less than 1,000 pounds (454 kg) of Pacific ocean perch are landed, the 20 percent limit does not apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>Twenty percent of all legal fish on board including Pacific ocean perch is equivalent to 25 percent of all legal groundfish on board other than Pacific ocean perch.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Open-access Fishery.</textblock>
    <textblock>See section G. Within the 10,000 pound (4,536 kg) trip limit for rockfish taken in the open-access fishery, no more than 3,000 pounds (1,361 kg) or 20 percent of all legal fish on board, whichever is less, may be POP. If less than 1,000 pounds (454 kg) of Pacific ocean perch are landed, the 20 percent limit does not apply.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
