<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00036</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Discussion of Regulation</textblock>
    <textblock>The circumstances creating the need for this regulation is information received by Chevron and by the Coast Guard that vessels intend to protest and possibly interfere with drilling operations at this site. This is the first site at which drilling will begin in this particular area, which has been a subject of controversy. Precautionary measures for safety at a drilling site require that the structure and waters around it be maintained free of interference and traffic in order to allow for immediate evacuation of personnel aboard the structure and by attending vessels in case of emergency. The establishment of a safety zone will prevent non-attending vessels from remaining in close proximity to the offshore structure and hindering any necessary evacuation of the area.</textblock>
    <textblock>The final rule amends part 147 to add a temporary safety zone around the Chevron Well</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>1, Destin Dome</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>97, which is about 27 miles south of Pensacola, Florida. The regulation contains a description of the area of the safety zone, including the location of the center of the structure and information pertinent to the safety zone. The regulations restrict the entry of vessels into the safety zone, except for attending vessels and those vessels authorized by the Commander, Eighth Coast Guard District.</textblock>
    <textblock>Economic Assessment and Certification</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulation is not considered a significant regulatory action under Executive Order 12866 and is nonsignificant under Department of Transportation regulatory policies and procedures (44 FR 11034; February 26, 1979). The economic impact has been found to be so minimal that a full regulatory evaluation is unnecessary. The Coast Guard certifies that this regulation will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federalism Assessment</textblock>
    <textblock>This action has been analyzed in accordance with the principles and criteria contained in Executive Order 12612, and it has been determined that this rulemaking does not raise sufficient federalism implications to warrant the preparation of a Federalism Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Assessment</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard has considered the environmental impact of this regulation and concluded that under section 2.B.2.c of Commandant Instruction M16475.1B, it will have no significant environmental impact and it is categorically excluded from further environmental documentation. A Categorical Exclusion Determination is available in the docket for examination or a copy may be obtained by contracting the person identified under ``</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT.</textblock>
    <textblock>''</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The rule contains no information collection or recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 33 CFR Part 147</textblock>
    <textblock>Continental shelf, Marine safety, Navigation (water).</textblock>
    <textblock>Final Regulation</textblock>
    <textblock>In consideration of the foregoing, part 147 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations, is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 147_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for this part is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>43 U.S.C. 1333 as amended; 49 CFR 1.46.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. A new §147.T801 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§147.T801</textblock>
    <textblock>Safety Zone: Chevron</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>1 Well at Destin Dome</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>97.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Description.</textblock>
    <textblock>The area within a line 500 meters from each point on the structure's outer edge. The position of the center of the structure is 29</textblock>
    <textblock>○51</textblock>
    <textblock>’57.91</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N, 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○20</textblock>
    <textblock>’07.74</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective date.</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulation becomes effective November 3, 1993. It terminates on September 1, 1994, unless sooner terminated by Commander, Eighth Coast Guard District.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulation.</textblock>
    <textblock>No vessel may enter or remain in this safety zone except the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) An attending vessel or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A vessel authorized by the Commander, Eighth Coast Guard District.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: November 3, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>J.C. Card,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Rear Admiral, U.S. Coast Guard Commander, Eighth Coast Guard District.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-264 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-14-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
