<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00120</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>E. Other natural or manmade factors affecting its continued</textblock>
    <textblock>existence</textblock>
    <textblock>Splittail are vulnerable to extinction from stochastic</textblock>
    <textblock>events because of the consistent decline in population indices and</textblock>
    <textblock>severely constricted ranges and distribution.</textblock>
    <textblock>Poor water quality also may adversely affect splittail, either</textblock>
    <textblock>through direct exposure to toxins or depletion of zooplankton or</textblock>
    <textblock>invertebrate food sources. All major rivers that are tributary to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Estuary are exposed to large volumes of agricultural and industrial</textblock>
    <textblock>chemicals that are applied in the Central Valley watershed (Nichols et</textblock>
    <textblock>al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1986). Agricultural chemicals and their residues, as well as</textblock>
    <textblock>chemicals originating in urban runoff, find their way into the rivers</textblock>
    <textblock>and Estuary. Approximately 10 percent of the total pesticide use in the</textblock>
    <textblock>United States occurs in the Sacramento and San Joaquin River watersheds,</textblock>
    <textblock>primarily on orchards, alfalfa, and rice during the months of January to</textblock>
    <textblock>June of each year (Jewel Bennett, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service,</textblock>
    <textblock>in</textblock>
    <textblock>litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993). Recently, high concentrations of organophosphate and</textblock>
    <textblock>carbamate pesticides from agricultural uses have been documented</textblock>
    <textblock>entering the Estuary. These pesticides are acutely toxic to zooplankton</textblock>
    <textblock>and fishes as far west as Martinez in Suisun Bay and as far south as</textblock>
    <textblock>Vernalis on the San Joaquin River (Bennett,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993). The</textblock>
    <textblock>periods of pesticide use coincide with the timing of migration,</textblock>
    <textblock>spawning, and early development of splittail. During rainfall runoff</textblock>
    <textblock>events, acutely toxic pulses of pesticides move down the rivers and</textblock>
    <textblock>through the Estuary with remarkable persistence and relatively little</textblock>
    <textblock>dilution.</textblock>
    <textblock>Toxicology studies of rice field irrigation drain water of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Colusa Basin Drainage Canal have documented significant toxicity of</textblock>
    <textblock>drain water to striped bass embryos and larvae,</textblock>
    <textblock>Oryzias latipes</textblock>
    <textblock>larvae</textblock>
    <textblock>(in the Cyprinodontidae family), and the opossum shrimp, which is the</textblock>
    <textblock>major food organism of striped bass larvae and juveniles (Bailey</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1991). This drainage canal flows into the Sacramento River just north</textblock>
    <textblock>of the City of Sacramento. The majority of drain water samples</textblock>
    <textblock>collected during April and May 1990 were acutely toxic to striped bass</textblock>
    <textblock>larvae (96 hour exposures); this was the third consecutive year that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Colusa Basin rice irrigation drain water was acutely toxic (Bailey</textblock>
    <textblock>et</textblock>
    <textblock>al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1991). Splittail may be similarly affected by agricultural and</textblock>
    <textblock>industrial chemical run-off.</textblock>
    <textblock>Some heavy metal contaminants have been released into the Estuary</textblock>
    <textblock>from industrial and mining enterprises. While the effects of these</textblock>
    <textblock>contaminating compounds on splittail larvae and their zooplankton food</textblock>
    <textblock>resources are not well known, the compounds could adversely affect</textblock>
    <textblock>survival. In addition, increases in urban development in the Sacramento</textblock>
    <textblock>Valley will continue to result in concurrent increases in urban runoff.</textblock>
    <textblock>Selenium has been found in aquatic organisms (Saiki and Lowe 1987) and</textblock>
    <textblock>fish species in the San Joaquin River watershed (Nakamoto and Hassler</textblock>
    <textblock>1992). Selenium has been shown to cause developmental defects in and</textblock>
    <textblock>mortality of fish species (Hermanutz 1992).</textblock>
    <textblock>In recent years, untreated discharges of ship ballast water has</textblock>
    <textblock>introduced exotic aquatic species to the Estuary ecosystem (Carlton</textblock>
    <textblock>et</textblock>
    <textblock>al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1990). Several exotic species may adversely affect the splittail.</textblock>
    <textblock>An asian clam (</textblock>
    <textblock>Potamocorbula amurensis),</textblock>
    <textblock>introduced as veliger larvae in</textblock>
    <textblock>1986, was first discovered in Suisun Bay during October 1986. By June</textblock>
    <textblock>1987, the Asian clam was widespread in Suisun, San Pablo, and San</textblock>
    <textblock>Francisco Bays irrespective of salinity, water depth, and sediment type</textblock>
    <textblock>at densities greater than 10,000 individuals per square meter. Asian</textblock>
    <textblock>clam densities declined to 4,000 individuals per square meter as the</textblock>
    <textblock>population aged during the year (Carlton</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1990). Persistently low</textblock>
    <textblock>river outflow and concomitant elevated salinity levels may have</textblock>
    <textblock>contributed to this species' population explosion (Carlton</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1990).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Asian clam could potentially play an important role in affecting the</textblock>
    <textblock>phytoplankton dynamics in the Estuary. The clam may have an effect on</textblock>
    <textblock>higher trophic levels by decreasing phytoplankton biomass.</textblock>
    <textblock>Historically,</textblock>
    <textblock>Eurytemora affinis,</textblock>
    <textblock>the native euryhaline copepod,</textblock>
    <textblock>has been the most important food for larval fishes in the Estuary.</textblock>
    <textblock>Three non-native species of euryhaline copepods (</textblock>
    <textblock>Sinocalanus doerrii,</textblock>
    <textblock>Pseudodiaptomus forbesi,</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>Pseudodiaptomus marinus)</textblock>
    <textblock>became established</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Delta between 1978 and 1987 (Carlton</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1990), while E.</textblock>
    <textblock>affinis</textblock>
    <textblock>populations have declined since 1980. It is not known if the</textblock>
    <textblock>exotic species have displaced</textblock>
    <textblock>E. affinis</textblock>
    <textblock>or whether changes in the</textblock>
    <textblock>estuarine ecosystem now favor</textblock>
    <textblock>S. doerrii</textblock>
    <textblock>and the two</textblock>
    <textblock>Pseudodiaptomus</textblock>
    <textblock>species (Moyle</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1989).</textblock>
    <textblock>S. doerrii</textblock>
    <textblock>is difficult for larval fishes</textblock>
    <textblock>to catch because of its fast swimming and effective escape response</textblock>
    <textblock>(Meng and Orsi 1991). Reduced feeding efficiency and ingestion rates</textblock>
    <textblock>weaken and slow the growth of splittail young and make them more</textblock>
    <textblock>vulnerable to starvation or predation.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
