<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>December 29, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>COMMITTEE FOR THE IMPLEMENTATION OF TEXTILE AGREEMENTS</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Adjustment of Import Limits for Certain Cotton and Man-Made Fiber Textile Products Produced or Manufactured in Brazil</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements (CITA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Issuing a directive to the Commissioner of Customs reducing limits.</textblock>
  </action>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nicole Bivens Collinson, International Trade Specialist, Office of Textiles and Apparel, U.S. Department of Commerce, (202) 482-4212. For information on the quota status of these limits, refer to the Quota Status Reports posted on the bulletin boards of each Customs port or call (202) 927-5850. For information on embargoes and quota re-openings, call (202) 482-3715.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 11651 of March 3, 1972, as amended; section 204 of the Agricultural Act of 1956, as amended (7 U.S.C. 1854).</textblock>
    <textblock>The current limits for Categories 218 and 350 are being reduced for carryforward used.</textblock>
    <textblock>A description of the textile and apparel categories in terms of HTS numbers is available in the CORRELATION: Textile and Apparel Categories with the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (see</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice 57 FR 54976, published on November 23, 1992). Also see 58 FR 14381, published on March 17, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>The letter to the Commissioner of Customs and the actions taken pursuant to it are not designed to implement all of the provisions of the bilateral agreement, but are designed to assist only in the implementation of certain of its provisions.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rita D. Hayes,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements</textblock>
    <textblock>December 29, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Commissioner of Customs,</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Treasury, Washington, DC 20229.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dear Commissioner: This directive amends, but does not cancel, the directive issued to you on March 12, 1993, by the Chairman, Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements. That directive concerns imports of certain cotton, wool and man-made fiber textile products, produced or manufactured in Brazil and exported during the twelve-month period which began on April 1, 1993 and extends through March 31, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective on January 10, 1994, you are directed to amend the directive dated March 12, 1993 to reduce the limits for the following categories, as provided under the terms of the current bilateral agreement between the Governments of the United States and the Federative Republic of Brazil:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements has determined that these actions fall within the foreign affairs exception to the rulemaking provisions of 5 U.S.C. 553(a)(1).</textblock>
    <textblock>Sincerely,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <table>
    <textblock>1Category</textblock>
    <textblock>1Adjusted twelve-month limit1</textblock>
    <textblock>Sublevels in the aggregate</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>218</textblock>
    <textblock>4,261,627 square meters.</textblock>
    <textblock>350</textblock>
    <textblock>127,310 dozen.</textblock>
    <textblock>1The limits have not been adjusted to account for any imports exported after March 31, 1993.</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rita D. Hayes,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-198 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DR-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
