<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00027</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>15. Section 295.21 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§295.21</textblock>
    <textblock>Qualification of applicants.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Assistance under this subpart is available to industry-led joint research and development ventures only, subject to the limitations set out in §295.3 of these regulations. These ventures may include universities, independent research organizations, and governmental entities; however, the Program will not provide funding directly to any university or governmental organization.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Applications for funding under this subpart may be submitted on behalf of an industry-led joint research and development venture by one or more businesses or independent research organizations that are members of the venture. Applications must, however, include letters of commitment from all proposed members of the venture, verifying the availability of matching funds, and authorizing the party or parties submitting the proposal to act on behalf of the venture with the Program on all matters pertaining to the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>16. Section 295.22 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§295.22</textblock>
    <textblock>Limitations on assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>An award will be made under this subpart only if the award will facilitate the formation of a joint venture or the initiation of a new research and development project by an existing joint venture.</textblock>
    <textblock>17. Section 295.24 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§295.24</textblock>
    <textblock>Registration.</textblock>
    <textblock>Joint research and development ventures selected for funding must notify the Department of Justice or the Federal Trade Commission under the National Cooperative Research Act of 1984. No funds will be released prior to receipt by the Program of copies of such notification.</textblock>
    <textblock>18. The heading for subpart C is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart C_Assistance to Single-Applicant U.S. Businesses</textblock>
    <textblock>19. Section 295.30 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§295.30</textblock>
    <textblock>Types of assistance available.</textblock>
    <textblock>This subpart describes the types of assistance that may be provided under the authority of 15 U.S.C. 278n(b)(2). Such assistance includes but is not limited to entering into cooperative agreements with United States businesses, especially small businesses.</textblock>
    <textblock>20. Section 295.31 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§295.31</textblock>
    <textblock>Qualification of applicants.</textblock>
    <textblock>Awards under this subpart will be available to all businesses, subject to the limitations set out in §295.3 of these regulations. The Program will not directly provide funding under this subpart to any governmental entity, academic institution or independent research organization.</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-69 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
