<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00061</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00034</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>II. Provisions of This Final Notice With Comment Period</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Elimination of the A&amp;G Add-on</textblock>
    <textblock>On August 10, 1993, the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993 (OBRA '93), Public Law 103-66, was enacted. Section 13564(b) of OBRA '93 amended section 1861(v)(1)(L)(ii) of the Act to require that, effective for cost reporting periods beginning on or after</textblock>
    <textblock>October 1, 1993, we no longer include a payment adjustment for the administrative and general costs of hospital-based HHAs in computing the HHA limits. Under this provision, hospital-based HHAs and freestanding HHAs will be treated identically for payment purposes. Thus, in computing a hospital-based HHA's cost limits for cost reporting periods beginning on or after October 1, 1993, the A&amp;G add-on amounts that were to apply, as set forth in Table II of the July 8, 1993 notice (58 FR 36753), will not be used. Other components of the July 8, 1993 notice, specifically the per-visit limits in Table I, the wage indexes in Tables IIIa and IIIb, and the cost reporting year adjustment factors in Table IV, will continue to be used to compute the limits.</textblock>
    <textblock>We note that section 13564(a) of OBRA '93 amended section 1861(v)(1)(L)(iii) of the Act to provide that there be no changes in the per-visit cost limits for home health services for cost reporting periods beginning on or after July 1, 1994, and before July 1, 1996. Since the effective date of that provision is different from that of the elimination of the A&amp;G add-on, we intend to publish a separate notice in a future</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>to explain the effects of the delay in the update. Again, the only change in the methodology for computing the HHA cost limits that is effective for cost reporting periods beginning on or after October 1, 1993 is the elimination of the A&amp;G add-on for hospital-based HHAs.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Computing the Cost Limit for a Hospital-Based HHA</textblock>
    <textblock>The example below illustrates how an adjusted occupational therapy per-visit cost limit is calculated for a hospital-based HHA in Dallas, Texas, with a 12-month cost reporting period beginning October 1, 1993. Because the A&amp;G add-on has been eliminated, this example is identical to the example contained in our July 8, 1993 notice (58 FR 36752) of the calculation of a limit for a free-standing HHA, with the exception of the application of a different cost reporting period adjustment factor, as set forth in Table IV of that notice. These factors are based on the month and year in which an HHA's cost reporting period begins, and are used to account for inflation in costs that occurs after the effective date of the latest schedule of HHA limits. Thus, in the example below, the adjustment factor from Table IV of the July 8, 1993 notice for an HHA with a cost reporting period beginning October 1, 1993 is applied.</textblock>
    <textblock>To arrive at the adjusted limit, the HHA's intermediary first determines the adjusted labor-related component by multiplying the labor-related component of the limit by the appropriate wage index value, and then adjusts for budget neutrality. The adjusted limit is the sum of the adjusted labor-related component, plus the nonlabor component, plus other adjustments (if applicable), multiplied by the applicable cost reporting period adjustment factor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example:</textblock>
    <textblock>Calculation of an Adjusted Occupational Therapy</textblock>
    <textblock>Limit for a Hospital-Based HHA in Dallas, Texas for a Cost</textblock>
    <textblock>Reporting Period Beginning October 1, 1993 (using the</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate tables from the July 8, 1993 schedule of limits)</textblock>
    <textblock>If an HHA uses a cost reporting period that is not 12 months in duration, a special adjustment factor is calculated. This is necessary because inflation projections are computed to the midpoint of the cost reporting period, and the adjustment factors in Table IV are based on 12-month cost reporting periods. For cost reporting periods other than 12 months, the calculation must be made for the midpoint of the specific cost reporting period. In these cases, the intermediary for the HHA obtains this adjustment factor from HCFA.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the July 8, 1993 notice, we also set forth an example of a cost-limit calculation with A&amp;G add-on for a hospital-based HHA in State College, Pennsylvania (58 FR 36754). That example, as well as any other references in that document to the A&amp;G add-on, are no longer applicable for cost reporting periods beginning on or after October 1, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Impact Statement</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12866 (E.O. 12866) requires us to prepare an analysis for any rule that meets one of the E.O. 12866 criteria for a ``significant regulatory action''; that is, that may_</textblock>
    <textblock>• Have an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more; or adversely affect, in a material way, the economy, a sector of the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, or State, local, or tribal governments or communities;</textblock>
    <textblock>•Create a serious inconsistency or otherwise interfere with an action taken or planned by another agency;</textblock>
    <textblock>•Materially alter the budgetary impact of entitlements, grants, user fees, or loan programs or the rights and obligations of recipients thereof; or</textblock>
    <textblock>•Raise novel legal or policy issues arising out of legal mandates, the President's priorities, or the principles set forth in E.O. 12866.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Labor Component (Table I)</textblock>
    <textblock>$76.27</textblock>
    <textblock>Wage Index Value (Table III)</textblock>
    <textblock>×0.9599</textblock>
    <textblock>n,s</textblock>
    <textblock>Labor Portion</textblock>
    <textblock>$73.21</textblock>
    <textblock>Special Labor Adjustment for Budget Neutrality</textblock>
    <textblock>×1.027</textblock>
    <textblock>n,s</textblock>
    <textblock>Adjusted Labor Portion</textblock>
    <textblock>$75.19</textblock>
    <textblock>Nonlabor Component (Table I)</textblock>
    <textblock>+16.68</textblock>
    <textblock>OSHA Adjustment</textblock>
    <textblock>+0.18</textblock>
    <textblock>n,s</textblock>
    <textblock>$92.05</textblock>
    <textblock>Cost Reporting Period. Adjustment Factor (Table IV)</textblock>
    <textblock>× 1.0126</textblock>
    <textblock>n,s</textblock>
    <textblock>Adjusted Occupational Therapy Limit</textblock>
    <textblock>$93.21</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
