<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00036</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Acid Rain Program: Notice of Public Comment Period and</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Retired Unit Exemptions</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4822-6]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of proposed retired unit exemptions.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) is issuing for comment draft, five-year retired unit exemptions to 11 utility units under the Acid Rain Program regulations (40 CFR part 72).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on retired unit exemptions must be received no later than February 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative Records</textblock>
    <textblock>. The administrative record for each exemption, except information protected as confidential, may be viewed at the addresses listed in</textblock>
    <textblock>``SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>. Send comments, requests for public hearings, and requests to receive notice of future actions concerning a retired unit exemption to David Kee, Director, Air and Radiation Division, EPA Region 5 (A-18J), Ralph H. Metcalfe Federal Bldg., 77 West Jackson Blvd., Chicago, IL 60604.</textblock>
    <textblock>Submit all comments in duplicate and identify the unit to which the comments apply, the commenter's name, address, and telephone number, and the commenter's interest in the matter and affiliation, if any, to the owners and operators of the unit covered by the exemption. All timely comments will be considered, except those pertaining to standard provisions under 40 CFR 72.9 and issues not relevant to the exemption.</textblock>
    <textblock>Hearings</textblock>
    <textblock>. To request a public hearing, state the issues proposed to be raised in the hearing. EPA may schedule a hearing if EPA finds that it will contribute to the decision-making process by clarifying significant issues affecting the exemption.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Regarding the Acme and Avon Lake plants: Franklin Echevarria at (312) 886-9653. Regarding the Poston plant: Allan Batka at (312) 353-7316. Air and Radiation Division, EPA Region 5 (A-18J), Ralph H. Metcalfe Federal Bldg., 77 West Jackson Blvd., Chicago, IL 60604.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Retired Unit Exemptions</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA proposes to issue exemptions from the Acid Rain permit and continuous emission monitoring requirements for the following units in Ohio: Acme units 9, 11, 13, 14, 15, 91, and 92; Avon Lake unit 11; and Poston units 1, 2, and 3. The designated representative for Acme and Avon Lake is Fred J. Lange Jr. and the designated representative for Poston is John McManus.</textblock>
    <textblock>Addresses</textblock>
    <textblock>The administrative records for each plant may be viewed during normal business hours at EPA Region 5, 17th floor, Ralph H. Metcalfe Federal Bldg., 77 West Jackson Blvd., Chicago, IL 60604.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 23, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Doris Price,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Acid Rain Division,</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Atmospheric Programs, Office of Air and Radiation.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-185 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
