<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00037</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Safey Zone; Upper Mississippi River</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>33 CFR Part 165</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[COTP St. Louis Regulation 93-037]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 2115-AA97</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Coast Guard, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Temporary final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard is establishing a safety zone on the Upper Mississippi River. This regulation is needed to control vessel traffic in the regulated area to provide safe working conditions and navigation within the affected area. The regulation will prohibit navigation in the regulated area for the safety of vessel traffic and the protection of life and property associated with bridge and span removal.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulation is effective December 21, 1993 and will terminate on January 21, 1994 unless sooner terminated by the Captain of the Port.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>LT Timothy Deal, Operations Officer, Captain of the Port, St. Louis, Missouri at (314) 539-3823.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Drafting Information</textblock>
    <textblock>The drafters of this regulation are MK1 Christopher C. Schulz, Project Officer, Marine Safety Office, St. Louis, Missouri and LCDR A. O. Denny, Project Attorney, Second Coast Guard District Legal Office.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory History</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with 5 U.S.C. 553, a notice of proposed rulemaking has not been published for this regulation and good cause exists for making it effective in less than 30 days from the date of publication. Following normal rulemaking procedures would have been impracticable. Specifically, the nature of repairs to the Burlington Highway Bridge at mile 404.2 Upper Mississippi River leaves insufficient time to publish a notice of proposed rule making. The Coast Guard deems it to be in the public's best interest to issue a regulation without waiting for a comment period since the conditions present an immediate hazard.</textblock>
    <textblock>Background and Purpose</textblock>
    <textblock>Extensive renovation of the bridge is required and removal of the center is to be accomplished from a vessel located in the navigation channel and this action will impede normal traffic flow. As a result of these conditions this regulation is necessary to provide safe working conditions and navigation within the affected area.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Evaluation</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulation is not considered a significant regulatory action under Executive Order 12866 and not significant under Department of Transportation Regulatory Policies and Procedures (44 FR 11040; February 26, 1979), it will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities, and it contains no collection of information requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard expects the impact of this regulation to be so minimal that a Regulatory Evaluation is unnecessary. The imposed restrictions are anticipated to be of short duration. To avoid any unnecessary adverse economic impact on businesses which use the river for commercial purposes, Captain of the Port, St. Louis, Missouri will monitor the situation and will authorized entry into the closed area as conditions warrant. Changes will be announced by Marine Safety Information Radio Broadcast on VHF Marine Band Radio, Channel 22 (157.1 MHZ). Mariners may also call the Port Operations Officer, Captain of the Port, St. Louis, Missouri at (314) 539-3823 for current information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federalism Assessment</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the principles and criteria of Executive Order 12612, this regulation does not raise sufficient federalism implications to warrant the preparation of a Federalism Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Assessment</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard considered the environmental impact of this proposal and concluded that, under section 2.B.2.g.[5] of Commandant Instruction M16475.1B, this proposal is categorically excluded from further environmental documentation as an action to protect public safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subject in 33 CFR Part 165</textblock>
    <textblock>Harbors, Marine safety, Navigation (water), Records and recordkeeping,</textblock>
    <textblock>Security measures, Waterways.</textblock>
    <textblock>Temporary Regulation</textblock>
    <textblock>In consideration of the foregoing, subpart C of part 165 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations, is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 165_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 165 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>33 U.S.C. 1231; 50 U.S.C. 191; CFR 1.46 and 33 CFR 1.05-1(g), 6.01-1, 6.04-6, and 160.5.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. A temporary ยง165.T02-077 is added, to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง165.T02-077</textblock>
    <textblock>Safety zone: Upper Mississippi River.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Location.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Upper Mississippi River between mile 403.2 and 405.2 is established as a safety zone.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective dates.</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulation becomes effective on December 21, 1993 and will terminate on January 21, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The general regulations under ยง165.23 of this part which prohibit entry into the described zones without authority of the Captain of the Port apply. The Captain of the Port, St Louis, Missouri will notify the maritime community of river conditions affecting the areas covered by this safety zone by Marine Safety Information Radio Broadcast on VHF Marine Band Radio, Channel 22 (157.1 MHZ).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 17, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>S.P. Cooper,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Commander, U.S. Coast Guard, Captain of the Port, St. Louis, Missouri.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-269 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-14-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
