<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00033</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>III.D.10.b. (formerly C.5.) would be revised to clarify what</textblock>
    <textblock>is meant by the outer 2/3 of the chart range.</textblock>
    <textblock>III.D.10.c. (formerly C.14.) would be amended by revising the</textblock>
    <textblock>corrective action. It would no longer require recordation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>``as found'' and ``as left'' readings, which are meaningless.</textblock>
    <textblock>III.D.11.a., b., and c. (new) would be added as requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>for Electronic Flow Computers (EFCs). The requirements for EFCs</textblock>
    <textblock>would be no more stringent than those for chart recorders. The</textblock>
    <textblock>current static pressure, differential pressure, and temperature</textblock>
    <textblock>would have to be displayed on a continuous basis, and the EFC</textblock>
    <textblock>would be required to have a back-up power source capable of</textblock>
    <textblock>retaining data collected for a minimum of 35 days.</textblock>
    <textblock>III.E.3. and 4. (formerly C.25. and 26.) would be amended to</textblock>
    <textblock>make them read as requirements rather than as descriptions or</textblock>
    <textblock>definitions, as they appear to do in the existing Order.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other editorial changes have been proposed to correct errors in</textblock>
    <textblock>the existing Order and cross-references that must be changed as a</textblock>
    <textblock>result of the proposed reorganization of the Order.</textblock>
    <textblock>The principal authors of this proposed rule are Lonny R.</textblock>
    <textblock>Bagley, Inspection and Enforcement Specialist, Montana State</textblock>
    <textblock>Office, Richard Estabrook, Petroleum Engineer, Ukiah District</textblock>
    <textblock>Office, California, Michael Kolling, Petroleum Engineering</textblock>
    <textblock>Technician, Dickinson District Office, North Dakota, Will Lambert,</textblock>
    <textblock>Petroleum Engineer, Grand Junction District Office, Colorado, and</textblock>
    <textblock>Larry Bray, Petroleum Engineering Technician, Roswell Resource</textblock>
    <textblock>Area Office, New Mexico, assisted by the staff of the Division of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legislation and Regulatory Management, all of the BLM.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is hereby determined that this proposed rule does not</textblock>
    <textblock>constitute a major Federal action significantly affecting the</textblock>
    <textblock>quality of the human environment, and that no detailed statement</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to Section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy</textblock>
    <textblock>Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)) is required. The Bureau of</textblock>
    <textblock>Land Management has determined that this proposed rule is</textblock>
    <textblock>categorically excluded from further environmental review pursuant</textblock>
    <textblock>to 516 Departmental Manual (DM), Chapter 2, Appendix 1, Item 1.10,</textblock>
    <textblock>and that the proposal would not significantly affect the 10</textblock>
    <textblock>criteria for exceptions listed in 516 DM 2, Appendix 2. Pursuant</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Council on Environmental Quality regulations (40 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>1508.4) and environmental policies and procedures of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Interior, ``categorical exclusions'' means a</textblock>
    <textblock>category of actions that do not individually or cumulatively have</textblock>
    <textblock>a significant effect on the human environment and that have been</textblock>
    <textblock>found to have no such effect in procedures adopted by a Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>agency and for which neither an environmental assessment nor an</textblock>
    <textblock>environmental impact statement is required.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule has been reviewed under Executive Order 12866.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department has determined under the Regulatory Flexibility</textblock>
    <textblock>Act (5 U.S.C. 601</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>) that it will not have a significant</textblock>
    <textblock>economic impact on a substantial number of small entities for the</textblock>
    <textblock>same reasons. The rule codifies industry standards that apply to</textblock>
    <textblock>all entities in the industry, regardless of size. The Order would</textblock>
    <textblock>not require a substantial amount of additional information or</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring. Some additional equipment may be required in certain</textblock>
    <textblock>cases, but the total cost of these changes would not approach the</textblock>
    <textblock>threshold specified in the Executive Order. Costs to the public</textblock>
    <textblock>should not increase at all as a result of the Order.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department certifies that this proposed rule does not</textblock>
    <textblock>represent a governmental action capable of interference with</textblock>
    <textblock>constitutionally protected property rights. There would be no</textblock>
    <textblock>taking of private property without due process. Failure to abate</textblock>
    <textblock>violations could result in assessments under the Mineral Leasing</textblock>
    <textblock>Act and/or penalties under the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty</textblock>
    <textblock>Management Act, and possibly lease cancellation if the failure</textblock>
    <textblock>continues, but not without due process. Therefore, as required by</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12630, the Department of the Interior has</textblock>
    <textblock>determined that the proposed rule would not cause a taking of</textblock>
    <textblock>private property.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department has certified to the Office of Management and</textblock>
    <textblock>Budget that this proposed rule meets the applicable standards</textblock>
    <textblock>provided in section 1(a) and 2(b)(2) of Executive Order 12788.</textblock>
    <textblock>The information collection requirement(s) contained in Part</textblock>
    <textblock>3160 that relate to this Order have been approved by the Office</textblock>
    <textblock>of Management and Budget under 44 U.S.C. 3501</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>assigned clearance number 1004-0134.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 43 CFR Part 3160</textblock>
    <textblock>Government contracts; Mineral royalties; Oil and gas</textblock>
    <textblock>exploration; Oil and gas production; Public lands_Mineral</textblock>
    <textblock>resources; Indian lands_Mineral resources; Reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons stated above, under the authority of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Mineral Leasing Act of 1920, as amended and supplemented (30</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S.C. 181</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.),</textblock>
    <textblock>the Department proposes to amend part 3160,</textblock>
    <textblock>Group 3100, subchapter C, chapter II of title 43 of the Code of</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Regulations as set forth below:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 3160_ONSHORE OIL AND GAS OPERATIONS</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 3160 continues to read as</textblock>
    <textblock>follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>43 U.S.C. 1733; 30 U.S.C. 181</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.;</textblock>
    <textblock>30 U.S.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>351-359; 30 U.S.C. 301-306; 25 U.S.C. 396; 25 U.S.C. 396a-396q,</textblock>
    <textblock>397, 398, 398a-398e, 399; 43 U.S.C. 1457; see also 40</textblock>
    <textblock>Op.Atty.Gen. 41; 40 U.S.C. 471</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.;</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 4321</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.;</textblock>
    <textblock>43 U.S.C. 6508; 30 U.S.C. 1701</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.;</textblock>
    <textblock>and 25 U.S.C. 2101</textblock>
    <textblock>et</textblock>
    <textblock>seq.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
