<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00052</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Medicare, Medicaid and CLIA Programs; Personnel Requirements for Cytotechnologists</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>42 CFR Part 493</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[HSQ-210-FC]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Health Care Financing Administration (HCFA), and Public Health Service (PHS), HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final Rule with Comment Period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule amends certain personnel requirements for cytotechnologists that perform testing in laboratories subject to the requirements of the Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments of 1988 (CLIA). We are providing an adequate period of time for individuals to gain the necessary 2 years experience performing cytology testing which is currently included in two of the provisions for qualifying as a cytotechnologist. Also, we are extending the time for individuals to either meet the educational qualifications by virtue of completing training in an approved cytotechnology training program or be certified by an approved organization. We are making these changes to prevent the loss of qualified personnel in the field of cytotechnology.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>These regulations are effective on January 6, 1994. Comments will be considered if we receive them at the appropriate address, as provided below, no later than 5 p.m. on March 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mail an original and 3 copies of comments to the following address:</textblock>
    <textblock>Health Care Financing Administration, Department of Health and Human Services, Attention: HSQ-210-FC, P.O. Box 26676, Baltimore, MD 21207.</textblock>
    <textblock>If you prefer, you may deliver your written comments to one of the following addresses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 309-G, Hubert H. Humphrey Building, 200 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20201, or</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 132, East High Rise Building, 6325 Security Boulevard, Baltimore, MD 21207.</textblock>
    <textblock>Due to staffing and resource limitations, we cannot accept facsimile (FAX) transmissions. In commenting, please refer to file code HSQ-210-FC. Comments received timely will be available for public inspection as they are received, generally beginning approximately 3 weeks after publication of a document, in Room 309-G of the Department's offices at 200 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC, on Monday through Friday of each week from 8:30 a.m. to 5 p.m. (phone: (202) 690-7890).</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Cheryl Wiseman, (410) 597-5906.</textblock>
  </further>
</doc>
