<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00079</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>During the development of EPA's proposal, it has been suggested that the years 1964 to 1976 could be used as an alternative historical reference period. This period almost literally replicates the intended late 1960's to early 1970's. EPA has not chosen that period for two reasons. First, it is an extremely limited sample of the variation of conditions within water year categories. Second, including the year 1976 is inappropriate, given that by 1976 the decline of certain aquatic resources was already apparent.</textblock>
    <textblock>Another suggested possibility is that use of the 1955 to 1975 time period may be a better indicator of conditions in the late 1960's to early 1970's. The 1955-1975 period excludes water years before the CVP's pumping facilities were operational, but still provides a larger sample across certain water year types than would using the 1965 to 1974 period alone. As the table above indicates, using this 1955 to 1975 period would decrease the number of Chipps Island days from 116 to approximately 104 days during dry years, and from 119 to approximately 104 days during below normal years.</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA did not use this 1955-1975 period as the historical reference period because, as explained above, it believes the 1940 to 1975 period provides a larger and more representative sample of hydrological conditions across all year types similar to those in the late 1960's to early 1970's.</textblock>
    <textblock>Given the importance of this issue, EPA requests comments on the suitability of the above suggestions or of other historical reference periods for the salinity criteria. EPA is especially interested in how the use of alternative periods could provide a better estimate of the hydrological and ecological conditions in the estuary in the late 1960's to early 1970's. In addition, EPA is soliciting comment on alternative approaches to developing reference conditions for water year types for which there are limited historical examples.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. During the spawning season, several species appear to be carried through the Delta to Suisun Bay during periods of elevated Delta flows caused by upstream storm events. The proposed Roe Island salinity criteria are partly intended to protect the normal dispersal of these young fish throughout Suisun Bay over a number of tidal cycles. As explained in more detail above, the proposed Roe Island criteria include a ``trigger'' that activates the criteria only after natural hydrological conditions push the 2 ppt isohaline to Roe Island. EPA is requesting comment on this trigger, including comment on the following specific questions:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Would a trigger at some upstream site, such as Middle Ground, retain the desired link to storm events while ensuring a more frequent triggering of the standard?</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Should the criteria be triggered only by storm events actually occurring in the February through June period? This refinement would prevent the criteria from being triggered, for example, solely by a large storm occurring in January, the runoff from which may keep the 2 ppt isohaline below Roe Island into February.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Should the trigger be stated as a single day when mean salinities are less than 2 ppt, or by a longer averaging period (14 days, 28 days, etc.)?</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Year</textblock>
    <textblock>1Dry years</textblock>
    <textblock>1Below normal</textblock>
    <textblock>Number of days between February and June when 2 ppt isohaline was west of Chipps Island;</textblock>
    <textblock>1930</textblock>
    <textblock>146</textblock>
    <textblock>1932</textblock>
    <textblock>151</textblock>
    <textblock>1935</textblock>
    <textblock>150</textblock>
    <textblock>1936</textblock>
    <textblock>151</textblock>
    <textblock>1937</textblock>
    <textblock>150</textblock>
    <textblock>1939</textblock>
    <textblock>106</textblock>
    <textblock>1944</textblock>
    <textblock>142</textblock>
    <textblock>1945</textblock>
    <textblock>150</textblock>
    <textblock>1946</textblock>
    <textblock>150</textblock>
    <textblock>1947</textblock>
    <textblock>111</textblock>
    <textblock>1948</textblock>
    <textblock>143</textblock>
    <textblock>1949</textblock>
    <textblock>141</textblock>
    <textblock>1950</textblock>
    <textblock>150</textblock>
    <textblock>1955</textblock>
    <textblock>129</textblock>
    <textblock>1957</textblock>
    <textblock>147</textblock>
    <textblock>1959</textblock>
    <textblock>81</textblock>
    <textblock>1960</textblock>
    <textblock>123</textblock>
    <textblock>1961</textblock>
    <textblock>89</textblock>
    <textblock>1962</textblock>
    <textblock>136</textblock>
    <textblock>1964</textblock>
    <textblock>75</textblock>
    <textblock>1966</textblock>
    <textblock>112</textblock>
    <textblock>1968</textblock>
    <textblock>83</textblock>
    <textblock>1972</textblock>
    <textblock>63</textblock>
    <textblock>1979</textblock>
    <textblock>117</textblock>
    <textblock>1981</textblock>
    <textblock>76</textblock>
    <textblock>1985</textblock>
    <textblock>31</textblock>
    <textblock>1987</textblock>
    <textblock>46</textblock>
    <textblock>1989</textblock>
    <textblock>39</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
