<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00084</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>CDFG, 1992d. Impact of water management on splittail in the Sacramento-San Joaquin estuary. State Water Resources Control Board Hearing for setting interim standards for the Delta. 7 pp. WRINT-DFG-5.</textblock>
    <textblock>CDFG, 1992e. A Model for Evaluating the Impacts of Freshwater Outflow and Export on Striped Bass in the Sacramento-San Joaquin Estuary. 57 pp. WRINT-DFG-3.</textblock>
    <textblock>CDFG, 1993. Unpublished data. San Francisco Bay Study. March 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>California Department of Water Resources, 1986. Dayflow Program Documentation and Dayflow Data Summary: User's Guide. Attachments A-G. February 1986.</textblock>
    <textblock>Caywood, M.L. 1974. Contributions to the life history of the splittail</textblock>
    <textblock>Pogonichthys macrolepidotus</textblock>
    <textblock>(Ayres) M.S. Thesis, California State University, Sacramento. 77 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Chadwick, H.K. 1958. A study of the planktonic eggs and larvae of the Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta with special reference to the striped bass (</textblock>
    <textblock>Roccus saxatilis</textblock>
    <textblock>). California Department of Fish and Game, Inland Fisheries Branch Administrative Report 58-5. 24 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cloern, J.E., A.E. Alpine, B.E. Cole, R.L.J. Wong, J.F. Arthur, and M.D. Ball. 1983. River discharge controls phytoplankton dynamics in Northern San Francisco Bay estuary. Estuar. Coast. Shelf Sci. 12:415-429.</textblock>
    <textblock>Collins, J.N. and T.C. Foin, 1993. Evaluations of the Impacts of Aqueous Salinity on the Shoreline Vegetation of Tidal Marshlands in the San Francisco Estuary.</textblock>
    <textblock>In:</textblock>
    <textblock>SFEP. Managing Freshwater Discharge to the San Francisco Bay-Delta Estuary: the Scientific Basis for an Estuarine Standard. Appendix C.</textblock>
    <textblock>Daniels, R.A. and P.B. Moyle, 1983. Life history of splittail (Cyprinidae:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pogonichthys macrolepidotus</textblock>
    <textblock>) in the Sacramento-San Joaquin estuary. Fish. Bull. 84:105-117.</textblock>
    <textblock>Farley, T.C., 1966. Striped bass,</textblock>
    <textblock>Roccus saxatilis,</textblock>
    <textblock>spawning in the Sacramento San Joaquin River systems during 1963 and 1964. DFG Fish Bull. 136 pages 28-43.</textblock>
    <textblock>Five Agency Delta Salmon Team, 1991a. Evaluation of the Feasibility of Protecting Downstream Migrant Chinook Salmon Smolts in the Sacramento River and San Joaquin River with Physical Facilities, July 15, 1991.</textblock>
    <textblock>Five Agency Delta Salmon Team, 1991b. Benefit/Cost Evaluations of Alternative Salmon Protective Measures in the Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta. Draft Report. March 13, 1991. 101 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Granholm, S.L., 1987a. Special-status wildlife species of the Suisun Bay tidal marshes, and expected impacts of reduced freshwater inflows. Sierra Club Legal Defense Fund Exhibit 4, SWRCB San Francisco Bay/Delta Hearings.</textblock>
    <textblock>Granholm, S.L., 1987b. Expected impacts of reduced freshwater inflows on representative birds and mammals of the Suisun Bay tidal marshes. Sierra Club Legal Defense Fund Exhibit 5, SWRCB San Francisco Bay/Delta Hearings.</textblock>
    <textblock>Harvey, T.E., K.J. Miller, R.L. Hothem, M.J. Rauzon, G.W. Page, R.A. Keck, 1992. Status and Trends Report on Wildlife of the San Francisco Estuary. January 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Herbold, B., A.D. Jassby, P.B. Moyle, 1992. San Francisco Estuary Project Status and Trends Report on Aquatic Resources in the San Francisco Estuary. March 1992. 257 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Heubach, W., 1969.</textblock>
    <textblock>Neomysis awatschensis</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Sacramento-San Joaquin Estuary.</textblock>
    <textblock>Limnological Oceanography</textblock>
    <textblock>14:533-546.</textblock>
    <textblock>Jassby, A.D., 1993. Isohaline Position as a Habitat Indicator for Estuarine Resources: San Francisco Estuary. In SFEP 1993. Managing Freshwater Discharge to the San Francisco Bay/Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta Estuary: The Scientific Basis for an Estuarine Standard, Appendix 3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Kelley, D.W., S. Greene &amp; W.T. Mitchell, 1991. Estimating the Effect of Changing Delta Environmental Conditions on Sacramento Basin Fall Run Chinook Salmon Stock. Analysis made under the direction of the Delta Salmon Team of the Five Agency Salmon Management Group. July 1991.</textblock>
    <textblock>Kimmerer, W. 1992. An evaluation of existing data in the entrapment zone of the San Francisco Bay estuary. IESP Technical Report 33. 49 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Kjelson, M., S. Green &amp; P. Brandes, 1989. A Model for Estimating Mortality and Survival of Fall-run Chinook Salmon Smolts in the Sacramento River Delta between Sacramento and Chipps Island.</textblock>
    <textblock>Knutson, A.C. Jr. and J.J. Orsi, 1983. Factors regulating abundance and distribution of the shrimp</textblock>
    <textblock>Neomysis mercedis</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Sacramento-San Joaquin Estuary. Transactions American Fisheries Society 112:476-485.</textblock>
    <textblock>Mann, R. and R. Abbott, 1992. Water Temperature Control in the Sacramento-San Joaquin Bay/Delta: Toward a Reasonable Strategy. Biosystems Analysis, Inc., J-621. October 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Marshall, J.T., Jr., 1948. Ecologic races of song sparrows in the San Francisco Bay region, Part I. Habitat and abundance. Condor 50(5) 193-215.</textblock>
    <textblock>Meiorin, E.C., M.N. Josselyn, R. Crawford, J. Calloway, K. Miller, R. Pratt, T. Richardson and R. Leidy, 1991. Status and Trends Report on Wetlands and Related Habitats in the San Francisco Estuary. San Francisco Estuary Project, December 1991.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monroe, M.W. and J. Kelly. 1992. State of the Estuary: a report on conditions and problems in the San Francisco Bay/Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta estuary. San Francisco Estuary Project, San Francisco, California. 270 pages + 2 maps.</textblock>
    <textblock>Moyle, P.B. 1976. Inland Fishes of California. University of California Press, Berkeley, California. 405 pages.</textblock>
    <textblock>Moyle, P.B. 1980. Sacramento splittail</textblock>
    <textblock>in</textblock>
    <textblock>D.S. Lee et al. editors, Atlas of North American Freshwater Fishes. N.Carolina Mus. Nat. Hist., Raleigh, N.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>Moyle, P.B. 1992. Causes in Decline of Estuarine Fish Species. WRINT-NHI-9.</textblock>
    <textblock>Moyle, P.B. and J.J. Cech Jr., 1988. Fishes An Introduction to Ichthyology. Prentice Hall, New Jersey, 559 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Moyle, P.B. and B. Herbold, 1989. Status of the delta smelt,</textblock>
    <textblock>Hypomesus transpacificus,</textblock>
    <textblock>Report to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Office of Endangered Species, Sacramento, and State of California, Department of Fish and Game, Inland Fisheries Division.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
