<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00042</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>E. Other Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>The following are minimum standards that apply to all sales</textblock>
    <textblock>and sales allocation meter installations.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. If, for any reason, the measuring equipment is out of</textblock>
    <textblock>service or malfunctioning so that the quantity of gas delivered</textblock>
    <textblock>is not known, the volume delivered during this period shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>estimated using one of the following methods, in this order of</textblock>
    <textblock>priority:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Record data on check metering equipment if used in lieu of</textblock>
    <textblock>main meter recordings. If check meters are not installed or are</textblock>
    <textblock>found to be recording inaccurately, then</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Base corrections on the percentage error found during the</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument test. If that is not feasible, then</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Estimate the quantity of gas run, based on deliveries made</textblock>
    <textblock>under similar conditions when the metering equipment was</textblock>
    <textblock>registering accurately.</textblock>
    <textblock>Violation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Minor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Corrective Action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimate volumes delivered during those</textblock>
    <textblock>periods cited using one or more of the approved methods</textblock>
    <textblock>identified in the order of priority and, where necessary, submit</textblock>
    <textblock>a report showing corrected volumes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abatement Period:</textblock>
    <textblock>60 days.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The Btu content shall be determined at least annually,</textblock>
    <textblock>unless otherwise required by the authorized officer, by means of</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) a recording calorimeter, (2) calculations based on a complete</textblock>
    <textblock>compositional analysis of the gas and the heating value of each</textblock>
    <textblock>constituent, in accordance with AGA Committee Report No. 3, or</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) any other method acceptable to the authorized officer. The</textblock>
    <textblock>authorized officer shall be apprised of the method used for each</textblock>
    <textblock>determination and be furnished with all needed analytical data or</textblock>
    <textblock>other documentation upon request. The Btu content most recently</textblock>
    <textblock>determined and used for royalty purposes shall be reported.</textblock>
    <textblock>Violation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Minor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Corrective Action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Determine Btu content and submit a report.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abatement Period:</textblock>
    <textblock>30 days.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. For purposes of measurement and meter calibration,</textblock>
    <textblock>atmospheric pressure shall be established through an actual</textblock>
    <textblock>measurement or assumed to be a constant value based on the</textblock>
    <textblock>elevation at the metering station.</textblock>
    <textblock>Violation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Minor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Corrective Action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Recalibrate gas meter and submit a report</textblock>
    <textblock>indicating corrected volumes using the adjusted absolute zero or</textblock>
    <textblock>properly calculated pressure extensions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abatement Period:</textblock>
    <textblock>30 days.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. The method and frequency of determining specific gravity</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be determined by use of one of the following methods:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Continuous recording gravitometer;</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Complete compositional analysis of a spot or cumulative gas</textblock>
    <textblock>sample determined at least annually.</textblock>
    <textblock>Violation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Minor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Corrective Action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Determine specific gravity of gas by</textblock>
    <textblock>approved method and submit a report with corrected volume.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abatement Period:</textblock>
    <textblock>30 days.</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Gas Measurement by Other Methods or at Other Locations</textblock>
    <textblock>Acceptable to the Authorized Officer</textblock>
    <textblock>Using any method of gas measurement other than by orifice</textblock>
    <textblock>meter at a location on the lease, unit, unit participating area,</textblock>
    <textblock>or communitized area, requires prior approval from the authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>officer pursuant to 43 CFR 3162.7-3. Other measurement methods</textblock>
    <textblock>include, but are not limited to:</textblock>
    <textblock>Turbine metering systems</textblock>
    <textblock>Positive displacement meter</textblock>
    <textblock>Pitot tube</textblock>
    <textblock>Orifice well tester</textblock>
    <textblock>Critical flow prover</textblock>
    <textblock>Gas-oil ratio</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
