<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00171</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Training, job search and relocation allowances.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) If an individual fails, with good cause, to complete training, a job search, or a relocation, any payment or portion of a payment made under this part 617 to such individual or any person that is not properly and necessarily expended in attempting to complete such training, job search, or relocation, shall constitute an overpayment.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If an individual fails, without good cause, to complete training, a job search, or a relocation, any payment made under this part 617 to such individual or any person shall constitute an overpayment.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Such overpayment shall be recovered or waived as provided in paragraph (a) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Final determination.</textblock>
    <textblock>Except for overpayments determined by a court of competent jurisdiction, no repayment may be required, and no deduction may be made, under this section until a determination under paragraph (a) of this section by the State agency has been made, notice of the determination and an opportunity for a fair hearing thereon has been given to the person or individual concerned, and the determination has become final.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Deposit.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any amount recovered by a State agency under this section shall be deposited into the Federal fund or account from which payment was made.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Procedural requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The provisions of paragraphs (c), (e), and (g) of §617.50 shall apply to determinations and redeterminations made pursuant to this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The provisions of §617.51 shall apply to determinations and redeterminations made pursuant to this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Fraud detection and prevention.</textblock>
    <textblock>State procedures for the detection and prevention of fraudulent overpayments of TAA shall be, as a minimum, commensurate with the procedures adopted by the State with respect to State unemployment compensation and consistent with the Secretary's ``Standard for Fraud and Overpayment Detection,'' Employment Security Manual, Part V, sections 7510-7515 (Appendix B of this Part).</textblock>
    <textblock>(h)</textblock>
    <textblock>Debts due the United States or Others.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Notwithstanding any provision of this part 617, TAA payable to a person or an individual under this part 617 shall be applied by the State agency for the recovery by offset of any debt due the United States from the person or individual.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) TAA shall not be applied or used by the State agency in any manner for the payment of any debt of any person or individual to any State or any other entity or person, except that TRA payable to an individual shall be payable to someone other than the individual if required by State law and Federal law to satisfy the individual's obligation for child support or alimony.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Definition of person.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of this section, a person includes any employer or other entity or organization as well as the officers and officials thereof who may bear individual responsibility.</textblock>
    <textblock>28. Section 617.59 is amended by adding a new paragraph (h) and a new paragraph (i) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§617.59</textblock>
    <textblock>Agreements with State agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(h)</textblock>
    <textblock>Program coordination.</textblock>
    <textblock>State agencies providing employment services, training and supplemental assistance under Subpart C of this part shall, in accordance with their Agreements under this section, coordinate such services and payments with programs and services provided by State Service Delivery Areas, Private Industry Councils, and substate grantees under the Job Training Partnership Act and with the State agency administering the State law.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Administration absent State Agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>In any State in which no Agreement under this section is in force, the Secretary shall administer the Act and this part 617 and pay TAA hereunder through appropriate arrangements made by the Department, and for this purpose the Secretary or the Department shall be substituted for the State or cooperating State agency wherever appropriate in this part 617. Such arrangements shall include the requirement that TAA be administered in accordance with this part 617, and the provisions of the applicable State law except to the extent that such State law is inconsistent with any provision of this part 617 or section 303 of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 503) or section 3304(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (26 U.S.C. 3304(a)), and shall also include provision for a fair hearing for any individual whose application for TAA is denied. A final determination under paragraph (i) of this section as to entitlement to TAA shall be subject to review by the courts in the same manner and to the same extent as is provided by section 205(g) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 405(g)).</textblock>
    <textblock>29. Section 617.60 is added and reserved to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§617.60</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative requirements. [Reserved]</textblock>
    <textblock>30. Section 617.64 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§617.64</textblock>
    <textblock>Termination of TAA program benefits.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following rules are applicable to the termination of TAA benefits under the Act:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) No application for TRA, or transportation or subsistence payment while in training approved under subpart C of this part 617, shall be approved, and no payment of TRA or payment for transportation or subsistence occurring on or before the termination date shall be made after the termination date specified in the Act, unless the claim for TRA or an invoice for transportation and subsistence is presented to the State agency and a final determination is made on the amount payable on or before the termination date in the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) No payment of job search or relocation allowances shall be made after the termination date specified in the Act, unless an application for such allowances was approved, such job search or relocation was completed, and a final determination made on the amount payable for such benefits by the State agency on or before the termination date in the Act.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
