<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00127</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00073</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 19(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463, 5 U.S.C., Appendix I), notice is hereby given for RTCA Special Committee 169 meeting to be held January 11-12, 1994, starting at 9:30 a.m. The meeting will be held at the RTCA Conference Room, 1140 Connecticut Avenue, NW., Suite 1020, Washington, DC 20036.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agenda for this meeting is as follows: (1) Chairman's introductory remarks; (2) Review of meeting agenda; (3) Approval of the Summary of the ninth meeting held July 22-23, 1993; (4) Report of Air Traffic Services Data Link Communications Working Group (WG-1) activities and approval of MOPS for Aircraft Contest Management (CM) Equipment; (5) Report on Working Group 3, Flight Information Services Communications, activities; (6) Discuss Working Group 4 status; (7) Task Force 2 update on issues applicable to SC-169; (8) Other Business: (a) Discussion of implementation issues (b) FANS-1 status; (9) Date and place of next meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Attendance is open to the interested public but limited to space available. With the approval of the Chairman, members of the public may present oral statements at the meeting. Persons wishing to present statements or obtain information should contact the RTCA Secretariat, 1140 Connecticut Avenue, NW., Suite 1020, Washington, DC 20036; (202) 833-9339. Any member of the public may present a written statement to the committee at any time.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on December 28, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>RTCA, Inc.; Aeronautical Data Link Applications; RTCA Special Committee 169, Tenth Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Joyce J. Gillen,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Designated Officer.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-242 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
