<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00043</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00027</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>This notice corrects a notice (FR Doc. 93-31063) published on page 67412 of the issue for Tuesday, December 21, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the third column, under the Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco heading, the entry for First Security Corporation is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. First Security Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>, Salt Lake City, Utah; to engage</textblock>
    <textblock>de novo</textblock>
    <textblock>through its subsidiary, First Security Investor Services, Inc., Salt Lake City, Utah, in the purchase and sale, on the order of investors as a ``riskless principal'', of obligations of the United States, general obligations of states and their political subdivisions and other obligations that state member banks of the Federal Reserve System may be authorized to underwrite and deal in under 12 U.S.C. 24 and 335, including bankers' acceptances and certificates of deposit, under the same limitations as would be applicable if the activity were performed by Applicant's subsidiary state member banks or its subsidiary nonmember banks as if they were member banks, pursuant to  225.25(b)(16) of the Board's Regulation Y.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this applicatio must be received by January 10, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, December 30, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>First Security Corporation; Application to Engage de novo in Permissible Nonbanking Activities</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jennifer J. Johnson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Secretary of the Board.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-215 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6210-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
