<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00052</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00032</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93D-0398]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Proposed Guideline Regarding Microbiological Testing for Antimicrobial Food-Animal Drugs; Availability</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration, HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is announcing the availability of a proposed guideline entitled ``Microbiological Testing of Antimicrobial Drug Residues in Food'' prepared by the Center for Veterinary Medicine (CVM) regarding the tests required for food-animal antimicrobial drug products to establish their human-food safety. This proposed guideline provides criteria for determining which antimicrobials will require supplemental testing, and recommends test procedures that are necessary to ensure that antimicrobial residues will not cause intestinal microflora perturbations in the consumer.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Submit written comments by April 6, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Submit written requests for single copies of the proposed guideline to the Communications and Education Branch (HFV-12), Center for Veterinary Medicine, Food and Drug Administration, 7500 Standish Pl., Rockville, MD 20855, 301-594-1755, or the contact person (address below). Send two self-addressed adhesive labels to assist that office in processing your requests. Submit written comments on the proposed guideline to the Dockets Management Branch (HFA-305), Food and Drug Administration, rm. 1-23, 12420 Parklawn Dr., Rockville, MD 20857. Requests and comments should be identified with the docket number found in brackets in the heading of this document. A copy of the proposed guideline and received comments are available for public examination in the Dockets Management Branch between 9 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through Friday.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Haydee Fernandez, Center for Veterinary Medicine (HFV-154), Food and Drug Administration, 7500 Standish Pl., Rockville, MD 20855, 301-594-1684.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is announcing the availability of a proposed guideline entitled ``Microbiological Testing of Antimicrobial Drug Residues in Food'' regarding required testing for food-animal antimicrobial drug products. In evaluating new animal drug applications (NADA's) the agency must determine, among other factors, the safety of the intended use of the drug, including the cumulative effect on man or animal required by section 512(d)(2)(B) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (the act) (21 U.S.C. 360b(d)(2)(B)). The proposed guideline provides criteria that will be used to determine which antimicrobial drugs will require supplemental testing to ensure that antimicrobial residues will not cause intestinal microflora perturbations in the consumer exposed to antimicrobial residues.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is well known that therapeutic doses of antibiotics can cause adverse effects on the intestinal microflora ecology. In most cases the lowest dose at which these perturbations occur have not been determined; however, CVM believes that the ecology of the human intestinal microflora should not be disturbed by the residues of antimicrobials used in food-animals.</textblock>
    <textblock>In June 1992, CVM sponsored a symposium on the Microbiological Significance of Drug Residues in Food to evaluate scientific expertise in this area. Information discussed at the symposium reaffirmed CVM's conclusion that the residue antimicrobial activity is a valid endpoint for establishing residue tolerances for antimicrobial animal drugs.</textblock>
    <textblock>CVM proposes establishing two categories for antimicrobial drugs: (1) ``New Animal Antimicrobial Drugs Requiring Additional Human Food Safety Microbiological Testing'' and (2) ``New Animal Antimicrobial Drugs Exempt from Additional Human Food Safety Microbiological Testing.'' To qualify for exemption from additional microbiological testing, the antimicrobial drug must have either: (1) ``Very low'' residue levels, (2) residues with limited antimicrobial activity, or (3) no adverse effects on intestinal microflora at approved dosages. Antimicrobial drugs will require additional testing in cases where a safe residue concentration retains antimicrobial activity in humans at residue exposure levels greater than 1 part per million in the total diet.</textblock>
    <textblock>CVM requests comments regarding how the proposed guideline should relate the effects of low doses of antibiotics observed in model systems to potential adverse biological effects in humans. In addition, information is requested on the appropriate endpoints for monitoring the effects of the different classes of antibiotics.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons may, on or before April 6, 1994, submit to the Dockets Management Branch (address above) written comments on the proposed guideline. Two copies of any comments are to be submitted, except that individuals may submit one copy. Comments are to be identified with the docket number found in brackets in the heading of this document. The proposed guideline and received comments may be seen in the office above between 9 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through Friday.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 28, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William K. Hubbard,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Deputy Commissioner for Policy.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-114 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
