<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00046</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>We refer to the performance requirements we use to</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluate the performance of intermediaries and carriers in</textblock>
    <textblock>meeting their contractual obligations to HCFA in our</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations and program instructions as criteria and</textblock>
    <textblock>standards. When we developed our regulations, criteria were</textblock>
    <textblock>expected to be distinguished from standards; we intended to</textblock>
    <textblock>measure broad categorizations of performance using criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>(42 CFR 421.120) and to measure statistical and performance</textblock>
    <textblock>data using standards (§421.122). As planned, a contractor</textblock>
    <textblock>had to be evaluated by and pass the requirements of the</textblock>
    <textblock>criteria before we evaluated contractor performance using</textblock>
    <textblock>statistical standards. However, in practice, the standards</textblock>
    <textblock>have been used to measure a contractor's compliance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of the criteria. The separate reliance on</textblock>
    <textblock>statistical standards diminished and we have developed a</textblock>
    <textblock>CPEP under which standards are used to measure the</textblock>
    <textblock>performance of specific activities in a defined criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>instead of ``statistical'' standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Summary of the Proposed Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 3, 1992, we published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(57 FR 57125) a proposed rule describing technical</textblock>
    <textblock>revisions we proposed to make to Medicare regulations in</textblock>
    <textblock>order to simplify and improve our system for evaluating the</textblock>
    <textblock>performances of fiscal intermediaries and carriers in the</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of the Medicare program. These technical</textblock>
    <textblock>revisions are necessary to bring our regulations up to date</textblock>
    <textblock>with our actual use of criteria and standards in performance</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluations.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the preamble to the proposed rule we described how</textblock>
    <textblock>the reliance on statistical standards diminished and that</textblock>
    <textblock>current ``standards'' are used to measure the performance of</textblock>
    <textblock>specific activities in a defined criterion. That is,</textblock>
    <textblock>measurement and evaluation using criteria and standards have</textblock>
    <textblock>evolved into a one-step process. In addition, we noted that</textblock>
    <textblock>certain functions that were included in the original planned</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluation structure have been transferred to more</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate review activities. We, therefore, proposed to</textblock>
    <textblock>amend §§421.3, 421.112(b), 421.118(b) and 421.122 to delete</textblock>
    <textblock>reference to statistical standards and to replace the</textblock>
    <textblock>general standards for the areas evaluated formerly by</textblock>
    <textblock>statistical standards with a general explanation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>areas evaluated by performance standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>We also mentioned in the proposed rule that our</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations do not contain requirements relating to</textblock>
    <textblock>measurement of carrier performance that are parallel to</textblock>
    <textblock>those for intermediaries. For consistency, we proposed to</textblock>
    <textblock>establish a new §421.201, ``Performance Criteria and</textblock>
    <textblock>Standards,'' that would measure and evaluate carrier</textblock>
    <textblock>performance of functional responsibilities, such as,</textblock>
    <textblock>accurate and timely processing of claims, responsiveness to</textblock>
    <textblock>beneficiaries', physicians' and suppliers' concerns, and</textblock>
    <textblock>proper management of administrative funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>We proposed to base performance criteria and standards</textblock>
    <textblock>on the experience of carriers nationwide, changes in carrier</textblock>
    <textblock>operations due to fiscal constraints, and our objectives in</textblock>
    <textblock>achieving better performance. Before the beginning of each</textblock>
    <textblock>CPEP evaluation period, we would publish the performance</textblock>
    <textblock>criteria and standards as a notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>We also announced that we would add a new §421.203,</textblock>
    <textblock>``Carrier's failure to perform efficiently and effectively,''</textblock>
    <textblock>to explain the adverse action that may be taken by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary if the carrier fails to meet criteria and</textblock>
    <textblock>standards specified at §421.201. The content is parallel</textblock>
    <textblock>to §421.124, which applies to intermediaries. This new</textblock>
    <textblock>§421.203 does not add or change carrier obligations. It</textblock>
    <textblock>merely codifies in regulations a provision specific to</textblock>
    <textblock>carriers that has been in effect since Public Law 98-369.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Analysis of and Response to Public Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>We received 10 timely items of correspondence in</textblock>
    <textblock>response to the December 3, 1992 proposed rule. The</textblock>
    <textblock>comments were from intermediaries, carriers, contractor</textblock>
    <textblock>advocacy groups, and provider advocacy groups. A summary of</textblock>
    <textblock>the comments and the Department's responses follow:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>Several commenters suggested that a process</textblock>
    <textblock>be developed by HCFA for receiving comments, complaints, or</textblock>
    <textblock>problems with carrier performance by physicians or</textblock>
    <textblock>professional organizations and that the information</textblock>
    <textblock>generated by this process be included in the overall</textblock>
    <textblock>performance evaluation of a carrier.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Beginning in Fiscal Year 1994, HCFA will</textblock>
    <textblock>review both intermediaries' and carriers' efforts to enhance</textblock>
    <textblock>customer satisfaction through the use of customer</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfaction surveys, including the National Physician</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey. Results of the surveys will be used to establish</textblock>
    <textblock>performance data on customer satisfaction and to identify</textblock>
    <textblock>areas in need of improvement. The results will be</textblock>
    <textblock>summarized for publication in the report of contractor</textblock>
    <textblock>performance.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
