<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00147</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>52.</textblock>
    <textblock>Information on waivers.</textblock>
    <textblock>The UCSP, commenting on §617.67(c), argues that workers should be furnished information on applying for a waiver of the training requirement in order to receive TRA payments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Department's response.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department does not believe a specific provision is needed for the reasons explained in the response to item 12, above.</textblock>
    <textblock>53.</textblock>
    <textblock>Homework.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) commented that a major problem has recently arisen which affects workers, when the Department lifted the restrictions prohibiting homework in five of the six industries, and announced it will shortly lift the re-straints on homework in the women's and children's apparel industry. While this matter is not finally resolved due to court challenges, the TAA regulations have to anticipate the situation of potentially extensive homework in these industries.</textblock>
    <textblock>Department's response.</textblock>
    <textblock>This issue is beyond the scope of the 1988 Amendments to the TAA program, and the final rule in this document.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other changes.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to the changes discussed above in responses to comments received, other changes are made in the final rule in this document to correct printing errors, and to make technical and conforming changes that either do not affect the substance of the regulations, or, in the case of other provisions (including the transition provisions of §617.67), are necessary to conform to other changes in the final regulations. Further, references to compliance with ``the Act and this Part'' are changed to eliminate references to the Act so that it is clear that the regulations are controlling and express the Department's interpretations of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Drafting Information</textblock>
    <textblock>This document was prepared under the direction and control of the Director, Office of Trade Adjustment Assistance, Employment and Training Administration, U.S. Department of Labor, 200 Constitution Avenue NW., Washington, DC 20210: telephone: (202) 219-5555 (this is not a toll free number).</textblock>
    <textblock>Classification Executive Order 12866</textblock>
    <textblock>The final rule in this document is not classified as a ``major rule'' under Executive Order 12866 on Federal Regulations, because it is not likely to result in (1) an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more; (2) a major increase in costs or prices for consumers, individual industries, Federal, State, or local government agencies, or geographic regions; or (3) significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, or the ability of United States-based enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises in domestic or export markets.</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the requirements of the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980, 44 U.S.C. Ch. 35, approval of the recordkeeping requirement contained at §§617.19(d) and 617.57 has been obtained from the Office of Management and Budget (control number 12050016, for reporting forms ETA 563 and ETA 9027). OMB control number 12050222 applies to forms used by States to convey reports to the Department as required in §§617.52(c) and 617.54.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>No regulatory flexibility analysis is required where the rule ``will not .␣.␣. have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities.'' 5 U.S.C. 605(b). The definition of the term ``small entity'' under 5 U.S.C. 601 (6) does not include States. Since these regulations involve an entitlement program administered by the States, and are directed to the States, no regulatory flexibility analysis is required. The Secretary has certified to the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration to this effect. Accordingly, no regulatory flexibility analysis is required.</textblock>
    <textblock>Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Number</textblock>
    <textblock>This program is listed in the Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance at No. 17.245, ``Trade Adjustment Assistance_Workers.''</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 20 CFR Part 617</textblock>
    <textblock>Job search assistance, labor, reemployment services, relocation assistance, trade readjustment allowances, unemployment compensation, vocational education.</textblock>
    <textblock>Words of Issuance</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set out in the preamble, part 617 of title 20, Code of Federal Regulations, is amended as set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Signed at Washington, DC on December 21, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Doug Ross,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary of Labor.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
