<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00176</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>2. The Secretary interprets all the above sections to require that a State law provide for:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Such contact by claimants with public employment offices or claims offices or both, (1) as will reasonably insure the payment of unemployment compensation only to individuals who are unemployed and who are able to work and available for work, and (2) that claimants are afforded such placement and other employment services as are necessary and appropriate to facilitate their return to suitable work as soon as possible; and</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Methods of administration which do not unreasonably limit the opportunity of individuals to establish their right to unemployment compensation due under such States law.</textblock>
    <textblock>5001␣Claim Filing and Claimant Reporting Requirements Designed to Satisfy Secretary's Interpretation</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Claim filing_total or part-total unemployment</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Individuals claiming unemployment compensation for total or part-total unemployment are required to file a claim weekly or biweekly, in person or by mail, at a public employment office or a claims office (these terms include offices at itinerant points) as set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Except as provided in paragraph 3, a claimant is required to file in person.</textblock>
    <textblock>a. His new claim with respect to a benefit year, or his continued claim for a waiting week or for his first compensable week of unemployment in such year; and</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Any other claim, when requested to do so by the claims personnel at the office at which he files his claim(s) because questions about his right to benefits are raised by circumstances such as the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The conditions or circumstances of his separation from employment;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
