<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00119</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Suisun Bay is the best known nursery habitat for reproduction and</textblock>
    <textblock>larval survival of splittail, but the habitat has been deleteriously</textblock>
    <textblock>altered by higher salinities in the spring. These higher salinities are</textblock>
    <textblock>caused by a large number of freshwater diversions that allow seawater to</textblock>
    <textblock>intrude farther upstream. At present, there are relatively few periods</textblock>
    <textblock>when freshwater outflow volumes through the Delta and Suisun Bay of any</textblock>
    <textblock>significance are mandated for wildlife or fisheries. State and Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies had planned to increase 1991 and 1992 water supplies for out-of-stream uses at the expense of environmental protection of estuarine</textblock>
    <textblock>fish and wildlife resources in the fifth and potentially sixth years of</textblock>
    <textblock>drought (Morat 1991). Because of significantly higher than normal</textblock>
    <textblock>precipitation and subsequent higher instream flows after March 1991, a</textblock>
    <textblock>State agency request for relaxation of Delta water quality standards was</textblock>
    <textblock>withdrawn. Should a California drought return, water quality relaxation</textblock>
    <textblock>action likely will be requested again to favor out-of-stream water use</textblock>
    <textblock>over the need to protect aquatic habitats for fish and wildlife.</textblock>
    <textblock>Present regulatory processes do not ensure that water inflows to</textblock>
    <textblock>Suisun Bay and the western Estuary will be adequate to maintain the</textblock>
    <textblock>entrapment zone near or in Suisun Bay to benefit splittail. The</textblock>
    <textblock>California State Water Resources Control Board (Board) has the authority</textblock>
    <textblock>to condition or require changes in the amount of water inflow and the</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of water exported or diverted from the Delta. In testimony given</textblock>
    <textblock>before the Board's Water Quality/Water Rights Hearings in 1987, a</textblock>
    <textblock>Service biologist expressed concern for several Delta species including</textblock>
    <textblock>splittail (Lorentzen 1987). The Board did not take regulatory or legal</textblock>
    <textblock>action to protect this fish or its habitat during the four following</textblock>
    <textblock>years. On May 1, 1991, the Board adopted the Water Quality Control Plan</textblock>
    <textblock>for Salinity for the San Francisco Bay-Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta</textblock>
    <textblock>Estuary (1991 Bay/Delta Plan). On September 3, 1991, under provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Clean Water Act, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)</textblock>
    <textblock>disapproved certain water quality standards for the Board's failure to</textblock>
    <textblock>adopt criteria to protect estuarine habitat. In 1993, EPA began the</textblock>
    <textblock>process of formulating replacement standards for those portions of the</textblock>
    <textblock>1991 Bay/Delta Plan that were disapproved. In January 1992, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Governor of California announced a new water policy that included a</textblock>
    <textblock>directive to the Board to establish ``interim measures'' to reverse the</textblock>
    <textblock>decline of fishes in the Bay and Delta. Accordingly, the Board released</textblock>
    <textblock>an interim water quality plan (Draft Decision 1630) in December 1992</textblock>
    <textblock>that immediately was suspended by the Governor.</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA's proposed rule to promulgate Water Quality Standards for</textblock>
    <textblock>Surface Waters of the Sacramento River, San Joaquin River, and San</textblock>
    <textblock>Francisco Bay and Delta is published in this same</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>separate part; however, enforcement of these standards may be difficult. The Service is aware that the salinity standards currently in effect</textblock>
    <textblock>(Water Right Decision 1485) are inconsistently implemented and</textblock>
    <textblock>frequently violated. Institutional guarantees of compliance have been</textblock>
    <textblock>lacking in the past and are needed in the future before existing</textblock>
    <textblock>mechanisms can contribute to the protection of this species.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service currently is analyzing the potential effects on the</textblock>
    <textblock>splittail and other fish and wildlife resources in California as a</textblock>
    <textblock>result of recent enactment of the Central Valley Project Improvement Act</textblock>
    <textblock>(Pub. L. 102-575). Two of the stated purposes of this act are to:</textblock>
    <textblock>``Protect, restore, and enhance fish, wildlife, and associated habitats</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Central Valley and Trinity River basins of California'' and ``to</textblock>
    <textblock>contribute to the State of California's interim and long-term efforts to</textblock>
    <textblock>protect the San Francisco Bay-Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta Estuary.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 3406(b)(2) dedicates 800,000 acre-feet of Central Valley Project</textblock>
    <textblock>water annually for various purposes, including the benefit of federally</textblock>
    <textblock>listed species. Although the Service is reasonably certain that the</textblock>
    <textblock>splittail will realize some benefit from implementation of the Central</textblock>
    <textblock>Valley Project Improvement Act, the magnitude and timeliness of these</textblock>
    <textblock>protections may be inadequate to prevent further decline of splittail.</textblock>
    <textblock>Protective measures currently being implemented to benefit the delta</textblock>
    <textblock>smelt will beneficially affect the splittail by restricting pumping</textblock>
    <textblock>under certain conditions. However, the ecological requirements of each</textblock>
    <textblock>species differ, especially with respect to timing of important</textblock>
    <textblock>developmental stages and habitat use. Splittail need flooded lowland</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat for spawning and are particularly vulnerable to disturbance or</textblock>
    <textblock>destruction of marshy habitat. Therefore, the protections afforded the</textblock>
    <textblock>delta smelt, listed as threatened in 1993 under the Endangered Species</textblock>
    <textblock>Act, will not be sufficient to prevent further decline of the splittail.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons stated above, the Service considers the existing</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory mechanisms inadequate to ensure the long-term existence of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Sacramento splittail.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
