<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00008</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Rural Electrification Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Rural Telephone Bank</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Amendment to the Rural Electrification Act's ``Buy American'' Provision</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Rural Electrification Administration and Rural Telephone Bank, USDA.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Amendment to the Rural Electrification Act's ``Buy American'' Provision.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The recently passed North America Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act has amended the Rural Electrification Act's ``Buy American'' provision. Previously, the provision required borrowers, when using loan funds, to purchase only equipment that was manufactured in the United States and that was made mostly from materials and supplies originating in the United States. The amended provision permits borrowers to also purchase equipment, under similar conditions, from Canadian or Mexican manufacturers.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>For telephone program matters: George Bagnall, Chief, Engineering Standards Branch, Telecommunications Standards Division, Rural Electrification Administration, Room 2846, South Building, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington DC 20250-1500, telephone number (202) 720-0698.</textblock>
    <textblock>For electric program matters: Harvey L. Bowles, Chairman, Technical Standards Committee ``A'' (Electric), Electric Staff Division, Rural Electrification Administration, Room 1246, South Building, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington, DC 20250-1500, telephone number (202) 720-0980.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act, Public Law 103-182, (NAFTA Implementation Act) was signed into law on December 8, 1993. Section 381 (d) of Subtitle G of Title III of the NAFTA Implementation Act amends the REA ``Buy American'' provision established by Section 401 of the Rural Electrification Act of 1938, 52 Stat. 313, 318, 7 U.S.C. 901 et. seq., (1938 RE Act). The REA ``Buy American'' provision was revised by adding ``, Mexico, or Canada'' after every reference therein to the ``United States.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Prior to its amendment by the NAFTA Implementation Act, the 1938 RE Act generally required borrowers, when using loan funds, to purchase equipment that was manufactured in the United States that was made mostly from materials and supplies originating in the United States. The NAFTA Implementation Act amendment of the 1938 RE Act takes effect on January 1, 1994. Generally speaking, after December 31, 1993, borrowers using funds from loans which have been made or guaranteed by REA or the Rural Telephone Bank will be able to satisfy REA's ``Buy American'' provision by purchasing equipment that has been manufactured in North America and made mostly of materials and supplies originating in North America, i.e., in the United States, Mexico, or Canada.</textblock>
    <textblock>The REA ``Buy American'' provision as revised by the NAFTA Implementation Act reads as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>In making loans pursuant to this title and pursuant to the Rural Electrification Act of 1936, the Administrator of Rural Electrification Administration shall require that, to the extent practicable and the cost of which is not unreasonable, the borrower agree to use in connection with the expenditure of such funds only such unmanufactured articles, materials, and supplies, as have been mined or produced in the United States, Mexico, or Canada, and only such manufactured articles, materials, and supplies as have been manufactured in the United States, Mexico, or Canada substantially all from articles, materials or supplies, mined, produced, or manufactured, as the case may be, in the United States, Mexico, or Canada.</textblock>
    <textblock>The amended provision applies to all procurements within REA's jurisdiction that commence after December 31, 1993, which involve any REA, Rural Telephone Bank or guaranteed loan funds. REA is notifying borrowers, as well as Canadian and Mexican manufacturers with current REA technically-accepted products, of this change in the REA ``Buy American'' provision.</textblock>
    <textblock>REA is also making technical revisions to its existing forms of loan contracts and loan contract amendments to conform them to the 1938 RE Act as amended by NAFTA. REA will begin using these revised forms for all transactions entered into after December 31, 1993. In addition, REA is making similar technical revisions to its recommended forms of contracts providing for the purchase of materials and supplies. These changes will have no effect on any contract which is fully in effect prior to January 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Michael V. Dunn,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Under Secretary, Small Community and Rural Development.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc 94-233 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-15-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
