<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00114</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00063</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>I</textblock>
    <textblock>The Boston Edison Company (BECo, the licensee) is the holder of Facility Operating License No. DRP-35, which authorizes the operation of Pilgrim Nuclear Power Station (the facility), at steady state power levels not in excess of 1998 megawatts thermal. This facility is a boiling water reactor located in Plymouth, Massachusetts. The license provides, among other things, that Pilgrim Nuclear Power Station is subject to all rules, regulations, and orders of the Commission now or hereafter in effect.</textblock>
    <textblock>II</textblock>
    <textblock>BECo is preparing to implement the Final Rule on Standards for Protection Against Radiation, 10 CFR part 20, on January 1, 1994. Section 20.1902(d) of the Final Rule specifies posting requirements for airborne radioactivity areas (ARA) and ยง20.1003 defines an ARA based on the derived air concentrations (DAC) values of radionuclides provided in Table 1 of Appendix B to 10 CFR part 20.</textblock>
    <textblock>III</textblock>
    <textblock>By letter dated September 13, 1993, the licensee requested an exemption, pursuant to 10 CFR 20.2301, from the DAC values for Kr-89 and Xe-137 in Table 1 of appendix B to 10 CFR part 20 and provided alternative values in order to use more appropriate specific DAC values for these radionuclides. The requested exemption would constitute a permanent change to the Final Rule values for Kr-89 and Xe-137 for the facility.</textblock>
    <textblock>Based on the NRC staff evaluation, it was calculated that the dose equivalent, in units of rem, that corresponds to an exposure of 2,000 hours at the requested DACs of 10</textblock>
    <textblock>^6</textblock>
    <textblock>uCi/cm for Kr-89 and 10</textblock>
    <textblock>^5</textblock>
    <textblock>uCi/cm for Xe-137 is below the limiting dose values used for determining the radionuclide-specific DAC values in Appendix B to 10 CFR 20.001-20.2402 (and in Federal Guidance Report No. 11). Therefore, the staff finds the specific DAC values acceptable alternatives for use in place of the generic DAC value of 10</textblock>
    <textblock>^7</textblock>
    <textblock>uCi/ml for these radionuclides when determining whether an area is, and requires posting as, an airborne radioactivity area.</textblock>
    <textblock>IV</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, the Commission has determined that, pursuant to 10 CFR 20.2301, the requested exemption from the DAC values for Kr-89 and Xe-137 in Table 1 of Appendix A to 10 CFR part 20 and use of the values specified in the licensee's request is authorized by law, and will not result in undue hazard to life or property. The exemption request has been evaluated in a Safety Evaluation dated December 29, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, the Commission hereby grants BECo and exemption from the values in the Final Rule for Kr-89 and Xe-137 and approves the use of the proposed values in their request when determining whether an area is, and requires posting as, an airborne radioactivity area. This exemption constitutes a permanent change to the applicability of the Regulations in this regard for the facility.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to 10 CFR 51.32, the Commission has determined that the granting of this Exemption will have no significant impact on the quality of the human environment (58 FR 68672 dated December 28, 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>This exemption is effective upon issuance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated at Rockville, Maryland, this 29th day of December 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 50-293]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Boston Edison Co., (Pilgrim Nuclear Power Station); Exemption</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jose A. Calvo,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Division of Reactor Projects I/II, Office of Nuclear Reactor Regulation.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-254 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7590-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
