<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00051</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(iii) Proper management of administrative funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The standards evaluate the specific requirements of each functional responsibility or criterion.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Basis for criteria and standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>HCFA bases the performance criteria and standards on_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Nationwide carrier experience;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Changes in carrier operations due to fiscal constraints; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) HCFA's objectives in achieving better performance.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Publication of criteria and standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Before the beginning of each evaluation period, which usually coincides with the Federal fiscal year period of October 1-September 30, HCFA publishes the performance criteria and standards as a notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. HCFA may not necessarily publish the criteria and standards every year. HCFA interprets the statutory phrase ``before the beginning of each evaluation period'' as allowing publication of the criteria and standards after the Federal fiscal year begins, as long as the evaluation period of the carriers for the new criteria and standards begins after the publication of the notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. A new ยง421.203 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง421.203</textblock>
    <textblock>Carrier's failure to perform efficiently and effectively.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Failure by a carrier to meet, or demonstrate the capacity to meet, the criteria and standards specified in ยง421.201 may be grounds for adverse action by the Secretary, such as contract termination or non-renewal.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Notwithstanding whether or not a carrier meets the criteria and standards specified in ยง421.201, if the cost incurred by the carrier to meet its contractual requirements exceeds the amount that HCFA finds to be reasonable and adequate to meet the cost which must be incurred by an efficiently and economically operated carrier, those high costs may also be grounds for adverse action.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Program No. 93.773, Medicare_Hospital Insurance; and Program No. 93.774, Medicare_Supplementary Medical Insurance Program)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: October 20, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Bruce C. Vladeck,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator, Health Care Financing Administration.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 2, 1993.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna E. Shalala,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-63 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4120-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
