<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00026</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-2-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Site Selection Process for Proposed East Coast Florida National Estuarine Research Reserve; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Ocean and Coastal Resource Management, National Ocean Service, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, DOC.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of public meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Office of Ocean and Coastal Resource Management announces a public meeting on the proposed East Coast Florida National Estuarine Research Reserve.</textblock>
    <textblock>This meeting will be conducted pursuant to section 315 of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972, (CZMA) as amended. The CZMA requires the conduct of at least one public meeting by the State during the site selection process. This meeting must be held in the vicinity of the proposed site. The State of Florida, Department of Environmental Protection has selected the Guana, Tolomato and Matanzas River area in St. Johns and Flagler Counties for consideration for nomination as a National Estuarine Research Reserve. The Public Meeting will be held on Thursday, January 20, 1994, at the St. Johns County Auditorium, 4020 Lewis Speedway, St. Augustine, Florida beginning at 7 p.m. A copy of the agenda may be obtained by contacting Mr. Danny Riley or Mr. Larry Nall at (404) 488-3456.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>June Cradick, Sanctuaries and Reserves Division, Office of Ocean and Coastal Resource Management, NOS/NOAA, 1305 East-West Highway, 12th floor, Silver Spring, Maryland 20910, (301) 713-3133.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Federal Domestic Assistance Catalog 11.429 Coastal Zone Management Program Administration)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 23, 1993.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>W. Stanley Wilson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Administrator for Ocean Services and Coastal Zone Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-260 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-08-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
