<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00043</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The requirements and minimum standards for gas measurement on</textblock>
    <textblock>the lease, unit, unit participating area, or communitized area by</textblock>
    <textblock>an alternate method of measurement, or at a location off the</textblock>
    <textblock>lease, unit, unit participating area, or communitized area by</textblock>
    <textblock>either an authorized or an alternate method of measurement, are</textblock>
    <textblock>as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Measurement on the Lease, Unit, Unit Participating Area, or</textblock>
    <textblock>Communitized Area</textblock>
    <textblock>A written application for approval of an alternate gas</textblock>
    <textblock>measurement method shall be submitted to the authorized officer</textblock>
    <textblock>and written approval obtained before any such alternate gas</textblock>
    <textblock>measurement method is installed or operated. Any operator</textblock>
    <textblock>requesting approval of any alternate gas sales measurement system</textblock>
    <textblock>shall submit performance data, actual field test results, or any</textblock>
    <textblock>other supporting data or evidence acceptable to the authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>officer, that will demonstrate that the proposed alternate gas</textblock>
    <textblock>sales measurement system will meet or exceed the objectives of</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicable minimum standards or will not adversely affect</textblock>
    <textblock>royalty income or production accountability.</textblock>
    <textblock>Violation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Major.</textblock>
    <textblock>Corrective Action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Submit application and obtain approval.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abatement Period:</textblock>
    <textblock>Prior to sales or removal.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Measurement at a Location Off the Lease, Unit, Unit</textblock>
    <textblock>Participating Area, or Communitized Area</textblock>
    <textblock>a. A written application for off-lease measurement shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>submitted to the authorized officer and written approval obtained</textblock>
    <textblock>before any such off-lease gas measurement facilities are</textblock>
    <textblock>installed or operated. The application for approval of off-lease</textblock>
    <textblock>measurement shall justify the location of the measurement</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities at the desired off-lease location before approval will</textblock>
    <textblock>be granted, but no additional approval as to the gas sales</textblock>
    <textblock>measurement method is required, provided measurement is to be</textblock>
    <textblock>accomplished by orifice meter pursuant to the requirements and</textblock>
    <textblock>minimum standards of this Order.</textblock>
    <textblock>Violation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Minor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Corrective Action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Submit application and obtain approval.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abatement Period:</textblock>
    <textblock>20 days.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. If gas measurement is to be accomplished at a location off</textblock>
    <textblock>the lease, unit, unit participating area, or communitized area by</textblock>
    <textblock>any alternate measurement method (any method other than</textblock>
    <textblock>measurement by orifice meter), then the application, in addition</textblock>
    <textblock>to justifying the location of the measurement facilities, shall</textblock>
    <textblock>also demonstrate the acceptability of the alternate measurement</textblock>
    <textblock>method pursuant to Section III.F.1. of this Order.</textblock>
    <textblock>Violation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Major.</textblock>
    <textblock>Corrective Action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Submit application and obtain approval.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abatement Period:</textblock>
    <textblock>Prior to sales.</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Variances From Minimum Standards</textblock>
    <textblock>An operator may request that the authorized officer approve a</textblock>
    <textblock>variance from any of the minimum standards prescribed in Article</textblock>
    <textblock>III. All such requests shall be submitted in writing to the</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate authorized officer and shall provide information as</textblock>
    <textblock>to the circumstances warranting approval of the variance(s)</textblock>
    <textblock>requested and the proposed alternative means by which the related</textblock>
    <textblock>minimum standard(s) will be satisfied. The authorized officer,</textblock>
    <textblock>after considering all relevant factors, shall approve the</textblock>
    <textblock>requested variance(s) if it is determined that the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>alternative(s) meets or exceeds the objectives of the applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>minimum standard(s), or does not adversely affect royalty income</textblock>
    <textblock>or production accountability.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, approval may be given orally by the authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>officer before the operator initiates actions which require a</textblock>
    <textblock>variance from minimum standards. The oral request, if granted,</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be followed by a written request not later than the fifth</textblock>
    <textblock>business day following oral approval, and written approval will</textblock>
    <textblock>then be appropriate.</textblock>
    <textblock>The authorized officer may also issue NTLs that establish</textblock>
    <textblock>modified standards and requirements for specific geographic areas</textblock>
    <textblock>of operations.</textblock>
    <textblock>After notice to the operator, the authorized officer may also</textblock>
    <textblock>require compliance with standards that exceed those contained in</textblock>
    <textblock>this Order whenever such additional requirements are necessary to</textblock>
    <textblock>achieve protection of royalty income or production</textblock>
    <textblock>accountability. The rationale for any such additional</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements shall be documented in writing to the operator.</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-149 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-84-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
