<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00048</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-0-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>We believe that the composition of a contractor's</textblock>
    <textblock>workload (for example, number of hospital inpatient bills</textblock>
    <textblock>versus number of outpatient bills or laboratory bills, etc.)</textblock>
    <textblock>is an important factor in the amount of costs it incurs</textblock>
    <textblock>since some claims are inherently more problematic and</textblock>
    <textblock>difficult to resolve. In order to give full consideration</textblock>
    <textblock>of each contractor's unique situation, we currently apply a</textblock>
    <textblock>``complexity index'' to develop the BPRs' unit cost targets.</textblock>
    <textblock>This methodology allows us to correlate the contractor's</textblock>
    <textblock>costs with its individual workload composition. The use of</textblock>
    <textblock>the complexity index allows us to identify the contractors</textblock>
    <textblock>whose unit costs appear to be out of proportion to the type</textblock>
    <textblock>and medium (electronic versus hardcopy) of workload they</textblock>
    <textblock>must process.</textblock>
    <textblock>Use of the complexity index methodology allows us to</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluate each contractor's costs with full consideration of</textblock>
    <textblock>its unique workload mix and within the national forum of its</textblock>
    <textblock>peers. In this way, we identify our high cost contractors.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, since the use of the complexity index methodology</textblock>
    <textblock>is an administrative tool to identify contractors with</textblock>
    <textblock>aberrant costs and can be changed or modified as required,</textblock>
    <textblock>we do not believe it necessary to outline this methodology</textblock>
    <textblock>in the regulation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>Several commenters stated that the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§§421.124(a) and 421.203(a) on high cost contractors do not</textblock>
    <textblock>specify the types of adverse action we may take on the</textblock>
    <textblock>grounds of excessive cost. Contractors are uncertain about</textblock>
    <textblock>how we would go about the process of applying sanctions and</textblock>
    <textblock>what these sanctions might be.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Adverse contract actions are listed in</textblock>
    <textblock>§§421.124(a) and 421.203(a) of the proposed regulation, but</textblock>
    <textblock>we are not limited to those. Adverse contract actions are</textblock>
    <textblock>further defined in the intermediary and carrier manual</textblock>
    <textblock>issuances released within the HCFA Program Manual Issuances</textblock>
    <textblock>System, which contain the details of the CPEP. Adverse</textblock>
    <textblock>actions range in severity commensurate with relative</textblock>
    <textblock>performance and include, but are not limited to, such</textblock>
    <textblock>actions as, Regional Office Letter of Admonition; Central</textblock>
    <textblock>Office Letter of Admonition; deletion of the automatic</textblock>
    <textblock>renewal clause from the contract without performance goals</textblock>
    <textblock>established; deletion of the automatic renewal clause from</textblock>
    <textblock>the contract with performance goals established; limited</textblock>
    <textblock>contract automatic-renewal clause and provision for</textblock>
    <textblock>termination upon 90 days notice; reduction in territory or</textblock>
    <textblock>``carve-out''; non-renewal; and termination.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>A commenter was unsure whether, if HCFA does</textblock>
    <textblock>not publish the CPEP standards during a fiscal year, there</textblock>
    <textblock>would be no performance evaluation for that year or whether</textblock>
    <textblock>the previous year's CPEP would apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>In general, the evaluation period which the</textblock>
    <textblock>criteria and standards measure is the Federal fiscal year.</textblock>
    <textblock>We make every effort to publish the criteria and standards</textblock>
    <textblock>prior to the beginning of the Federal fiscal year, that is,</textblock>
    <textblock>October 1st. If we do not publish a</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice</textblock>
    <textblock>before the new fiscal year begins, readers may presume that,</textblock>
    <textblock>until and unless notified otherwise, the criteria and</textblock>
    <textblock>standards which were previously in effect remain in effect.</textblock>
    <textblock>When a new CPEP is published, it usually applies to a</textblock>
    <textblock>prospective period, as stated in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>One commenter states that contractors</textblock>
    <textblock>participate in pilot projects which may involve additional</textblock>
    <textblock>funding from HCFA. They assume this ``additional funding''</textblock>
    <textblock>would not be considered as ``excessively high costs''.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>We encourage contractors to participate in</textblock>
    <textblock>pilot projects which may result in improved quality, service</textblock>
    <textblock>or efficiency in the administration of the Medicare program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Where a contractor's participation in a pilot study or</textblock>
    <textblock>program adversely affects its performance evaluation,</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate adjustments are made to mitigate the impact of</textblock>
    <textblock>the pilot study or program.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
