<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00117</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940106-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Summary of Factors Affecting the Species</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 4 of the Endangered Species Act (16 U.S.C. 1531</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>) and</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations (50 CFR part 424) promulgated to implement the listing</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions of the Act set forth the procedures for adding species to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Lists. A species may be determined to be endangered or</textblock>
    <textblock>threatened because of one or more of the five factors described in</textblock>
    <textblock>section 4(a)(1). These factors and their application to the Sacramento</textblock>
    <textblock>splittail (</textblock>
    <textblock>Pogonichthys macrolepidotus</textblock>
    <textblock>) are as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>A. The Present or Threatened Destruction, Modification, or Curtailment of Its Habitat or Range</textblock>
    <textblock>The Sacramento splittail was once</textblock>
    <textblock>widely distributed in the Central Valley of California from Redding to</textblock>
    <textblock>the modern-day site of Friant Dam near the City of Fresno. It is now</textblock>
    <textblock>restricted to western, northern, and southern portions of the Delta due</textblock>
    <textblock>to dams, diversions, dredging, and the diking and filling of historic</textblock>
    <textblock>flood basins. Within the species' constricted range, splittail have</textblock>
    <textblock>declined by 62 percent since 1984. However, the overall percentage</textblock>
    <textblock>decline over its historical range is much greater. Populations have</textblock>
    <textblock>fluctuated somewhat in the past, with most recruitment taking place in</textblock>
    <textblock>wet years. In wet years since 1976, however, splittail recruitment has</textblock>
    <textblock>declined consistently with catches per unit effort of 12.3, 8.1, 2.0,</textblock>
    <textblock>1.3, and 0.3 for 1978, 1982, 1983, 1986, and 1993, respectively.</textblock>
    <textblock>Splittail declines are highest (82 percent) in the shallow-water Suisun</textblock>
    <textblock>Bay area, which is the center of its distribution. This may reflect the</textblock>
    <textblock>loss of productive brackish-water habitat in Suisun and Grizzly Bays due</textblock>
    <textblock>to increased salinities caused by low outflows.</textblock>
    <textblock>Currently, Delta water diversions and exports total to about 9</textblock>
    <textblock>million acre-feet per year. Federal and State projects presently export</textblock>
    <textblock>about 6 million acre-feet per year when sufficient water is available,</textblock>
    <textblock>and in-Delta agricultural uses result in diversion of about 3 million</textblock>
    <textblock>additional acre-feet per year. Plans currently being prepared could</textblock>
    <textblock>potentially induce increased exports and diversions in the future. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Service knows of 22 major Central Valley Project, State Water Project,</textblock>
    <textblock>or private organization proposals that would result in increased water</textblock>
    <textblock>exports from the Delta, reduced water inflow to the Delta, changes in</textblock>
    <textblock>the timing and volume of Delta inflow, or increases in heavy metal</textblock>
    <textblock>contamination of the Delta. These proposed projects or actions include</textblock>
    <textblock>but are not limited to Central Valley Project Operations Criteria and</textblock>
    <textblock>Plan (including Friant Contract Renewals), Los Banos Grandes Reservoir,</textblock>
    <textblock>Los Vaqueros Reservoir, South Delta Water Management Program, South</textblock>
    <textblock>Delta Water Barriers Project, North Delta Water Management Project, West</textblock>
    <textblock>Delta Water Management Project, Coastal Aqueduct proposal, Delta</textblock>
    <textblock>Wetlands Corporation Water Storage Project, Folsom Dam Reoperation,</textblock>
    <textblock>Oroville Dam Reoperation, Auburn Dam, Central Valley Project contract</textblock>
    <textblock>renewals, the Central Valley Project and State Water Project wheeling</textblock>
    <textblock>purchase agreement, reactivation of the San Luis Drain, Stanislaus-Calaveras River Basin Water Use Program, Suisun Marsh Project Phase</textblock>
    <textblock>Three and Four, Kern Water Bank, Arvin Edison water storage and exchange</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal, Federal Water Project change in diversion point, and State</textblock>
    <textblock>Water Project Pump additions. These projects would modify or destroy</textblock>
    <textblock>the habitat of this species.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because the Federal pumping plant has been operated at capacity for</textblock>
    <textblock>many years except for a few drought years, increased exports at this</textblock>
    <textblock>plant appear unlikely. However, the State Water Project pumping plant</textblock>
    <textblock>and the capacity of the State Aqueduct have considerable unused</textblock>
    <textblock>capacity. The California Department of Water Resources (1992) reported</textblock>
    <textblock>the past and projected State Water Project deliveries from Delta sources</textblock>
    <textblock>during the years of 1962 to 2035. In the 1980s, deliveries ranged from</textblock>
    <textblock>1.5 million acre-feet to 2.8 million acre-feet. By 2010, deliveries of</textblock>
    <textblock>up to 4.2 million acre-feet are planned.</textblock>
    <textblock>Since 1983, the proportion of water exported from the Delta during</textblock>
    <textblock>October through March has been higher than in earlier years (Moyle</textblock>
    <textblock>et</textblock>
    <textblock>al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1992). The timing of these proportionally higher exports have</textblock>
    <textblock>coincided with the spawning season of the splittail. Federal and State</textblock>
    <textblock>water diversion projects in the southern Delta export, by absolute</textblock>
    <textblock>volume, mostly Sacramento River water with some San Joaquin River water.</textblock>
    <textblock>Moreover, during periods of high export pumping and low to moderate</textblock>
    <textblock>river outflows, reaches of the San Joaquin River reverse direction and</textblock>
    <textblock>flow upstream to the pumping plants located in the southern Delta. The</textblock>
    <textblock>State-operated pumping plant presently exports water at rates up to</textblock>
    <textblock>6,400 cubic feet per second (cfs). The State is considering proposals</textblock>
    <textblock>to export an additional 3,900 cfs. The Federal pumping plant can export</textblock>
    <textblock>water at rates up to 4,600 cfs. In addition, local private diverters</textblock>
    <textblock>export up to 5,000 cfs from about 1,800 diversions scattered throughout</textblock>
    <textblock>the Delta.</textblock>
    <textblock>When total diversion rates are high relative to Delta outflow, and</textblock>
    <textblock>the lower San Joaquin River and other channels have a net upstream</textblock>
    <textblock>(i.e., reverse or negative) flow, out-migrating larval and juvenile fish</textblock>
    <textblock>of many species become disoriented. Large mortalities occur as a result</textblock>
    <textblock>of loss to pumps and predation by striped bass at the various water</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities and other diversion sites. Because data from State and</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal pumping facilities indicate that splittail migrate upstream to</textblock>
    <textblock>spawn, positive outflows are also important to transport splittail young</textblock>
    <textblock>downstream (Meng 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>In recent years, the number of days of reversed San Joaquin River</textblock>
    <textblock>flow have increased (Moyle</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1992), particularly during the</textblock>
    <textblock>February-June spawning months for splittail. All size classes of</textblock>
    <textblock>splittail young suffer near total loss when they are entrained by the</textblock>
    <textblock>pumping plants and diversions in the south Delta. Few young are</textblock>
    <textblock>effectively salvaged at the Federal and State pumping plant screens.</textblock>
    <textblock>This species' embryonic, larval, and postlarval mortality rates also are</textblock>
    <textblock>higher when reduced outflows cause increases in salinity and relocation</textblock>
    <textblock>of the entrapment zone (Moyle and Yoshiyama 1992).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
