<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00073</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>List of Subjects</textblock>
    <textblock>42 CFR Part 412</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedure, Health facilities, Medicare, Puerto Rico, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>42 CFR Part 413</textblock>
    <textblock>Health facilities, Kidney diseases, Medicare, Puerto Rico, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>42 CFR chapter IV is amended as set forth below:</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Part 412 is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 412_PROSPECTIVE PAYMENT SYSTEMS FOR INPATIENT HOSPITAL SERVICES</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 412 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Secs. 1102, 1815(e), 1871, and 1886 of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1302, 1395g(e), 1395hh, and 1395ww).</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart A_General Provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>2. In ยง412.2, the introductory language in paragraph (c) is republished, paragraphs (c)(3) and (4) are revised, and paragraph (c)(5) is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง412.2</textblock>
    <textblock>Basis of payment.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Inpatient operating costs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The prospective payment system provides a payment amount for inpatient operating costs, including_</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Special care unit operating costs (intensive care type unit services, as described in ยง413.53(b) of this chapter);</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Malpractice insurance costs related to services furnished to inpatients; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Certain preadmission services furnished by the hospital or by an entity wholly owned or operated by the hospital (that is, any entity for which the hospital itself is the sole owner or operator) to the patient during the 3 days immediately preceding the date of the patient's admission to the hospital. A hospital is considered the sole operator of an entity if the hospital has exclusive responsibility for conducting or overseeing the entity's routine operations, regardless of whether the hospital also has policymaking authority over the entity. The specific preadmission services (other than ambulance services) included in the inpatient hospital operating costs are the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Diagnostic services (including clinical diagnostic laboratory tests) furnished on or after January 1, 1991.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Other services related to the admission furnished on or after October 1, 1991. Other services related to the admission means services (other than diagnostic services) that are furnished in connection with the principal diagnosis that requires the beneficiary to be admitted as an inpatient.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
