<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00058</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00044</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The notificants listed below have applied under the Change in Bank Control Act (12 U.S.C. 1817(j)) and  225.41 of the Board's Regulation Y (12 CFR 225.41) to acquire a bank or bank holding company. The factors that are considered in acting on the notices are set forth in paragraph 7 of the Act (12 U.S.C. 1817(j)(7)).</textblock>
    <textblock>The notices are available for immediate inspection at the Federal Reserve Bank indicated. Once the notices have been accepted for processing, they will also be available for inspection at the offices of the Board of Governors. Interested persons may express their views in writing to the Reserve Bank indicated for that notice or to the offices of the Board of Governors. Comments must be received not later than January 31, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta</textblock>
    <textblock>(Zane R. Kelley, Vice President) 104 Marietta Street, N.W., Atlanta, Georgia 30303:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Charles William Gerlach</textblock>
    <textblock>, Palm Beach, Florida; to acquire 69.2 percent of the voting shares of White Eagle Financial Group, Inc., Boca Raton, Florida, and thereby indirectly acquire Admiralty Bank, Palm Beach Gardens, Florida.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis</textblock>
    <textblock>(James M. Lyon, Vice President) 250 Marquette Avenue, Minneapolis, Minnesota 55480:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Reuben A. Ellingson and Eunice R. Ellingson Family Revocable Trust</textblock>
    <textblock>, Bottineau, North Dakota; to acquire 16.53 percent of the voting shares of State Bank of Bottineau Holding Company, Bottineau, North Dakota, and thereby indirectly acquire State Bank of Bottineau, Bottineau, North Dakota.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Kathleen A. Nesvig</textblock>
    <textblock>, to acquire 17.22 percent of the voting shares of Omega City Holding Company, La Moure, North Dakota, and thereby indirectly acquire The First State Bank of La Moure, La Moure, North Dakota.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City</textblock>
    <textblock>(John E. Yorke, Senior Vice President) 925 Grand Avenue, Kansas City, Missouri 64198:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Don Bodard</textblock>
    <textblock>, Shawnee, Oklahoma; to acquire 100 percent of the voting shares of First Medicine Lodge Bancshares, Inc., Medicine Lodge, Kansas, and thereby indirectly acquire The First National Bank of Medicine Lodge, Medicine Lodge, Kansas.</textblock>
    <textblock>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, January 6, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Charles William Gerlach, et al.; Change in Bank Control Notices; Acquisitions of Shares of Banks or Bank Holding Companies</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jennifer J. Johnson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Secretary of the Board.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-653 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6210-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
