<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00006</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00003</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration</textblock>
    <textblock>Alteration of Jet Route J-171; CO</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 71</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Airspace Docket No. 93-ANM-20]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This action revokes a portion of Jet Route J-171 from Hugo, CO, to Kiowa, CO, because the Kiowa, CO, Very High Frequency Omnidirectional Range/Tactical Navigation (VORTAC) facility will be decommissioned after the new Denver International Airport becomes operational. This action supports the new Denver International Airport airspace realignment.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>0901 U.T.C., March 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Norman W. Thomas, Airspace and Obstruction Evaluation Branch (ATP-240), Airspace-Rules and Aeronautical Information Division, Air Traffic Rules and Procedures Service, Federal Aviation Administration, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591; telephone: (202) 267-9230.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>History</textblock>
    <textblock>On August 6, 1993, the FAA proposed to amend part 71 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (14 CFR part 71) to remove that portion of Jet Route J-171 from Hugo, CO, to Kiowa, CO (58 FR 42038).</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested parties were invited to participate in this rulemaking proceeding by submitting written comments on the proposal to the FAA. No comments objecting to the proposal were received. Except for editorial changes, this amendment is the same as that proposed in the notice. Jet routes are published in paragraph 2004 of FAA Order 7400.9A dated June 17, 1993, and effective September 16, 1993, which is incorporated by reference in 14 CFR 71.1 (58 FR 36298; July 6, 1993). The jet route listed in this document will be published subsequently in the Order.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>This amendment to part 71 of the Federal Aviation Regulations revokes a portion of Jet Route J-171 from Hugo, CO, to Kiowa, CO. The Kiowa, CO, VORTAC will be decommissioned after the new Denver International Airport becomes operational. This accommodates the new Denver International Airport airspace realignment.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA has determined that this regulation only involves an established body of technical regulations for which frequent and routine amendments are necessary to keep them operationally current. It, therefore; (1) Is not a ``significant regulatory action'' under Executive Order 12866; (2) is not a ``significant rule'' under DOT Regulatory Policies and Procedures (44 FR 11034; February 26, 1979); and (3) does not warrant preparation of a regulatory evaluation as the anticipated impact is so minimal. Since this is a routine matter that will only affect air traffic procedures and air navigation, it is certified that this rule will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities under the criteria of the Regulatory Flexibility Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 14 CFR Part 71</textblock>
    <textblock>Airspace, Incorporation by reference, Navigation (air).</textblock>
    <textblock>Adoption of the Amendment</textblock>
    <textblock>In consideration of foregoing, the Federal Aviation Administration amends 14 CFR part 71, as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 71_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 71 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>49 U.S.C. app. 1348(a), 1354(a), 1510; E.O. 10854, 24 FR 9565, 3 CFR, 1959-1963 Comp., p. 389; 49 U.S.C. 106(g); 14 CFR 11.69.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง71.1</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The incorporation by reference in 14 CFR 71.1 of the Federal Aviation Administration Order 7400.9A, Airspace Designations and Reporting Points, dated June 17, 1993, and effective September 16, 1993, is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Paragraph 2004_Jet Routes</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>J-171 [Revised]</textblock>
    <textblock>From Tobe, CO, to Hugo, CO.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Harold W. Becker,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Airspace-Rules and Aeronautical Information Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-783 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
