<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-1-00033</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Qualified Domestic Relations Orders</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF LABOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Pension and Welfare Benefits Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>29 CFR Part 2530</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pension and Welfare Benefits Administration, Labor.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Reopening and extension of comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document reopens and extends the comment period regarding a request for information by the Department of Labor (the Department) to assist it in assessing the need for a regulation clarifying certain statutory requirements set forth in title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code (the Code) with regard to qualified domestic relations orders (QDROs). The request for information was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on October 21, 1993 (58 FR 54444).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department has received a number of requests from members of the public for additional time to prepare comments.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The comment period is reopened and extended through February 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments (preferably at least six copies) should be addressed to the Office of Regulations and Interpretations, Pension and Welfare Benefits Administration, room N-5669, U.S. Department of Labor, Washington, DC 20210. Attention: QDRO RFI. All comments received will be available for public inspection at the Public Disclosure Room, Pension and Welfare Benefits Administration, U.S. Department of Labor, room N-5507, 200 Constitution Ave., NW., Washington, DC 20210.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Deborah Hobbs, Office of Regulations and Interpretations, Pension and Welfare Benefits Administration, U.S. Department of Labor, Washington, DC 20210, telephone (202) 219-7901; or Susan Rees, Plan Benefits Security Division, Office of the Solicitor, U.S. Department of Labor, Washington, DC 20210, telephone (202) 219-9141. These are not toll-free numbers.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 21, 1993, the Department published a request for information in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 54444) to assist it in assessing the need for a regulation clarifying certain statutory requirements set forth in title I of ERISA and in the Code with regard to qualified domestic relations orders. In that notice, the Department invited all interested persons to submit written comments concerning the request for information on or before December 20, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department has received a number of requests from members of the public for additional time to prepare comments. In order to provide the public with an additional opportunity to submit comments, the Department believes that it is appropriate to reopen and extend the comment period. Accordingly, this notice reopens and extends the period during which comments on the request for information will be received through Friday, February 18, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Reopening and Extension of Comment Period</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the period of time for submission of public comments in response to the request for information concerning qualified domestic relations orders, published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on October 21, 1993, is reopened and extended through February 18, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Signed at Washington, DC, this 30th day of December, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Olena Berg,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary for Pension and Welfare Benefits, U.S. Department of Labor.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-639 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4510-29-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
