<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00028</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Consistent with the NPRM, the final changes to</textblock>
    <textblock>§§404.1579(e)(2), 404.1594(e)(2), 416.994(b)(4)(ii) and</textblock>
    <textblock>416.994a(g)(2) also explain that we will consider the factors</textblock>
    <textblock>described in §§404.911 and 416.1411 for purposes of determining</textblock>
    <textblock>generally whether an individual has good cause for failure to</textblock>
    <textblock>cooperate in a review of his or her entitlement to benefits based</textblock>
    <textblock>on disability. (Current §§404.911 and 416.1411 explain the</textblock>
    <textblock>factors we consider in determining whether an individual has good</textblock>
    <textblock>cause for missing a deadline to request review of a determination</textblock>
    <textblock>or decision under our administrative review process. As</textblock>
    <textblock>explained later in this preamble, we are amending §§404.911 and</textblock>
    <textblock>416.1411, which apply to title II and title XVI cases,</textblock>
    <textblock>respectively, to provide explicitly for the consideration of the</textblock>
    <textblock>limitations described in section 10305 of OBRA 1989 in</textblock>
    <textblock>determining whether an individual has good cause for missing a</textblock>
    <textblock>deadline to request review.) We are also revising</textblock>
    <textblock>§§404.1586(d) and 416.986(c) to clarify that we will</textblock>
    <textblock>consider the factors described in §§404.911 and 416.1411,</textblock>
    <textblock>respectively, for purposes of determining generally whether an</textblock>
    <textblock>individual has good cause for failure to cooperate in a review of</textblock>
    <textblock>his or her continuing entitlement to title II benefits, or</textblock>
    <textblock>continuing eligibility for title XVI benefits, based on</textblock>
    <textblock>blindness.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Without Fault_Waiver of Adjustment or Recovery of</textblock>
    <textblock>Overpayments</textblock>
    <textblock>Under sections 204(b) and 1631(b)(1)(B) of the Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>recovery or adjustment of overpayments to a title II or title XVI</textblock>
    <textblock>beneficiary may be waived in situations where the individual is</textblock>
    <textblock>without fault in connection with the overpayment and recovery or</textblock>
    <textblock>adjustment would defeat the purposes of the program or would be</textblock>
    <textblock>against equity and good conscience or, with respect to the</textblock>
    <textblock>title XVI program, would impede efficient or effective</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of title XVI because of the small amount involved.</textblock>
    <textblock>Our existing regulations explain that in determining whether an</textblock>
    <textblock>individual was without fault, all pertinent factors surrounding</textblock>
    <textblock>the overpayment will be considered, including the individual's</textblock>
    <textblock>age, intelligence, education, and physical and mental</textblock>
    <textblock>capabilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 10305(b) of OBRA 1989 amended section 204(b) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Act to provide that the Secretary, in making determinations or</textblock>
    <textblock>decisions of ``without fault'' for purposes of section 204(b), must</textblock>
    <textblock>take into account any physical, mental, educational, or</textblock>
    <textblock>linguistic limitations (including any lack of facility with the</textblock>
    <textblock>English language) the individual has. In addition, the amendment</textblock>
    <textblock>to section 1631(c)(1) of the Act made by section 10305(e) of OBRA</textblock>
    <textblock>1989 provides that, for the purposes of the title XVI program,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary must take these same limitations into account in</textblock>
    <textblock>determining, among other things, whether an individual is without</textblock>
    <textblock>fault.</textblock>
    <textblock>We are making the following changes in our regulations which</textblock>
    <textblock>implement sections 204(b) and 1631(b)(1)(B) of the Act to reflect</textblock>
    <textblock>the pertinent amendments made by section 10305.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Amend §404.507 to provide that in making</textblock>
    <textblock>determinations of without fault with respect to title II</textblock>
    <textblock>overpayments, we will take into account any physical, mental,</textblock>
    <textblock>educational, or linguistic limitations (including any lack of</textblock>
    <textblock>facility with the English language) the individual has.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
