<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00121</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00024</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Based on the eight comments received,</textblock>
    <textblock>45</textblock>
    <textblock>the Commission has added the lowercase ``l'' as an alternative to the uppercase ``L'' as the symbol for the SI metric liter and milliliter. The comments point out that while the uppercase ``L'' is the preferred symbol, there is no international agreement on requiring only the uppercase ``L.'' Indeed, international law may require permitting the use of the lowercase ``l.'' As Mr. John H. Woelflein commented:</textblock>
    <textblock>Because the BIPM SI brochure as well as ISO 1000 give the symbol for liter as ``l,L'', the US is obligated as a Meter Convention signatory to permit the use of either symbol. Otherwise, imported products which use the lower case ``l'' could be excluded by Customs authorities. Of course, the capital ``L'' is preferred for USA use.</textblock>
    <textblock>46</textblock>
    <textblock>Further, companies that export products often prefer to use the lowercase ``l'' ``as being more acceptable in some countries.''</textblock>
    <textblock>47</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 500.24␣Supplemental Statements</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 500.25␣Net Quantity, Average Quantity, Permitted Variations</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 500.26␣Representations of Servings, Uses, Applications</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 500.27␣Multiunit Packages</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 500.28␣Variety Packages</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 500.29␣Combination Packages.</textblock>
    <textblock>The amendments to these six sections renumber them, add metric examples and parentheticals, and make reference to ``mass'' as well as weight where appropriate. In the amendment to §500.26 the reference to the National Bureau of Standards has been changed to read ``National Institute of Standards and Technology.''</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Other Statutory and Regulatory Considerations</textblock>
    <textblock>In promulgating the amendments to the FPLA regulations, the Commission has considered certain statutory and regulatory requirements. These requirements arise under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321); the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. 3501); the Metric Conversion Act (15 U.S.C. 205b); the Commission's Regulatory Review Program; and the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. 603).</textblock>
    <textblock>A. National Environmental Policy Act</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the Commission's rules (16 CFR subpart I, section 1.81</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>) implementing the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321), no ``major'' rule amendment ``significantly affecting the quality of the human environment'' will be proposed unless an environmental assessment or impact statement has been prepared (16 CFR 1.82). For the following reasons, it is not appropriate to have an environmental assessment or statement for the amendments to regulations issued implementing the metric amendments to FPLA.</textblock>
    <textblock>First, the amendments do not ``significantly affect the quality of the human environment'' because they do not independently create significant new duties. Moreover, any environmental consequences that may come from metric measurement translation and disclosure are not the result of the amendments to the regulations, but instead are consequences of the amendments to FPLA by Congress. Second, the environmental effects, if any, of the amendments are so uncertain that any environmental analysis would be based on speculation. (See, 16 CFR 1.83(a).) Third, under section 13 of the amended FPLA, labels printed prior to February 14, 1994 may continue to be used until the supply is exhausted. Thus, companies will not have to discard unused labels into the waste stream and, by so doing, cause damage to the environment. Therefore, the amendments to the FPLA regulations are unlikely to cause any significant impact on the environment.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Md Ag, 5, 1; Mech, 7, 2; Mich Ag, 6, 2; Micr, 4, 1; NCWM, 19, 3; Pier, 2, 1; Soko, 8, 2; and Woel, 3, 2.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>45</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Woel, 3, 2.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>46</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Soko, 8, 2.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>47</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
