<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00123</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00088</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 4, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>On June 15, 1992, the Midwest Clearing Corporation (``MCC'') submitted a proposed rule change (File No. SR-MCC-92-06) to the Securities and Exchange Commission (``Commission'') pursuant to section 19(b) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (``Act'').</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of the proposal appeared in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on September 17, 1992, to solicit comment from interested persons.</textblock>
    <textblock>No comments were received by the Commission. This order approves the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Description of the Proposal</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the rule change is to expedite the settlement of claims for dividends or for registered bond interest by shortening the time frames during which MCC requires delivery of Claim Forms by participants who are filing claims against other participants. Under MCC's Dividend Settlement Service (``DSS''), MCC processes participants' claims for dividends and registered bond interest. DDS procedures require that before a participant can submit a claim against another participant, it must deliver to MCC a Notice of Intent. The Notice of Intent must include either documents which establish the basis for the claim or a written explanation of the basis for the claim.</textblock>
    <textblock>MCC rules require the claiming participant to deliver two copies of a Claim Form to the participant against whom the claim is made. The Claim Form must now be delivered within five business days, previously within ten business days, after delivering the Notice of Intent to MCC.</textblock>
    <textblock>Where the Notice of Intent is delivered six months or more after the record date of the dividend or interest claimed, the Claim Form must now be delivered within ten business days, previously within twenty business days, after the delivery of the Notice of Intent to MCC.</textblock>
    <textblock>Both the Notice of Intent and Claim Form must be delivered through the facilities of MCC.</textblock>
    <textblock>Once MCC receives the Notice of Intent and Claim Form, MCC distributes them to the participant against whom the claim is made on the same day the Claim Form is received.</textblock>
    <textblock>MCC's rules require the participant receiving the Claim Form to respond by the Charge Date, which appears on the Claim Form. A participant who receives a Claim Form may honor it, may file an Intent Rejection with MCC, or may take no action. If an Intent Rejection is filed, the participants may settle the matter themselves or may submit the matter to arbitration. If the participant receiving the Claim Form honors the claim or fails to respond, MCC will debit that participant's account and will credit the account of the claiming participant.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission believes that the proposal is consistent with the Act and particularly with section 17A of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 17A(b)(3)(F) of the Act requires that the rules of clearing agencies be designed to promote the prompt and accurate clearance and settlement of securities transactions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Moreover, in section 17A(a)(1) of the Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>Congress encourages the use of efficient and effective safe procedures for securities clearance and settlement.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission believes that shortening the time frames for filing claim forms, from ten business days to five business days and from twenty business days to ten business days, should result in more efficient and effective claim processing at MCC. Shortening the time frames also should encourage participants to settle their claims and disputes involving dividends and interest in a more prompt manner.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Conclusion</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons discussed above, the Commission believes that the proposal is consistent with the requirements of the Act, particularly section 17A of the Act, and the rules and regulations thereunder.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is therefore ordered,</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 19(b)(2) of the Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>that the above-mentioned proposed rule change (File No. SR-MCC-92-06) be, and hereby is, approved.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Commission by the Division of Market Regulation, pursuant to delegated authority.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Release No. 34-33414; File No. SR-MCC-92-06]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Self-Regulatory Organizations; Midwest Clearing Corp.; Order Approving Proposed Rule Change to Reduce the Time Frames for Processing Dividend Settlement Service Claims</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Securities Exchange Act Release No. 31170 (September 10, 1992), 57 FR 43040.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>MCC Rules, Art. V, R. 7, Section 4.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Id.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>MCC Rules, Art. V, R. 7, Sections 3 and 4.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78q-1 (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78q-1(b)(3)(F) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78q-1(a)(1) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(2) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 200.30-3(a)(12) (1991).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-741 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
