<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>•Amend §404.510 to provide that in determining whether an</textblock>
    <textblock>individual is without fault with respect to a title II deduction</textblock>
    <textblock>overpayment, we will consider all pertinent circumstances,</textblock>
    <textblock>including an individual's age and intelligence and any physical,</textblock>
    <textblock>mental, educational, or linguistic limitations of the individual</textblock>
    <textblock>(including any lack of facility with the English language). In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition, to eliminate any ambiguity with respect to the</textblock>
    <textblock>application of the amendment to section 204(b) of the Act made by</textblock>
    <textblock>section 10305(b) of OBRA 1989 in cases involving title II</textblock>
    <textblock>deduction overpayments, the changes to §404.510 will:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) clarify that the situations described in §404.510 in which</textblock>
    <textblock>an individual will be considered without fault in connection with</textblock>
    <textblock>a deduction overpayment are not all-inclusive; and (2) eliminate</textblock>
    <textblock>the provision in paragraph (n) of §404.510 which requires that</textblock>
    <textblock>for an individual to be considered without fault with respect to</textblock>
    <textblock>a deduction overpayment in certain circumstances described in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (n), such individual must have made a bona fide attempt</textblock>
    <textblock>to restrict his or her annual earnings or otherwise comply with</textblock>
    <textblock>the deduction provisions of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Amend §404.511(b) to show that the Social Security</textblock>
    <textblock>Administration generally will not find an individual to be</textblock>
    <textblock>without fault when, after having been exonerated for a title II</textblock>
    <textblock>``deduction overpayment'' and after having been advised of the</textblock>
    <textblock>correct interpretation of the deduction provision, the individual</textblock>
    <textblock>incurs another ``deduction overpayment'' under the same</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances as the first overpayment. The change to</textblock>
    <textblock>§404.511(b) also explains that in determining ``without fault''</textblock>
    <textblock>under such circumstances, however, any physical, mental,</textblock>
    <textblock>educational, or linguistic limitations (including any lack of</textblock>
    <textblock>facility with the English language) the individual has will be</textblock>
    <textblock>taken into consideration.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Amend §416.552 to provide that we will take into account</textblock>
    <textblock>any physical, mental, educational, or linguistic limitations</textblock>
    <textblock>(including any lack of facility with the English language) the</textblock>
    <textblock>individual has in determining whether the individual is without</textblock>
    <textblock>fault for purposes of the waiver of adjustment or recovery of a</textblock>
    <textblock>title XVI overpayment.</textblock>
    <textblock>In general, under section 1631(b)(4) of the Act and the</textblock>
    <textblock>implementing regulation, §416.556, if any title XVI overpayment</textblock>
    <textblock>is attributable solely to the ownership or possession by an</textblock>
    <textblock>individual (or by an individual and his or her spouse, if any) of</textblock>
    <textblock>countable resources having a value which exceeds, by $50 or less,</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicable limitation on resources specified in the Act and</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations, such individual (and spouse if any) will be deemed</textblock>
    <textblock>to have been without fault in connection with the overpayment,</textblock>
    <textblock>and waiver of adjustment or recovery will be made, unless the</textblock>
    <textblock>failure to report the value of the excess resources correctly and</textblock>
    <textblock>in a timely manner was willful and knowing. Based on the</textblock>
    <textblock>amendment to section 1631(c)(1) of the Act made by</textblock>
    <textblock>section 10305(e) of OBRA of 1989, we are amending §416.556(b) to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide that in determining whether failure to report the excess</textblock>
    <textblock>resources correctly and in a timely manner was willful and</textblock>
    <textblock>knowing, and, thus, whether the individual was at fault, we will</textblock>
    <textblock>take into account any physical, mental, educational, or</textblock>
    <textblock>linguistic limitations (including any lack of facility with the</textblock>
    <textblock>English language) the individual has.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Good Faith_Waiver of Recovery of Overpayments_Continuation</textblock>
    <textblock>of Disability Benefits Pending Appeal</textblock>
    <textblock>Under sections 223(g) and 1631(a)(7) of the Act and the</textblock>
    <textblock>implementing regulations at §§404.1597a and 416.996, a title II</textblock>
    <textblock>or title XVI beneficiary receiving benefits based on disability</textblock>
    <textblock>whom the Secretary determines is no longer disabled based on</textblock>
    <textblock>medical factors has the option of having his or her benefits</textblock>
    <textblock>continued through a hearing before an administrative law judge</textblock>
    <textblock>(ALJ). Benefits paid during this period are considered</textblock>
    <textblock>overpayments if the beneficiary loses the appeal. However, if</textblock>
    <textblock>the beneficiary acted in good faith in pursuing the appeal,</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment can be waived (sections 223(g)(2)(B) and</textblock>
    <textblock>1631(a)(7)(B)(ii) of the Act and 404.1597a(j) and 416.996(g) of</textblock>
    <textblock>our regulations). Our regulations establish a presumption that</textblock>
    <textblock>appeals are made in good faith unless the beneficiary fails,</textblock>
    <textblock>without good cause, to cooperate during the appeal.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
