<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00031</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00025</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 6, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 3, 1994, Overthrust Pipeline Company (Overthrust), tendered for filing and acceptance tariff sheets to Original Volume No. 1 and First Revised Volume No. 1-A of its FERC Gas Tariff to implement revised base rates, to become effective February 1, 1994. This filing is a general rate case submitted principally to comply with the terms of Overthrust's last settlement at Docket No. RP85-60. Overthrust tendered for filing and acceptance the following tariff sheets to is FERC Gas Tariff:</textblock>
    <textblock>Original Volume No. 1</textblock>
    <textblock>Sixteenth Revised Sheet No. 6</textblock>
    <textblock>Second Revised Sheet No. 8</textblock>
    <textblock>Second Revised Sheet No. 40</textblock>
    <textblock>Second Revised Sheet No. 41</textblock>
    <textblock>First Revised Volume No. 1-A</textblock>
    <textblock>First Revised Sheet No. 4</textblock>
    <textblock>First Revised Sheet No. 5</textblock>
    <textblock>First Revised Sheet No. 12</textblock>
    <textblock>First Revised Sheet No. 21</textblock>
    <textblock>First Revised Sheet No. 70</textblock>
    <textblock>First Revised Sheet No. 76</textblock>
    <textblock>First Revised Sheet No. 77</textblock>
    <textblock>Overthrust requests an effective date of February 1, 1994, for the tendered tariff sheets.</textblock>
    <textblock>Overthrust states that the rates that it has proposed are based on the overall cost of service for the test period consisting of the twelve months ended October 31, 1993, adjusted to include the annual effect of: (a) Those costs which began to be incurred during the twelve month period but were not in effect for the full period; (b) those costs which have been incurred, increased or decreased since October 31, 1993; and (c) those added costs which are known and measurable with reasonable accuracy and which will become effective within nine months after October 31, 1993. Further, Overthrust states that the proposed rates would increase annual transportation revenues by approximately $3.1 million based on the 12-month period ended October 31, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Overthrust further states that it has included the Commission's Annual Adjustment Charge (ACA) as a direct cost in the rate case and proposes to eliminate the ACA provision from its FERC Gas Tariffs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Overthrust states that copies of this filing were served upon Overthrust's jurisdictional customers, the Public Service Commission of The State of New York and the Public Service Commission of Wyoming.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rules 211 and 214 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (18 CFR 385.211 and 385.214). All such motions or protests should be filed on or before January 13, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. RP94-104-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Overthrust Pipeline Co.; Proposed Changes in FERC Gas Tariff</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-729 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
