<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00005</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Public Information Collection Requirement Submitted to OMB for Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Defense has submitted to OMB for clearance, the following proposal for collection of information under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C., chapter 35).</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>DoD FAR Supplement (DFARS), Part 225, International Acquisition, and Subpart 252.2, Texts of Provisions and Clauses.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of request:</textblock>
    <textblock>Emergency Processing_Approval date requested: December 31, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Number of respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>3,465.</textblock>
    <textblock>Responses per respondent:</textblock>
    <textblock>4.7.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual responses:</textblock>
    <textblock>16,333.</textblock>
    <textblock>Average burden per response:</textblock>
    <textblock>.25 Hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual burden hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>4,083.</textblock>
    <textblock>Needs and uses:</textblock>
    <textblock>The provisions at DFARS 252.225-7006, Buy American Act_Trade Agreements Act_Balance of Payment Program Certificate, and 252.227-7035, Buy American Act_North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act_Balance of Payments Program Certificate, require offerors to identify end products that are not domestic. This information is necessary to evaluate offerors under policy providing a preference for certain products. Under trade agreements, including the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act, unless specifically exempted by statute or regulation, agencies are required to evaluate offers (over certain dollar limitations), without regard to restrictions of the Buy American Act or the Balance of Payments program. Offerors identify excluded end products in these two provisions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Affected public:</textblock>
    <textblock>Businesses of other for-profit; non-profit institutions; and small businesses or organizations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency:</textblock>
    <textblock>On occasion.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondent's obligation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Required to obtain or retain a benefit.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB desk officer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Peter N. Weiss. Written comments and recommendations on the proposed information collection should be sent to Mr. Weiss at the Office of Management and Budget, Desk Officer for DoD, room 3235, New Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503.</textblock>
    <textblock>DOD clearance officer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. William P. Pearce. Written requests for copies of the information collection proposal should be sent to Mr. Pearce, WHS/DIOR, 1215 Jefferson Davis Highway, suite 1204, Arlington, VA 22202-4302.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 6, 1994.</textblock>
  </action>
  <signer>
    <textblock>L.M. Bynum,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Alternate OSD Federal Register Liaison Officer, Department of Defense.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-675 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 5000-04-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
