<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00118</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00085</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Procurement Regulatory Activity Report, No. 9; Availability</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>OFFICE OF MANAGEMENT AND BUDGET</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of Federal Procurement Policy</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Management and Budget, Office of Federal Procurement Policy.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability of the Procurement Regulatory Activity Report, Number 9.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Subsections 25(g) (1) and (2) of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy (OFPP) Act, as amended by Public Law 100-679, codified at 41 U.S.C. 421(g), require the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy to publish a report within six months after the date of enactment and every six months thereafter relating to the development of procurement regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, OFPP has prepared the ninth Procurement Regulatory Activity Report. This report is designed to satisfy all aspects of subsections 25(g) (1) and (2) of the OFPP Act, and includes information on the status of each regulation; a description of those regulations required by statute; a description of the methods by which public comment was sought; regulations, policies, procedures, and forms under review by the OFPP; whether the regulations have paperwork requirements; the progress made in promulgating and implementing the Federal Acquisition Regulation; and such other matters as the Administrator determines to be useful.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Those persons interested in obtaining a copy of the Procurement Regulatory Activity Report may contact the Executive Office of the President Publications Service, room 2200, 725 17th Street, NW., Washington, DC 20503, or phone (202) 395-7332.</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR ADDITIONAL INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>For additional information write or call the Office of Federal Procurement Policy, 725 17 St., NW., Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-6803.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 6, 1994.</textblock>
  </address>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Steven Kelman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-745 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3110-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
