<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00015</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>17. Wisconsin Power and Light Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-296-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 17, 1993, Wisconsin Power and Light Company tendered for filing with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission four Letter Agreements between Wisconsin Power and Light Company (WP&amp;L) and Manitowoc Public Utilities (MPU). Under the Negotiated Capacity Agreement, WP&amp;L will make capacity and associated energy available to MPU and negotiated degrees of firmness, variable capacity charges, and variable time duration. Under the General Purpose Energy Agreement, WP&amp;L will make non-firm energy available to MPU, with terms and quantities to be arranged by mutual agreement. Under the Emergency Energy Agreement, WP&amp;L will make non-firm emergency energy available to MPU in quantities that, in WP&amp;L's sole judgement, it can supply. Under the Negotiated Capacity Sub-Agreement, WP&amp;L will supply MPU with 10 MW of firm power and energy from June 1, 1994 through</textblock>
    <textblock>May 31, 1995.</textblock>
    <textblock>Wisconsin Power and Light respectfully requests an effective date sixty (60) days from the date of filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the filing has been served on the Public Service Commission of Wisconsin.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>18. Commonwealth Edison Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-297-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 20, 1993, Commonwealth Edison Company (Edison) submitted a Service Agreement, dated November 16, 1993, establishing PSI Energy, Inc. (PSI) as a customer under the terms of Edison's Power Sales Tariff PS-1 (PS-1 Tariff). The Commission has previously designated the PS-1 Tariff as FERC Electric Tariff, Original Volume No. 2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Edison requests an effective date of December 1, 1993, and accordingly seeks waiver of the Commission's notice requirements. Copies of this filing were served upon PSI and the Illinois Commerce Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>19. Jersey Central Power &amp; Light Co., et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-298-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 20, 1993, Jersey Central Power &amp; Light Company, Metropolitan Edison Company, Pennsylvania Electric Company and GPU Nuclear Corporation, (the GPU Companies) tendered for filing rate schedules relating to the provision of operating and maintenance services for five generating stations located in New Jersey and Pennsylvania, namely, the Yards Creek and Kinzua (Seneca) pumped storage hydroelectric stations, the Homer City coal-fired generating station, and the Three Mile Island Oyster Creek nuclear generating stations. The subject rate schedules were filed in response to the Orders of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission issued July 30, 1993 and October 19, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the filing have been furnished to the Pennsylvania Public Utility Commission of New Jersey Board of Regulatory Commissioners.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>20. Jersey Central Power &amp; Light Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-299-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 20, 1993, in response to the Orders of the Commission, dated July 30, 1993 and October 19, 1993, relating to the Prior Notice and Filing Requirements of the Federal Power Act in FERC Docket No. PL93-2, Jersey Central Power &amp; Light Company (JCP&amp;L) tendered for filing a proposed rate schedule supplement showing JCP&amp;L's charges to Atlantic City Electric Company (ACE) to defray JCP&amp;L's cost of operation and maintenance of certain interconnection facilities during the years 1982-1993 and proposed for 1994 relating to JCP&amp;L's Interconnection Agreement with Atlantic City Electric Company (ACE) dated as of March 1, 1978.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the filing have been furnished to the New Jersey Board of Regulatory Commissioners.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>21. Central Vermont Public Service Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-300-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that Central Vermont Public Service Corporation (CVPS) on December 20, 1993, tendered for filing Borderline Agreement between New York State Electric &amp; Gas Corporation and CVPS.</textblock>
    <textblock>CVPS requests the Commission to waive its notice of filing requirements to permit the original contracts to become effective according to their respective terms.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>22. Central Hudson Gas &amp; Electric Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-302-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 20, 1993, Central Hudson Gas and Electric Corporation (CHG&amp;E) tendered for filing an amendment to FERC Docket No. ER85-648-000 dated May 4, 1990 between CHG&amp;E and New York Power Authority (NYPA). The amended agreement expands the firm transmission service provided by CHG&amp;E for NYPA to include service on behalf of Economic Development Customers located in Orange &amp; Rockland Utilities, Inc. service territory. In addition, the point of delivery of NYPA power and energy to CHG&amp;E will be changed to CHG&amp;E's Rock Tavern substation.</textblock>
    <textblock>All other provisions of Docket ER85-648-000 shall remain in effect. CHG&amp;E states that copies of the subject filing were served upon NYPA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
