<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00016</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>23. Central Hudson Gas &amp; Electric Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-303-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 20, 1993, Central Hudson Gas &amp; Electric Corporation (CHG&amp;E) tendered for filing an amendment to FERC Contract No. 73 dated March 11, 1991 between CHG&amp;E and Orange &amp; Rockland Utilities, Inc. (O&amp;R). The amended contract expands the transmission wheeling service provided by CHG&amp;E to O&amp;R to include the purchase of capacity and energy from the various sources of the New York Power Authority.</textblock>
    <textblock>All other provisions including the rate that will be charged, of the existing contract remain in effect. CHG&amp;E states that copies of the subject filing were served upon O&amp;R.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>24. Central Hudson Gas &amp; Electric Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-304-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 20, 1993, Central Hudson Gas &amp; Electric Corporation (CHG&amp;E) tendered for filing an amendment to FERC Contract No. 26 dated August 26, 1993 between CHG&amp;E and New York State Electric and Gas Corporation (NYSEG). The amended contract provides for an increase in the facilities charge associated with investment at the Smithfield Substation due to the replacement of a motor-operated manually controlled air break switch with a supervisory controlled circuit breaker.</textblock>
    <textblock>The facilities charge increases from $57.00 per month to $2,415.00 per month and is retroactive to August 16, 1991 the date on which the circuit breaker was placed in service.</textblock>
    <textblock>All other provisions of FERC Contract No. 26 shall remain in effect. CHG&amp;E states that copies of the subject filing were served upon NYSEG.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>25. Nevada Power Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-305-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 20, 1993, Nevada Power Company (NPC), tendered for filing the Participation Agreement Reid Gardner Unit 4 (Agreement) between NPC and the California Department of Water Resources (CDWR) and subsequent changes to the transmission rate included in this Agreement. This Agreement provides for the Terms and Conditions for participation in the operation of the Reid Gardner Unit 4, a coal-fired steam generation unit of approximately 250 MW located at NPC's Reid Gardner generating station site in Clark County, Nevada.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to 18 CFR 35.11, NPC requests waiver of the Commission's notice requirements, 18 CFR 35.3, to allow for an effective date of May 10, 1983. Additionally, pursuant to the Commission's findings in FERC docket No. PL93-2-002, NPC requests that all amnesty provisions be allowed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of this filing were served on CDWR and the Nevada Public Service Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>26. Keystone Energy Service Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-306-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 20, 1993, Keystone Energy Service Company, L.P. (Keystone) tendered for filing, pursuant to Section 205 of the Federal Power Act and Rule 207 of the Rules of Practice and Procedure of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (the ``Commission'') a ``Petition for Acceptance of Initial Rate Schedule and Waiver of Certain Commission Regulations'' and an Initial Rate Schedule requesting the Commission approve, on a market basis, an Agreement for the Purchase of Electric Power between Keystone and Atlantic City Electric Company (ACE), as amended for the sale of capacity and associated from Keystone's cogeneration facility located in Logan Township, New Jersey. Keystone has requested a waiver of the notice requirements to permit filing of the Initial Rate Schedule more than 120 days prior to the proposed effective date.</textblock>
    <textblock>Keystone has served a copy of the Petition on ACE.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>27. Central Vermont Public Service Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-307-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 20, 1993, Central Vermont Public Service Corporation Inc. (CVPS), tendered for filing six Interconnections Agreements with the following Vermont facilities: Comtu Falls Corporation, Hydro Energies Corporation, Emerson Falls Hydro, Inc., Killington Hydroelectric Inc., Martinsville Hydro Corporation, and Springfield Hydroelectric Company as provided for pursuant to PL93-2-002.</textblock>
    <textblock>CVPS requests the Commission to waive its notice of filing requirements to permit the original contracts to become effective according to their respective terms.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>28. Illinois Power Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-311-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 20, 1993, Illinois Power Company (IP) tendered for filing changes to Appendix A to the Interconnection Agreement between Central Illinois Power Service Company (CIPS), Illinois Power Company (IP), and Union Electric Company (UE). The changes provide for an additional point of interconnection between CIPS and IP, CIPS-IP Connection 39 - Sidney - West Kansas. IP proposes an effective date of October 1, 1983, and therefore, requests waiver of the Commission's notice requirements. The other changes to Appendix A include minor revisions to existing connection point working and the deletion of four connection points.</textblock>
    <textblock>IP also tenders for filing a Reserve and Emergency Interchange Agreement and appendices ``G'', ``H'', ``I'', and ``J'' dated December 15, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Finally, IP tenders for filing a revised Appendix ``Q'' to the Facility Use Agreement between IP and CIPS dated January 17, 1956.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the filing have been served on CIPS, UE, and the Illinois Commerce Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
