<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00039</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(2) Your failure or delay in reporting is not willful. ``Not</textblock>
    <textblock>willful'' means that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) You did not have full knowledge of the existence of your</textblock>
    <textblock>obligation to make a required report; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) You did not intentionally, knowingly, and purposely fail</textblock>
    <textblock>to make a required report.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, in either case we may require that you refund an</textblock>
    <textblock>overpayment caused by your failure to report. See subpart E of</textblock>
    <textblock>this part for waiver of recovery of overpayments.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) In determining whether you have good cause for failure to</textblock>
    <textblock>report timely, we will take into account any physical, mental,</textblock>
    <textblock>educational, or linguistic limitations (including any lack of</textblock>
    <textblock>facility with the English language) you may have.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. The authority citation for subpart I of part 416 is</textblock>
    <textblock>revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Secs. 1102, 1614(a), 1619, 1631 (a), (c) and</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)(1), and 1633 of the Social Security Act; 42 U.S.C. 1302,</textblock>
    <textblock>1382c(a), 1382h, 1383 (a), (c) and (d)(1), and 1383b; secs. 2, 5,</textblock>
    <textblock>6, and 15 of Pub. L. 98-460, 98 Stat. 1794, 1801, 1802, and 1808.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Section 416.918 is amended by adding a new sentence at</textblock>
    <textblock>the end of paragraph (a) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§416.918</textblock>
    <textblock>If you do not appear at a consultative examination.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣* We will consider your physical, mental,</textblock>
    <textblock>educational, and linguistic limitations (including any lack of</textblock>
    <textblock>facility with the English language) when determining if you have</textblock>
    <textblock>a good reason for failing to attend a consultative examination.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>10. Section 416.930 is amended by revising the introductory</textblock>
    <textblock>text of paragraph (c) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§416.930</textblock>
    <textblock>Need to follow prescribed treatment.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Acceptable reasons for failure to follow prescribed</textblock>
    <textblock>treatment.</textblock>
    <textblock>We will consider your physical, mental, educational, and</textblock>
    <textblock>linguistic limitations (including any lack of facility with the</textblock>
    <textblock>English language) when determining if you have an acceptable</textblock>
    <textblock>reason for failure to follow prescribed treatment. The following</textblock>
    <textblock>are examples of a good reason for not following treatment:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
