<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-1-00003</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-1-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Comments are specifically invited on the overall</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory, economic, environmental, and energy aspects</textblock>
    <textblock>of the proposed rule. All comments submitted will be</textblock>
    <textblock>available, both before and after the closing date for</textblock>
    <textblock>comments, in the Rules Docket for examination by</textblock>
    <textblock>interested persons. A report that summarizes each FAA-public contact concerned with the substance of this</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal will be filed in the Rules Docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Commenters wishing the FAA to acknowledge receipt</textblock>
    <textblock>of their comments submitted in response to this notice</textblock>
    <textblock>must submit a self-addressed, stamped postcard on which the following</textblock>
    <textblock>statement is made: ``Comments to Docket No. 93-CE-58-AD.'' The postcard will be date stamped and returned to the commenter.</textblock>
    <textblock>Availability of NPRMs</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person may obtain a copy of this NPRM by</textblock>
    <textblock>submitting a request to the FAA, Central Region, Office</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Assistant Chief Counsel, Attention: Rules</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. 93-CE-58-AD, room 1558, 601 E. 12th Street,</textblock>
    <textblock>Kansas City, Missouri 64106.</textblock>
    <textblock>Discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>Service history of certain Piper Models PA34-200,</textblock>
    <textblock>PA34-200T, PA34-220T, PA44-180, and PA44-180T airplanes</textblock>
    <textblock>reveals several occurrences of cracked main landing</textblock>
    <textblock>gear (MLG) trunnions. Five of these occurrences</textblock>
    <textblock>resulted when the left MLG trunnion, part number (P/N)</textblock>
    <textblock>67926-12, separated from Piper Model PA34-200T</textblock>
    <textblock>airplanes during the landing roll. Further</textblock>
    <textblock>investigation revealed that the left MLG collapsed</textblock>
    <textblock>because of a transverse fracture in the trunnion at the</textblock>
    <textblock>rear web lower end fillet. Metallurgical examination</textblock>
    <textblock>of four of these MLG trunnions further disclosed that</textblock>
    <textblock>the fractures originated from very shallow fatigue</textblock>
    <textblock>cracks originating from several areas along the rear surface</textblock>
    <textblock>at the lower end of the fillet web. The length of</textblock>
    <textblock>these fatigue cracks ranged from .20 to .40 inches.</textblock>
    <textblock>Piper has issued Service Bulletin (SB) 787B, dated</textblock>
    <textblock>August 25, 1993, which specifies procedures for</textblock>
    <textblock>inspecting the MLG trunnions on certain Piper Models</textblock>
    <textblock>PA34-200, PA34-200T, PA34-220T, PA44-180, and PA44-180T</textblock>
    <textblock>airplanes, and references replacing MLG trunnions with</textblock>
    <textblock>parts of improved design.</textblock>
    <textblock>After examining the circumstances and reviewing</textblock>
    <textblock>all available information related to the incidents</textblock>
    <textblock>described above including the referenced service</textblock>
    <textblock>information, the FAA has determined that AD action</textblock>
    <textblock>should be taken to prevent collapse of the main landing</textblock>
    <textblock>gear caused by cracked trunnions, which could result in</textblock>
    <textblock>airplane damage.</textblock>
    <textblock>Since an unsafe condition has been identified that</textblock>
    <textblock>is likely to exist or develop in other Piper Models</textblock>
    <textblock>PA34-200, PA34-200T, PA34-220T, PA44-180, and PA44-180T</textblock>
    <textblock>airplanes of the same type design, the proposed AD</textblock>
    <textblock>would require repetitively inspecting the main landing</textblock>
    <textblock>gear trunnions for cracks, replacing any trunnions</textblock>
    <textblock>found cracked, and eventually replacing the landing</textblock>
    <textblock>gear trunnions with parts of improved design as</textblock>
    <textblock>terminating action for the repetitive inspection</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement. The proposed inspections would be</textblock>
    <textblock>accomplished in accordance with Piper SB No. 787B,</textblock>
    <textblock>dated August 25, 1993. The proposed replacement would</textblock>
    <textblock>be accomplished in accordance with the applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>maintenance manual.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
