<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-1-00023</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-1-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>I. Introduction</textblock>
    <textblock>On July 23, 1993, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (Commission) issued a notice of proposed rulemaking (NOPR)</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>in which the Commission proposed to amend 18 CFR Parts 141 and 385 to provide for the electronic filing of FERC Form No. 1, ``Annual Report of Major electric utilities, licensees and others'' (Form 1). Under the proposed rule, in addition to paper copies, future Form 1 filings would also be made by means of a computer diskette incorporating software programming developed by the Commission. Electronic reporting of Form 1 was proposed to commence with reporting year 1993, due on or before April 30, 1994. No change was proposed in Form 1 itself.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission also proposed to amend 18 CFR part 375 to delegate to the Chief Accountant or his designee the authority to act on requests for waiver of the Form 1 and Form 1-F</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>filing requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested parties were requested to submit written comments. Comments were received from 22 electric utilities,</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>three industry associations</textblock>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
    <textblock>and the Energy Information Administration of the U.S. Department of Energy.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>58 FR 40606 (July 29, 1993); IV FERC Stats. &amp; Regs. ¶32,498 (1993).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>FERC Form No. 1-F, ``Annual Report of Nonmajor public utilities and licensees.''</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>No party objected to the proposal to delegate authority to rule on requests for waiver of the Form 1 and Form 1-F filing requirements. The proposal is being implemented by a separate order issued concurrently with this notice.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>American Electric Power System, Arizona Public Service Company, Carolina Power &amp; Light Company, Cincinnati Gas &amp; Electric Company, Commonwealth Edison Company, Commonwealth Energy System, Delmarva Power &amp; Light Company, Duke Power Company, Florida Power &amp; Light Company, Florida Power Corporation, Idaho Power Company, Iowa Illinois Gas &amp; Electric Company, Kansas City Power &amp; Light Company, Kentucky Utilities Company, Nantahala Power and Light Company, New England Power Service Company, Ohio Edison Company, PSI Energy, Inc., Pennsylvania Power &amp; Light Company, Southern Company Services, Inc., UtiliCorp United, Inc., Wisconsin Public Service Corporation.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>American Public Power Association, Edison Electric Institute, Wisconsin Utilities Association, Inc.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
