<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00003</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93-161-1]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Receipt of Permit Applications for Release Into the Environment of Genetically Engineered Organisms</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, USDA.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>We are advising the public that four applications for permits to release genetically engineered organisms into the environment are being reviewed by the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service. The applications have been submitted in accordance with 7 CFR part 340, which regulates the introduction of certain genetically engineered organisms and products.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the applications referenced in this notice, with any confidential business information deleted, are available for public inspection in room 1141, South Building, U.S. Department of Agriculture, 14th Street and Independence Avenue SW., Washington, DC, between 8 a.m. and 4:30 p.m., Monday through Friday, except holidays. Persons wishing to inspect an application are encouraged to call ahead on (202) 690-2817 to facilitate entry into the reading room. You may obtain copies of the documents by writing to the person listed under</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Arnold Foudin, Deputy Director, Biotechnology Permits, Biotechnology, Biologics, and Environmental Protection, APHIS, USDA, room 850, Federal Building, 6505 Belcrest Road, Hyattsville, MD 20782, (301) 436-7612.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The regulations in 7 CFR part 340, ``Introduction of Organisms and Products Altered or Produced Through Genetic Engineering Which Are Plant Pests or Which There Is Reason to Believe Are Plant Pests,'' require a person to obtain a permit before introducing (importing, moving interstate, or releasing into the environment) into the United States certain genetically engineered organisms and products that are considered ``regulated articles.'' The regulations set forth procedures for obtaining a permit for the release into the environment of a regulated article, and for obtaining a limited permit for the importation or interstate movement of a regulated article.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to these regulations, the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service has received and is reviewing the following applications for permits to release genetically engineered organisms into the environment:</textblock>
    <textblock>Done in Washington, DC, this 6th day of January 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Application No.</textblock>
    <textblock>1Applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>1Date received</textblock>
    <textblock>1Organisms</textblock>
    <textblock>1Field test location</textblock>
    <textblock>93-320-01</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Department of Agriculture, Agricultural Research Service</textblock>
    <textblock>11-16-93</textblock>
    <textblock>Barley plants genetically engineered to express resistance to barley yellow dwarf virus</textblock>
    <textblock>California, Idaho, Illinois.</textblock>
    <textblock>93-340-01, renewal of permit 93-214-01, issued on 09-10-93</textblock>
    <textblock>PanAmerican Seed</textblock>
    <textblock>12-06-93</textblock>
    <textblock>Carrot plants genetically engineered to express modified nutritional value</textblock>
    <textblock>Illinois.</textblock>
    <textblock>93-340-02</textblock>
    <textblock>PetoSeed Company Incorporated</textblock>
    <textblock>12-06-93</textblock>
    <textblock>Carrot plants genetically engineered to express modified nutritional value</textblock>
    <textblock>Idaho.</textblock>
    <textblock>93-341-01</textblock>
    <textblock>University of California, Berkeley</textblock>
    <textblock>12-07-93</textblock>
    <textblock>A strain of the bacterium</textblock>
    <textblock>Erwinia herbicola</textblock>
    <textblock>genetically engineered to inhibit production of 3-indole acetic acid</textblock>
    <textblock>California.</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lonnie J. King,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Actng Administrator, Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-673 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-34-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
