<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00030</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 10305(d) of OBRA 1989 amended section 223(g)(2)(B)</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Act to require that the Secretary take into account any</textblock>
    <textblock>physical, mental, educational, or linguistic limitations an</textblock>
    <textblock>individual may have (including any lack of facility with the</textblock>
    <textblock>English language) in determining whether an individual's appeal</textblock>
    <textblock>is made in good faith.</textblock>
    <textblock>Based on this amendment and the amendment to title XVI of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Act made by section 10305(e) of OBRA 1989, we are amending</textblock>
    <textblock>§§404.1597a(j)(3) and 416.996(g)(2) to provide that we will take</textblock>
    <textblock>into account any physical, mental, educational, or linguistic</textblock>
    <textblock>limitations (including any lack of facility with the English</textblock>
    <textblock>language) the individual has in determining whether the</textblock>
    <textblock>individual acted in good faith in pursuing the appeal.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Determinations of Good Cause or of Fraud or Similar</textblock>
    <textblock>Fault in Connection With the Administrative Review Process</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 10305(e) amended section 1631(c)(1) of the Act to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide that the Secretary shall specifically take into account</textblock>
    <textblock>any physical, mental, educational, or linguistic limitations of</textblock>
    <textblock>an individual (including any lack of facility with the English</textblock>
    <textblock>language) in determining, with respect to the eligibility of the</textblock>
    <textblock>individual for benefits under title XVI, whether the individual</textblock>
    <textblock>acted in good faith or was at fault, and in determining fraud,</textblock>
    <textblock>deception, or intent.</textblock>
    <textblock>The changes we are making in part 416 of the regulations in</textblock>
    <textblock>connection with the administrative review process are based on</textblock>
    <textblock>the amendment to section 1631(c)(1). We are making comparable</textblock>
    <textblock>changes in part 404 in the interest of consistency.</textblock>
    <textblock>Our current regulations provide that a determination or</textblock>
    <textblock>decision which we make about an individual's rights under title</textblock>
    <textblock>II or title XVI of the Act is generally final and binding unless</textblock>
    <textblock>the individual files a request for review of the determination or</textblock>
    <textblock>decision within a specified time period. However, the time</textblock>
    <textblock>period to request review will be extended if good cause can be</textblock>
    <textblock>established for missing the deadline to request review</textblock>
    <textblock>(§§404.911 and 416.1411). Also, under our regulations, we may</textblock>
    <textblock>reopen a determination or decision at any time if it was obtained</textblock>
    <textblock>by fraud or similar fault (§§404.988(c)(1) and 416.1488(c)), or,</textblock>
    <textblock>in title II cases, if certain other circumstances exist</textblock>
    <textblock>(§404.988(c)).</textblock>
    <textblock>Under our regulations, a request for a hearing before an ALJ</textblock>
    <textblock>may be dismissed if neither the person requesting the hearing nor</textblock>
    <textblock>his or her designated representative appears at the time and</textblock>
    <textblock>place set for the hearing. However, if good cause for failure to</textblock>
    <textblock>appear can be established, the hearing request will not be</textblock>
    <textblock>dismissed (§§404.957(b) and 416.1457(b)).</textblock>
    <textblock>We are making the following changes to §§404.911, 404.936,</textblock>
    <textblock>404.957, 404.988, 416.1411, 416.1436, 416.1457, and 416.1488 to</textblock>
    <textblock>reflect the consideration of the factors described in section</textblock>
    <textblock>10305 of OBRA 1989.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Amend §§404.911(a) and (b)(9) and 416.1411(a) and (b)(9) to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide that in determining whether an individual had good cause</textblock>
    <textblock>for missing a deadline to request review, we will take into</textblock>
    <textblock>account any physical, mental, educational, or linguistic</textblock>
    <textblock>limitations of the individual (including any lack of facility</textblock>
    <textblock>with the English language) which may have prevented the</textblock>
    <textblock>individual from filing a timely request or from understanding or</textblock>
    <textblock>knowing about the need to file a timely request for review.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Amend §§404.936 and 416.1436 to further describe</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances which an individual, who will not be represented at</textblock>
    <textblock>a hearing before an ALJ, may give for requesting a change in the</textblock>
    <textblock>time or place of the hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Amend §§404.957(b) and 416.1457(b) to require that in</textblock>
    <textblock>making determinations of whether an individual had good cause for</textblock>
    <textblock>failure to appear for a hearing before an ALJ, we will take into</textblock>
    <textblock>account any physical, mental, educational, or linguistic</textblock>
    <textblock>limitations (including any lack of facility with the English</textblock>
    <textblock>language) the individual has.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
