<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00045</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>These requirements are not met by ``mere conclusory allegations of the pleadings_nor by mere relevance to the case_but require an affirmative showing *␣*␣* that each condition as to which the examination is sought is really and genuinely in controversy and that good cause exists for ordering each particular examination.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Schlagenhauf,</textblock>
    <textblock>379 U.S. at 118. Precedent establishes that it is the moving party which has the burden of demonstrating that this standard is met.</textblock>
    <textblock>Id.</textblock>
    <textblock>a. ``In Controversy'' Requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal precedents have varied in their interpretation of the ``in controversy'' requirement. In negligence cases, courts generally have been receptive to defendants' requests for such examinations where physical or mental injury is claimed. See</textblock>
    <textblock>Brandenberg</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>El Al Israel Airlines,</textblock>
    <textblock>79 F.R.D. 543 (1978) (ordering psychiatric examination of plaintiff alleging negligent, careless and reckless treatment caused her ``physical, emotional, mental stress, and mental and psychiatric injuries'');</textblock>
    <textblock>Martin</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Tindell,</textblock>
    <textblock>98 So.2d 473,</textblock>
    <textblock>cert. denied,</textblock>
    <textblock>355 U.S. 959 (negligence case indicating physical exams are granted as a matter of course in such cases). Even in negligence cases, however, examinations may not be ordered where damages only for past injury are alleged, rather than damages for present suffering.</textblock>
    <textblock>Winters</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Travia,</textblock>
    <textblock>495 F.2d 839 (2d Cir. 1974);</textblock>
    <textblock>Coca-Cola Bottling Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Torres,</textblock>
    <textblock>255 F.2d 149 (1st Cir. 1958).</textblock>
    <textblock>In the civil rights cases, however, courts have demonstrated greater reluctance to order such examinations. In</textblock>
    <textblock>Cody</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Marriot Corporation,</textblock>
    <textblock>103 F.R.D. 421, 422-23 (D. Mass. 1984), the court indicated that the standard for ordering such examinations in discrimination cases is more stringent than in tort cases involving negligence.</textblock>
    <textblock>The reported civil rights cases interpreting Rule 35 have generally involved requests by defendants for mental examinations of plaintiffs. A review of employment discrimination cases interpreting Rule 35 demonstrates that mental examinations of plaintiffs are not routinely ordered in such cases simply because plaintiffs may claim damages for emotional distress. Furthermore, a claim of emotional distress is not considered to place automatically a plaintiff's mental condition in controversy.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cody,</textblock>
    <textblock>referred to,</textblock>
    <textblock>supra,</textblock>
    <textblock>was one important employment discrimination case involving the application of Rule 35. Citing</textblock>
    <textblock>Schlagenhauf</textblock>
    <textblock>, Cody refused to order a mental examination of a plaintiff who claimed emotional distress as a result of employment discrimination.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cody</textblock>
    <textblock>indicated that the outcome might have been different had the plaintiff not merely ``made a claim of emotional distress'' but instead had made ``a claim of a psychiatric disorder requiring psychiatric or psychological counseling.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Cody,</textblock>
    <textblock>103 F.R.D. at 423. This distinction, based on the severity of the injury alleged, has also been applied in other tort contexts. See,</textblock>
    <textblock>e.g., Anson</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Fickel,</textblock>
    <textblock>110 F.R.D. 184, 186 (N.D. Ind. 1986) (traffic accident case citing</textblock>
    <textblock>Cody</textblock>
    <textblock>and making same distinction).</textblock>
    <textblock>Cody</textblock>
    <textblock>also noted that the moving party had shown no authority for the proposition that ``emotional distress'' is synonymous with ``mental condition,'' as that term is used in Rule 35.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cody,</textblock>
    <textblock>103 F.R.D. at 422 n.2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cody</textblock>
    <textblock>indicated that if, in contrast, the plaintiff were to use the services of a psychiatrist or psychologist at a later date for use at trial, the court would consider allowing the defendants to conduct the Rule 35(a) examination.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cody,</textblock>
    <textblock>103 F.R.D. at 423.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thus,</textblock>
    <textblock>Cody</textblock>
    <textblock>suggested two factors that differentiate the circumstances in which the ``in controversy'' requirement would or would not be met.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. ``Good Cause'' Requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to the ``in controversy'' requirement, an examination may only be ordered if ``good cause'' is also shown. The good-cause requirement is not a ``mere formality,'' but is a ``plainly expressed limitation on [Rule 35's] use *␣*␣*.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Schlagenhauf,</textblock>
    <textblock>379 U.S. at 118.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
