<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-1-00021</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Proposed Alteration VOR Federal Airways</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 71</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Airspace Docket No. 93-AGL-2]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule; withdrawal.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This action withdraws the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPRM) published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on October 15, 1993. The NPRM proposed to alter the descriptions of VOR Federal Airways V-7, V-51, V-97, and V-399, respectively, by reducing the standard width of these airways. The FAA has determined that withdrawal of the proposal at this time is warranted because a change in air traffic control (ATC) procedures would alleviate the need to alter these airways.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>This withdrawal is effective January 12, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Patricia P. Crawford, Airspace and Obstruction Evaluation Branch (ATP-240), Airspace-Rules and Aeronautical Information Division, Air Traffic Rules and Procedures Service, Federal Aviation Administration, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591; telephone: (202) 267-9255.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 15, 1993, a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>to amend 14 CFR part 71 of the Federal Aviation Regulations to alter the descriptions of V-7, V-51, V-97, and V-399, respectively, by reducing the standard width of these airways located in the states of Indiana and Illinois (58 FR 53459). This action was proposed to redefine the lateral boundaries of the airways to provide for more efficient utilization of the airspace. No comments were received on the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA has decided to withdraw the proposal at this time to provide an opportunity to reexamine the operations effecting these airways in the Lafayette Air Traffic Control Tower (ATCT) and Chicago Air Route Traffic Control Center (ARTCC) areas. This proposal was initiated to simplify air traffic operations and to provide for more efficient utilization of that airspace. The FAA has determined that changing the ATC procedures and delegating to Chicago ARTCC the control responsibility previously handled by Lafayette ATCT would alleviate the need to alter these airways.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 14 CFR Part 71</textblock>
    <textblock>Airspace, Incorporation by reference, Navigation (air).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Withdrawal</textblock>
    <textblock>In consideration of the foregoing, the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking, Airspace Docket No. 93-AGL-2, as published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on October 15, 1993 (58 FR 53459), is hereby withdrawn.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>49 U.S.C. app. 1348(a), 1354(a), 1510; E.O. 10854, 24 FR 9565, 3 CFR, 1959-1963 Comp., p. 389; 49 U.S.C. 106(g); 14 CFR 11.69.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Harold W. Becker,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Airspace-Rules and Aeronautical Information Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-782 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
