<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00027</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>•Fraudulent Behavior or Failure To Cooperate or To Take</textblock>
    <textblock>Any Required Action in Disability Determinations</textblock>
    <textblock>Under sections 223(f) and 1614(a)(4) of the Act, title II or</textblock>
    <textblock>title XVI disability benefits may be terminated if a prior</textblock>
    <textblock>favorable determination of disability was fraudulently obtained</textblock>
    <textblock>or if the beneficiary fails, without good cause, to cooperate</textblock>
    <textblock>with the Secretary in reviewing his or her entitlement or to</textblock>
    <textblock>follow prescribed treatment which is expected to restore his or</textblock>
    <textblock>her ability to work.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 10305(c) of OBRA 1989 amended section 223(f) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Act to provide that in making, for purposes of section 223(f),</textblock>
    <textblock>any determination or decision relating to fraudulent behavior by</textblock>
    <textblock>any individual or failure by any individual without good cause to</textblock>
    <textblock>cooperate or to take any required action, the Secretary shall</textblock>
    <textblock>take into account any physical, mental, educational, or</textblock>
    <textblock>linguistic limitations (including any lack of facility with the</textblock>
    <textblock>English language) the individual may have. In addition, with</textblock>
    <textblock>respect to making similar determinations and decisions for</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of section 1614(a)(4) of the Act, section 1631(c)(1) of</textblock>
    <textblock>title XVI of the Act, as amended by OBRA 1989, requires the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary to take these limitations into account in determining</textblock>
    <textblock>whether an individual acted in good faith or was at fault, and in</textblock>
    <textblock>determining fraud, deception, or intent.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 404.1518, 404.1530, 404.1579, 404.1594, 416.918,</textblock>
    <textblock>416.930, 416.994 and 416.994a reflect the pertinent provisions of</textblock>
    <textblock>sections 223(f) and 1614(a)(4) of the Act. We are making the</textblock>
    <textblock>following changes in these regulations:</textblock>
    <textblock>•Amend §§404.1518 and 416.918 to provide that we will take</textblock>
    <textblock>into account any physical, mental, educational, or linguistic</textblock>
    <textblock>limitations (including any lack of facility with the English</textblock>
    <textblock>language) the individual has when determining if the individual</textblock>
    <textblock>has a good reason for failing to attend a consultative</textblock>
    <textblock>examination which we have arranged for the individual. These</textblock>
    <textblock>specific amendments were not included in the NPRM. Current</textblock>
    <textblock>§§404.1518 and 416.918 provide that we may determine that an</textblock>
    <textblock>individual who is applying for benefits based on disability or</textblock>
    <textblock>blindness is not disabled or blind, or that an individual who is</textblock>
    <textblock>entitled to or eligible for benefits based on disability or</textblock>
    <textblock>blindness is no longer disabled or blind, if we find that the</textblock>
    <textblock>individual failed or refused to attend a consultative examination</textblock>
    <textblock>without a good reason. While §§404.1518 and 416.918 provide</textblock>
    <textblock>rules for determining whether an individual has a good reason for</textblock>
    <textblock>such failure or refusal and, thus, are within the scope of the</textblock>
    <textblock>amendments to sections 223(f) and 1631(c)(1) of the Act, we</textblock>
    <textblock>inadvertently failed to include these regulations when we</textblock>
    <textblock>developed the proposed regulations to implement section 10305 of</textblock>
    <textblock>OBRA 1989. We are amending §§404.1518(a) and 416.918(a) in the</textblock>
    <textblock>final rule to make it clear that we will consider an individual's</textblock>
    <textblock>physical, mental, educational, and linguistic limitations</textblock>
    <textblock>(including any lack of facility with the English language) in</textblock>
    <textblock>determining whether the individual has a good reason for failing</textblock>
    <textblock>to attend a consultative examination. In connection with this</textblock>
    <textblock>change, we also are making related changes, which were not in the</textblock>
    <textblock>NPRM, to §§404.1579(e)(2), 404.1586(d), 404.1594(e)(2),</textblock>
    <textblock>416.986(c), 416.994(b)(4)(ii) and 416.994a(g)(2) to include in</textblock>
    <textblock>these sections a cross-reference to §404.1518 or §416.918, as</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate, to clarify that §§404.1518 and 416.918 provide the</textblock>
    <textblock>rules for determining whether an individual has a good reason for</textblock>
    <textblock>not attending a consultative examination. Current</textblock>
    <textblock>§416.994a(g)(2) already contains such a cross-reference.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Amend §§404.1530(c) and 416.930(c) to provide that we will</textblock>
    <textblock>take into account any physical, mental, educational, or</textblock>
    <textblock>linguistic limitations (including any lack of facility with the</textblock>
    <textblock>English language) the individual has when deciding if the</textblock>
    <textblock>individual has acceptable reasons for failure to follow</textblock>
    <textblock>prescribed treatment.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Amend §§404.1579 (e)(1) and (e)(2), 404.1594 (e)(1) and</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)(2), 416.994 (b)(4)(i) and (b)(4)(ii) and 416.994a (g)(1) and</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)(2) to indicate that we will take into account any physical,</textblock>
    <textblock>mental, educational, or linguistic limitations (including any</textblock>
    <textblock>lack of facility with the English language) the individual has in</textblock>
    <textblock>determining whether a prior favorable determination or decision</textblock>
    <textblock>was fraudulently obtained or in determining whether an individual</textblock>
    <textblock>has good cause for failure to supply evidence we ask for or to go</textblock>
    <textblock>for a physical or mental examination. The amendments to these</textblock>
    <textblock>sections of the regulations include certain technical changes</textblock>
    <textblock>that were not reflected in the NPRM. For the final rule, we are</textblock>
    <textblock>adding the phrase ``or decision'' to §§404.1579(e)(1),</textblock>
    <textblock>404.1594(e)(1), 416.994(b)(4)(i) and 416.994a(g)(1) to clarify</textblock>
    <textblock>that these provisions apply not only to determinations we make,</textblock>
    <textblock>but also to decisions we make. Section 416.994a(g)(1) already</textblock>
    <textblock>contains this language. Also, as discussed above,</textblock>
    <textblock>§§404.1579(e)(2), 404.1586(d), 404.1594(e)(2), 416.986(c),</textblock>
    <textblock>416.994(b)(4)(ii) and 416.994a(g)(2) of the final rule include a</textblock>
    <textblock>cross-reference to §404.1518 or §416.918, as appropriate, which</textblock>
    <textblock>provides rules for determining whether an individual has good</textblock>
    <textblock>cause for failing to attend a consultative examination.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
