<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00066</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Medicare Program; Payment for Preadmission Services</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Health Care Financing Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>42 CFR Parts 412 and 413</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[BPD-731-IFC]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 0938-AG00</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Health Care Financing Administration (HCFA), HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interim final rule with comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This interim final rule specifies that inpatient hospital operating costs include certain preadmission services furnished by the hospital (or by an entity that is wholly owned or operated by the hospital) to the patient up to 3 days before the date of the patient's admission to that hospital. These provisions implement amendments made to section 1886(a)(4) of the Social Security Act by section 4003 of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective Date:</textblock>
    <textblock>This interim final rule with comment period is effective on January 12, 1994. We refer the reader to section V.A. of this preamble for a discussion of specific provisions that apply to specific periods.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment Period:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments will be considered if we receive them at the appropriate address, as provided below, no later than 5 p.m. on March 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mail written comments (an original and 3 copies) to the following address:</textblock>
    <textblock>Health Care Financing Administration,</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Health and Human Services,</textblock>
    <textblock>Attention: BPD-731-IFC, P.O. Box 7517,</textblock>
    <textblock>Baltimore, MD 21207.</textblock>
    <textblock>If you prefer, you may deliver your written comments (an original and 3 copies) to one of the following addresses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 309-G, Hubert H. Humphrey Building,</textblock>
    <textblock>200 Independence Avenue, SW.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20201, or</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 132, East High Rise Building,</textblock>
    <textblock>6325 Security Boulevard,</textblock>
    <textblock>Baltimore, MD 21207.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because of staffing and resource limitations, we cannot accept comments by facsimile (FAX) transmission. In commenting, please refer to file code BPD-731-IFC. Comments received timely will be available for public inspection as they are received, generally beginning approximately 3 weeks after publication of a document, in room 309-G of the Department's offices at 200 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC, on Monday through Friday of each week from 8:30 a.m. to 5 p.m. (phone: 202-690-7890).</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies:</textblock>
    <textblock>To order copies of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>containing this document, send your request to: New Orders, Superintendent of Documents, P.O. Box 371954, Pittsburgh, PA 15250-7954. Specify the date of the issue requested and enclose a check or money order payable to the Superintendent of Documents, or enclose your Visa or Master Card number and expiration date. Credit card orders can also be placed by calling the order desk at (202) 783-3238 or by faxing to (202) 275-6802. The cost for each copy is $4.50. As an alternative, you can view and photocopy the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>document at most libraries designated as Federal Depository Libraries and at many other public and academic libraries throughout the country that receive the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Thomas Hoyer, (410) 966-4607.</textblock>
  </further>
</doc>
