<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00074</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00054</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>2. If the applicant's eligibility to participate in the Faculty Loan Repayment Program is based on section 738(a)(2) of the Act (i.e. based on his or her enrollment in an accredited health professions school), he or she also agrees to:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Maintain full-time enrollment, (as determined by the School), in good academic standing as determined by the School, in the final year of the course of study leading to a degree in medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, pharmacy, podiatric medicine, optometry, veterinary medicine, nursing, or public health, or schools offering graduate programs in clinical psychology in which the applicant is currently enrolled, until completion of such course of study;</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Enter into a contract with an accredited school described in subsection (a) of Section 738 to serve as a ``new'' member of the faculty of the school for not less than 2 years according to the requirements described in subsection (a)(5) of section 738.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Begin service obligations as contracted.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section C_Breach of Written Loan Repayment Contract</textblock>
    <textblock>1. If the participant fails to comply with section B.1.c. of this contract or is dismissed for disciplinary reasons or voluntarily terminates the contracts, neither the Secretary nor the School is obligated to continue loan repayments as stated in Sec. A of this Contract. The participant shall be liable to the United States and the School for the amounts specified in paragraph 2 of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. If the applicant agrees to serve as a full-time faculty member for two years or more and fails to serve the 2-year minimum requirement, he or she is liable to pay monetary damages to the United States amounting to the sum of (a) the total amounts specified in Section A.2 of this contract plus (b) an ``unserved obligation penalty'' of $1,000 for each month unserved as set forth in paragraph 3 of this section plus (c) any tax assistance paid plus (d) interest, penalties and administrative charges for past due payments.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The ``Unserved Obligation Penalty'' means the amount equal to the number of months of obligated services that were not completed by an individual, multiplied by $1,000 except that in any case in which the individual fails to serve 1 year, the unserved obligation penalty shall be equal to the full period of obligated service multiplied by $1,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. If the applicant agrees to serve more than the 2-year minimum service obligations and has completed the 2-year minimum he or she will be liable for such sums paid for any months that are not a full year beyond the 2-year minimum requirement as agreed to in Section B.1.c of this contract, plus an ``unserved obligation penalty'' of $1,000 for each month unserved.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Any amount the United States is entitled to recover shall be paid within one year of the date the Secretary determines that the applicant is in breach of this written contract. Failure to pay by the due date will incur delinquent charges provided by Federal Law. (45 CFR 30.13).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section D_Cancellation, Suspension, &amp; Waiver of Obligation</textblock>
    <textblock>Any service or payment obligation may be canceled, suspended, or waived under certain circumstances described below: (1) In the event of death or permanent and total disability, the Secretary will cancel obligations under this contract. To receive cancellation in the event of death, the executor of the estate must submit an official death certificate to the Secretary. To receive cancellation for permanent and total disability, applicant or his/her representative must apply to the Secretary, submitting medical evidence of my condition, and the Secretary may cancel this obligation in accordance with applicable Federal statutes and regulations; (2) Upon receipt of supporting documentation the Secretary may waive or suspend service or payment obligation under this contract if the Secretary determines that: (a) meeting the terms and conditions of the contract is impossible or would involve extreme hardship; and (b) enforcement of the obligations would be unconscionable. (3) Deferment will be granted in the event of long term illness. Supporting documentation should be sent to: Division of Disadvantaged Assistance, Room 8A-09 Parklawn Building, 5600 Fishers Lane, Rockville, MD 20857.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary or his/her authorized representative must sign this contract before it becomes effective.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant Name (Please Print)</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXXXXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant Signature*</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXXXXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>Date</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXXXXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary of Health and Human Services or Designee</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXXXXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>Date</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXXXXXX</textblock>
  </text>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Before signing, be sure you have completed section B.1.c. on page 1 of this contract indicating the number of years of service you agree to perform.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>*</textblock>
  </footname>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-669 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-15-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
