<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00104</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>INTERNATIONAL TRADE COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Investigation No. 332-351]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Monitoring of U.S. Imports of Peppers</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>United States International Trade Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of institution of investigation.</textblock>
  </action>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>December 30, 1993.</textblock>
  </date>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act, P.L. 103-182, directs the Commission to monitor imports of fresh or chilled peppers, other than chili peppers (HTS subheading 0709.60.00), until January 1, 2009, as if a proper request for such monitoring had been made under section 202(d) of the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2252(d)), for purposes of expediting an investigation concerning provisional relief under section 202 of the Trade Act of 1974. As a result, the Commission instituted investigation No. 332-351, under section 332(g) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (19 U.S.C. 1332(g)), for the purpose of monitoring imports of fresh or chilled peppers.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the course of the investigation, the Commission will monitor U.S. imports of fresh or chilled peppers from all foreign suppliers. In addition, the Commission will investigate and gather data, to the extent possible, on U.S. growers in such areas as shipments, prices, market share, employment levels, profit-or-loss, and efforts to compete. Wherever possible, the Commission will rely on existing data from other government agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Although section 316 does not require that the Commission publish reports summarizing the information obtained as a result of such monitoring, the Commission plans to publish statistical annual reports of certain trade data through the year 2008.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Timothy McCarty (202-205-3324) or</textblock>
    <textblock>Lowell Grant (202-205-3312), Agriculture Division, Office of Industries, or William Gearhart (202-205-3091), Office of the General Counsel, U.S. International Trade Commission. Hearing impaired persons can obtain information on this study by contacting the Commission's TDD terminal on (202) 205-1810.</textblock>
    <textblock>WRITTEN SUBMISSIONS:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to submit written statements at any time during the investigation. Commercial or financial information which a submitter desires the Commission to treat as confidential must be submitted on separate sheets of paper, each clearly marked ``Confidential Business Information'' at the top. All submissions requesting confidential treatment must conform with the requirement of section 201.6 of the Commission's</textblock>
    <textblock>Rules of Practice and Procedure</textblock>
    <textblock>(19 CFR 201.6). All written submissions, except for confidential business information, will be made available for inspection by interested persons. All submission should be addressed to the Secretary at the Commission's office in Washington, DC.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued: January 4, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By order of the Commission.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna R. Koehnke,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-770 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7020-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
