<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00027</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 6, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 28, 1993, Granite State Gas Transmission, Inc. (Granite State) tendered for filing the tariff sheets listed below in its FERC Gas Tariff, Third Revised Volume No. 1, containing changes in rates for effectiveness on December 28, 1993:</textblock>
    <textblock>Original Sheet No. 32</textblock>
    <textblock>Original Sheet No. 33</textblock>
    <textblock>Original Sheet No. 34</textblock>
    <textblock>According to Granite State, three additional tariff sheets, having no rate effect, are also submitted for editorial purposes in the tariff:</textblock>
    <textblock>First Revised Sheet No. 20_Revised Index</textblock>
    <textblock>Original Sheet Nos. 27-30 and 35-99_Reservations for Future Use</textblock>
    <textblock>Granite State further states that the rate changes on Original Sheet Nos. 32 through 34 are submitted as a limited Section 4 filing to pass through to its customers, Bay State Gas Company and Northern Utilities, Inc., transitional costs pursuant to Order Nos. 636, et al., that have been directly billed to Granite State by upstream pipeline suppliers following the effectiveness of their restructuring proceedings. According to Granite State, it has been directly billed transitional costs by Algonquin Gas Transmission Company, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company and National Fuel Gas Supply Corporation and its filing allocates such directly billed costs to its customers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Granite State further states that it commenced its restructured operations on November 1, 1993, pursuant to a compliance plan approved by the Commission in Docket No. RS93-1-000. It is further said that Granite State previously filed tariff sheets with the Commission to recover certain of the upstream supplier transitional costs and the filing was rejected in a Letter Order issued July 28, 1993 advising that Granite State could file to recover such costs in a limited Section 4 filing when it had completed its restructuring process. (Docket Nos. TM93-14-4-000, et al.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Granite State states that copies of its filing have been served on its customers, Bay State Gas Company and Northern Utilities, Inc., and the regulatory commissions of the States of Maine, Massachusetts and New Hampshire.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Sections 211 and 214 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedures (18 CFR 385.211 and 385.214). All such motions or protests should be filed on or before January 13, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. RP94-91-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Granite State Gas Transmission, Inc.; Proposed Changes in FERC Gas Tariff</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-725 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
