<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00112</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00024</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>3. Mr. J. D. Buchanan (``Buch'')_11. Mr. Buchanan is a Canadian resident who had responsibility for metric conversion in Canada.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Borden, Inc. (``Bord'')_9 and 20. Borden sells products subject to the Commission's FPLA regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Cramer Products, Inc. (``Cram'')_18. Cramer is a small, employee-owned manufacturer of products for athletics and physical education.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. First Brands Corporation (``Frst'')_15. First sells products subject to the Commission's FPLA regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Maryland State Department of Agriculture, Weights and Measures Section (``Md Ag'')_5.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Mr. Eugene A. Mechtly (``Mech'')_7.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Michigan State Department of Agriculture (``Mich Ag'')_6.</textblock>
    <textblock>10. Micro Motion, Inc. (``Micr'')_4.</textblock>
    <textblock>11. Congresswoman Jan Meyers (``Cong. Meyers'')_17. Congresswoman Meyers is the Ranking Minority Member of the House Committee on Small Business.</textblock>
    <textblock>12. The National Conference on Weights and Measures (``NCWM'')_19. NCWM is a voluntary standards-writing body whose members are State and local weights and measures officials, as well as Federal Government, business, industry, and consumer representatives.</textblock>
    <textblock>13. The National Institute of Standards and Technology_Metric Program (``NIST'')_12. NIST, a unit of the Department of Commerce, has responsibility for guiding the Federal Government's conversion to usage of the metric system of measurement.</textblock>
    <textblock>14. Pier 1 Imports (``Pier'')_2. Pier sells products subject to the Commission's regulations issued under FPLA.</textblock>
    <textblock>15. The Procter &amp; Gamble Company (``PG'')_10. PG sells products subject to the Commission's regulations issued under FPLA.</textblock>
    <textblock>16. Mr. Louis F. Sokol (``Soko'')_8.</textblock>
    <textblock>17. Mr. Larry Stempnik (``Stem'')_13.</textblock>
    <textblock>18. Standards and Metric Practices Subcommittee of the Metric Operating Committee of the Interagency Council on Metric Policy (``SMPS'')_16. SMPS was responsible for writing Federal Standard 376B, ``Preferred Metric Units for General Use by the Federal Government.''</textblock>
    <textblock>19. Mr. John H. Woelflein (``Woel'')_3. Mr. Woelflein is a member of the U.S. Metric Association, Inc., the National Conference on Weights and Measures, and the New Hampshire Metric Advisory Council.</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Comment Suggestions Beyond Commission's Authority Under FPLA</textblock>
    <textblock>Two comments suggested that the Commission amend the regulations issued under the FPLA in ways that are beyond the Commission's authority and that would conflict with the 1992 metric amendments to the FPLA. Specifically, NCWM suggested that packages that are ``rational'' metric sizes, e.g., 250 mL, 500 mL, 1,2,3, and 4 liter, not be required to have inch/pound content declarations;</textblock>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
    <textblock>and Mr. Berke questioned the value of having metric equivalents on consumer packages and objected to the mandatory use of metric labeling.</textblock>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
    <textblock>As discussed above,</textblock>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
    <textblock>the 1992 amendments to section 4(a)(2) of the FPLA provide that the net quantity of contents shall be stated ``using the most appropriate units of</textblock>
    <textblock>both</textblock>
    <textblock>the customary inch/pound system *␣*␣*␣ and, *␣*␣*␣ the SI metric system'' (</textblock>
    <textblock>emphasis supplied</textblock>
    <textblock>). Thus, Congress has required by statute that both customary inch/pound and SI metric units are to be used for content disclosure. The Commission cannot issue regulations that contravene the statutory requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Discussion of Rule Amendments Being Adopted</textblock>
    <textblock>Each amendment the Commission is adopting today is identified below. The substantive revisions are described in detail. Minor, self-explanatory changes are merely noted. Comments about a proposed amendment are discussed with that amendment. If none of the comments addressed a proposed amendment, the Commission adopts the amendment without discussion.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>NCWM, 19, 5.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Berk, 1, 1-2.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Section II 3 C,</textblock>
    <textblock>supra</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
