<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00106</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00073</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Investigation No. 337-TA-354]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Certain Tape Dispensers; Decision Not To Review an Initial Determination Granting Motion To Amend Notice of Investigation To Clarify Identity of One Respondent and To Delete Another Respondent</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. International Trade Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the U.S. International Trade Commission has determined not to review the presiding administrative law judge's (ALJ) initial determination (ID) in the above-captioned investigation granting complainant Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing, Inc.'s (``3M'') motion to amend the notice of investigation to correct the identification of one respondent and to delete another respondent.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>James M. Lyons, Esq., Office of the General Counsel, U.S. International Trade Commission, 500 E Street, SW., Washington, DC 20436. Telephone: (202) 205-3094.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission instituted this investigation, which concerns allegations of violations of section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 in the importation and sale of certain tape dispensers, on July 15, 1993. Complainant 3M alleges infringement of U.S. Letters Patent Des. 289,180.</textblock>
    <textblock>On November 29, 1993, complainant filed a second motion to amend the notice of investigation to clarify the identity of the named respondents. Complainant moved to delete one respondent, Shiang Shin Trading Co., and to change the identification of another respondent, Safina Office Products, to Shiang Shin International, Inc., d/b/a Safina Office Products. In requesting this action, 3M stated that an affidavit received from one of the respondents had revealed that Safina Office Products is merely the assumed name for Shiang Shin International, Inc. and that Shiang Shin Trading Co. is an unrelated company that is not involved in the importation or sale of the subject tape dispensers. The Commission investigative attorney supported the motion. On December 13, 1993, the ALJ issued an ID (Order No. 4) granting complainant's motion.</textblock>
    <textblock>This action is taken under the authority of section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930, 19 U.S.C. 1337, and Commission interim rule 210.53(h), 19 CFR 210.53(h).</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the ID and all other nonconfidential documents filed in connection with this investigation are available for inspection during official business hours (8:45 a.m. to 5:15 p.m.) in the Office of the Secretary, U.S. International Trade Commission, 500 E Street, SW., Washington, DC 20436, telephone 202-205-2000. Hearing-impaired individuals are advised that information on this matter can be obtained by contacting the Commission's TDD terminal at (202) 205-1810.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued: January 7, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By order of the Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna R. Koehnke,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-773 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7020-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
