<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00115</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00082</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NATIONAL SCIENCE FOUNDATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Antarctic Conservation Act of 1978; Notice of Permit Modification</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>agency:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Science Foundation.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <summary>
    <textblock>summary:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Foundation modified a permit to conduct activities regulated under the Antarctic Conservation Act of 1978 (Pub. L. 95-541; Code of Federal Regulations title 45, part 670).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>for further information contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Guy G. Guthridge, (703) 306-1031. Permit Office, Office of Polar Programs, room 755, National Science Foundation, Arlington, Virginia 22230.</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>John L. Bengtson, National Marine Mammal Laboratory, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, Seattle, Washington 98115.</textblock>
    <textblock>description of permit and modification:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Foundation issued a permit to Dr. Bengtson, a marine mammals specialist, on 25 November 1992 after posting a notice in the 26 October 1992</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. Public comments were not received. The permit allows capture, handling, and release of six species of antarctic seals as part of a study, supported by NSF and NOAA, of the ecology, abundance, and distribution of pack ice seals.</textblock>
    <textblock>The modification, issued on 30 December 1993 and good until the permit expires on 31 December 1994, allows Dr. Bengtson's project to inject stable isotopes before taking blood samples (a procedure that enables estimates of body composition); to collect tissue biopsies for study of genetics, contaminants, and diet; and to fly as low as 200 feet for aerial surveys when called for by conditions of survey design or human safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>NSF review supports the applicant's statement that the requested modifications will not increase jeopardy to seals or other wildlife and that the information obtained will be valuable in determining the role of seals in the marine ecosystem.</textblock>
    <textblock>location:</textblock>
    <textblock>Antarctic waters.</textblock>
  </further>
  <date>
    <textblock>dates:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 1, 1993-December 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Guy G. Guthridge,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Permit Office, Office of Polar Programs.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-662 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7555-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
