<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00070</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00054</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Definitions</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of the FLRP in FY 1994, an ``Individual from a Disadvantaged</textblock>
    <textblock>Background'' is defined as in 42 CFR 57.1804, as one who:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Comes from an environment that has inhibited the individual from obtaining the knowledge, skill, and abilities required to enroll in and graduate from a health professions school, or from a program providing education or training in an allied health profession; or</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Comes from a family with an annual income below a level based on low</textblock>
    <textblock>income thresholds according to a family size published by the U.S. Bureau of the Census, adjusted annually for changes in the Consumer Price Index, and adjusted by the Secretary for use in health professions and nursing programs. The Secretary will periodically publish these income levels in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. The following income figures determine what constitutes a low income family for purposes of the Faculty Loan Repayment Program for FY l994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The term ``Living expenses'' means the costs of room and board, transportation and commuting costs, and other costs incurred during an individual's attendance at a health professions school, as estimated each year by the school as part of the school's standard student budget. (National Health Service Corps Loan Repayment Program, 42 CFR 62.22)</textblock>
    <textblock>The term ``Reasonable educational expenses and living expenses'' means the costs of those educational and living expenses which are equal to or less than the sum of the school's estimated standard student budgets for educational and living expenses for the degree program and for the year(s) during which the Program participant is/was enrolled in the school. (National Health Service Corps Loan Repayment Program, 42 CFR 62.22)</textblock>
    <textblock>The term ``Unserved Obligation Penalty'' means the amount equal to the number of months of obligated service that were not completed by an individual, multiplied by $1,000, except that in any case in which the individual fails to serve 1 year, the unserved obligation penalty shall be equal to the full period of obligated service multiplied by $1,000. (Section</textblock>
    <textblock>338E of the Act) See ``Breach of Contract'' section below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Program Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>The following requirements will be applied to the applicant and to the school.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Size of parents' family§1</textblock>
    <textblock>1Income level2</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>$9,4l9</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>l2,202</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>l4,523</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>l8,596</textblock>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
    <textblock>2l,930</textblock>
    <textblock>6 or more</textblock>
    <textblock>24,648</textblock>
    <textblock>1Includes only dependents listed on Federal income tax forms.</textblock>
    <textblock>2Adjusted gross income for calendar year 1993 rounded to $100.</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
