<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00012</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Revocation of Jet Route J-201</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 71</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Airspace Docket No. 93-ANM-40]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This action revokes Jet Route J-201 located between the Myton, UT, Very High Frequency Omnidirectional Range/Tactical Air Navigation (VORTAC) facility and the Scottsbluff, NE, VORTAC. This jet route failed to meet the necessary criteria required for extended service volume protection during the latest flight check. The FAA has issued several notices to airmen (NOTAM) stating that J-201 is canceled and flight is not authorized. These NOTAM's will be canceled once this final rule becomes effective on March 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>0901 u.t.c., March 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Norman W. Thomas, Airspace and Obstruction Evaluation Branch (ATP-240), Airspace-Rules and Aeronautical Information Division, Air Traffic Rules and Procedures Service, Federal Aviation Administration, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591; telephone: (202) 267-9230.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>This amendment to part 71 of the Federal Aviation Regulations revokes J-201 between the Myton, UT, VORTAC and the Scottsbluff, NE, VORTAC. During the latest flight check, this jet route failed to meet the necessary criteria required for extended service volume protection. The FAA has issued several NOTAM's stating that J-201 is canceled and flight is not authorized. These NOTAM's will be canceled once this final rule becomes effective on March 3, 1994. I find that notice and public procedure under 5 U.S.C. 553(b) are unnecessary because this is a minor technical amendment in which the public is not particularly interested. Jet routes are published in Paragraph 2004 of FAA Order 7400.9A dated June 17, 1993, and effective September 16, 1993, which is incorporated by reference in 14 CFR 71.1 (58 FR 36298; July 6, 1993). The jet route listed in this document will be removed subsequently from the Order.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA has determined that this regulation only involves an established body of technical regulations for which frequent and routine amendments are necessary to keep them operationally current. It, therefore_(1) is not a ``significant regulatory action'' under Executive Order 12866; (2) is not a ``significant rule'' under DOT Regulatory Policies and Procedures (44 FR 11034; February 26, 1979); and (3) does not warrant preparation of a regulatory evaluation as the anticipated impact is so minimal. Since this is a routine matter that will only affect air traffic procedures and air navigation, it is certified that this rule will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities under the criteria of the Regulatory Flexibility Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 14 CFR Part 71</textblock>
    <textblock>Airspace, Incorporation by reference, Navigation (air).</textblock>
    <textblock>Adoption of the Amendment</textblock>
    <textblock>In consideration of the foregoing, the Federal Aviation Administration amends 14 CFR part 71 as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 71_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for 14 CFR part 71 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>49 U.S.C. app. 1348(a), 1354(a), 1510; E.O. 10854, 24 FR 9565, 3 CFR, 1959-1963 Comp., p. 389; 49 U.S.C. 106(g); 14 CFR 11.69.</textblock>
    <textblock>§71.1</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The incorporation by reference in 14 CFR 71.1 of the Federal Aviation Administration Order 7400.9A, Airspace Designations and Reporting Points, dated June 17, 1993, and effective September 16, 1993, is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Paragraph 2004_Jet Routes</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>J-201␣[Removed]</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Harold W. Becker,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Airspace-Rules and Aeronautical Information Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-790 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
