<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00049</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>This rule was listed as item 1623 in the Department's Semiannual Agenda of Regulations published on October 25, 1993 (58 FR 56408, 56445) under Executive Order 12866 and the Regulatory Flexibility Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance program number and title is 14.400, Equal Opportunity in Housing.)</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 24 CFR Part 104</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedure, Aged, Fair Housing, Individuals with disabilities, Mortgages, Penalties.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly 24 CFR part 104 is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 104_ADMINISTRATIVE PROCEEDINGS UNDER SECTION 812 OF THE FAIR HOUSING ACT</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 104 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 3535(d) and 3600-3620.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 104.500 is amended by revising paragraph (c)(3) and by adding paragraph (c)(5) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§104.500</textblock>
    <textblock>Discovery.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)␣*␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Requests for the production of documents or other evidence, for inspection and other purposes.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Upon motion of a party, the presiding administrative law judge may issue an order requiring a physical or mental examination of a party or of a person in the custody or under the legal control of a party.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Section 104.540 is amended by revising the section heading, by removing paragraphs (a)(3) and (b)(4), and by adding paragraph (d) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§104.540</textblock>
    <textblock>Physical and mental examinations.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Upon motion of any party, when the mental or physical condition (including the blood group) of a party or of a person in the custody or under the legal control of a party, is in controversy, the presiding administrative law judge may order the party to submit to a physical or mental examination by a suitably licensed or certified examiner or to produce for examination the person in the party's custody or legal control. The order may be made only on motion for good cause shown and upon notice to the person to be examined and to all parties and shall specify the time, place, manner, conditions, and scope of the examination and the person or persons by whom it is to be made. A report of the examiner shall be made in accordance with Rule 35(b) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 17, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Roberta Achtenberg,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary for Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-691 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4210-28-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
