<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00130</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00092</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 4, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>On September 17, 1992, The Options Clearing Corporation (``OCC'') submitted a proposed rule change (File No. SR-OCC-92-29) to the Securities and Exchange Commission (``Commission'') pursuant to section 19(b) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (``Act'')</textblock>
    <textblock>concerning delivery-versus-payment (``DVP'') settlement procedures. Notice of the proposal appeared in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 14, 1992, to solicit comment from interested persons.</textblock>
    <textblock>No comments were received by the Commission. This order approves the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Description of the Proposal</textblock>
    <textblock>OCC is amending its Rule 1606A to modify its DVP settlement procedures. First, the proposal clarifies that a clearing member that elects to settle using DVP procedures in Rule 1606A is not discharged from its obligation to U.S. dollars or to deliver foreign currency in settlement of the exercise of foreign currency options until the earlier of the time when (i) the clearing member's agent bank irrevocably pays U.S. dollars or delivers foreign currency to OCC's correspondent bank on behalf of the clearing member of (ii) OCC's correspondent bank irrevocably credits OCC's account with the U.S. dollars or the foreign currency deliverable by the clearing member's agent bank whether or not the clearing member's agent bank has paid U.S. dollars or delivered foreign currency to OCC's correspondent bank. Second, the proposal emphasizes the conditional nature of OCC's obligation in the DVP settlement process. OCC is obligated to cause its correspondent bank to deliver the quantity of U.S. dollars or foreign currency payable by OCC only against receipt from the agent bank of the quantity of U.S. dollars or foreign currency payable to OCC. Finally, the proposal clarifies that OCC's delivery obligation is to the party designated in the DVP authorization, which may or may not be the clearing member's agent bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>II Discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission believes that the proposal is consistent with the Act and in particular section 17A of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 17A(b)(3) (A) and (F) of the Act</textblock>
    <textblock>require that a clearing agency be organized and its rules designed to promote the prompt and accurate clearance and settlement of securities transactions and to assure the safeguarding of funds in the custody or control of the clearing agency or for which it is responsible.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposal clarifies certain DVP settlement procedures and describes with more precision when a clearing member is discharged from its delivery and payment obligations in foreign currency options. It also clarifies OCC's payment and delivery obligations in connection with DVP settlement. In particular, the proposal clarifies that OCC's obligation arises only after the clearing member's agent bank fulfills its obligation to OCC's correspondent bank. The Commission believes that this effort by OCC to clarify the terms of DVP settlement should add certainty to the settlement process and should provide an added measure of protection for OCC. Because the rule change should further enable OCC to comply with its statutory obligations to provide prompt and accurate clearance and settlement of securities transactions and to assure the safeguarding of securities and funds, the Commission believes that approval of the rule change is warranted.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Conclusion</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons discussed above, the Commission believes that the proposal is consistent with the requirements of the Act, particularly with section 17A of the Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>and the rules and regulations thereunder.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is therefore ordered</textblock>
    <textblock>, Pursuant to section 19(b)(2) of the Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>that the above-mentioned proposed rule change (File No. SR-OCC-92-29) be, and hereby is, approved.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Commission by the Division of Market Regulation, pursuant to delegated authority.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Release No. 34-33411; International Series Release No. 627; File No. SR-OCC-92-29]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Self-Regulatory Organizations; the Options Clearing Corp.; Order Approving a Proposed Rule Change Relating to Delivery-Versus-Payment Settlement Procedures</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Securities Exchange Act Release No. 31566 (December 4, 1992), 57 FR 59190.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78q-1 (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78q-1(b)(3) (A) and (F) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78q-1 (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(2) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 200.30-3(a)(12) (1991).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-743 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
