<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00072</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00054</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>1. The extent to which the applicant meets the requirements of section</textblock>
    <textblock>738 of the Act;</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The completeness, accuracy, and validity of the applicant's responses</textblock>
    <textblock>to application requirements;</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The submission of the signed contract with the school;</textblock>
    <textblock>4. An applicant's earliest available date to begin service as a faculty member provided funding is available for that year; and</textblock>
    <textblock>5. An applicant's availability to enter into a service contract for a longer period than the mandatory 2-year minimum.</textblock>
    <textblock>Factors to assure equitable distribution (e.g. geographic, discipline) will be considered in determining the funding of completed applications.</textblock>
    <textblock>National Health Objectives for the Year 2000</textblock>
    <textblock>The Public Health Service (PHS) is committed to achieving the health promotion and disease prevention objectives of Healthy People 2000, a PHS-led national activity for setting priority areas. The Disadvantaged Health Professions Faculty Loan Repayment Program is related to the priority area of Educational and Community-Based Programs. Potential applicants may obtain a copy of Healthy People 2000 (Full Report; Stock No. 017-001-00474-0) or Healthy People 2000 (Summary Report; Stock No. 017-001-00473-1) through the Superintendent of Documents, Government Printing Office, Washington, D.C. 20402-9325 (Telephone (202) 783-3238).</textblock>
    <textblock>Application Requests</textblock>
    <textblock>Requests for application materials and questions regarding program information and business should be directed to: Norman Roskos, Chief, Analysis and Evaluation Branch, Division of Disadvantaged Assistance, Bureau of Health Professions, Health Resources and Services Administration, 5600 Fishers Lane, Room 8A-09, Rockville, Maryland 20857, Telephone: (301) 443-3680, FAX: (301) 443-5242.</textblock>
    <textblock>Completed applications should be returned to the address listed above. The application deadline date is June 30, 1994. Applications shall be considered to be ``on time'' if they are either:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Received on or before the established deadline date, or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Sent on or before the established deadline date and received in time for orderly processing. (Applicants should request a legibly dated U.S. Postal Service postmark or obtain a legibly dated receipt from a commercial carrier or U.S. Postal Service. Private metered postmarks shall not be acceptable as proof of timely mailing.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Late applications not accepted for processing will be returned to the applicant.</textblock>
    <textblock>The application form and instructions for this program have been approved by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) under the Paperwork Reduction Act. The OMB clearance number is 0915-0150.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Disadvantaged Health Professions Faculty Loan Repayment Program is listed at 93.923 in the Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance. It is not subject to the provisions of Executive Order 12372, Intergovernmental Review of Federal Programs (as implemented through 45 CFR part 100).</textblock>
    <textblock>This program is not subject to the Public Health System Reporting Requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 9, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John H. Kelso,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
