<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00052</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Public Law 92-463, the National Center for Health Statistics (NCHS), Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), announces the following meetings.</textblock>
    <textblock>Name:</textblock>
    <textblock>NCVHS Subcommittee on Long-Term Care Statistics.</textblock>
    <textblock>Time and Date:</textblock>
    <textblock>9 a.m.-2 p.m., February 8, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 703A, Hubert H. Humphrey Building, 200 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington DC 20201.</textblock>
    <textblock>Status:</textblock>
    <textblock>Open.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose:</textblock>
    <textblock>The subcommittee will work on its report and revise its charge. Afterward, members will receive a briefing on disability-related risk adjusters and long-term care data needs for health care reform.</textblock>
    <textblock>Name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Joint meeting of NCVHS Subcommittees on State and Community Health Statistics and Long-Term Care Statistics.</textblock>
    <textblock>Time and Date:</textblock>
    <textblock>2 p.m.-5 p.m., February 8, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 703A, Hubert H. Humphrey Building, 200 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20201.</textblock>
    <textblock>Status:</textblock>
    <textblock>Open.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose:</textblock>
    <textblock>The subcommittees will meet jointly to discuss issues related to State and local long-term care data.</textblock>
    <textblock>Name:</textblock>
    <textblock>NCVHS Subcommittee on State and Community Health Statistics.</textblock>
    <textblock>Time and Date:</textblock>
    <textblock>9 a.m.-5 p.m., February 9, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 703A, Hubert H. Humphrey Building, 200 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20201.</textblock>
    <textblock>Status:</textblock>
    <textblock>Open.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose:</textblock>
    <textblock>The subcommittee will meet to discuss issues related to State and community health statistics and to develop a work plan for the coming year.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contact Person for More Information:</textblock>
    <textblock>Substantive program information as well as summaries of the meetings and a roster of committee members may be obtained from Gail F. Fisher, Ph.D., Executive Secretary, NCVHS, NCHS, room 1100, Presidential Building, 6525 Belcrest Road, Hyattsville, Maryland 20782, telephone 301/436-7050.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Committee on Vital and Health Statistics (NCVHS); Meetings</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Elvin Hilyer,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Director for Policy Coordination, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-699 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-18-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
