<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00088</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00060</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. N-93-3699]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Submission of Proposed Information Collection to OMB</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Administration, HUD.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed information collection requirement described below has been submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for review, as required by the Paperwork Reduction Act. The Department is soliciting public comments on the subject proposal.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to submit comments regarding this proposal. Comments should refer to the proposal by name and should be sent to: Joseph F. Lackey, Jr., OMB Desk Officer, Office of Management and Budget, New Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Kay F. Weaver, Reports Management Officer, Department of Housing and Urban Development, 451 7th Street, Southwest, Washington, DC 20410, telephone (202) 708-0050. This is not a toll-free number. Copies of the proposed forms and other available documents submitted to OMB may be obtained from Ms. Weaver.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department has submitted the proposal for the collection of information, as described below, to OMB for review, as required by the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. chapter 35).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Notice lists the following information: (1) The title of the information collection proposal; (2) the office of the agency to collect the information; (3) the description of the need for the information and its proposed use; (4) the agency form number, if applicable; (5) what members of the public will be affected by the proposal; (6) how frequently information submissions will be required; (7) an estimate of the total number of hours needed to prepare the information submission including number of respondents, frequency of response, and hours of response; (8) whether the proposal is new or an extension, reinstatement, or revision of an information collection requirement; and (9) the names and telephone numbers of an agency official familiar with the proposal and of the OMB Desk Officer for the Department.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 3507 of the Paperwork Reduction Act, 44 U.S.C. 3507; Section 7(d) of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act, 42 U.S.C. 3535(d).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 14, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Kay Weaver,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, IRM Policy and Management Division.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Submission of Proposed Information Collection to OMB</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposal:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Fund Availability for HOPE for Public and Indian Housing Homeownership Program (HOPE 1) (FR-3501).</textblock>
    <textblock>Office:</textblock>
    <textblock>Public and Indian Housing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of the need for the information and its proposed use:</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of this information collection is to provide grants to Resident Councils, Resident Management Corporations, Public Housing Authorities, and Indian Housing Agencies. They will use the grants to plan and implement the conversion of public housing to public housing resident and low income homeownership.</textblock>
    <textblock>Form number:</textblock>
    <textblock>None.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>State or local Governments, businesses or other for-profit, and non-profit institutions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of submission:</textblock>
    <textblock>Semi-annually and recordkeeping.</textblock>
    <textblock>Reporting burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>Total estimated burden hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>13,100.</textblock>
    <textblock>Status:</textblock>
    <textblock>Reinstatement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Gary Van Buskirk, HUD, (202) 708-4233; Joseph F. Lackey, Jr., OMB, (202) 395-7316.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 14, 1993.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Number of respondents</textblock>
    <textblock>1×</textblock>
    <textblock>1Frequency of response</textblock>
    <textblock>1×</textblock>
    <textblock>1Hours per response</textblock>
    <textblock>1=</textblock>
    <textblock>1Burden hours</textblock>
    <textblock>Information Collection</textblock>
    <textblock>100</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>91</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>9,100</textblock>
    <textblock>Recordkeeping</textblock>
    <textblock>100</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>40</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>4,000</textblock>
  </table>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-689 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4210-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
