<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-1-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Special Analyses</textblock>
    <textblock>It has been determined that this notice of proposed rulemaking is not a significant regulatory action as defined in Executive Order 12866. It also has been determined that section 553(b) of the Administrative Procedure Act (5 U.S.C. chapter 5) and the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. chapter 6) do not apply to these regulations and, therefore, a Regulatory Flexibility Analysis is not required. Pursuant to section 7805(f) of the Internal Revenue Code, a copy of this notice of proposed rulemaking will be submitted to the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration for comment on its impact on small business.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments and Request for Public Hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>Before these proposed regulations are adopted as final regulations, consideration will be given to any written comments that are submitted timely (preferably a signed original and eight copies) to the IRS. All comments will be available for public inspection and copying. A public hearing may be scheduled if requested in writing by a person that timely submits written comments. If a public hearing is scheduled, notice of the date, time, and place for the hearing will be published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Drafting Information</textblock>
    <textblock>The principal author of these proposed regulations is Mary Gillmarten of the Office of Associate Chief Counsel (International), Internal Revenue Service. Other personnel from the Internal Revenue Service and Treasury Department participated in developing the regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 26 CFR Part 1</textblock>
    <textblock>Income taxes, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Amendments to the Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, 26 CFR part 1 is proposed to be amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 1_INCOME TAXES</textblock>
    <textblock>Paragraph 1</textblock>
    <textblock>. The authority citation for part 1 continues to read in part as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>26 U.S.C. 7805 *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>Par. 2.</textblock>
    <textblock>The heading of §1.936-6 is amended by removing the colon after the word ``make'' and by adding in its place a semicolon.</textblock>
    <textblock>Par. 3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1.936-6, paragraph (b)(1) is amended by:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Revising</textblock>
    <textblock>Q &amp; A. 10</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Designating the first sentence of</textblock>
    <textblock>A. 11</textblock>
    <textblock>as paragraph (i) and revising it.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Designating the flush text and example following newly designated</textblock>
    <textblock>A. 11</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) as paragraph (ii).</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Revising</textblock>
    <textblock>Q &amp; A. 12</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Revising</textblock>
    <textblock>A. 13</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. The revisions read as follows:</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
