<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00101</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00068</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force Risk Identification and Assessment Committee Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Interior, Fish and Wildlife Service.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice announces a meeting of the Risk Identification and Assessment Committee (Committee), a committee of the Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force. The Committee meeting will focus on evaluating potential pathways of nonindigenous species introduction using the pathway evaluation process developed at the previous meeting.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Risk Identification and Assessment Committee will meet from 9 a.m. to 3 p.m. on Wednesday, January 26, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Risk Identification and Assessment Committee meeting will be held at the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service Building, room 500, 4401 N. Fairfax Drive, Arlington, Virginia 22203.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Richard Orr, Risk Identification and Assessment Committee Chairman, U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, 6505 Belcrest Rd., room 810, Hyattsville, MD (301) 436-8939.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App. I), this notice announces a meeting of the Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force Risk Identification and Assessment Committee established under the authority of the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 (Pub. L. 101-646, 104 Stat. 4761, 16 U.S.C. 4701</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>, November 29, 1990). Minutes of the meetings will be maintained by the Coordinator, Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force, room 840, 4401 North Fairfax Drive, Arlington, Virginia 22203 and the Risk Identification and Assessment Committee Chairman, U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, 6505 Belcrest Rd., room 810, Hyattsville, MD 20782 and will be available for public inspection during regular business hours, Monday through Friday within 30 days following the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: 5 January 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Gary Edwards,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Co-Chair, Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force Assistant Director_Fisheries.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-656 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-55-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
