<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00046</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00034</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[OPP-42024H; FRL-4743-5]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Approval of Amendment to Texas Plan for Certification of Applicators of Compound 1080 Livestock Protection Collars</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of approval of amended certification plan.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>On August 13, 1993, EPA announced its intention to approve an amendment to the Texas Plan for Certification of Applicators of Compound 1080 Livestock Protection Collars (LPC's). Public comments were solicited on this amended plan. The amended plan permits pooling of LPC's among certified LPC applicators. No comments were received and EPA therefore approves the amended plan.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Jerry Oglesby, Pesticides and Toxic Substances Branch, Region VI, Environmental Protection Agency, 1445 Ross Ave., Dallas, TX 75202-2733, Telephone: 214-655-7563.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the provision of section 11(a)(2) of the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA) and 40 CFR part 171, the Texas Department of Agriculture submitted to EPA for approval, revisions to its current plan for certification of LPC applicators. The amendment to the Texas LPC certification plan permits the designation of collar pool agents. Certified LPC applicators are permitted to participate in a collar pool administered by a collar pool agent. The purpose of the collar pool is to reduce the number of LPC's in circulation by a pooling of LPC's. Certified LPC applicators will check out the LPC's from the collar pool agent immediately prior to use. When no longer needed, a LPC will be returned to the collar pool agent for distribution to another certified LPC applicator. All collar pool agents are considered agents of the registrant and are required to keep the same records. Further, the collar pool system will not affect the recordkeeping or reporting requirements of LPC users. EPA announced its intention to approve the amended plan in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of August 13, 1993 (58 FR 43115), and solicited comments. No comments were received and EPA therefore approves the amended plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the amended plan are available for review at the following locations during normal business hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Texas Department of Agriculture, Stephen F. Austin Building, Rm. 1034F, 17th St. and Congress Ave., Austin, TX 78711, Telephone 512-463-0013.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Environmental Protection Agency, Region VI, 1445 Ross Ave., 12th Floor, Suite 1200, Dallas, TX 75202, Telephone: 214-655-7239.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 6, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Allyn M. Davis,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Administrator, Region VI.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-497 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
