<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-1-00043</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-1-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>Due to the preliminary nature of this document and lack of necessary information on costs, the FHWA is unable to evaluate the effects of the potential regulatory changes on small entities. Based on the information received in response to this notice, the FHWA intends, in compliance with the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. 601-612), to carefully consider the economic impacts of these potential changes on small entities. The FHWA solicits comments, information, and data on these impacts.</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12612 (Federalism Assessment)</textblock>
    <textblock>This action has been analyzed in accordance with the principles and criteria contained in Executive Order 12612, and it has been determined that this action does not have sufficient federalism implications to warrant the preparation of a federalism assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12372 (Intergovernmental Review)</textblock>
    <textblock>Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Program Number 20.217, Motor Carrier Safety. The regulations implementing Executive Order 12372 regarding intergovernmental consultation on Federal programs and activities apply to this program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>This action does not contain a collection of information requirement for purposes of the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. 3501</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>)</textblock>
    <textblock>National Environmental Policy Act</textblock>
    <textblock>This agency has analyzed this action for the purpose of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>) and has determined that this action would not have any effect on the quality of the environment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulation Identification Number</textblock>
    <textblock>A regulatory identification number (RIN) is assigned to each regulatory action listed in the Unified Agenda of Federal Regulations. The Regulatory Information Service Center publishes the Unified Agenda in April and October of each year. The RIN contained in the heading of this document can be used to cross reference this action with the Unified Agenda.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 49 CFR Part 393</textblock>
    <textblock>Freight transportation, Highway safety, Highways and roads, Motor carriers, Motor vehicle safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>49 U.S.C. app. 2505; 49 U.S.C. 3102; 49 CFR 1.48.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued on January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rodney E. Slater,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Federal Highway Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-738 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-22-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
