<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00096</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00063</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Task Force on Lead-Based Paint Hazard Reduction and Financing; Open Meeting</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of the Secretary_Office of Lead-Based Paint Abatement and Poisoning Prevention</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. N-93-3701; FR-3633-N-01]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Lead-Based Paint Abatement and Poisoning Prevention, HUD.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of open meetings.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Task Force was established by the Secretary pursuant to section 1015 of the Residential Lead-Based Paint Hazard Reduction Act of 1992. The charter of the Task Force was approved July 14, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Task Force includes individuals representing the Department of Housing and Urban Development; the Farmers Home Administration; the Department of Veterans Affairs; the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation; the Federal National Mortgage Association; the Environmental Protection Agency; employee organizations in the building and construction trades industry; landlords; tenants; primary lending institutions; private mortgage insurers; single-family and multifamily real estate interests; nonprofit housing developers; property liability insurers; public housing agencies; low-income housing advocacy organizations; national, State, and local lead-poisoning prevention advocates and experts; and community-based organizations located in areas with substantial rental housing. These members were selected on the basis of personal experience and expert knowledge.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meetings will be held on February 9, 1994 (9 to 5:30), and February 10th, 1994 (9 to 1), (EST), at the Holiday Inn Capitol, 550 ``C'' St, SW. (corner of 6th &amp; C Streets), Washington, DC 20024.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Members of the public are invited to provide written material to: Ruth Wright, Task Force Staff Director, Department of Housing and Urban Development, 451 7th Street SW., room B-133, Washington, DC 20410.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ruth Wright, Task Force Staff Director, Department of Housing and Urban Development, 451 7th Street SW., room B-133, Washington, DC 20410; telephone (202) 755-1805. The TTD numbers are (202) 708-9300 or 1-800-877-8339. (Except for the ``800'' number, these are not toll-free numbers.)</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The first meeting of the Task Force was on November 8, 1993, in Washington, DC. An announcement will be published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>at least 15 days before each meeting. All meetings will be open to the public, with limited seating available on a first-come, first-served basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>The mandate of the Task Force is to make recommendations to the Secretary of HUD and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) concerning:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Incorporating the need to finance lead-based paint hazard reduction into underwriting standards;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Developing new loan products and procedures for financing lead-based paint hazard evaluation and reduction activities;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Adjusting appraisal guidelines to address lead safety;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Incorporating risk assessments or inspections for lead-based paint as a routine procedure in the origination of new residential mortgages;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Revising guidelines, regulations, and educational pamphlets issued by the Department of Housing and Urban Development and other Federal agencies relating to lead-based paint poisoning prevention;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Reducing the current uncertainties of liability related to lead-based paint in rental housing, by clarifying standards of care for landlords and lenders and by exploring the ``safe harbor'' concept;</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Increasing the availability of liability insurance for owners of rental housing and certified contractors and establishing alternative systems to compensate victims of lead-based paint poisoning; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) Evaluating the utility and appropriateness of requiring both risk assessments or inspections and notification to prospective lessees of rental housing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 4852a, 4852b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 20, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Arthur S. Newburg,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Lead-Based Paint Abatement and Poisoning Prevention.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-694 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4210-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
