<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00002</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93-162-1]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Availability of Environmental Assessments and Findings of No Significant Impact</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, USDA.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>We are advising the public that two environmental assessments and findings of no significant impact have been prepared by the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service relative to the issuance of permits to allow the field testing of genetically engineered organisms. The environmental assessments provide a basis for our conclusion that the field testing of these genetically engineered organisms will not present a risk of introducing or disseminating a plant pest and will not have a significant impact on the quality of the human environment. Based on its findings of no significant impact, the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service has determined that environmental impact statements need not be prepared.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the environmental assessments and findings of no significant impact are available for public inspection at USDA, room 1141, South Building, 14th Street and Independence Avenue SW., Washington, DC, between 8 a.m. and 4:30 p.m., Monday through Friday, except holidays. Persons wishing to inspect those documents are encouraged to call ahead on</textblock>
    <textblock>(202) 690-2817 to facilitate entry into the reading room.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Arnold Foudin, Deputy Director, Biotechnology Permits, Biotechnology, Biologics, and Environmental Protection, APHIS, USDA, room 850, Federal Building, 6505 Belcrest Road, Hyattsville, MD 20782, (301) 436-7612. For copies of the environmental assessments and findings of no significant impact, write to Mr. Clayton Givens at the same address. Please refer to the permit numbers listed below when ordering documents.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The regulations in 7 CFR part 340 (referred to below as the regulations) regulate the introduction (importation, interstate movement, and release into the environment) of genetically engineered organisms and products that are plant pests or that there is reason to believe are plant pests (regulated articles). A permit must be obtained before a regulated article may be introduced into the United States. The regulations set forth the procedures for obtaining a limited permit for the importation or interstate movement of a regulated article and for obtaining a permit for the release into the environment of a regulated article. The Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS) has stated that it would prepare an environmental assessment and, when necessary, an environmental impact statement before issuing a permit for the release into the environment of a regulated article (see 52 FR 22906).</textblock>
    <textblock>In the course of reviewing each permit application, APHIS assessed the impact on the environment that releasing the organisms under the conditions described in the permit application would have. APHIS has issued permits for the field testing of the organisms listed below after concluding that the organisms will not present a risk of plant pest introduction or dissemination and will not have a significant impact on the quality of the human environment. The environmental assessments and findings of no significant impact, which are based on data submitted by the applicants and on a review of other relevant literature, provide the public with documentation of APHIS' review and analysis of the environmental impacts associated with conducting the field tests.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental assessments and findings of no significant impact have been prepared by APHIS relative to the issuance of permits to allow the field testing of the following genetically engineered organisms:</textblock>
    <textblock>The environmental assessments and findings of no significant impact have been prepared in accordance with: (1) The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) (42 U.S.C. 4321</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>), (2) Regulations of the Council on Environmental Quality for Implementing the Procedural Provisions of NEPA</textblock>
    <textblock>(40 CFR parts 1500-1508), (3) USDA Regulations Implementing NEPA (7 CFR part 1b), and (4) APHIS Guidelines Implementing NEPA (44 FR 50381-50384, August 28, 1979, and 44 FR 51272-51274, August 31, 1979).</textblock>
    <textblock>Done in Washington, DC, this 6th day of January 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Permit No.</textblock>
    <textblock>1Permittee</textblock>
    <textblock>1Date issued</textblock>
    <textblock>1Organisms</textblock>
    <textblock>1Field test location</textblock>
    <textblock>93-252-01</textblock>
    <textblock>Monsanto Agricultural Company</textblock>
    <textblock>11-17-93</textblock>
    <textblock>Potato plants genetically engineered to express resistance to potato leaf roll virus</textblock>
    <textblock>Florida.</textblock>
    <textblock>93-281-01, renewal of permit 92-174-02, issued on 11-03-92</textblock>
    <textblock>Pioneer Hi-Bred International, Incorporated</textblock>
    <textblock>11-17-93</textblock>
    <textblock>Corn plants genetically engineered to express resistance to maize dwarf mosaic virus strain A, maize chlorotic mottle virus, or maize chlorotic dwarf virus</textblock>
    <textblock>Hawaii, Puerto Rico.</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lonnie J. King,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Administrator, Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-672 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-34-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
