<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00064</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-2-00049</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket C-2858]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>California and Hawaiian Sugar Co.</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Trade Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of period for public comment on petition to modify or vacate consent order.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>California and Hawaiian Sugar Company (``C&amp;H''), a respondent in Docket No. C-2858, is subject to an order prohibiting it from representing that its granulated sugar is different or superior unless (a) such difference or superiority relates to a consumer use of such sugar which is specified in the advertisement; (b) such difference or superiority is substantiated; and (c) such substantiation includes competent and reliable evidence that the difference or superiority is discernible to or of benefit to the class of consumers to whom the representation is directed. C&amp;H filed a petition on December 16, 1993, requesting that the Commission reopen and modify the order to allow C&amp;H to advertise all truthful, nondeceptive differences between its sugar and competing sugar that are substantiated by competent and reliable evidence. In the alternative, C&amp;H requests that the Commission vacate the order.</textblock>
    <textblock>This document announces the public comment period on this petition.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The deadline for filing comments in this matter is January 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be sent to the Office of the Secretary, Federal Trade Commission, 6th Street and Pennsylvania Avenue NW., Washington, DC 20580. Requests for copies of the petition should be sent to Public Reference Branch, room 130.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Robert M. Frisby, Enforcement Division, Bureau of Consumer Protection, Federal Trade Commission, Washington, DC 20580, (202) 326-2098.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The order in Docket No. C-2858 was published at 42 FR 6800 on February 4, 1977, reported at 89 F.T.C. 15. C&amp;H argues that significant changes in constitutional law and Commission policy since 1976 justify reopening the docket and modifying the order. C&amp;H maintains that the U.S. Supreme Court has extended First Amendment protection to purely commercial speech and views as particularly suspect prohibitions on expression such as those in the order. C&amp;H also contends that the burden of proof in restricting commercial speech lies with the party seeking to restrict it and that the Commission has provided no evidence that the order directly advances its interests in a reasonable manner. In addition, C&amp;H argues that since 1976 the Commission altered its position concerning truthful comparative advertising and now actively encourages such advertising. C&amp;H notes that since 1976 the Commission has adopted a ``reasonable consumer'' standard. C&amp;H also contends that the public interest justifies reopening and setting aside the order because consumers have a constitutional right to receive uncensored distribution of truthful information. Furthermore, C&amp;H maintains that market efficiency requires that consumers be given access to truthful information and that the order improperly discriminates among competitors. The petition was placed on the public record on December 23, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donald S. Clark,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-751 Filed 1-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6750-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
