<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00033</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940112-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>For the reasons set out in the preamble, subparts E, F, J, and P</textblock>
    <textblock>of part 404 and subparts B, E, G, I, N, Q and V of part 416 of 20</textblock>
    <textblock>CFR chapter III are amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 404_FEDERAL OLD-AGE, SURVIVORS AND DISABILITY</textblock>
    <textblock>INSURANCE (1950-␣␣)</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for subpart E continues to</textblock>
    <textblock>read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Secs. 202, 203, 204 (a) and (e), 205(a),</textblock>
    <textblock>222(b), 223(e), 224, 227, and 1102 of the Social Security Act;</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 402, 403, 404 (a) and (e), 405(a), 422(b), 423(e), 424,</textblock>
    <textblock>427, and 1302.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 404.422 is amended by adding two new</textblock>
    <textblock>sentences immediately before the second sentence of the</textblock>
    <textblock>introductory text of paragraph (e) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§404.422</textblock>
    <textblock>Deductions because of refusal to accept rehabilitation</textblock>
    <textblock>services.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)␣*␣*␣* In determining whether an individual has good cause</textblock>
    <textblock>for refusing rehabilitation services, we will take into account</textblock>
    <textblock>any physical, mental, educational, or linguistic limitations</textblock>
    <textblock>(including any lack of facility with the English language) the</textblock>
    <textblock>individual may have which may have caused the individual to</textblock>
    <textblock>refuse such services. We also consider other factors that may</textblock>
    <textblock>have caused an individual to refuse such services. *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Section 404.454 is amended by revising the third and</textblock>
    <textblock>fourth sentences of the introductory text of paragraph (a), by</textblock>
    <textblock>removing the word ``or'' that follows the semicolon at the end of</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (a)(7), by removing the period at the end of paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)(8) and replacing it with ``; or'', and by adding a new</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (a)(9) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§404.454</textblock>
    <textblock>Good cause for failure to make required reports.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>General</textblock>
    <textblock>. *␣*␣* The failure of the individual to submit</textblock>
    <textblock>evidence to establish good cause within a specified time may be</textblock>
    <textblock>considered a sufficient basis for a finding that good cause does</textblock>
    <textblock>not exist (see §404.705). In determining whether good cause for</textblock>
    <textblock>failure to report timely has been established by the individual,</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration is given to whether the failure to report within</textblock>
    <textblock>the proper time limit was the result of untoward circumstances,</textblock>
    <textblock>misleading action of the Social Security Administration,</textblock>
    <textblock>confusion as to the requirements of the Act resulting from</textblock>
    <textblock>amendments to the Act or other legislation, or any physical,</textblock>
    <textblock>mental, educational, or linguistic limitations (including any</textblock>
    <textblock>lack of facility with the English language) the individual may</textblock>
    <textblock>have. *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) Failure of the individual to understand reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibilities due to his or her physical, mental, educational,</textblock>
    <textblock>or linguistic limitation(s).</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>4. The authority citation for subpart F continues to</textblock>
    <textblock>read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Secs. 204(a)-(d), 205(a), and 1102 of the Social</textblock>
    <textblock>Security Act; 42 U.S.C. 404(a)-(d), 405(a), and 1302.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Section 404.507 is amended by revising the third sentence</textblock>
    <textblock>of the introductory text to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§404.507</textblock>
    <textblock>Fault.</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣*␣* In determining whether an individual is at fault, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Social Security Administration will consider all pertinent</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances, including the individual's age and intelligence,</textblock>
    <textblock>and any physical, mental, educational, or linguistic limitations</textblock>
    <textblock>(including any lack of facility with the English language) the</textblock>
    <textblock>individual has. *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Section 404.510 is amended by revising the section</textblock>
    <textblock>heading, by removing the last sentence of paragraph (n) and by</textblock>
    <textblock>revising the introductory text of §404.510 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§404.510</textblock>
    <textblock>When an individual is ``without fault'' in a deduction</textblock>
    <textblock>overpayment.</textblock>
    <textblock>In determining whether an individual is ``without fault'' with</textblock>
    <textblock>respect to a deduction overpayment, the Social Security</textblock>
    <textblock>Administration will consider all pertinent circumstances,</textblock>
    <textblock>including the individual's age and intelligence, and any</textblock>
    <textblock>physical, mental, educational, or linguistic limitations</textblock>
    <textblock>(including any lack of facility with the English language) the</textblock>
    <textblock>individual has. Except as provided in §404.511 or elsewhere in</textblock>
    <textblock>this subpart F, situations in which an individual will be</textblock>
    <textblock>considered to be ``without fault'' with respect to a deduction</textblock>
    <textblock>overpayment include, but are not limited to, those that are</textblock>
    <textblock>described in this section. An individual will be considered</textblock>
    <textblock>``without fault'' in accepting a payment which is incorrect because</textblock>
    <textblock>he/she failed to report an event specified in sections 203 (b) and</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) of the Act, or an event specified in section 203(d) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Act as in effect for monthly benefits for months after December</textblock>
    <textblock>1960, or because a deduction is required under section 203 (b),</textblock>
    <textblock>(c), (d), or section 222(b) of the Act, or payments were not</textblock>
    <textblock>withheld as required by section 202(t) or section 228 of the Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>if it is shown that such failure to report or acceptance of the</textblock>
    <textblock>overpayment was due to one of the following circumstances:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
