<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00088</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00064</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee Meeting on Rotorcraft Issues</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of public meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice announces a public meeting of the FAA's Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee on rotorcraft issues to discuss current rulemaking actions and future activities and plans.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held on February 4, 1994, at 9 a.m. PST. Arrange for oral presentations by January 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held at the Hilton Hotel, Mezzanine, at 777 Convention Way, Anaheim, California 92802, telephone (714) 750-4321.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Barbara Herber, Office of Rulemaking, Aircraft &amp; Airport Rules Division, ARM-200, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591, telephone (202) 267-3498.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This public meeting is announced pursuant to section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463; 5 U.S.C. App. II). The agenda will include:</textblock>
    <textblock>•Review of the JAR/FAR 27 and 29 Harmonization rulemaking package.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Report on the status of the Occupant Restraint rulemaking package.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Review the status of the External Loads rulemaking package.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Discussion of future activities and plans.</textblock>
    <textblock>Attendance is open to the public but will be limited to the space available. The public must make arrangements by January 21, 1994, to present oral statements at the meeting. Written statements may be presented to the committee at any time by providing 16 copies to the Assistant Executive Director or by providing the copies to him at the meeting. In addition, sign and oral interpretation, as well as a listening device, can be made available at the meeting if requested 10 calendar days before the meeting. Arrangements may be made by contacting the person listed under the caption ``</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT</textblock>
    <textblock>.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Fort Worth, Texas, on January 6, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Mike Mathias,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Assistant Executive Director for Rotorcraft Issues, Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1174 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
