<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-1-00010</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-1-00003</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Petition for Rulemaking; Summary of Petitions Received; Dispositions of Petitions Issued</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Chapter I</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Summary Notice No. PR-94-1]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of petitions for rulemaking received and of dispositions of prior petitions.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to FAA's rulemaking provisions governing the application, processing, and disposition of petitions for rulemaking (14 CFR part 11), this notice contains a summary of certain petitions requesting the initiation of rulemaking procedures for the amendment of specified provisions of the Federal Aviation Regulations and of denials or withdrawals of certain petitions previously received. The purpose of this notice is to improve the public's awareness of, and participation in, this aspect of FAA's regulatory activities. Neither publication of this notice nor the inclusion or omission of information in the summary is intended to affect the legal status of any petition or its final disposition.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on petitions received must identify the petition docket number involved and must be received March 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send comments on any petition in triplicate to:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration,</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the Chief Counsel,</textblock>
    <textblock>Attn: Rules Docket No.</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>,</textblock>
    <textblock>800 Independence Avenue, SW.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20591</textblock>
    <textblock>The petition, any comments received, and a copy of any final disposition are filed in the assigned regulatory docket and are available for examination in the Rules Docket (AGC-200), room 915G, FAA Headquarters Building (FOB 10A), 800 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20591; telephone (202) 267-3132.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Frederick M. Haynes, Office of Rulemaking (ARM-1), Federal Aviation Administration, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591; telephone (202) 267-3939.</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice is published pursuant to paragraphs (b) and (f) of ยง11.27 of part 11 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (14 CFR part 11).</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 6, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donald P. Byrne,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Chief Counsel for Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Petitions for Rulemaking</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>27454.</textblock>
    <textblock>Petitioner:</textblock>
    <textblock>Precision Airmotive Corporation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations Affected:</textblock>
    <textblock>14 CFR part 21.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of Rule Change Sought:</textblock>
    <textblock>To require disclosure to the Type Certificate of Supplemental Type Certificate holder, and if identified, the Original Equipment Manufacture design owner of the names of applicants for Parts Manufacturer Approval and the parts for which approval is sought.</textblock>
    <textblock>Petitioner's Reason for the Request:</textblock>
    <textblock>The petitioner feels this will enable the Type Certificate holder or Supplemental Type Certificate holder or the Original Equipment Manufacturer design owner to obtain information necessary to meet their obligations under the law and FAA regulation to provide post-sale safety information and warnings.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1171 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
