<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00024</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 10, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that the following filings have been made with</textblock>
    <textblock>the Commission:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Northern States Power Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. EL91-2-002]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 30, 1993, Northern States Power Company (Northern States) tendered for filing its refund report in the above-referenced docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 24, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Wisconsin Public Service Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. EL93-54-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 20, 1993, Wisconsin Public Service Corporation (WPSC) tendered for filing an amendment to its petition for waiver of the Commission's fuel clause regulations in this docket. WPSC's petition sought waiver to permit the refund to its wholesale customers of Spent Nuclear Fuel Disposal Costs that have been and will be refunded to WPSC by the United States Department of Energy. WPSC states that the amendment modifies the method of calculating the refunds to be provided to its wholesale customers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 24, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Public Service Company of Oklahoma</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. EL94-14-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that the Notice of Filing issued in Docket No. ER94-233-000 on December 16, 1993 (58 FR 68403, December 27, 1993), should have been issued under Docket No. EL94-14-000.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Commonwealth Edison Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER93-777-002]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 30, 1993, Commonwealth Edison Company (Edison) tendered for filing a revised FERC Transmission Service Tariff TS-1 in compliance with the Commission's order issued in Docket No. ER93-777-000 on November 30, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the filing has been served on the Illinois Commerce Commission and all parties to the proceeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 24, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Potomac Electric Power Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-111-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 28, 1993, The Potomac Electric Power Company (Pepco) tendered for filing answers to questions from the Commission's Staff regarding the filing submitted on November 3, 1993, which answers supplement the filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 24, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Pacific Gas and Electric Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-134-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 4, 1994, Pacific Gas and Electric Company (PG&amp;E) tendered an amended filing under Federal Energy Regulatory Commission Docket No. ER94-134-000, regarding a rate schedule change to Rate Schedule FERC No. 79, between PG&amp;E, the Western Area Power Administration (Western), and the Trinity Public Utilities District (TPUD).</textblock>
    <textblock>PG&amp;E's amended filing is made in response to FERC Staff inquiries regarding an Operating Agreement, filed as part of Docket No. ER94-134-000. In this amended filing PG&amp;E provided information regarding the cost and ownership of certain switches to be installed under the Operating Agreement, and has explained why TPUD provided PG&amp;E an Agreement, and has explained why TPUD provided PG&amp;E an indemnification against possible damages resulting from an islanding procedure discussed in the Operating Agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of this filing have been served upon Western, TPUD and the California Public Utilities Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 24, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. EL91-2-002, et al.]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Northern States Power Company, et al.;</textblock>
    <textblock>Electric Rate and Corporate Regulation Filings</textblock>
  </doctitle>
</doc>
