<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00114</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00075</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Review</textblock>
    <textblock>January 12, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of the Treasury has submitted the following public information collection requirement(s) to OMB for review and clearance under the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980, Public Law 96-511. Copies of the submission(s) may be obtained by calling the Treasury Bureau Clearance Officer listed. Comments regarding this information collection should be addressed to the OMB reviewer listed and to the Treasury Department Clearance Officer, Department of the Treasury, room 3171 Treasury Annex, 1500 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20220.</textblock>
    <textblock>SPECIAL REQUEST:</textblock>
    <textblock>This form was developed as a direct result of the enactment of the ``Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act,'' Title I of Public Law 103-159, which provides, in part, for a national waiting period of 5 days before a licensed importer, manufacturer, or dealer may lawfully transfer a handgun to a nonlicensed individual. The Act provides that the waiting period provisions of the law become effective 90 days after the date of enactment, i.e., February 28, 1994; therefore, the Department of the Treasury, on behalf of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms, is requesting Office of Management and Budget (OMB) review and approval by January 14, 1994. We are submitting this form for public comment by close of business February 1, 1994. Although this will not allow time for comment on this draft of the form, your comments are welcome and should be submitted for consideration for possible future revisions of the form.</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>New.</textblock>
    <textblock>Form Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>ATF F 5300.35.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Review:</textblock>
    <textblock>New Collection.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Statement of Intent to Obtain a Handgun(s).</textblock>
    <textblock>Description:</textblock>
    <textblock>This form is used to establish the eligibility of the buyer and to determine if a handgun sale is legal, prior to actual delivery of the handgun. It becomes part of the dealer's records and is used by Law Enforcement in investigations/inspections to trace firearms or to confirm criminal activity of persons who have violated the Gun Control Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals or households, Businesses or other for- profit, Federal agencies or employees.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Number of Respondents/Recordkeepers:</textblock>
    <textblock>8,000,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Burden Hours Per Respondent/Recordkeeping:</textblock>
    <textblock>6 minutes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>On occasion.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Total Reporting/Recordkeeping Burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>1,316,750 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Clearance Officer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Robert N. Hogarth, (202) 927-8930 , Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms, room 3200, 650 Massachusetts Avenue, NW.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20226.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB Reviewer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Milo Sunderhauf, (202) 395-6880, Office of Management and Budget, room 3001, New Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Public Information Collection Requirements Submitted to OMB for</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Dale A. Morgan,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Departmental Reports Management Officer.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE: 4810-31-P</textblock>
  </billing>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEN19JA94.000</textblock>
  </import>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4810-31-C</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
