<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00012</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(C) That if the household timely elects allotment reduction,</textblock>
    <textblock>such reduction will begin with the first allotment issued after</textblock>
    <textblock>such election, as provided in §273.12(c)(2) of this part;</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) That if the household fails to make a timely election, the</textblock>
    <textblock>reduction will begin with the first allotment issued 10 days after</textblock>
    <textblock>the date of the demand letter, as provided in §273.12(c)(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>Further collection actions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Inadvertent household error claims.</textblock>
    <textblock>Participating households which are liable for inadvertent household error claims</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be deemed to have elected allotment reduction unless they</textblock>
    <textblock>notify the State agency of their choice of repayment method within</textblock>
    <textblock>20 days of the date an initial demand letter, or a demand letter</textblock>
    <textblock>for payment following a fair hearing which sustains the claim, is</textblock>
    <textblock>mailed or otherwise delivered to them.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Intentional Program violation claims.</textblock>
    <textblock>Participating</textblock>
    <textblock>households which are liable for intentional Program violation</textblock>
    <textblock>claims shall elect a method of repayment on the date of receipt of</textblock>
    <textblock>the demand letter required in §273.16(e)(9) and (g)(3) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this part (or if the date of receipt is not a business day, on the</textblock>
    <textblock>next business day) or be deemed to have elected allotment</textblock>
    <textblock>reduction. Each State agency shall determine a deadline for</textblock>
    <textblock>receipt of such elections for them to be considered timely. In no</textblock>
    <textblock>event shall that deadline exceed 10 days from the date the demand</textblock>
    <textblock>letter is mailed or otherwise delivered to liable households.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) *␣*␣* The State agency may also pursue other collection</textblock>
    <textblock>actions, as appropriate, to obtain restitution of a claim against</textblock>
    <textblock>any household which fails to respond to a written demand letter for</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment of any inadvertent household error or administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>error claim. *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(h)</textblock>
    <textblock>Retention rates.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following retention rates shall</textblock>
    <textblock>apply for claims collected by the State agency, including the value</textblock>
    <textblock>of allotment reductions for the purpose of collecting claims but</textblock>
    <textblock>not allotment reductions due to disqualification:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) For amounts collected prior to October 1, 1990, the State</textblock>
    <textblock>agency shall retain 25 percent of the value of inadvertent</textblock>
    <textblock>household error claims collected and 50 percent of the value of</textblock>
    <textblock>intentional Program violation claims collected;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For amounts collected during the period October 1, 1990</textblock>
    <textblock>through September 30, 1995, the State agency shall retain 10</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of the value of inadvertent household error claims</textblock>
    <textblock>collected and 25 percent of the value of intentional Program</textblock>
    <textblock>violation claims collected;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) For amounts collected on or after October 1, 1995, the</textblock>
    <textblock>State agency shall retain 25 percent of the value of inadvertent</textblock>
    <textblock>household error claims collected and 50 percent of the value of</textblock>
    <textblock>intentional Program Violation claims collected;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The State agency shall not retain any percentage of the</textblock>
    <textblock>value of administrative error claims collected.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Submission of payments.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The State agency shall retain the value of funds</textblock>
    <textblock>collected for inadvertent household error, intentional Program</textblock>
    <textblock>violation, or administrative error claims rather than forwarding</textblock>
    <textblock>the payments to FNS. This amount includes the total value of</textblock>
    <textblock>allotment reductions to collect claims, but does not include the</textblock>
    <textblock>value of benefits not issued as a result of a household member</textblock>
    <textblock>being disqualified. The State's grant and letter of credit will be</textblock>
    <textblock>established or amended on a quarterly basis to reflect the State</textblock>
    <textblock>agency's retention of the value of claims collected as specified in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (h) of this section unless the State agency requests or</textblock>
    <textblock>has requested that payment be by check. The State agency may</textblock>
    <textblock>request that FNS accept checks from the State for FNS-209 amounts</textblock>
    <textblock>due FNS, or that FNS pay the State by check for FNS-209 amounts due</textblock>
    <textblock>the State. If the State agency fails to pay FNS the amount due as</textblock>
    <textblock>reported on the FNS-209, FNS shall offset the amount due from the</textblock>
    <textblock>State's letter of credit. For FNS-209 reporting purposes, State</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies shall calculate the retention amount using the appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>rate specified in paragraph (h) of this section which is in effect</textblock>
    <textblock>during the reporting period for the report. For those claims</textblock>
    <textblock>collected in Fiscal Year 1990 or earlier for which adjustments are</textblock>
    <textblock>made and reported in Fiscal Year 1991 or 1992, States may request</textblock>
    <textblock>a correction to reflect the difference between the old, higher rate</textblock>
    <textblock>(paragraph (h)(1) of this section) which is applicable to those</textblock>
    <textblock>claims, and the new, lower rate (paragraph (h)(2) of this section)</textblock>
    <textblock>at which the adjustments to those claims were reported on the FNS-209. One request for correction for each of fiscal years 1991 and</textblock>
    <textblock>1992 may be filed with FNS after the fiscal year, but no later than</textblock>
    <textblock>November 30, 1991 for Fiscal Year 1991 reporting and no later than</textblock>
    <textblock>November 30, 1992 for Fiscal Year 1992 reporting. The request must</textblock>
    <textblock>be in writing, must include appropriate verifying documentation,</textblock>
    <textblock>and must reflect the net effect of all increases and decreases</textblock>
    <textblock>resulting from the application of the old retention rate.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 276_STATE AGENCY LIABILITIES AND FEDERAL SANCTIONS</textblock>
    <textblock>6. The authority citation for part 276 continues to read as</textblock>
    <textblock>follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>7 U.S.C. 2011-2032.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. In §276.2 paragraph (e)(3) is revised to read as</textblock>
    <textblock>follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§276.2</textblock>
    <textblock>State agency liabilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV reimbursements.</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The State agency shall reimburse FNS through an</textblock>
    <textblock>adjustment to the Letter of Credit (LOC) unless it requests or has</textblock>
    <textblock>requested that it be allowed to pay by check. The reimbursement</textblock>
    <textblock>amount shall be reported quarterly on the Form FNS-209, Status of</textblock>
    <textblock>Claims Against Households, to be offset against LOC credit</textblock>
    <textblock>adjustments reported on that form. The State agency may request</textblock>
    <textblock>that FNS accept checks from the State for the amount due FNS. If</textblock>
    <textblock>a State agency fails to pay FNS the amount due as reported on the</textblock>
    <textblock>FNS-209, FNS shall offset the amount due from the State agency's</textblock>
    <textblock>Letter of Credit. The State agency shall maintain monthly records</textblock>
    <textblock>which detail the computation of reimbursement amounts reported on</textblock>
    <textblock>the Form FNS-209 for audit purposes.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 277_PAYMENTS OF CERTAIN ADMINISTRATIVE COSTS OF STATE</textblock>
    <textblock>AGENCIES</textblock>
    <textblock>8. The authority citation for part 277 continues to read as</textblock>
    <textblock>follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>7 U.S.C. 2011-2032.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. In §277.4:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Paragraph (b)(1) is revised; and</textblock>
    <textblock>b. New paragraphs (b)(11) and (b)(12) are added. The revision and additions read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§277.4</textblock>
    <textblock>Funding.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Reimbursement Rate.</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣*␣*</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
