<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00033</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Specifically TGPL proposes to abandon interruptible transportation service provided to the following Joint Venture Participants under the following rate schedules:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Carolina Pipeline Company_Rate Schedule X-137</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Delmarva Energy Company, an affiliate of Delmarva Power and Light Company_Rate Schedule X-154</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Eastern Shore Natural Gas Company_Rate Schedule X-155</textblock>
    <textblock>4. NCNG Exploration Corporation, an affiliate of North Carolina Natural Gas Corporation_Rate Schedule X-130</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Pennsylvania Gas and Water Company_Rate Schedule X-156</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Eastern Pennsylvania Exploration Company_Rate Schedule X-139</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Piedmont Exploration Company, Inc., an affiliate of Piedmont Natural Gas Company, Inc._Rate Schedule X-132</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Rockingham Exploration Company, an affiliate of North Carolina Gas Service Division of Pennsylvania and Southern Gas Company_Rate Schedule X-133</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Tar Heel Energy Corporation, an affiliate of Public Service Company of North Carolina, Inc._Rate Schedule X-134</textblock>
    <textblock>10. United Cities Gas Company; North and South Carolina Divisions_Rate Schedule X-135</textblock>
    <textblock>11. South Jersey Exploration Company_Series of</textblock>
    <textblock>interruptible transportation agreements.</textblock>
    <textblock>TGPL states that in order to reduce the administrative burden of executing and filing new transportation agreements each year and to provide additional receipt point flexibility, TGPL and the Joint Venture Participants have agreed to terminate existing interruptible transportation agreements and to enter into any necessary new interruptible transportation agreements pursuant to TGPL's Rate Schedule IT.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 31, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph F at the end of this notice.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
