<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(8) Permitting restrictions;</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) Crew limits;</textblock>
    <textblock>(10) Small mesh line;</textblock>
    <textblock>(11) on board observers;</textblock>
    <textblock>(12) Any other management measures currently included in the FMP.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) After developing management actions and receiving public testimony, the Council shall make a recommendation to the Regional Director. The Council's recommendation must include supporting rationale and, if management measures are recommended, an analysis of impacts, and a recommendation to the Regional Director on whether to publish the management measures as a final rule. If the Council recommends that the management measures should be published as a final rule, the Council must consider at least the following factors and provide support and analysis for each factor considered:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Whether the availability of data on which the recommended management measures are based allows for adequate time to publish a proposed rule, and whether regulations have to be in place for an entire harvest/fishing season;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Whether there has been adequate notice and opportunity for participation by the public and members of the affected industry in the development of the Council's recommended management measures;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Whether there is an immediate need to protect the resource; and,</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Whether there will be a continuing evaluation of management measures adopted following their promulgation as a final rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) If the Council's recommendation includes adjustments or additions to management measures, and if after reviewing the Council's recommendation and supporting information:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The Regional Director concurs with the Council's recommended management measures and determines that the recommended management measures may be published as a final rule based on the factors specified in paragraph (d) of this section, the action will be published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>as a final rule; or,</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The Regional Director concurs with the Council's recommendation and determines that the recommended management measures should be published first as a proposed rule, the action will be published as a proposed rule in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. After additional public comment, if the Regional Director concurs with the Council recommendation, the action will be published as a final rule in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The Regional Director does not concur, the Council will be notified, in writing, of the reasons for the non-concurrence.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) Nothing in this section is meant to derogate from the authority of the Secretary to take emergency action under section 305(e) of the Magnuson Act.</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1188 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
