<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00005</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In section 911 of Public Law 102-237, which was signed December 13,</textblock>
    <textblock>1991, Congress resolved this issue by providing that for an IHE</textblock>
    <textblock>claim, ``the household shall be given notice permitting it to elect</textblock>
    <textblock>another means of repayment [other than allotment reduction] and</textblock>
    <textblock>given 10 days to make such an election before the State agency</textblock>
    <textblock>commences action to reduce the household's monthly allotment.'' The</textblock>
    <textblock>Department understands by this language that no action to reduce</textblock>
    <textblock>the household's monthly allotment may be taken by the State agency</textblock>
    <textblock>until the eleventh day following the household's receipt of notice</textblock>
    <textblock>of the IHE claim.</textblock>
    <textblock>Typically households first receive notice about IHE claims through</textblock>
    <textblock>the mail in demand letters. Consequently, there is no practical</textblock>
    <textblock>way to determine exactly when households receive such notices and,</textblock>
    <textblock>in turn, the eleventh day afterwards. There is also the problem of</textblock>
    <textblock>allowing for return mail time. This rule provides that within 20</textblock>
    <textblock>days of the date of the demand letter, households must notify State</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies of their choice of repayment method or be deemed to have</textblock>
    <textblock>elected allotment reduction. This timeframe should allow for the</textblock>
    <textblock>newly required 10-day decision timeframe and adequate mail time,</textblock>
    <textblock>five days for delivery to households and five days for household</textblock>
    <textblock>return mail to State agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>As discussed below, the provision is restated to deal with IHE and</textblock>
    <textblock>IPV claims separately and to clarify that the timeframe for the IHE</textblock>
    <textblock>claim repayment decision relates both to initial demand letters and</textblock>
    <textblock>to demand letters following fair hearings which sustain IHE claims.</textblock>
    <textblock>Finally, to take account of demand letters which may be handed to</textblock>
    <textblock>the household, the language makes clear that the 20-day period</textblock>
    <textblock>begins on the date the demand letter is mailed or otherwise</textblock>
    <textblock>delivered to the household.</textblock>
    <textblock>Several commenters objected to the statement in the preamble to the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule to the effect that the claim itself was the adverse</textblock>
    <textblock>action, not the collection action. (This statement was made in</textblock>
    <textblock>connection with exempting the initiation of allotment reductions</textblock>
    <textblock>from the adverse notice requirements when households have been</textblock>
    <textblock>provided notice about appeal rights on the underlying claim. That</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal is discussed later in this preamble.) The Department</textblock>
    <textblock>would like to clarify this matter. Current rules require that</textblock>
    <textblock>households be provided specific information about their rights to</textblock>
    <textblock>appeal recipient claims. Once this information is provided, if a</textblock>
    <textblock>fair hearing is requested and a determination to sustain the claim</textblock>
    <textblock>is made, the household's remaining decision is how it will pay the</textblock>
    <textblock>claim. Making that decision should take relatively little time.</textblock>
    <textblock>To clarify how this policy applies to IHE claims, the final rule</textblock>
    <textblock>provides that in cases of IHE claims, if a fair hearing sustains</textblock>
    <textblock>the claim, the household must notify the State agency of its</textblock>
    <textblock>election of repayment method within 20 days of receipt of the</textblock>
    <textblock>notice of the hearing decision or be deemed to have elected</textblock>
    <textblock>allotment reduction.</textblock>
    <textblock>With respect to IPV claims, the final rule provides that households</textblock>
    <textblock>must elect a method of repayment on the date of receipt of the</textblock>
    <textblock>demand letter required by 7 CFR 273.16(e)(9), 7 CFR 273.16(f)(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>and (g)(3) of current rules (or if the date of receipt is not a</textblock>
    <textblock>business day, on the next business day) or be deemed to have</textblock>
    <textblock>elected allotment reduction. The final rule requires that for an</textblock>
    <textblock>IPV claim, the first claim demand letter following an action which</textblock>
    <textblock>establishes the claim, inform the household about this timeframe</textblock>
    <textblock>for election of a method of repayment and the consequence of</textblock>
    <textblock>failing to meet it. This is intended to clarify that the timeframe</textblock>
    <textblock>for electing a repayment option begins with the demand for</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment.</textblock>
    <textblock>The final rule also provides that each State agency must, for IPV</textblock>
    <textblock>claims, determine a deadline for the return of completed election</textblock>
    <textblock>forms in order to determine if the election is timely. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Department does not expect State agencies to set such deadlines</textblock>
    <textblock>case by case. State agencies should establish uniform timeframes</textblock>
    <textblock>for responses to demands for repayment of IPV claims, if necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>allowing for situations such as mail time to and from remote areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>The final rule states that the deadline cannot exceed 10 days from</textblock>
    <textblock>the date that the demand letter is mailed or otherwise delivered to</textblock>
    <textblock>liable households. The time period is set at a maximum of 10 days</textblock>
    <textblock>because the law requires a ``same day'' decision from households and</textblock>
    <textblock>a relatively short response time is appropriate to that statutory</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to these changes, to accommodate the different</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for IHE and IPV claims relating to repayment</textblock>
    <textblock>decisions, the final rule treats IHE and IPV claims in separate</textblock>
    <textblock>sections. Furthermore, since recoupment is a method of collection</textblock>
    <textblock>which is used only for participating households, when appropriate,</textblock>
    <textblock>the final rule refers to ``participating households.'' In 7 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>273.18(d)(4), which contains the policies on repayment decision</textblock>
    <textblock>timeframes, the heading is changed to ``Further collection actions''</textblock>
    <textblock>since that more accurately describes the material in the paragraph.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also, because IHE and IPV claims are treated in separate</textblock>
    <textblock>subparagraphs, the first sentence of paragraph (4)(i) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule has been deleted to eliminate potential confusion.</textblock>
    <textblock>This deletion also eliminates the redundant phrase ``do not respond</textblock>
    <textblock>timely or fail to respond.''</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department was concerned that a significant number of</textblock>
    <textblock>commenters believed that in reducing the time for electing</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment for IHE claims the proposed rule would also have abridged</textblock>
    <textblock>the right to appeal the claim. Consequently, in addition to</textblock>
    <textblock>treating IHE and IPV claims separately, the final rule sets forth</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for the content of the initial demand letter for IHE</textblock>
    <textblock>claims separately from the content of a demand letter for IHE</textblock>
    <textblock>claims which are sustained by fair hearings. An initial IHE demand</textblock>
    <textblock>letter needs to inform the household that it has an option of</textblock>
    <textblock>timely electing a repayment method</textblock>
    <textblock>or</textblock>
    <textblock>requesting a fair hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>A demand letter provided after a hearing decision which sustains</textblock>
    <textblock>the claim would not offer the hearing option. Similarly, the first</textblock>
    <textblock>demand letter for an IPV claim can only be issued following an</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative disqualification hearing or other action which</textblock>
    <textblock>establishes an IPV claim. The rule adds a phrase to clarify this</textblock>
    <textblock>point.</textblock>
    <textblock>In response to other comments, the final rule makes several other</textblock>
    <textblock>changes with respect to the required content of the demand letter</textblock>
    <textblock>for IHE and IPV claims. One commenter recommended that the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed list of repayment methods in 7 CFR 273.18(d)(3)(iii) be</textblock>
    <textblock>expanded to include repayment in coupons. However, a full list of</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment methods is already contained in 7 CFR 273.18(g).</textblock>
    <textblock>Paragraph (d)(3)(i) of that section already requires that the</textblock>
    <textblock>demand letter inform the household of these methods of repayment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Consequently, in addition to being incomplete, the proposed list in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (d)(3)(iii) is redundant, and so the final rule deletes</textblock>
    <textblock>it.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
