<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00041</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00025</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 12, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 10, 1994, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company (Tennessee) tendered for filing (1) a schedule indicating the level of Tennessee's filed take-or-pay costs in relation to the overall cap on Tennessee's take-or-pay cost recovery, and (2) Substitute First Revised Sheet No. 39, which reflects the allocation of take-or-pay costs to Equitable Gas Company rather than Equitrans, Inc. The revised tariff sheet is proposed to be effective January 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Tennessee submits that the schedule and revised tariff sheet are filed in compliance with the Commission's December 30, 1993 order accepting for filing and suspending, with conditions, Tennessee's take-or-pay recovery filing in Docket No. RP94-69-000. See Tennessee Gas Pipeline Co., 65 FERC 61,428.</textblock>
    <textblock>Tennessee states that copies of the filing are being served on all participants to this proceeding and all affected customers and state commissions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to protest said filing should file a protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rule 211 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure. All such protests should be filed on or before January 20, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Tennessee Gas Pipeline Co.; Compliance</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. RP94-69-001]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1183 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
