<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00078</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00056</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>II. Discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission believes that this proposal is consistent with the Act, particularly Section 17A of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 17A(b)(3) (A) and (F) of the Act require that a clearing agency be organized and its rules be designed to promote, among other things, the prompt and accurate clearance and settlement of securities transactions and the safeguarding of securities and funds within its custody or control or for which it is responsible.</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposal permits Treasury securities in MBS' Participants Fund to be carried at 100% of their current market value, in place of the current practice of carrying them at the lesser of their par value or 100% of their current market value. MBS reports that its customers have requested the proposed single price determinant for valuing Treasuries because, from the customers' perspective, it constitutes a more straightforward business practice and is less onerous to apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>In assessing the merits of this proposed change in the valuation of a major clearing margin asset, the Commission recognizes that allowing MBS to value the Treasury securities at prices above par would add some market and interest rate risk to MBS' valuation formula. But the Commission believes that the risk of this valuation change is manageable and acceptable inasmuch as the Treasury securities in question: (1) will be limited to non-callable Treasuries, meaning there will be no risk that a bond trading at a premium will be called at par; and (2) will be valued and marked-to-the-market by MBS on a daily basis, meaning that the maximum marketplace risk exposure will be a one day price move.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposal also includes technical changes to MBS' practices concerning its Participants Fund. Among other things, the proposal clarifies, with no change in meaning, MBS' standards for accepting letters of credit for deposits into its Fund. In particular, the proposal clarifies a previously-approved MBS rule filing stating that no more than 25% of the Participants Fund may consist of letters of credit from any one issuer.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission believes, therefore, that this portion of the proposal is not making any significant changes to existing rules. The Commission believes that the 25% limitation is a prudent measure to safeguard against exposure to any one financial institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Conclusion</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set forth above, the Commission finds that the proposed rule change is consistent with the requirements of the Act and in particular the requirements of Section 17A of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is therefore ordered, pursuant to section 19(b)(2) of the Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>that the above-mentioned proposed rule change (File No. SR-MBS-92-03) be, and hereby is, approved.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Commission by the Division of Market Regulation, pursuant to delegated authority.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78q-1 (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78q-1(b)(3) (A) and (F) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Securities Exchange Act Release No. 30278 (January 22, 1992), 57 FR 3660 [File No. SR-MBS-90-08] (order approving proposed rule change).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78q-1 (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(2) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 200.30-3(a)(12) (1993).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1168 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
