<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00030</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Department of the Interior has determined that this rule will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities under the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. 601</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>). The State submittal that is the subject of this rule is based upon counterpart Federal regulations for which an economic analysis was prepared and certification made that such regulations would not have a significant economic effect upon a substantial number of small entities. Accordingly, this rule will ensure that existing requirements previously promulgated by OSM will be implemented by the State. In making the determination as to whether this rule would have a significant economic impact, the Department relied upon the data and assumptions for the counterpart Federal regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 30 CFR Part 906</textblock>
    <textblock>Intergovernmental relations, Surface mining, Underground mining.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Raymond L. Lowrie,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Director, Western Support Center.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set out in the preamble, title 30, chapter VII, subchapter T, the Code of Federal Regulations is amended as set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 906_COLORADO</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 906 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>30 U.S.C. 1201</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. In ยง906.15, a new paragraph (o) is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง906.15</textblock>
    <textblock>Approval of regulatory program amendments.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(o) The revisions to the following provisions of 2 CFR 407-2, the rules and regulations of the Colorado Mined Land Reclamation Board, as submitted on March 19, 1993, and revised on August 4, 1993, are approved on January 19, 1994. The amendment becomes effective upon State promulgation of the amendment in the same form as submitted to OSM.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 1.04(103a)_Definition of ``Reasonably Available Spoil.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 4.14.1(2)(a)_General Backfilling and Grading Requirements to Restore Approximate Original Contour.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 4.14.1(2)(f)_Incomplete Elimination of Highwalls for Continuously Mined Areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 4.14.1(2)(g)_Incomplete Elimination of Highwalls for Remining Operations in Previously Mined Areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 4.14.1(2)(h)_Placement of Spoil on the Area Outside the Mined-Out Area.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 4.14.2(1), (1)(a), and (1)(b)_General Slope Grading Requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 4.27.4 and 4.27.4(1)_Limited Variances from Approximate Original Contour Requirements.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1200 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-05-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
