<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00069</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Wednesday</textblock>
    <textblock>January 19, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part II</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Defense</textblock>
    <textblock>Army Corps of Engineers</textblock>
    <textblock>33 CFR Part 334</textblock>
    <textblock>Restricted Areas and Danger Zone, Cooper River and Tributaries, Charleston, SC; Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>/ Vol. 59, No. 12 / Wednesday, January 19, 1994 / Rules and Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>33 CFR Part 334</textblock>
    <textblock>Restricted Areas and Danger Zone, Cooper River and Tributaries, Charleston, SC</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Army Corps of Engineers</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>agency:</textblock>
    <textblock>Army Corps of Engineers, DoD.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>summary:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Army Corps of Engineers is establishing a danger zone in the waters of an unnamed tributary of Foster Creek, a tributary of the Cooper River. The danger zone generally borders the Charleston Naval Base and the Naval Weapons Station, Charleston and Berkeley Counties, South Carolina. The danger zone is needed to protect the public from the dangers associated with the possibility of an errant round from an existing pistol range impacting in the unnamed creek. In addition to these regulations, the Navy has received authorization from the Charleston District Engineer to erect a fence and a gate across the creek to control passage into the area. Although the area is not closed to the public on a full time basis, the Commanding Officer, Naval Weapons Station, may close the area at any time and reopen the area when he/she determines that such restrictions may be terminated.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>effective date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>for further information contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Tina Hadden at (803) 727-4330 or Mr. Ralph Eppard at (202) 272-1783.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>supplementary information:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commanding Officer, Naval Weapons Station, Charleston, South Carolina, has requested that the Corps expand the existing restricted areas by establishing a danger zone in the waters of the Cooper River and its tributaries pursuant to its authorities in section 7 of the Rivers and Harbors Act of 1917 (33 U.S.C. 1) and section XIX of the Army Appropriations Act of 1919 (33 U.S.C. 3). The danger zone will generally border the Charleston Naval Base and Naval Weapons Station. The danger zone is needed to provide a margin of safety for vessels operating in the unnamed creek which is a tributary to Foster Creek by prohibiting their entry into the area when determined appropriate by the Commanding Officer of the Naval Weapons Station. A firing range for pistol training exists on an upland area close to the waterway. Although the weapons are not directed or intentionally fired into the waterway, an errant round from the pistol range could impact into the water. Vessels shall also be prevented from entering the area by a fence and gate across the waterway. Closure of the gate and prohibited entry by these regulations shall be as required by the Commanding Officer of the Naval Weapons Station.</textblock>
    <textblock>We published these rules in the Notice of Proposed Rulemaking Section of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on September 10, 1993, (58 FR 47786) with the comment period expiring on October 12, 1993. We received no comments and accordingly, we are publishing these regulations as final without change.</textblock>
    <textblock>Economic Assessment and Certification</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule is issued with respect to a military function of the Defense Department and accordingly, the provisions of Executive Order 12866 do not apply. These rules have been reviewed under the Regulatory Flexibility Act (Public Law 96-354), which requires the preparation of a regulatory flexibility analysis for any regulation that will have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small businesses (i.e., small businesses and small governmental jurisdictions). These regulations may have a minimal impact on individuals fishing in the area. However, these regulations will not prohibit their entry into the area except on an intermittent basis as required for the Governments' operations. The area is not known to support a commercial fishery and will not affect the food fishing industry. In addition, there will be no fees or charges imposed by the base commander for registration or entry into the area. This will not result in any increase in costs to those fishermen. Accordingly, the preparation of a regulatory flexibility analysis is not warranted.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 33 CFR Part 334</textblock>
    <textblock>Navigation (water), Transportation, Danger zones.</textblock>
    <textblock>In consideration of the above, the Corps is amending part 334 of title 33 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 334_DANGER ZONE AND RESTRICTED AREA REGULATIONS</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 334 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>40 Stat. 266; (33 U.S.C. 1) and 40 Stat. 892 (33 U.S.C. 3).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 334.460 is amended by adding paragraphs (a)(12) and (b)(11) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§334.460</textblock>
    <textblock>Cooper River and tributaries at Charleston, SC.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The areas.␣*␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(12) Danger zone. That portion of Foster Creek beginning at the point of the southern shoreline of an unnamed tributary of Foster Creek at its intersection with Foster Creek at latitude 31</textblock>
    <textblock>○59</textblock>
    <textblock>’16</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N, longitude 79</textblock>
    <textblock>○57</textblock>
    <textblock>’23</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’; thence back proceeding along the eastern shoreline to the terminus of the tributary at latitude 32</textblock>
    <textblock>○59</textblock>
    <textblock>’49</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’, longitude 79</textblock>
    <textblock>○57</textblock>
    <textblock>’29</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’; thence back down the western shoreline of the unnamed tributary to latitude 32</textblock>
    <textblock>○59</textblock>
    <textblock>’15</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’, longitude 79</textblock>
    <textblock>○57</textblock>
    <textblock>’26</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The regulations.␣*␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(11) The Commanding Officer of the U.S. Naval Weapons Station, Charleston, South Carolina, may at his/her discretion, close passage to all watercraft and vessels in the danger zone described in paragraph (a)(12) until such time as he/she determines such restrictions should be terminated.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 29, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jimmy F. Bates,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Director of Civil Works.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1194 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3710-92-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
