<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-1-00023</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-1-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Takings Implication</textblock>
    <textblock>In compliance with Executive Order 12630 and the Attorney General's Guidelines for the Evaluation of Risk and Avoidance of Unanticipated Takings, the takings implications of this proposed rule have been reviewed and considered. It has been determined that there is no risk of a taking.</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12778, Civil Justice Reform Act</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposed rule has been reviewed under Executive Order 12778, Civil Justice Reform. If this proposed rule were adopted, (1) all state and local laws and regulations that are in conflict with this proposed rule or which would impede its full implementation would be preempted; (2) no retroactive effect would be given to this proposed rule; and (3) it would not require administrative proceedings before parties could file suit in court challenging its provisions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule will not result in additional paperwork not already approved for use. Therefore, the review provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. 3507) and implementing regulations at 5 CFR part 1320 do not apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in Part 292</textblock>
    <textblock>National recreation areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, for the reasons set forth in the preamble, it is proposed to amend Part 292 of Chapter II of Title 36 of the Code of Federal Regulations by revising Subpart F to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 292_NATIONAL RECREATION AREAS</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart F_Hells Canyon National Recreation Area_Federal Lands</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec.</textblock>
    <textblock>292.40␣Purpose and scope.</textblock>
    <textblock>292.41␣Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>292.42␣Management standards and guidelines.</textblock>
    <textblock>292.43␣Protection and preservation of cultural and paleontological resources.</textblock>
    <textblock>292.44␣Use of motorized and mechanical equipment.</textblock>
    <textblock>292.45␣Use of motorized and non-motorized rivercraft.</textblock>
    <textblock>292.46␣Timber harvesting activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>292.47␣Mining activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>292.48␣Grazing activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart F_Hells Canyon National Recreation Area_Federal Lands</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 10, Public Law 94-199, 89 Stat. 1117 (16 U.S.C. 460gg-7).</textblock>
    <textblock>§292.40</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose and scope.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose.</textblock>
    <textblock>The rules of this subpart establish standards and guidelines for the protection and preservation of historic, archaeological, and paleontological resources, the use of motorized and mechanical equipment, the use of motorized and nonmotorized rivercraft, and the management, utilization, and disposal of natural resources by timber harvesting, mining and grazing on National Forest System lands that comprise the Hells Canyon National Recreation Area located in the Wallowa-Whitman, Nez Perce, and Payette National Forests in the States of Idaho and Oregon as established by the Act of December 31, 1975, as amended (89 Stat. 1117, 16 U.S.C. 460gg</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>).</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Scope.</textblock>
    <textblock>Management of National Forest System lands within the Hells Canyon National Recreation Area is subject to all laws, rules, and regulations applicable to the National Forest System, except as otherwise provided in this subpart. In the event of a conflict or inconsistency between rules of this subpart and other rules within this title, the rules of this subpart shall take precedence to the extent permitted by law.</textblock>
    <textblock>§292.41</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Special terms used in this subpart are defined as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Act</textblock>
    <textblock>means the Act of December 31, 1975, as amended (Pub. L. 94-199, 89 Stat. 1117) which established the Hells Canyon National Recreation Area.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comprehensive Management Plan</textblock>
    <textblock>is the document that establishes the array, levels, and manner of resource uses within the HCNRA. It is incorporated as part of the Wallowa-Whitman National Forest Land and Resource Management Plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cultural Resources</textblock>
    <textblock>means historic and archaeological resources.</textblock>
    <textblock>HCNRA</textblock>
    <textblock>is the abbreviation for the Hells Canyon National Recreation Area.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
