<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00009</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[I.D. 011194A]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Pacific Fishery Management Council; Meetings</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of public meetings.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Pacific Fishery Management Council's Groundfish Management Team (GMT) will hold public meetings on</textblock>
    <textblock>January 25-27, 1994, at the Hatfield Marine Science Center, in the large conference room of the library in Newport, OR. On January 25 the meeting will begin at 8 a.m. and run into the evening. At 10 a.m. on January 25, the GMT will hold a workshop with members of the groundfish fishing industry. On January 26-27 the meetings will begin at 8 a.m. each morning and continue into the evening.</textblock>
    <textblock>The major focus of the workshop with the groundfish fishing industry will be on how to use information gathered by the fleet in stock assessments and other fishery management activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the remainder of the meeting the GMT will review the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Status of implementation of the license limitation program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The 1993 fisheries;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The management priorities for the year; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The individual transferrable quota proposal for the fixed gear sablefish fishery.</textblock>
    <textblock>These meetings are physically accessible to people with disabilities. Requests for sign language interpretation or other auxiliary aids should be directed to Michelle Perry Sailer on (503) 326-6352 at least five (5) days prior to the meeting date.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Lawrence D. Six, Executive Director, Pacific Fishery Management Council, 2000 SW. First Avenue, suite 420, Portland, OR 97201; telephone: (503) 326-6352.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 12, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard H. Schaefer,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Fisheries Conservation and Management, National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1190 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
