<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00130</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00080</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>VII. General</textblock>
    <textblock>A. The policy and procedures contained within this MOA do not create any rights, either substantive or procedural, enforceable by any party regarding an enforcement action brought by the United States. Deviation or variance from the administrative procedures included in this MOA will not constitute a defense for violators or others concerned with any Section 404 enforcement action.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Nothing in this MOA is intended to diminish, modify, or otherwise affect statutory or regulatory authorities of any of the signatory agencies. All formal guidance interpreting this MOA and background materials upon which this MOA is based will be issued jointly by the agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Nothing in this MOA will be construed as indicating a financial commitment by SCS, the Corps, EPA, or FWS for the expenditure of funds except as authorized in specific appropriations.</textblock>
    <textblock>D. This MOA will take effect on the date of the last signature below and will continue in effect until modified or revoked by agreement of all signatory agencies, or revoked by any of the signatory agencies alone upon 90 days written notice. Modifications to this MOA may be made by mutual agreement and Headquarters level approval by all the signatory agencies. Such modifications will take effect upon signature of the modified document by all the signatory agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>E. The signatory agencies will refer delineation requests to the appropriate agency pursuant to this MOA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 6, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>James R. Lyons,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary for Natural Resources and Environment, Department of Agriculture.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Robert Perciasepe,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Administrator for Water, Environmental Protection Agency.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>G. Edward Dickey,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works, Department of the Army.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>George T. Frampton, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary for Fish, Wildlife and Parks, Department of the Interior.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1311 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3710-92-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
