<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00104</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00070</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>3. An entirely new technology added to a project. The Delta Costs in this category would be all of the costs for the new technology to be incorporated into the project. Examples would be the installation of a system for heating a bridge deck or the installation of a cathodic protection system for a bridge structure. In general, Delta Costs will not include those costs associated with the normal construction of the project that are not a direct part of the new technology. Examples of features that normally would not be included in Delta Costs include: restriping surfaces after overlays, redecking in conjunction with the installation of a bridge deck heating system, improvement of subsurface and/or roadside drainage systems in conjunction with a pavement overlay project, and traffic control during construction (unless it is unique to the installation or changed in character and cost by the installation, in which cases the increased costs specifically attributable to the portions of the project would be included in the Delta Costs).</textblock>
    <textblock>Costs for data collection, data analysis, and information dissemination are eligible for 100 percent ART funding on approved T&amp;E projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>In those instances where the technology used on an approved T&amp;E project fails and the State is required to repair the roadway to restore it to full standards, a pro rata share of the repair or replacement costs can be eligible for Federal-aid funds for that system where the installation took place. Such repair of the roadway will not be considered maintenance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Technical Assistance</textblock>
    <textblock>State highway agencies with approved T&amp;E projects shall be provided with technical assistance to carry out projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>Evaluation Plans</textblock>
    <textblock>When an evaluation plan that includes the construction of a full scale field T&amp;E project has been developed by HITEC, it will be submitted to the FHWA for review and proposed ART Program funding. The following sections shall be included in the evaluation plan for the proposed T&amp;E project. This information does not have to be submitted with the application to HITEC, but will be developed as a part of the HITEC evaluation process.</textblock>
    <textblock>Project Plan</textblock>
    <textblock>The specific purpose and objectives of the T&amp;E project must be delineated, followed by a description of:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The components of the technology to be evaluated,</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The proposed installations, and</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Planned observations, including qualitative and quantitative requirements for the term of the project.</textblock>
    <textblock>A time/phase chart or time line for the complete project must be included. If the T&amp;E project is to be a part of a larger construction project, the entire construction project must be described in general detail, and the new technology described in specific detail within the project.</textblock>
    <textblock>Data Collection</textblock>
    <textblock>The design of each data collection element must be based on the principles of scientific inquiry and structured so that both the internal and external validity of the data are fully addressed and the results can be applied to other situations. A detailed plan for the collection of data must accompany the proposal for the project. The plan must, as a minimum, include:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The type of data to be collected and the reasons for collecting it,</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Criteria and procedures for locating and placing the new technology and for selecting data collection locations,</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Instrumentation to be used for each set of data to be obtained,</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Timing of the data collection (e.g., calendar time, clock time, environmental conditions if limiting, and the interval between readings),</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Procedures for collecting the data, and</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Frequency and quantity of data to be obtained during the testing period.</textblock>
    <textblock>Data collection will be directed toward the determination of functional performance and life cycle costs and, where applicable, will include:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Design, construction, maintenance, and operations criteria and cost data,</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Relevant environmental and operational characteristics and data at the test site,</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Interim maintenance and repair history,</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Assessment of safety in both construction or installation and in operations,</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Measures of the impact on traffic operations,</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Measures of the impact on contiguous property and occupants,</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Performance data (e.g., visibility, reflectivity, riding quality, deflection, skid resistance, traffic capacity, and flow characteristics), and</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Other data as needed to fully meet the project objectives.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cost and Budget</textblock>
    <textblock>Detailed information on the estimated total costs and annual costs of the proposed project must be presented, with a breakdown of capital costs for equipment, instruments, and special materials; payroll costs for labor for installation and operation of the new technology; payroll costs, travel, and other expenses for observations, data collection, and analysis; costs for information storage and data retrieval; and costs for publication and distribution of reports and other proposed technology transfer activities. The proposed source, amount, and allocation of funds for the non-Federal portion of the costs must be described in the cost and budget data section of the proposal. Up to 80 percent of the costs of construction for the T&amp;E project may be provided by Federal funds; however, the level of cost-sharing offered by the proposing agency will be a factor considered in the selection of the projects to be funded under the ART Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Reporting Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>An annual progress report will be required of each public agency for each T&amp;E project for which the testing, data collection, and evaluation is underway. In order to meet Congressional deadlines, the report must be received by the FHWA no later than September 30 each year. The report should include:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. A brief description of the plan for the T&amp;E project, including a description of the technology being evaluated, the scope and objectives of the project, the evaluation procedures being used, and the time period and location(s) for the full program;</textblock>
    <textblock>2. A detailed description of the activities conducted during the report period, including the tests performed, the equipment being used, all test location characteristics, and a compilation of the data collected to date;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
