<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00058</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00039</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Public Law 92-463, notice is hereby given of a meeting of the Division of Research Grants Behavioral and Neurosciences Special Emphasis Panel.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be closed in accordance with the provisions set forth in section 552b(c)(4) and 552b(c)(6). Title 5, U.S.C. and section 10(d) of Public Law 92-463, for the review, discussion and evaluation of individual grant applications in the various areas and disciplines related to behavior and neuroscience. These applications and the discussions could reveal confidential trade secrets or commercial property such as patentable material and personal information concerning individuals associated with the applications, the disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Office of Committee Management, Division of Research Grants, Westwood Building, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland 20892, telephone 301-594-7265, will furnish summaries of the meeting and roster of panel members.</textblock>
    <textblock>Meeting To Review Individual Grant Applications</textblock>
    <textblock>Scientific Review Administrator:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Leonard Jacubczak (301) 594-7198.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date of Meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 19, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Place of Meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>Westwood Bldg, Rm325C, NIH, Bethesda, MD (Telephone Conference).</textblock>
    <textblock>Time of Meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>2 p.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice is being published less than 15 days prior to the meeting due to the difficulty of coordinating the attendance of members because of conflicting schedules.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Program Nos. 93.306, 93.333, 93.337, 93.393-93.396, 93.837-93.844, 93.846-93.878, 93.892, 93.893, National Institutes of Health, HHS)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 13, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Institutes of Health</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Division of Research Grants; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Susan K. Feldman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Committee Management Officer, NIH.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1406 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4140-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
