<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00083</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00060</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Shipping Coordinating Committee Subcommittee on Safety of Life at Sea, Working Group on Bulk Chemicals; Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>The Working Group on Bulk Chemicals (BCH) of the Subcommittee on Safety of Life at Sea (SOLAS) will conduct an open meeting at 9:30 a.m. on February 8, 1994, in room 4436, Nassif Building, 400 Seventh Street, SW., Washington, DC 20590. The purpose of the meeting is to review the results of the Twenty-third session of BCH held in September 1993 and to discuss air pollution issues in preparation for the 28 February meeting of the BCH working group on air pollution to be held at IMO Headquarters in London.</textblock>
    <textblock>Among other things, the items of particular interest are:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Amendments and interpretation of the Code for the Construction and Equipment of Ships Carrying Dangerous Chemicals in Bulk (BCH Code) and the International Code for the Construction and Equipment of Ships Carrying Dangerous Chemicals in Bulk (IBC Code).</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Amendments and interpretation of the provisions of Annex II of the International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution from Ships (MARPOL 73/78).</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Amendments and interpretation of the provisions of the Code for the Construction and Equipment of Ships Carrying Liquefied Gases in Bulk (GC Code) and the International Code for the Construction and Equipment of Ships Carrying Liquefied Gases In Bulk (IGC Code).</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Guidelines for technical assessment for intervention under the 1973 Intervention Protocol.</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Role of the human element in maritime casualties.</textblock>
    <textblock>f. Air pollution from ships.</textblock>
    <textblock>g. Existing ships' standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>h. International Convention on Oil Pollution Preparedness, Response and Cooperation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Members of the public may attend this meeting up to the seating capacity of the room. Interested persons may seek information by writing: Commander K. J. Eldridge, U.S. Coast Guard (G-MTH-1), 2100 Second Street SW., Washington, DC 20593-0001 or by calling (202) 267-1217.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF STATE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Public Notice 1932]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Geoffrey Ogden,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, Shipping Coordinating Committee.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1198 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4710-07-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
