<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00063</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(A)</textblock>
    <textblock>Four or more years history.</textblock>
    <textblock>Calculate the total number of scallop DAS for each year, exclude the high and low years of days at sea and average the remaining years; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B)</textblock>
    <textblock>Three year history.</textblock>
    <textblock>Calculate the total number of scallop DAS for each year, average the high and low years of days at sea, and then average the result with the third year; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(C)</textblock>
    <textblock>Two year history.</textblock>
    <textblock>Calculate the total number of scallop DAS for each year, average the two years' DAS; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(D)</textblock>
    <textblock>One year history.</textblock>
    <textblock>Calculate the actual number of scallop DAS for that year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Pro-ration.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a limited access vessel entered the scallop fishery for the first time during the relevant time period, the first year shall be pro-rated to a full year by pro-rating on an annual basis the number of DAS the vessel actually incurred on trips landing more than 400 pounds (181.44 kg) of shucked scallops or more than 50 U.S. bushels (17.62 hl) of in-shell scallops to determine the number of days at sea the vessel would have incurred had the vessel been in the fishery for the full year. The pro-ration formula is as follows: The total number of scallop DAS in that year is divided by the percentage of the year the vessel was in the fishery (by month). In pro-rating the days for such vessels, the Regional Director shall take into account the date the vessel entered the fishery, the vessel's subsequent fishing history, and other relevant information.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv)</textblock>
    <textblock>New owner.</textblock>
    <textblock>Vessel owners who purchased their vessel during the 1985-1990 time period may request that the DAS formulas be based solely on their individual history in the scallop fishery, excluding all previous owner's scallop histories. Under this option a vessel's first year in the fishery may be pro-rated based on the criteria specified in paragraph (b)(1)(iii) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For vessels qualifying for a limited access scallop permit under paragraph §650.4(a)(1)(i)(C), pro-rate to a full year the total number of DAS for trips the vessel would have fished and landed over 400 pounds (181.44 kg) of shucked scallops or more than 50 U.S. bushels (17.62 hl) of in-shell scallops in 1990 based on the actual number of DAS the vessel did fish in 1990 and the criteria specified in paragraph (b)(1)(iii) of this section. Then, calculate the average number of DAS for trips landing more than 400 pounds (181.44 kg) of shucked scallops or more than 50 U.S. bushels (17.62 hl) of in-shell scallops for the years 1991 and 1992. The number of days to determine the category shall be the lower number between the pro-rated 1990 days and the average of DAS in 1991 and 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>DAS allocations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each vessel qualifying for one of the three categories specified in paragraph (a) of this section shall be allocated, annually, the maximum number of DAS it may participate in the limited access scallop fishery, according to the category for which it qualifies. A vessel whose owner/operator has declared it out of the scallop fishery pursuant to the provisions of §650.26, or has used up its allocated DAS, may leave port without being assessed a DAS as long as it does not possess or land more than 400 pounds (181.44 kg) of shucked scallops or 50 U.S. bushels (17.61 hl) of in-shell scallops and complies with the other requirements of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual DAS allocations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The annual allocations of DAS for each category of vessel specified in paragraph (a) of this section shall be as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Accrual of DAS.</textblock>
    <textblock>DAS shall accrue in hourly increments, with all partial hours counted as full hours. A DAS is calculated beginning when a vessel leaves port and ending when the vessel returns to port as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) DAS for vessels that are under the VTS monitoring system described in §650.26(a) are counted beginning with the first hourly location signal received showing that the vessel crossed the COLREGS Demarcation Line leaving port and ending with the first hourly location signal received showing that the vessel crossed the COLREGS Demarcation Line upon its return to port.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) DAS for vessels fishing under the call-in notification system described in §650.26(b) are counted beginning once the phone call has been received and confirmation given by the Regional Director. A DAS ends when after returning to port, the phone call has been received, and confirmation given by the Regional Director.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Adjustments in annual DAS allocations</textblock>
    <textblock>. Adjustments or changes in annual DAS allocations, if required to meet fishing mortality reduction goals, may be made following a reappraisal and analysis under the framework provisions specified in subpart C of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of initial DAS category.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Regional Director will attempt to notify all owners of vessels that are deemed eligible to be issued a limited access scallop permit pursuant to §650.4(a)(6) as to which category the vessel qualifies for based on data, information and other evidence available to the Regional Director.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Appeal of DAS category.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Appeal criteria.</textblock>
    <textblock>A vessel's owner may appeal his/her vessel's initial placement into a vessel category to the Regional Director within 30 days of receipt of the notice of a vessel's DAS category. Any such appeal must be based on one or more of the following grounds, must be in writing, and must state the grounds for the appeal:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The information used by the Regional Director was based on mistaken or incorrect data;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The applicant was prevented by circumstances beyond his/her control from meeting relevant criteria; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The applicant has new or additional information.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The Regional Director will appoint a designee who will make an initial decision on the appeal.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1DAS category</textblock>
    <textblock>1 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>11995-96</textblock>
    <textblock>11997</textblock>
    <textblock>11998-99</textblock>
    <textblock>12000+</textblock>
    <textblock>Full-time</textblock>
    <textblock>204</textblock>
    <textblock>182</textblock>
    <textblock>164</textblock>
    <textblock>142</textblock>
    <textblock>120</textblock>
    <textblock>Part-time</textblock>
    <textblock>91</textblock>
    <textblock>82</textblock>
    <textblock>66</textblock>
    <textblock>57</textblock>
    <textblock>48</textblock>
    <textblock>Occasional</textblock>
    <textblock>18</textblock>
    <textblock>16</textblock>
    <textblock>14</textblock>
    <textblock>12</textblock>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
