<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00019</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Education Commission on Time and Learning; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Education Commission on Time and Learning, Education.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of public meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice sets forth the schedule and proposed agenda of a forthcoming public Meeting of the National Education Commission on Time and Learning. This notice also describes the functions of the Commission. Notice of this Meeting is required under section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATE, time and location:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 4, 1994 from 1 p.m. to 2 p.m., National Education Commission on Time and Learning, Headquarters Offices_The Conference Room, 1255 22nd Street, NW_suite 502, Washington, DC 20037, Telephone: (202) 653-5019.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Julia Anna Anderson, Deputy Executive Director, 1255 22nd Street NW., suite 502, Washington, DC 20202-7591.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The National Education Commission on Time and Learning is established under section 102 of the Education Council Act of 1991 (20 U.S.C. 1221-1). The Commission is established to examine the quality and adequacy of the study and learning time of elementary and secondary students in the United States, including issues regarding the length of the school day and year, how time is being used for academic subjects, the use of incentives, how time is used outside of school, the extent and role of homework, year-round professional opportunities for teachers, the use of school facilities for extended learning programs, if appropriate a model for adopting a longer day or year, suggested changes for state laws and regulations, and an analysis and estimate of the additional costs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting of the Commission is open to the public. The proposed agenda includes a discussion of procedures for assuring expeditious completion of Commission tasks. Records are kept of all Commission proceedings, and are available for public inspection at the Office of the Commission at 1255 22nd Street NW., suite 502, Washington, DC 20202-7591 from the hours of 9 a.m. to 5:30 p.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 13, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John Hodge Jones,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, National Education Commission on Time and Learning.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1252 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4000-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
