<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00038</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 12, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 10, 1994 Eastern Shore Natural Gas Company (ESNG) tendered for filing as part of its FERC Gas Tariff, First Revised Volume No. 1, certain revised tariff sheet included in Appendix A attached to the filing. Such sheet is proposed to be effective November 1, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>ESNG states that the above referenced tariff sheet is being filed due to the improper carrying forward of the CWS and CFSS Demand Charges, calculated correctly on the back-up sheets, but keypunched incorrectly on Substitute Forty-Second Revised Sheet No. 6.</textblock>
    <textblock>ESNG states that copies of the filing have been served upon its jurisdictional customers and interested State Commissions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to protest said filing should file a protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rule 211 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (18 CFR 385.211). All such protests should be filed on or before January 20, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. TQ94-3-23-001 and TM94-5-23-001]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Eastern Shore Natural Gas Co; Proposed Changes in FERC Gas Tariff</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1180 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
