<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00051</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00035</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 12, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Communications Commission has submitted the following information collection requirement to OMB for review and clearance under the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. 3507).</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of this submission may be purchased from the Commission's copy contractor, International Transcription Service, Inc., 2100 M Street NW., suite 140, Washington, DC 20037, (202) 857-3800. For further information on this submission contact Judy Boley, Federal Communications Commission, (202) 632-0276. Persons wishing to comment on this information collection should contact Timothy Fain, Office of Management and Budget, room 3235 NEOB, Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-3561.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>3060-0012</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Application for Additional Time to Construct a Radio Station (Under 47 CFR parts 21, 23, and 25)</textblock>
    <textblock>Form Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>FCC Form 701</textblock>
    <textblock>Action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Revisions of a currently approved collection</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Businesses or other for-profit (including small businesses)</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>On occasion reporting requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Annual Burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>200 responses; 2 hours average burden per response; 400 hours total annual burden</textblock>
    <textblock>Needs and Uses:</textblock>
    <textblock>FCC Form 701 is used when applying for additional time to construct a radio or satellite station. In addition to the requirements contained in the form, applicants may be subject to other requirements contained in the Rules. FCC Form 701 is used by agency staff personnel to determine whether to grant the applicant's request for an additional period of time to construct a station. The agency could not determine whether the applicant's request for additional time should be granted without the information collection. Other showings may be necessary in addition to those specified in the application form to comprise a complete filing. The form has been revised to include the certification required by the Commission's rules implementing the provisions of section 5301 of the Anti-Drug Abuse Act of 1988.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL COMMUNICATIONS COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Public Information Collection Requirement Submitted to Office of Management and Budget for Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William F. Caton,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1204 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
