<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00023</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>11. Portland General Electric Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-254-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 30, 1993, Portland General Electric Company (PGE) tendered for filing a Certificate of Concurrence under Docket No. ER94-254-000, relating an agreement, with amendment, for interconnection between PacifiCorp and Portland General Electric and a supplemental agreement for temporary use of facilities. Copies of these agreements and amendments have been served on the parties included in the distribution list defined in the filing letter.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 25, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>12. Northwestern Public Service Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-274-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 16, 1993, Northwestern Public Service Company tendered for filing various agreements for interconnection, emergency interconnection, wheeling and emergency type service, along with associated certificates of concurrence involving Northwestern Public Service Company, Rushmore Electric Power Cooperative, Inc., West Central Electric Cooperative, East River Electric Power Cooperative and the United States Department of Energy_Western Area Power Administration.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 24, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>13. PacifiCorp</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-280-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that PacifiCorp, on December 29, 1993, tendered for filing, in accordance with Commission's Order an amendment to its filing in the above referenced Docket No. ER94-280-000, an agreement regarding the installation of capacitors at Jim Bridger and Kinport substation dated August 6, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of this filing were supplied to Idaho Power Company, the Public Utility Commission of Oregon, the Utah Public Service Commission, the Idaho Public Utilities Commission and the Wyoming Public Service Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 25, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>14. Wisconsin Public Service Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-327-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 20, 1993, Wisconsin Public Service Corporation (``the Company'') of Green Bay Wisconsin, filed a proposed Supplement No. 4 to Supplement No. 9 to the Company's Service Agreement with WPPI which relates to WPPI peak shaving for the period January 1, 1996 through October 15, 1997.</textblock>
    <textblock>WPPI is the only customer currently peak shaving under the Company's W-1 full requirements tariff. WPPI supports the filing and the proposed effective date of January 1, 1996.</textblock>
    <textblock>The filing does not change the level of the Company's rates. The Company states that it has furnished copies of the filing to WPPI, its other customers who are served under the full requirements tariff, the Michigan Public Service Commission and the Public Service Commission of Wisconsin.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 24, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>15. Tiger Bay Limited Partnership</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. QF93-15-001]</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 10, 1994, Tiger Bay Limited Partnership tendered for filing an amendment to its initial filing in this docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>The amendment pertains to the ownership structure of the cogeneration facility. No determination has been made that the submittal constitutes a complete filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 31, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard Paragraphs</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rules 211 and 214 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (18 CFR 385.211 and 18 CFR 385.214). All such motions or protests should be filed on or before the comment date. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1233 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
