<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-1-00015</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Guaranty Agency Reserves Negotiated Rulemaking Advisory Committee Meeting</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of Postsecondary Education</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>34 CFR Chapter VI</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of first meeting of the Guaranty Agency Reserves Negotiated Rulemaking Advisory Committee.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice sets forth the date and location of the forthcoming meeting of the Guaranty Agency Reserves Negotiated Rulemaking Advisory Committee. The notice also describes the functions of the committee. Notice of this meeting is required under section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act. This document is intended to notify the general public of their opportunity to attend.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 26-27, 1994 from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Radisson Plaza Hotel at Mark Center, 5000 Seminary Road, Alexandria, Virginia, 22311.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>Jennifer Peck, Office of the Assistant for Postsecondary Education, U.S. Department of Education, 400 Maryland Avenue SW., (Room 4082, ROB-3), Washington, DC 20202-5100 Telephone: (202) 708-5547. Individuals who use a telecommunications device for the deaf (TDD) may call the Federal Information Relay Service (FIRS) at 1-800-877-8339 between 8 a.m. and 8 p.m., Eastern time, Monday through Friday.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Guaranty Agency Reserves Negotiated Rulemaking Advisory Committee is established by sections 422 and 457 of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended by the Student Loan Reform Act of 1993 (Pub. L. 103-66; 20 USC 1087g). The Committee is also established in accordance with the provisions of the Negotiated Rulemaking Act (Pub. L. 101-648, as amended; 5 USC 561). The advisory Committee is established to provide advice to the Secretary on the standards, criteria, procedures, and regulations governing advances for reserve funds of State and nonprofit private loan insurance programs. These standards, criteria, procedures and regulations will implement section 422 of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended by the Student Loan Reform Act of 1993 beginning with the academic year 1995-1996 (20 USC 1072).</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting is open to the public. The agenda for the initial meeting will include discussion of the committee's organizational structure and protocols, and establish a schedule to negotiate proposed rules by the summer.</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice is published less than 15 days of the first meeting due to administrative difficulties.</textblock>
    <textblock>Records are kept of all committee proceedings and are available for public inspection at the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education, room 4082, ROB-3, 7th and D Streets SW., Washington, DC from the hours of 9 a.m. and 5 p.m. weekdays, except Federal holidays.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 13, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David A. Longanecker,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary, Office of Postsecondary Education, U.S. Department of Education.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1433 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4000-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
