<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00056</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00037</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Agency Information Collection Under OMB Review</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the provisions of the Federal Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. chapter 35), we have submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) a request for a three-year approval of Form ACF-118 as proposed in this package. This request entitled: ``Child Care and Development Block Grant Preprint'' was previously approved under OMB Control Number 0970-0114. This request is sponsored by the Division of Child Care of the Administration for Children and Families (ACF).</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Administration for Children and Families</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of this information collection may be obtained from Stephen R. Smith of the Office of Information Systems Management, ACF, by calling 202-401-6964.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments and questions regarding this information collection should be sent directly to: Laura Oliven, OMB Desk Officer for ACF, OMB Reports Management Branch, New Executive Office Building, room 3002, 725 17th Street, NW., Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-7316.</textblock>
    <textblock>Information on Document</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Plan for Child Care and Development Block Grant Form ACF-118.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB NO.:</textblock>
    <textblock>0980-0241.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Child Care and Development Block Grant (the Block Grant) program provides funds to States, Territories, and Tribal Organizations to increase the affordability, availability and quality of child care services. Section 658E of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (section 5082 of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990, Public Law 101-508) requires lead agencies responsible for administering the Block Grant program to biennially submit a plan to the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services. The plan constitutes an agreement between the grantee and the Federal government as to how the Block Grant program will operate within the area served by the grantee. The plan also provides assurances that the program will be administered in conformance with the Act, pertinent Federal regulations, and other applicable instructions or guidelines issued by the Department.</textblock>
    <textblock>The preprint assists and guides lead agencies in submitting Block Grant plans. The plan preprint is arranged in five sections:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 1_Assurances; Part 2_Lead Agency Responsibilities; Part 3_Child Care Services; Part 4_Activities to Improve the Quality of Child Care and to Increase the Availability of Early Childhood Development and Before- and After-School Services; and Part 5_Program Operations. The standardized format will ensure that complete program information is submitted; provide usable information needed to compile and compare program data; and expedite timely reviews.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Number of Respondents</textblock>
    <textblock>: 269.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Frequency</textblock>
    <textblock>: 6.</textblock>
    <textblock>Average Burden Hours Per Response</textblock>
    <textblock>: 20.8.</textblock>
    <textblock>Total Burden Hours</textblock>
    <textblock>: 33,625.</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>Block Grant Plans are submitted biennially.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </address>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Larry Guerrero,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Director, Office of Information Systems Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1195 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4184-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
