<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00060</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00041</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Realty Action; Recreation and Public Purposes Act Classification, Yuba County, CA</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[CA-010-4210-01, CACA 33715]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The following described public land has been examined and found suitable for classification for lease or conveyance to the County of Yuba under the provisions of the Recreation and Public Purposes (R&amp;PP) Act, as Amended (43 U.S.C. 869</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>). The County of Yuba proposes to utilize the land for recreation in conjunction with the county's Hammond Grove Park which adjoins the subject tract.</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 16N, R. 5E., M.D.M.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 22: lot 5 (24.25-acres, more or less)</textblock>
    <textblock>Upon publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>the above land is segregated from settlement, location and entry under the public land laws and from the mining laws_except for lease or conveyance under the Recreation and Public Purposes Act. The previous Recreation and Public Purposes classification, S 066805, and R&amp;PP lease, CACA 3564, are hereby terminated.</textblock>
    <textblock>The land is not needed for Federal purposes. Lease or conveyance is consistent with current BLM land use planning and is considered to be in the public interest.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The lease/patent, would be subject to the following terms, conditions and reservations: (1) provisions of the Recreation and Public Purposes Act and to all applicable regulations of the Secretary of the Interior; (2) a right-of-way for ditches and canals constructed by the authority of the United States; (3) all minerals shall be reserved to the United States.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested parties may submit comments concerning the classification and/or the county's R&amp;PP application to the District Manager, c/o Area Manager, Folsom Resource Area, 63 Natoma Street, Folsom, CA 95630; comments must be received no later than 45 days from the date of publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional information concerning this action is available at the Folsom Resource Area Office. Contact Mike Kelly at (916) 985-4474 or at the address listed above.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>D.K. Swickard,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Area Manager.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1197 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-40-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
