<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00109</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00072</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Applications for Modification of Exemptions or Applications To Become a Party to an Exemption</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Research and Special Programs Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>List of applications for modification of exemptions or applications to become a party to an exemption.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the procedures governing the application for, and the processing of, exemptions from the Department of Transportation's Hazardous Materials Regulations (49 CFR part 107, subpart B), notice is hereby given that the Office of Hazardous Materials Safety has received the applications described herein. This notice is abbreviated to expedite docketing and public notice. Because the sections affected, modes of transportation, and the nature of application have been shown in earlier</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>publications, they are not repeated here. Requests for modifications of exemptions (e.g. to provide for additional hazardous materials, packaging design changes, additional mode of transportation, etc.) are described in footnotes to the application number. Application numbers with the suffix ``X'' denote a modification request. Application numbers with the suffix ``P'' denote a party to request. These applications have been separated from the new applications for exemptions to facilitate processing.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before February 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESS COMMENTS TO:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dockets Unit, Research and Special Programs Administration, U.S. Department of Transportation, Washington, DC 20590.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should refer to the application number and be submitted in triplicate. If confirmation of receipt of comments is desired, include a self-addressed stamped postcard showing the exemption number.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the applications are available for inspection in the Dockets Unit, room 8426, Nassif Building, 400 7th Street SW., Washington, DC.</textblock>
  </further>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Application No.</textblock>
    <textblock>1Applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>1Modification of exemption</textblock>
    <textblock>7887-X</textblock>
    <textblock>North Coast Rocketry, Inc., Salt Lake City, UT (see footnote 1)</textblock>
    <textblock>7887</textblock>
    <textblock>9157-X</textblock>
    <textblock>Matheson Gas Products, Secaucus, NJ (see footnote 2)</textblock>
    <textblock>9157</textblock>
    <textblock>10340-X</textblock>
    <textblock>Schutz Werk GmbH &amp; Co., Selters, West Germany (see footnote 3)</textblock>
    <textblock>10340</textblock>
    <textblock>11072-X</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Department of Defense, Falls Church, VA (see footnote 4)</textblock>
    <textblock>11072</textblock>
    <textblock>11147-X</textblock>
    <textblock>The Boeing Company, Seattle, WA (see footnote 5)</textblock>
    <textblock>11147</textblock>
    <textblock>11168-X</textblock>
    <textblock>Aldrich Chemical Company, Inc., Milwaukee, WI (see footnote 6)</textblock>
    <textblock>11168</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) To modify exemption to provide for potassium perchlorate, Division 5.1 as an additional commodity.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) To modify exemption to provide for cargo vessel as an additional mode of transportation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) To exempt IBCs containing residue of various classes of hazardous materials from the shipping paper requirements and provide for one-inch markings.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) To modify exemption to provide for on-deck stowage of shipborne steel barges containing Class 1 material.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) To reissue exemption originally issued on an emergency basis to authorize the shipment of aircraft safety equipment which utilize non-DOT specification cylinders containing a Division 2.2 material.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) To modify exemption to include cargo vessel as an additional mode of transportation.</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
