<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00006</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 6(c) of the Educational, Scientific and Cultural Materials Importation Act of 1966 (Pub. L. 89-651; 80 Stat. 897; 15 CFR 301), we invite comments on the question of whether instruments of equivalent scientific value, for the purposes for which the instruments shown below are intended to be used, are being manufactured in the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must comply with ยง301.5(a)(3) and (4) of the regulations and be filed within 20 days with the Statutory Import Programs Staff, U.S. Department of Commerce, Washington, DC. 20230. Applications may be examined between 8:30 a.m. and 5 p.m. in room 4211, U.S. Department of Commerce, 14th Street and Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>93-149.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>The George Washington University Medical Center, 2300 I Street, NW., Washington, DC 20037.</textblock>
    <textblock>Instrument:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mass Spectrometer, Model Delta S.</textblock>
    <textblock>Manufacturer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Finnigan MAT, Germany.</textblock>
    <textblock>Intended Use:</textblock>
    <textblock>The instrument will be used to investigate just how much the range of applications have been expanded by evaluating a wide variety of compound classes. It is proposed that intact biological macromolecules can be analyzed for isotopic content directly by the CRI-IRMS. This will greatly improve analyses in biological systems where either</textblock>
    <textblock>14</textblock>
    <textblock>C would have been a tracer or where the tedious sequence of hydrolysis followed by chromatographic separation and MS analysis of selected monomers would be required.</textblock>
    <textblock>Application Received by Commissioner of Customs:</textblock>
    <textblock>December 1, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>93-150.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, 4770 Buford Highway, NE., Mailstop F17, Atlanta, GA 30341-3724.</textblock>
    <textblock>Instrument:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mass Spectrometer, Model VG AutoSpec.</textblock>
    <textblock>Manufacturer:</textblock>
    <textblock>VG Analytical, United Kingdom.</textblock>
    <textblock>Intended Use:</textblock>
    <textblock>The instrument will be used for studies of extremely low levels of toxic organic compounds found in human serum to determine health effects associated with exposure to polychlorinated dibenzo dioxins/furnans, PCB's and polyaromatic hydrocarbons isolated from human serum.</textblock>
    <textblock>Application Received by Commissioner of Customs:</textblock>
    <textblock>December 9, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>93-151.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>Smithsonian Environmental Research Center, P.O. Box 28, 647 Contees Wharf Road, Edgewater, MD 21037.</textblock>
    <textblock>Instrument:</textblock>
    <textblock>Chlorophyll Fluorometer, Model PAM-101.</textblock>
    <textblock>Manufacturer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Heinz Walz, GmbH, Germany.</textblock>
    <textblock>Intended Use:</textblock>
    <textblock>The instrument will be used to study plant responses to light stress (visible and ultraviolet light), nutrient availability and changes in atmospheric carbon dioxide concentration. Measurements will be made using terrestrial plant communities at SERC, phytoplankton from the Rhode River and Chesapeake Bay, and greenhouse plants and algal cultures.</textblock>
    <textblock>Application Received by Commissioner of Customs:</textblock>
    <textblock>December 9, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>93-152.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>Texas A&amp;M University, Health and Kinesiology Department, College Station, TX 77843.</textblock>
    <textblock>Instrument:</textblock>
    <textblock>Muscle Research System, Model OPT1S.</textblock>
    <textblock>Manufacturer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Scientific Instruments, Germany.</textblock>
    <textblock>Intended Use:</textblock>
    <textblock>The instrument will be used in research to isolate mouse soleus and EDL muscle fibers and measure their force production upon exposure to varying concentrations of calcium.</textblock>
    <textblock>Application Received by Commissioner of Customs:</textblock>
    <textblock>December 9, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>93-153.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>University of California, Los Alamos National Laboratory, P.O. Box 990, Los Alamos, NM 87545.</textblock>
    <textblock>Instrument:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mass Spectrometer, Model PlasmaQuad.</textblock>
    <textblock>Manufacturer:</textblock>
    <textblock>VG Instruments, Inc., United Kingdom.</textblock>
    <textblock>Intended Use:</textblock>
    <textblock>The instrument will be used in an experiment to investigate the chemical and physical factors related to migration of the Actinides in Bentonite salt deposits. Samples will be injected into the mass spectrometer and the spectrometer will separate each element on the basis of mass-to-charge ratios. The final results will give concentrations of each element in the original sample.</textblock>
    <textblock>Application Received by Commissioner of Customs:</textblock>
    <textblock>December 15, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Applications for Duty-Free Entry of Scientific Instruments</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Frank W. Creel</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Statutory Import Programs Staff</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1264 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DS-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
