<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00002</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-0-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Revision of Delegations of Authority</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of the Secretary</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>7 CFR Part 2</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Agriculture.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document amends the delegations of authority to the Under Secretary for Small Community and Rural Development and the Administrator of the Rural Development Administration to administer the Rural Empowerment Zone and Enterprise Community Program authorized by Section 13301 of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993, Public Law 103-66, 26 U.S.C. 1391-1393. This action is being taken to select Empowerment Zones and Enterprise Communities and implement a cooperative program of assistance to communities and businesses within selected areas. The intended effect is to demonstrate the benefits of strategic planning and cooperative partnerships in promoting local self-sufficiency and economic enhancement.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Beverly C. Gillot, Rural Development Specialist, Rural Development Administration, United States Department of Agriculture, room 5405 South Agriculture Building, 14th Street and Independence Avenue, SW., AG Box 3202, Washington, DC 20250, telephone 202-690-2516.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 13301 of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993, Public Law 103-66, 26 U.S.C. 1391-1393, established the Rural Empowerment Zone and Enterprise Community Program. Under this program, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to designate up to 3 Empowerment Zones and up to 30 Enterprise Communities in rural areas. This document authorizes the Under Secretary for Small Community and Rural Development and the Administrator of the Rural Development Administration to carry out that program.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule relates to internal agency management. Therefore, pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 553, notice of proposed rule making and opportunity for comment are not required, and this rule is effective January 18, 1994. Further, since this rule relates to internal agency management, it is exempt from the provisions of Executive Order Nos. 12866 and 12778. This action is not a rule as defined by Public Law 96-354, the Regulatory Flexibility Act, and thus is exempt from the provisions of that Act. This rule also is exempt from the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act, as amended (42 U.S.C. Chapter 35).</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 7 CFR Part 2</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority delegations (Government agencies).</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, part 2, title 7, Code of Federal Regulations is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 2_DELEGATIONS OF AUTHORITY BY THE SECRETARY OF AGRICULTURE AND GENERAL OFFICERS OF THE DEPARTMENT</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 2 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>5 U.S.C. 301 and Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1953.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart C_Delegations of Authority to the Deputy Secretary, the Under Secretary for International Affairs and Commodity Programs, the Under Secretary for Small Community and Rural Development, and Assistant Secretaries</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 2.23 is amended by adding paragraph (b)(33) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§2.23</textblock>
    <textblock>Under Secretary for Small Community and Rural Development.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(32) Administer the Rural Empowerment Zone and Enterprise Community Program established by Section 13301 of Public Law 103-66 (26 U.S.C. 1391-1393).</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart I_Delegations of Authority by the Under Secretary for Small Community and Rural Development</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Section 2.71 is amended by adding paragraph (a)(34) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§2.71</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrator, Rural Development Administration.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(33) Administer the Rural Empowerment Zone and Enterprise Community Program established by Section 13301 of Public Law 103-66 (26 U.S.C. 1391-1393).</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>For Subpart C.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Mike Espy,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of Agriculture.</textblock>
    <textblock>For Subpart I.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Bob J. Nash,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Under Secretary for Small Community and Rural Development.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1123 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
