<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00030</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00019</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 12, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission's (Commission's) regulations, 18 CFR part 380 (Order No. 486, 52 FR 47897), the Office of Hydropower Licensing has reviewed the three applications for major license for the existing Rogers, Hardy, and Croton Hydroelectric Projects, located on the Muskegon River in Mecosta and Newaygo Counties, in southwest Michigan, and has prepared a final Multiple Project Environmental Assessment (MPEA) for the projects in cooperation with the U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Huron-Manistee National Forests.</textblock>
    <textblock>On September 8, 1993, a draft MPEA was issued and distributed to all parties, and comments were requested on the draft MPEA to be filed within 45 days. All comments that were filed have been considered in the final MPEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the final MPEA, the Commission and Forest Service staffs analyzed the site-specific and cumulative environmental effects of the existing projects, as proposed in a Settlement Agreement reached between Consumers Power Company and the state and Federal resource agencies. The Commission staff has concluded that approval of the applications for new license, with appropriate enhancement measures, would not constitute a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the final MPEA are available in the Public Reference Branch, room 3104, of the Commission's offices at 941 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Project Nos. 2451-004, 2452-007, and 2468-003 Michigan]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Consumers Power Co.; Availability of Final Multiple Project Environmental Assessment</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1178 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
