<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00072</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00052</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Coastal Barrier Improvement Act; Property Availability</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Resolution Trust Corporation.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the property known as Highland Acres, located in Passaic County, New Jersey is affected by Section 10 of the Coastal Barrier Improvement Act of 1990 as specified below.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES</textblock>
    <textblock>: Written notices of serious interest to purchase or effect other transfer of all or any portion of the property may be mailed or faxed to the RTC until April 19, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>: Copies of detailed descriptions of the property, including maps, can be obtained from or are available for inspection by contacting the following person:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Greg Zahm, Resolution Trust Corporation, Valley Forge Field Office, Post Office Box 1500, Valley Forge, PA 19482-1500, (215) 631-3505; FAX (215) 631-3703.</textblock>
  </address>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Highland Acres property is located at 1735 Union Valley Road, West Milford, New Jersey. The property is undeveloped and consists of approximately 211.2 acres of woodland and farmland. The site is bisected by Union Valley Road. The Highland Acres property is bounded on the southeast by Belcher Creek and the site contains wetlands, undeveloped floodplains, and is located within the boundary of a sole source aquifer. The property adjoins land managed by the City of Newark for watershed conservation purposes and Camp Hope, a Passaic County managed facility on the northeast. The property is covered property within the meaning of Section 10 of the Coastal Barrier Improvement Act of 1990, Public Law 101-591 (12 U.S.C. 1441a-3).</textblock>
    <textblock>Written notice of serious interest in the purchase or other transfer of all or any portion of the property must be received on or before April 19, 1994 by the Resolution Trust Corporation at the address stated above.</textblock>
    <textblock>Those entities eligible to submit written notices of serious interest are:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Agencies or entities of the Federal government;</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Agencies or entities of State or local government; and</textblock>
    <textblock>3. ``Qualified organizations'' pursuant to section 170(h)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (26 U.S.C. 170(h)(3)).</textblock>
    <textblock>Written notices of serious interest must be submitted in the following form:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Serious Interest</textblock>
    <textblock>RE: [insert name of property]</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register Publication Date:</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>[insert Federal Register publication date]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Entity name.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Declaration of eligibility to submit Notice under criteria set forth in Coastal Barrier Improvement Act of 1990, Public Law 101-591, section 10(b)(2), (12 U.S.C. 1441a-3(b)(2)), including, for qualified organizations, a determination letter from the Internal Revenue Service regarding the organization's status under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code (26 U.S.C. 170(h)(3)).</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Brief description of proposed terms of purchase or other offer for all or any portion of the property (e.g., price and method of financing).</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Declaration of entity that it intends to use the property for wildlife refuge, sanctuary, open space, recreational, historical, cultural, or natural resource conservation purposes as provided in a clear written description of the purpose(s) to which the property will be put and the location and acreage of the area covered by each purpose(s) including a declaration of entity that it will accept the placement, by the RTC, of an easement or deed restriction on the property consistent with its intended conservation use(s) as stated in its notice of serious interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Authorized Representative (Name/Address/Telephone/Fax).</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects: Environmental protection.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 12, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Resolution Trust Corporation.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William J. Tricarico,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1202 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6714-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
