<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00042</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00026</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Section 131 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended (42 U.S.C. 2160), notice is hereby given of a proposed ``subsequent arrangement'', under the Additional Agreement for Cooperation between the Government of the United States of America and the European Atomic Energy Community (EURATOM) concerning Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy, as amended, and the Agreement for Cooperation between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of Japan concerning Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy.</textblock>
    <textblock>The subsequent arrangement to be carried out under the above-mentioned agreements involves approval for the following retransfer: RTD/JA(EU)-72, for the transfer of 4.5 grams of uranium containing 4.2 grams of the isotope uranium-235 (93.33 percent enrichment) from Belgium to Japan for measurement of the fission rate in the fast critical assembly at the Japan Atomic Energy Research Institute.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with Section 131 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended, it has been determined that this subsequent arrangement will not be inimical to the common defense and security.</textblock>
    <textblock>This subsequent arrangement will take effect no sooner than fifteen days after the date of publication of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC on January 13, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of Arms Control and Nonproliferation</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Proposed Subsequent Arrangement</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Salvador N. Ceja,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Office of Nonproliferation Policy, Office of Arms Control and Nonproliferation.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1251 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
