<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00016</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Defense Contract Audit Agency</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Privacy Act of 1974; Notice to Amend Systems of Records</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Defense Contract Audit Agency, DoD.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice to amend systems of records.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Defense Contract Audit Agency proposes to amend five existing systems of records to its inventory of systems subject to the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a), as amended.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed actions will be effective on January 19, 1994, unless comments are received that would result in a contrary determination.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send comments to the Defense Contract Audit Agency, Information Resources Management Branch, CMR, 25 South Quaker Lane, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Dave Henshall at (703) 274-4400 or DSN 284-4400.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Defense Contract Audit Agency systems of records notices subject to the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a), as amended, have been published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>and are available from the above address.</textblock>
    <textblock>The amendments are not within the purview of subsection (r) of the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a), as amended, which requires the submission of altered systems reports. The specific changes to the systems of records notices are set forth below followed by the systems notices, as amended, published in their entirety.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 13, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Patricia L. Toppings,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Alternate OSD Federal Register Liaison Officer, Department of Defense.</textblock>
    <textblock>RDCAA 152.2</textblock>
    <textblock>System name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Personnel Security Data Files</textblock>
    <textblock>(February 22, 1993, 58 FR 10841).</textblock>
    <textblock>CHANGES:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of individuals covered by the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Delete from entry `all military personnel assigned, detailed, or attached to DCAA' and `who require access to classified information.'</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of records in the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Second paragraph, replace `military service, or' with `eligibility for assignment to sensitive duties, and.'</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Retention and disposal:</textblock>
    <textblock>Delete from entry `military personnel' and `transfer of military personnel from DCAA.'</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>RDCAA 152.2</textblock>
    <textblock>System name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Personnel Security Data Files.</textblock>
    <textblock>System location:</textblock>
    <textblock>Primary System: Security Officer, Headquarters, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>Decentralized Segment: Director of Personnel, Defense Contract Audit Agency; Chiefs of Personnel Divisions and Regional Security Officers at DCAA Regional Offices. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of individuals covered by the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>All applicants for employment with Defense Contract Audit Agency (DCAA); all DCAA employees; all persons hired on a contractual basis by, or serving in an advisory capacity to DCAA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of records in the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section One contains copies of individual's employment applications, security investigative questionnaires, requests for, and approval or disapproval of, emergency appointment authority; requests for investigation or security clearance; interim and final security clearance certificates.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section Two contains verification of investigations conducted to determine suitability, eligibility or qualifications for Federal civilian employment, eligibility for assignment to sensitive duties, and access to classified information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section Three contains summaries of reports of investigation, internal Agency memorandums and correspondence furnishing analysis of results of investigations in so far as their relationship to the criteria set forth in the E.O. 10450, in the Federal Personnel Manual and in Department of Defense and DCAA Directives and Regulations; comments and recommendations of the DCAA Central Clearance Group to the Director, DCAA, and determination by the Director, DCAA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority for maintenance of the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>10 U.S.C. 133; 50 U.S.C. 781; E.O. 10450, 10865, and E.O. 12356, National Security Information; and DoD Directive 5105.36 (32 CFR part 357).</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>To provide a basis for requesting appropriate investigations; to permit determinations on employment or retention; to authorize and record access to classified information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Routine uses of records maintained in the system, including categories of users and the purposes of such uses:</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>The `Blanket Routine Uses' that appear at the beginning of DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices apply to this system.</textblock>
    <textblock>Policies and practices for storing, retrieving, accessing, retaining, and disposing of records in the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Storage:</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections One and Three are on paper records stored in file folders. Section Two is on paper records and microfiche which are stored in file folders.</textblock>
    <textblock>Retrievability:</textblock>
    <textblock>Folders are filed by file series then by organizational element (DCAA Headquarters or DCAA field activities) and then alphabetically by last name of individual concerned.</textblock>
    <textblock>Safeguards:</textblock>
    <textblock>Records are stored in locked filing cabinets after normal business hours. Records are accessible only to authorized personnel who are properly cleared and trained and who require access in connection with their official duties.</textblock>
    <textblock>Retention and disposal:</textblock>
    <textblock>Records pertaining to Federal employees and persons furnishing services to DCAA on a contract basis are destroyed upon separation of employees, and upon termination of the contracts for contractor personnel. Records pertaining to applicants are destroyed if an appointment to DCAA is not made.</textblock>
    <textblock>System manager(s) and address:</textblock>
    <textblock>Security Officer, Headquarters, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notification procedure:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this record system should address written inquiries to the Records Administrator, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178. Telephone (703) 274-4400.</textblock>
    <textblock>Record access procedures:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals seeking access to records about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to the Records Administrator, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number and current business address.</textblock>
    <textblock>For personal visits, the individual should be able to provide some acceptable results of investigations received from Federal agencies and recommendations for action from appropriate DCAA Headquarters staff elements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Acceptable identification, that is, driver's license or employing offices' identification card. Visits are limited to those offices (Headquarters and 6 regional offices) listed in the official mailing addresses published as an appendix to DCAA's compilation of record system notices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contesting record procedures:</textblock>
    <textblock>DCAA's rules for accessing records, for contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in DCAA Instruction 5410.10; 32 CFR part 317; or may be obtained from the system manager.</textblock>
    <textblock>Record source categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>Security Officer and the Director of Personnel at Headquarters, DCAA; Chiefs of Personnel Divisions, Regional Security Officers, Chiefs of Field Audit Offices at the DCAA Regional Offices and the individual concerned.</textblock>
    <textblock>Exemptions claimed for the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>None.</textblock>
    <textblock>RDCAA 152.6</textblock>
    <textblock>System name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Regional and DCAI Security Clearance Request Files (February 22, 1993, 58 FR 10842).</textblock>
    <textblock>CHANGES:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of individuals covered by the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Delete from entry `all military personnel assigned, detailed, or attached to DCAA' and `who require access to classified information.'</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>Insert `requests for security investigations,' between `positions' and `for security clearance.' Delete `and' before `for security clearance.'</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Record source categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>Delete `Chiefs of DCAA Field Audit Offices, and.'</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>RDCAA 152.6</textblock>
    <textblock>System name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Regional and DCAI Security Clearance Request Files.</textblock>
    <textblock>System location:</textblock>
    <textblock>Primary System: Security Officers of Defense Contract Audit Agency Regional Offices and Security Control Officers, Defense Contract Audit Institute. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Decentralized Segment: Security Officer, Headquarters, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of individuals covered by the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>All applicants for employment with Defense Contract Audit Agency (DCAA); all DCAA employees; all persons hired on a contractual basis by, or serving in an advisory capacity to DCAA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of records in the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Files contain personnel security data forms submitted by employees and applicants required in the processing of security investigations; requests for various types of security clearance actions; and requests for and approvals/disapprovals of appointments to sensitive positions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority for maintenance of the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>10 U.S.C. 133; 50 U.S.C. 781; E.O. 10450, 10865, and 12356; and DoD Directive 5105.36 which is published in 32 CFR part 357.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>To prepare necessary paperwork and documentation upon which to base requests to Headquarters, DCAA for appointments to sensitive positions, requests for security investigations, for security clearance and to retain support documents pending approval of appointment and/or granting clearance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Routine uses of records maintained in the system, including categories of users and the purposes of such uses:</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>The `Blanket Routine Uses' that appear at the beginning of the DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices apply to this system.</textblock>
    <textblock>Policies and practices for storing, retrieving, accessing, retaining, and disposing of records in the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Storage:</textblock>
    <textblock>Paper records in file folders.</textblock>
    <textblock>Retrievability:</textblock>
    <textblock>Filed alphabetically by last name of individual concerned.</textblock>
    <textblock>Safeguards:</textblock>
    <textblock>Records are accessible only to those authorized personnel required to prepare, review, process, and type necessary documents. Records are stored in locked filing cabinets after normal business hours and are stored in locked rooms and buildings after normal business hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Retention and disposal:</textblock>
    <textblock>These are transitory files at DCAA Regional Offices and DCAI level and are maintained only during processing and pending final action on requests. Upon receipt of final action taken on request, files are destroyed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Segments of the system held by the Security Officer, DCAA are destroyed upon separation of the employee or after non-appointment of an applicant.</textblock>
    <textblock>System manager(s) and address:</textblock>
    <textblock>Security Officer, Headquarters, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regional Security Officers, DCAA and Security Control Officers, Defense Contract Audit Institute. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notification procedure:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written inquiries to the Records Administrator, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178. Telephone (703) 274-4400.</textblock>
    <textblock>Record access procedures:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to the Records Administrator, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>The request should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number, and current business address. Personal visits may be made but are limited to those offices (Headquarters and 6 Regional Offices) listed in DCAA's official mailing addresses published as an appendix to DCAA's compilation of record system notices. In personal visits, the individual should be able to provide acceptable identification, that is, driver's license or employing offices' identification card.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contesting record procedures:</textblock>
    <textblock>DCAA's rules for accessing records, for contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in DCAA Instruction 5410.10; 32 CFR part 317; or may be obtained from the system manager.</textblock>
    <textblock>Record source categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>Chiefs of Personnel Divisions and Regional Security Officers at the DCAA Regional Offices; the Manager, Defense Contract Audit Institute and the individual concerned.</textblock>
    <textblock>Exemptions claimed for the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>None.</textblock>
    <textblock>RDCAA 152.7</textblock>
    <textblock>System name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Clearance Certification (February 22, 1993, 58 FR 10843).</textblock>
    <textblock>CHANGES:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of individuals covered by the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Delete from entry `who require access to classified information' and replace `employed by the agency.'</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of records in the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Insert `and eligibility' between `clearance' and `certificates attesting to.'</textblock>
    <textblock>Insert `supervisor suitability/security statements' between `acknowledgment certificates' and `and special access.'</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>Insert `and eligibility' between `clearance' and `status.'</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Retention and disposal:</textblock>
    <textblock>Delete `military personnel' and `or military personnel.'</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>RDCAA 152.7</textblock>
    <textblock>System name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Clearance Certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>System location:</textblock>
    <textblock>Primary System: Regional Security Officers at Defense Contract Audit Agency (DCAA) Regional Offices; Security Control Officers at DCAA Field Audit Offices; Field Detachment and Defense Contract Audit Institute (DCAI). Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Decentralized Segments: Security Officer and Director of Personnel at Headquarters, DCAA and Chiefs of Personnel Divisions at DCAA Regional Offices. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of individuals covered by the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>All DCAA personnel employed by the Agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of records in the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Files contain interim and final security clearance and eligibility certificates attesting to type of investigation conducted and degree of access to classified information which is authorized copies, of security acknowledgement certificates supervisor suitability/security statements and special access briefing statements executed by individuals upon being granted security clearances or access to special access information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority for maintenance of the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>10 U.S.C. 133; 50 U.S.C. 781; E.O. 10450, 10865, and E.O. 12365, National Security Information; and DoD Directive 5105.36 which is published in 32 CFR part 357.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>To maintain a record of the security clearance and eligibility status of all DCAA personnel as well as certification of briefings for access to classified information and special access information.</textblock>
    <textblock>To DoD contractors to furnish notice of security clearance and access authorization of DCAA employees.</textblock>
    <textblock>Routine uses of records maintained in the system, including categories of users and the purposes of such uses:</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>The `Blanket Routine Uses' that appear at the beginning of the DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices apply to this system.</textblock>
    <textblock>Policies and practices for storing, retrieving, accessing, retaining, and disposing of records in the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Storage:</textblock>
    <textblock>Paper records in file folders.</textblock>
    <textblock>Retrievability:</textblock>
    <textblock>Retrieved by last name of individual concerned.</textblock>
    <textblock>Safeguards:</textblock>
    <textblock>Records are stored in locked filing cabinets after normal business hours and stored in locked rooms or buildings. Records are accessible only to those authorized personnel required to act upon a request for access to classified defense information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Retention and disposal:</textblock>
    <textblock>Files pertaining to Federal employees and persons furnishing services to DCAA on a contract basis are destroyed upon separation or transfer of employees and upon termination of contractor personnel.</textblock>
    <textblock>Files of individuals transferring within DCAA are transferred to security control office of gaining element for maintenance.</textblock>
    <textblock>System manager(s) and address:</textblock>
    <textblock>Security Officer, Headquarters, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178 and Regional Security Officers in DCAA Regional Offices. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notification procedure:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this record system should address written inquiries to the Records Administrator, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>Record access procedures:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals seeking access to records about themselves contained in this record system should address written inquiries to the Records Administrator, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>The request should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number, and current business address. Personal visits may be made but are limited to those offices (Headquarters and 6 Regional Offices) listed in DCAA's official mailing addresses published as an appendix to DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices. In personal visits, the individual should be able to provide acceptable identification, that is, driver's license or employing offices' identification card.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contesting record procedures:</textblock>
    <textblock>DCAA's rules for accessing records, for contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in DCAA Instruction 5410.10; 32 CFR part 317; or may be obtained from the system manager.</textblock>
    <textblock>Record source categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>Chiefs of Personnel Divisions and Regional Security Officers at the DCAA Regional Offices; Chiefs of DCAA field audit offices; the Manager, Defense Contract Audit Institute and the individual.</textblock>
    <textblock>Exemptions claimed for the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>None.</textblock>
    <textblock>RDCAA 152.17</textblock>
    <textblock>System name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Security Status Master List (February 22, 1993, 58 FR 10844).</textblock>
    <textblock>CHANGES:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of individuals covered by the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Delete the entry and replace with `All employees of DCAA; all persons hired on a contractual basis by or serving in an advisory capacity to DCAA.'</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Record access procedures:</textblock>
    <textblock>Third paragraph, delete first sentence and replace with `Personal visits are limited to the Headquarters listed in the appendix to DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices.'</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Record source categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>Delete `Chiefs of DCAA Field Audit Offices.'</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>RDCAA 152.17</textblock>
    <textblock>System name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Security Status Master List.</textblock>
    <textblock>System location:</textblock>
    <textblock>Security Office, Headquarters, Defense Contact Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of individuals covered by the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>All employees of DCAA; all persons hired on a contractual basis by or serving in an advisory capacity to DCAA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of records in the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Record contains type of investigation, date completed, file number, agency which conducted investigation, security clearance data information, name, Social Security Number, date and place of birth, organizational assignment, dates interim and final clearance issued, position sensitivity and related data.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority for maintenance of the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>10 U.S.C. 133; 50 U.S.C. 781; E.O. 10450, 10865, and E.O. 12356, National Security Information; and DoD Directive 5105.36 which is published in 32 CFR part 357.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>To maintain a ready reference of security clearances on DCAA personnel, to include investigative data and position sensitivity.</textblock>
    <textblock>To provide security clearance data to DoD contractors and other Federal agencies on DCAA employees assigned to or visiting a contractor facility or visiting or applying for employment with another Federal agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>Routine uses of records maintained in the system, including categories of users and the purposes of such uses:</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>The `Blanket Routine Uses' that appear at the beginning of DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices apply to this system.</textblock>
    <textblock>Policies and practices for storing, retrieving, accessing, retaining, and disposing of records in the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Storage:</textblock>
    <textblock>Stored in a card file.</textblock>
    <textblock>Retrievability:</textblock>
    <textblock>Cards are filed alphabetically by last name of individual concerned for all DCAA regional personnel. Separate file maintained alphabetically by last name of individual concerned for DCAA Headquarters elements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Safeguards:</textblock>
    <textblock>Cards are accessible only to those authorized personnel required to prepare, process, and type necessary documents; and answer authorized inquiries for information contained therein. Cards are stored in locked filing cabinets after normal business hours and are stored in a locked room and building which is protected by a guard force system after normal business hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Retention and disposal:</textblock>
    <textblock>These cards are destroyed two years after an individual is separated from DCAA.</textblock>
    <textblock>System manager(s) and address:</textblock>
    <textblock>Security Officer, Headquarters, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notification procedure:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written inquiries to the Records Administrator, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>Record access procedures:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to the Records Administrator, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written requests for information should contain the full name of the individual, current address and telephone number, and current business address.</textblock>
    <textblock>Personal visits are limited to the Headquarters listed in the appendix to DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices. For personal visits, the individual should be able to provide some acceptable identification, that is driver's license or employing office's identification card.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contesting record procedures:</textblock>
    <textblock>DCAA's rules for accessing records, for contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in DCAA Instruction 5410.10; 32 CFR part 317; or may be obtained from the system manager.</textblock>
    <textblock>Record source categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>Security Officer, Headquarters, DCAA; Director of Personnel, Headquarters, DCAA; Chiefs of Personnel Divisions, DCAA regional offices; Regional Security Officers, DCAA Regional Offices; Manager, DCAI; the individual concerned; and reports of investigation conducted by Federal investigative agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Exemptions claimed for the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>None.</textblock>
    <textblock>RDCAA 590.8</textblock>
    <textblock>System name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Field Audit Office Management Information System (FMIS) (February 22, 1993, FR 58 10852).</textblock>
    <textblock>CHANGES:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>System name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Delete entry and replace with `DCAA Management Information System (FMIS/AMIS)'.</textblock>
    <textblock>System location:</textblock>
    <textblock>Delete entry and replace with `Primary system: Field Audit Office Management Information System (FMIS) is located at all DCAA Headquarters, regional and field audit offices. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Secondary system: Agency Management Information System (AMIS) is located at the Naval Computer and Telecommunications Station, Washington, (Code N23), Washington Navy Yard, Washington, DC 20374-1435.'</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>Delete entry and replace with `To provide managers and supervisors with timely, on-line information regarding audit requirements, programs, and performance.'</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>RDCAA 590.8</textblock>
    <textblock>System name:</textblock>
    <textblock>DCAA Management Information System (FMIS/AMIS).</textblock>
    <textblock>System location:</textblock>
    <textblock>Primary system: Field Audit Office Management Information System (FMIS) is located at all DCAA Headquarters, regional and field audit offices. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Secondary system: Agency Management Information System (AMIS) is located at the Naval Computer and Telecommunications Station, Washington, (Code N23), Washington Navy Yard, Washington, DC 20374-1435.</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of individuals covered by the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>DCAA employees and contractors.</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of records in the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Records relating to audit work performed in terms of hours expended by individual employees, dollar amounts audited, exceptions reported, and net savings to the government as a result of those exceptions; records containing contractor and contract information; records containing reimbursable billing information; name, Social Security Number, pay grade and (optionally) address information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority for maintenance of the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>5 U.S.C. 301 and E.O. 9397.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>To provide managers and supervisors with timely, on-line information regarding audit requirements, programs, and performance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Routine uses of records maintained in the system, including categories of users and the purposes of such uses:</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to those disclosures generally permitted under 5 U.S.C. 552a(b) of the Privacy Act, these records or information contained therein may specifically be disclosed outside the DoD as a routine use pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552a(b)(3) as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>The `Blanket Routine Uses' that appear at the beginning of DCAA's compilation of systems of records notices apply to this system.</textblock>
    <textblock>Policies and practices for storing, retrieving, accessing, retaining, and disposing of records in the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Storage:</textblock>
    <textblock>Records are maintained in automated data systems.</textblock>
    <textblock>Retrievability:</textblock>
    <textblock>Records are retrieved by organizational levels, name of employee, Social Security Number, office symbol, audit activity codes, or any other combination of these identifiers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Safeguards:</textblock>
    <textblock>Automated records are protected by restricted access procedures. Access to records is strictly limited to authorized officials with a bona fide need for the records.</textblock>
    <textblock>Retention and disposal:</textblock>
    <textblock>Records are retained for two to five years and then destroyed by erasure.</textblock>
    <textblock>System manager(s) and address:</textblock>
    <textblock>Chief, Network Operations Branch, Technical Services Center, Headquarters, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notification procedure:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals seeking to determine whether information about themselves is contained in this system should address written inquiries to the Chief, Network Operations Branch, Technical Services Center, Headquarters, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178.</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals must furnish name, Social Security Number, approximate date of record, and geographic area in which consideration was requested for record to be located and identified. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to the DCAA's compilation of systems notices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Record access procedures:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals seeking access to information about themselves contained in this system should address written inquiries to the Chief, Network Operations Branch, Technical Services Center, Headquarters, Defense Contract Audit Agency, Cameron Station, Alexandria, VA 22304-6178. Official mailing addresses are published as an appendix to the DCAA's compilation of systems notices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals must furnish name, Social Security Number, approximate date of record, and geographic area in which consideration was requested for record to be located and identified.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contesting record procedures:</textblock>
    <textblock>DCAA's rules for accessing records, for contesting contents and appealing initial agency determinations are published in DCAA Instruction 5410.10; 32 CFR part 317; or may be obtained from the system manager.</textblock>
    <textblock>Record source categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individual employees, supervisors, audit reports and working papers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Exemptions claimed for the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>None.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1221 Filed 01-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 5000-04-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
