<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00062</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940119-2-00043</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>INSTITUTE OF AMERICAN INDIAN AND ALASKA NATIVE CULTURE AND ARTS DEVELOPMENT</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Request for Nominations to the Board of Trustees</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development (aka Institute of American Indian Arts).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Request for nominations.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board direct the Administration of the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development, including soliciting, accepting, and disposing of gifts, bequests, and other properties for the benefit of the Institute. The Institute, established under Public Law 99-498 (20 U.S.C. 4411</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>), provides scholarly study of and instruction in Indian art and culture, and establishes programs which culminate in the awarding of degrees in the various fields of Indian art and culture.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board consists of thirteen members appointed by the President of the United States, by and with the consent of the U.S. Senate, who are American Indians or persons knowledgeable in the field of Indian art and culture. This notice requests nominations to fill five appointments on the Board of Trustees.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nominations will be accepted until February 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nominations may be sent to the Chairman, Board of Trustees, Institute of American Indian Arts, Post Office Box 1836, Santa Fe, New Mexico 87504.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ken Blankenship, Chairman of the Board of Trustees, Institute of American Indian Arts, Post Office Box 20006, Santa Fe, New Mexico 87504; 505-988-6278.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Law 99-498 (20 U.S.C. 4412(a)(2)(b), requires the President to publish in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>an announcement regarding nominations of the Presidentially appointed members of the Board of Trustees of the Institute. On February 22, 1991 (56 FR 8099, February 26, 1991), the President delegated to the Chairman of the Board of Trustees the responsibility to publish an announcement regarding these nominations in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. All nominations submitted will be forwarded to the President for consideration.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 30, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Ken Blankenship,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, Board of Trustees, Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1217 Filed 1-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 0000-00-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
