<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00107</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00067</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee Meeting on Aircraft Certification Procedures Issues</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA is issuing this notice to advise the public of a meeting of the Federal Aviation Administration's Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee to discuss aircraft certification procedures issues.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held on January 28, 1994, at 9 a.m. Arrange for oral presentations by January 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held at the General Aviation Manufactures Association, suite 801, 1400 K Street NW., Washington DC 20005.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Kathy Ball, aircraft Certification Service (AIR-1), 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591, telephone (202) 267-8235.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463; 5 U.S.C. App. II), notice is given of a meeting of the Aviation Rulemaking advisory committee to be held on January 28, 1994, at the General Aviation Manufactures Association, suite 801, 1400 K Street NW, Washington, DC 20005. The agenda for the meeting will include:</textblock>
    <textblock>•Opening Remarks</textblock>
    <textblock>•Review of Action Items</textblock>
    <textblock>•Working Group Reports</textblock>
    <textblock>␣ICPTF</textblock>
    <textblock>␣ELT</textblock>
    <textblock>␣Delegation System</textblock>
    <textblock>␣Parts</textblock>
    <textblock>␣Production Certification</textblock>
    <textblock>•New Business</textblock>
    <textblock>Attendance is open to the interested public, but will be limited to the space available. The public must make arrangements by January 18, 1994, to present oral statements at the meeting. The public may present written statements to the committee at any time by providing 25 copies to the Assistant Executive Director for Aircraft Certification Procedures or by bringing the copies to him at the meeting. Arrangements may be made by contacting the person listed under the heading ``</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT</textblock>
    <textblock>.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Sign and oral interpretation can be made available at the meeting, as well as an assistive listening device, if requested 10 calendar days before the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William J. Sullivan,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Executive Director for Aircraft Certification Procedures, Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-632 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
