<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00086</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00019</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>5. Fees for Basic (Non-declinable) vs. Other Services</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 453.4(b) of the Rule imposes the general legal requirement that consumers' selection of funeral goods and services be permitted on an itemized basis. However, §453.4(b)(2)(i)(A) permits an exception to that general right to select. Under that provision, consumers may not decline the basic services of the funeral provider if the provider so requires. The provision in that event further requires that providers place on the GPL the following statement: ``However, any funeral arrangements you select will include a charge for our services.'' Providers under §453.2(b)(4)(iii)(C) must also place the following disclosure on the GPL in conjunction with the price for the services of funeral director and staff, if the fee cannot be declined: ``This fee for our services will be added to the total cost of the funeral arrangements you select. (This fee is already included in our charge for direct cremations, immediate burials, and forwarding or receiving remains.)''</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission, in promulgating that exception, reasoned that the process of selection itself involves use of the provider's services, irrespective of the actual goods and services chosen by consumers. The Commission thus permitted providers to make the services of the funeral provider non-declinable.</textblock>
    <textblock>157</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission also intended that the non-declinable fee for professional services would include only the charge for providers' basic services in arranging and planning the funeral, and not charges for services associated with providing any of the other sixteen items for which itemization is required on the GPL.</textblock>
    <textblock>158</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission, for example, specifically used the term ``basic services'' in referring to those services that consumers could not decline under §453.2(b)(4)(iii)(C) (the GPL service fee disclosure requirement).</textblock>
    <textblock>159</textblock>
    <textblock>The definition in the original Rule itself stated that the services of funeral director and staff ``are the services, not included in prices of other categories in §453.2(b)(4) which may be furnished by a funeral provider in arranging and supervising a funeral, such as conducting the arrangements conference, planning the funeral, obtaining necessary permits and placing obituary notices.''</textblock>
    <textblock>160</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission, however, did not codify in the Rule its intent regarding basic services other than in the definition. No substantive Rule provision thus clarifies that providers in disclosing itemized fees on the GPL must separate ``basic,'' non-declinable services from services associated with providing the other, declinable GPL goods and services, including such items as ``use of facilities for viewing,'' and ``use of facilities for funeral ceremony.'' The original staff compliance guidelines for the Rule, as a result, contained lengthy interpretations of the Rule on that issue, concluding that the non-declinable fee for ``services of funeral director and staff'' may not include a charge for those services involved in providing any of the other items required to be separately listed on the GPL. Charges for those services, the Guidelines stated, must be included in the price for each of those items. The Guidelines further concluded that the non-declinable fee for services may include the services listed in the Rule's definition of ``services of funeral director and staff.''</textblock>
    <textblock>161</textblock>
    <textblock>The only fee permitted by the Rule to be non-declinable at the outset of the funeral transaction is the charge for ``services of funeral director and staff'' and items that are required by law.</textblock>
    <textblock>162</textblock>
    <textblock>Several public hearing witnesses expressed their view, however, that the original disclosure requirement for the non-declinable services fee permitted the inclusion of service items that all consumers do not receive with their arrangements, so that consumers may be paying for services not received,</textblock>
    <textblock>163</textblock>
    <textblock>or that the services fee should be broken down to separate fees for arranging all funerals and fees for optional services.</textblock>
    <textblock>164</textblock>
    <textblock>These and other witnesses further suggested that consumers are unaware of that potential overpayment problem.</textblock>
    <textblock>165</textblock>
    <textblock>Still other witnesses identified another problem with the original services fee disclosure. Those participants testified that, although consumers who ``shop'' among providers rely on quotes for service fees as a basis for comparison, providers in fact appear to include different items in their service fee charges. Price comparison among funeral homes is difficult as a result.</textblock>
    <textblock>166</textblock>
    <textblock>The record contains no evidence or views specifically controverting this.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See R-B-5 at 42282.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>157</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Under §453.2(b)(4)(iii)(C), the non-declinable professional services fee also may include charges for unallocated provider overhead.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>158</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Id; see also, R-B-5 at 42285.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>159</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Section 453.1(o).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>160</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>R-B-6 at 28068-28069, 28076, and 28087.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>161</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Id. at 28077 (Illus.</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>12). Cemetery or crematory requirements, embalming as a ``practical necessity,'' and requests that are ``impossible, impractical or excessively burdensome'' to provide may result in ``non-declinable'' charges under certain conditions. Generally, however, those items are not considered ``non-declinable'' in the sense that consumers, at the outset of planning arrangements, have no choice but to purchase them.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>162</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Morrison, Tr. Vol. II, 771, 778; Karklin, consumer, Tr. Vol. I, 553; Carlson, Tr. Vol. I, 501-502; Snyder, Tr. Vol. III, 1252; Perguson, Tr. Vol. III, 1180; and Showalter, journalist/hospice counselor, Tr. Vol. II, 121, 148.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>163</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Klein, New York State Funeral Directing Advisory Board, Tr. Vol. II, 1040, 1062; Morrison, industry observer, Tr. Vol. II, 771, 778; Carlson, author, Tr. Vol. I, 500-502; Snyder, West Coast Director, Consumers Union, Tr. Vol. III, 1252-1253; Perguson, Seattle memorial society, Tr. Vol. III, 1219; and Blake, Wisconsin memorial society, Tr. Vol. II, 1121.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>164</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See, e.g., Bennett, Tr. Vol. I, 355; Carlson, Tr. Vol. I, 500-501; and Snyder, Tr. Vol. III, 1252.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>165</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Simms, funeral director, Tr. Vol. II, 495 (consumers rely on professional service price); Johnson, funeral director, Tr. Vol. I, 755-756; Botimer, funeral director, Tr. Vol. III, 1287; Starks, funeral director, Tr. Vol. II, 423-424); and Perguson, Seattle memorial society, Tr. Vol. III, 1177, 1180, 1219 (1987 Seattle survey for publication showed ``services'' vaguely and variously described).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>166</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
