<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00007</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The interim final rule also removed paragraph (c) of ยง906.365. That paragraph set forth quality requirements for oranges and grapefruit which were in effect through February 15, 1992. Thus, the provisions in that paragraph were obsolete.</textblock>
    <textblock>Texas grapefruit shipments to fresh markets in the United States, Canada, and Mexico are subject to handling requirements effective under this order. Exempt from such handling requirements are shipments made: (1) Within the production area in Texas; (2) in individually addressed gift packages aggregating not more than 500 pounds which are not for resale; (3) under the 400 pound minimum quantity exemption provision; and (4) for relief, charity, and home use. In addition, fruit shipped to approved processors located outside of the production area may be exempted from the handling requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>This final rule reflects the committee's and the Department's appraisal of the need to finalize the relaxed requirements set forth in the interim final rule. The Department believes that this action will have a beneficial impact on producers and handlers because it will permit 1993-94 season grapefruit shipments consistent with anticipated crop and market conditions. The application of handling requirements to Texas grapefruit over the years has been beneficial to the Texas citrus industry in marketing its crops.</textblock>
    <textblock>Based on the above, the Administrator of the AMS has determined that this action will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>After consideration of all relevant matter presented, the information and recommendations submitted by the committee, and other information, it is found that the relaxation set forth below will tend to effectuate the declared policy of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 7 CFR Part 906</textblock>
    <textblock>Grapefruit, Marketing agreements, Oranges, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set forth in the preamble, 7 CFR Part 906 is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 906_ORANGES AND GRAPEFRUIT GROWN IN LOWER RIO GRANDE VALLEY IN TEXAS</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for 7 CFR part 906 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>7 U.S.C. 601-674.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Accordingly, the interim final rule amending the provisions of ยง906.365, which was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>at 58 FR 54925, October 25, 1993, is adopted as a final rule without change.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Robert C. Keeney,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Director, Fruit and Vegetable Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-606 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
