<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00002</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Definition of ``Indian Tribal Household''</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Food and Nutrition Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>7 CFR Parts 253 and 254</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN Number 0584-AB67</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Food and Nutrition Service, USDA.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interim rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This interim rule broadens the current regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of ``Indian tribal household'' in the Food Distribution</textblock>
    <textblock>Program on Indian Reservations (FDPIR) and the</textblock>
    <textblock>Food Distribution Program for Indian Households in Oklahoma</textblock>
    <textblock>(FDPIHO). First, this change mandates that all</textblock>
    <textblock>households which pass the program means test, reside in</textblock>
    <textblock>designated areas near a reservation where an Indian Tribal</textblock>
    <textblock>Organization (ITO) or State agency provides program services, and</textblock>
    <textblock>include a Native American be eligible to participate in the</textblock>
    <textblock>FDPIR, regardless of the Native American's tribal affiliation or</textblock>
    <textblock>age. Secondly, it also makes such households which lack a Native</textblock>
    <textblock>American adult, but which include Native American children,</textblock>
    <textblock>eligible to participate in the FDPIHO. Finally, this rule</textblock>
    <textblock>clarifies that all households which pass the program means test</textblock>
    <textblock>and live on a reservation where an ITO or State agency</textblock>
    <textblock>administers the FDPIR, are eligible to receive benefits</textblock>
    <textblock>regardless of whether they contain a Native American.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>This interim rule becomes effective February 10, 1994. Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>must be received on or before March 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be sent to Philip K. Cohen, Chief,</textblock>
    <textblock>Program Administration Branch, Food Distribution Division, Food</textblock>
    <textblock>and Nutrition Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, 3101 Park</textblock>
    <textblock>Center Drive, room 502, Alexandria, Virginia 22302-1594,</textblock>
    <textblock>telephone (703) 305-2662.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Philip K. Cohen, Chief, Program</textblock>
    <textblock>Administration Branch, Food Distribution Division, Food and</textblock>
    <textblock>Nutrition Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, 3101 Park</textblock>
    <textblock>Center Drive, room 502, Alexandria, Virginia 22302-1594,</textblock>
    <textblock>telephone (703) 305-2662.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Classification</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12866</textblock>
    <textblock>This interim rule is issued in conformance with E.O. 12866.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>This action has been reviewed with regard to the requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. 601-12). Ellen Haas,</textblock>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary for Food and Consumer Services, has certified</textblock>
    <textblock>that this interim rule will not have a significant economic</textblock>
    <textblock>impact on a substantial number of small entities. Since this</textblock>
    <textblock>rule will not result in significant changes in participation for</textblock>
    <textblock>the Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations and the Food</textblock>
    <textblock>Distribution Program for Indian Households in Oklahoma, the</textblock>
    <textblock>impact on Indian Tribal Organizations and State agencies which</textblock>
    <textblock>participate in these programs will be minimal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12372</textblock>
    <textblock>The programs addressed in this action are listed in the Catalog</textblock>
    <textblock>of Federal Domestic Assistance under 10.550 and 10.570 and are</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to the provisions of Executive Order 12372, which</textblock>
    <textblock>requires intergovernmental consultation with state and local</textblock>
    <textblock>officials (7 CFR part 3015, subpart V, and final rule-related</textblock>
    <textblock>notice published June 24, 1983 (48 FR 29114)).</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>This interim rulemaking imposes no new reporting or recordkeeping</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions that are subject to Office of Management and Budget</textblock>
    <textblock>review in accordance with the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S.C. 3501-3520).</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
