<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-1-00019</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-1-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Availability of NPRMs</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person may obtain a copy of this NPRM by submitting a request to the FAA, New England Region, Office of the Assistant Chief Counsel, Attention: Rules Docket No. 93-ANE-31, 12 New England Executive Park, Burlington, MA 01803-5299.</textblock>
    <textblock>Discussion:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Civil Aviation Authority (CAA), which is the airworthiness authority of the United Kingdom, notified the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) that an unsafe condition may exist on Rolls-Royce, plc (R-R) Spey series turbofan engines. The CAA advises that they have received a report of a three-inch crack extending radially outward from the bore on a seventh stage high pressure compressor (HPC) disk installed in a R-R Spey Model 506-14D engine. The crack originated from a corrosion pit that apparently had been present at the disk's entry into service. Investigation indicated that failure of the engine due to disk burst was imminent. That condition, if not corrected, could result in a seventh stage HPC disk burst due to cracking attributed to corrosion, which may result in an uncontained engine failure.</textblock>
    <textblock>This engine model is manufactured in the United Kingdom and is type certificated for operation in the United States under the provisions of ยง21.29 of the Federal Aviation Regulations and the applicable bilateral airworthiness agreement. Pursuant to this bilateral airworthiness agreement, the CAA has kept the FAA informed of the situation described above. The FAA has examined the findings of the CAA, reviewed all available information, and determined that airworthiness directive (AD) action is necessary for products of this type design that are certificated for operation in the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 20, 1988, the FAA issued Telegraphic AD T88-22-51, which reduced cyclic life limits for seventh stage HPC disks from 40,000 total part cycles in service (TPC) to 35,000 TPC for the R-R Spey Model 506-14 and -14D engines. On January 26, 1989, the FAA issued Telegraphic AD T89-02-52, which supersedes Telegraphic AD T88-22-51, and currently requires repetitive inspections or further reduced cyclic life limits for seventh stage HPC disks.</textblock>
    <textblock>Since the issuance of these two previous AD's, further investigation of the cracked disk revealed that the crack originated from a corrosion pit that could have been present at the disk's entry into service. A testing program investigated the effects of corrosion on seventh stage HPC disks, and as a result of this investigation, disk cyclic life has been reevaluated, assuming the possible presence of corrosion at entry into service. To account for the possible presence of corrosion, this proposed AD would further reduce the cyclic life limit, and would require removing from service seventh stage HPC disks that exceed the revised cyclic life limits following the schedule established in this AD.</textblock>
    <textblock>This revised limit reduces the cyclic life limit below the point that intermediate, repetitive inspections are practical; therefore, this AD does not provide for repetitive inspections. In addition, this AD would increase the effectivity to include additional R-R Spey engine models not affected by the previous Telegraphic AD's.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rolls-Royce issued Mandatory Service Bulletin No. Sp72-1034, Revision 1, dated May 4, 1990, that describes the revised cyclic life limits for seventh stage HPC disks, and the additional R-R Spey engine models affected. The CAA classified this service bulletin as mandatory in order to assure the airworthiness of these R-R Spey series turbofan engines in the United Kingdom.</textblock>
    <textblock>Since an unsafe condition has been identified that is likely to exist or develop on other R-R Spey series turbofan engines of this same type design installed on aircraft registered in the United States, the proposed AD would supersede Telegraphic AD T89-02-52 to increase the AD's effectivity to include additional R-R Spey engine models, eliminate the option for repetitive inspections of seventh stage HPC disks, further reduce the cyclic life limits, and require removing from service disks that exceed the revised cyclic life limits following the schedule established in this AD. The actions are required to be accomplished in accordance with the service bulletin described previously.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
