<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00051</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00026</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Agency Information Collection Under OMB Review</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the provisions of the Federal Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (U.S.C. chapter 35), we are submitting to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) a request for approval of a new information collection on Cuban and Haitian entrants to the United States. This information collection, sponsored by the Office of Refugee Resettlement (ORR) at the Administration for Children and Families (ACF), is entitled: ``Entrant Information and Referral Form (Form ORR-5).'' This information collection on Cuban and Haitian entrants to the United States will allow ACF and the Department of Justice to provide information and placement services to the entrants.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Administration for Children and Families</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of this request for OMB approval may be obtained from Stephen R. Smith of the Office of Information Systems Management, ACF, by calling (202) 401-6964.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments and questions regarding this approval should be sent directly to: Laura Oliven, OMB Desk Officer for ACF, OMB Reports Management Branch, New Executive Office Building, 725 17th Street, NW., Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-7316.</textblock>
    <textblock>Information on the Document:</textblock>
    <textblock>Title: Entrant Information and Referral Form ORR-5.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Description:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Cuban/Haitian Entrant Program is authorized under Title V of the Refugee Education Assistance Act of 1980, Public Law 96-422. Section 501(a) of that Act directs the President to provide assistance and services to Cuban and Haitian entrants to the same extent as those available to refugees under title IV of the Immigration and Nationality Act (hereafter referred to as the ``Act''). An entrant differs from a refugee in the manner of his or her entry into the U.S. Refugees are identified as such by overseas consular officials who arrange for their transportation to the U.S. and for reception and placement services at the community of resettlement. An extensive case file is compiled by the consular official and precedes the refugee to his final destination where he is met by a representative of a national voluntary refugee resettlement agency (volging). The volging schedules case management and social services as needed for the refugee. Each step in the refugee resettlement process is documented and data are collected and maintained on the refugee by the Department of State's Refugee Data Center (RDC).</textblock>
    <textblock>The entrant usually arrives without prior contact with U.S. officials and therefore without documentation. The entrant's first contact with the U.S. government is with an officer of the Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) who determines the entrant's immigration status and whether the entrant is to be detained or released. If the entrant is found eligible to remain in the U.S., reception and placement services are arranged through the Community Relations Service (CRS) of the Department of Justice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because advance preparation is not possible for entrants, ORR and other Federal agencies have maintained an office in the Miami area to provide information and referral services for the influx of Cubans and Haitian entrants who have been arriving in the U.S. since 1959. ORR and the Community Relations Service (CRS) of the Department of Justice which maintains strong ties to the local Cuban and Haitian communities coordinate employment and referral services with community groups, local providers, immigration authorities, volgags, State agencies, hospitals, schools and Federal social services agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Miami office maintains a data base on entrants from which data is made available to the State Department, INS, Department of Justice, and the Department of Health and Human Services for statistical and management purposes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>4,000</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Frequency:</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>Average Burden Per Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>15 min.</textblock>
    <textblock>Total Burden Hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>1,000</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated:</textblock>
  </address>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Larry Guerrero,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Director, Office of Information Systems Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-600 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4184-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
