<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00108</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00068</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee Meeting on General Aviation and Business Airplane Issues</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA is issuing this notice to advise the public of a meeting of the Federal Aviation Administration's Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee to discuss general aviation and business airplane issues.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held on February 8, 1994, at 9 a.m. Arrange for oral presentations by January 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held at the American Psychiatric Association (APA), suite 800, 1400 K Street NW., Washington, DC 20005.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Pat Nininger, Small Airplane Directorate (ACE-112), 601 East 12th Street, Kansas City, Missouri 64106, telephone (816) 426-5688.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463; 5 U.S.C. App. II), notice is hereby given of a meeting of the Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee to be held on February 8, 1994, at the American Psychiatric Association (APA), suite 800, 1400 K Street NW., Washington DC 20005. The agenda for the meeting will include:</textblock>
    <textblock>•Opening Remarks</textblock>
    <textblock>•Review of Issues</textblock>
    <textblock>•Status Reports from the FAR/JAR Harmonizing Working Groups (Including acceptance of four NPRMs)</textblock>
    <textblock>Attendance is open to the interested public, but will be limited to the space available. The public must make arrangements by January 25, 1994, to present oral statements at the meeting. The public may present written statements to the committee, at any time, by providing 25 copies to the Assistant Executive Director, or by bringing the copies to him at the meeting. Arrangements may be made by contacting the person listed under the heading ``</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT</textblock>
    <textblock>.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Sign and oral interpretation can be made available at the meeting, as well as an assistive listening device, if requested 10 calendar days before the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John R. Colomy,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Executive Director for General Aviation and Business Airplane Issues, Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-633 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
