<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00105</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00065</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Proposed Advisory Circular 21-SCRAP; Disposition of Unsalvageable Aeronautical Parts and Materials</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice announces the availability of proposed Advisory Circular (AC) 21-SCRAP, Disposition of Unsalvageable Aeronautical Parts and Materials for review and comments. The proposed AC 21-SCRAP provides information and guidance concerning means to dispose of unairworthy aeronautical parts and materials in manners that would prevent the parts and materials from being used in aeronautical applications.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments submitted must identify the proposed AC 21-SCRAP File Number, PO-220-0373, and be received by March 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the proposed AC 21-SCRAP can be obtained from and comments sent to the following: Federal Aviation Administration, Production Certification Branch, AIR-220, Aircraft Manufacturing Division, Aircraft Certification Service, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591 (202) 267-8361.</textblock>
  </address>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed AC 21-SCRAP provides information and guidance to persons involved in the sale or maintenance of aeronautical parts on issues and practices related to the disposition of Unsalvageable aeronautical parts and materials.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments Invited</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to comment on proposed AC 21-SCRAP listed in this notice by submitting such written data, views, and arguments as they desire to the aforementioned address. All communications received on or before the closing date for comments will be considered by the Director, Aircraft Certification Service, before issuing the final AC.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments received on the proposed AC 21-SCRAP may be examined before and after the comment closing date in Room 333, FAA Headquarters Building (FOB-10A), 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591, between 8:30 a.m. and 4:30 p.m., Monday through Friday, except Federal Holidays.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC on January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Michael Gallagher,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Aircraft Manufacturing Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-630 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
