<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-1-00032</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Seiad Valley Viticultural Area</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>27 CFR Part 9</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Notice No. 787 and 93F-022P]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1512-AA07</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (ATF),</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Treasury.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of proposed rulemaking.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (ATF)</textblock>
    <textblock>is considering the establishment of a viticultural area</textblock>
    <textblock>located in Siskiyou County, California, to be known as</textblock>
    <textblock>``Seiad Valley.'' This proposal is the result of a petition</textblock>
    <textblock>filed by Brian J. Helsaple of Seiad Valley Vineyards.</textblock>
    <textblock>ATF believes that the establishment of viticultural areas</textblock>
    <textblock>and the subsequent use of viticultural area names as</textblock>
    <textblock>appellations of origin in wine labeling and advertising</textblock>
    <textblock>allows wineries to designate the specific areas where the</textblock>
    <textblock>grapes used to make the wine were grown and enables</textblock>
    <textblock>consumers to better identify the wines they purchase.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments must be received by March 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send written comments to: Chief, Wine and Beer</textblock>
    <textblock>Branch, Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms, P.O. Box</textblock>
    <textblock>50221, Washington, DC 20091-0221, Attn: Notice No. 787.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of written comments received in response to this</textblock>
    <textblock>notice of proposed rulemaking will be available for public</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection during normal business hours at: ATF Reference</textblock>
    <textblock>Library, Office of Public Affairs and Disclosure, room</textblock>
    <textblock>6300, 650 Massachusetts Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20226.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Marjorie D. Ruhf, Wine</textblock>
    <textblock>and Beer Branch, Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms,</textblock>
    <textblock>650 Massachusetts Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20226</textblock>
    <textblock>(202-927-8230).</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On August 23, 1978, ATF published Treasury Decision</textblock>
    <textblock>ATF-53 (43 FR 37672, 54624) revising regulations in 27 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>part 4. These regulations allow the establishment of</textblock>
    <textblock>definite American viticultural areas. The regulations also</textblock>
    <textblock>allow the name of an approved viticultural area to be used</textblock>
    <textblock>as an appellation of origin in the labeling and advertising</textblock>
    <textblock>of wine.</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 2, 1979, ATF published Treasury Decision</textblock>
    <textblock>ATF-60 (44 FR 56692) which added a new part 9 to 27 CFR,</textblock>
    <textblock>providing for the listing of approved American viticultural</textblock>
    <textblock>areas. Section 4.25a(e)(1), title 27, CFR, defines an</textblock>
    <textblock>American viticultural area as a delimited grape-growing</textblock>
    <textblock>region distinguishable by geographical features, the</textblock>
    <textblock>boundaries of which have been delineated in Subpart C of</textblock>
    <textblock>part 9. Section 4.25a(e)(2) outlines the procedure for</textblock>
    <textblock>proposing an American viticultural area. Any interested</textblock>
    <textblock>person may petition ATF to establish a grape-growing region</textblock>
    <textblock>as a viticultural area. The petition should include:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Evidence that the name of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>viticultural area is locally and/or nationally known as</textblock>
    <textblock>referring to the area specified in the petition;</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Historical or current evidence that the boundaries</textblock>
    <textblock>of the viticultural area are as specified in the petition;</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Evidence relating to the geographical features</textblock>
    <textblock>(climate, soil, elevation, physical features, etc.) which</textblock>
    <textblock>distinguish the viticultural features of the proposed area</textblock>
    <textblock>from surrounding areas;</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) A description of the specific boundaries of the</textblock>
    <textblock>viticultural area, based on features which can be found on</textblock>
    <textblock>United States Geological Survey (U.S.G.S.) maps of the</textblock>
    <textblock>largest applicable scale; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) A copy of the appropriate U.S.G.S. map(s) with the</textblock>
    <textblock>boundaries prominently marked.</textblock>
    <textblock>Petition</textblock>
    <textblock>ATF has received a petition from Brian J. Helsaple of</textblock>
    <textblock>Seiad Valley Vineyards proposing to establish a</textblock>
    <textblock>viticultural area in Siskiyou County, California, to be</textblock>
    <textblock>known as ``Seiad Valley.'' The proposed viticultural area is</textblock>
    <textblock>located in northwestern California, about 15 miles south of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Oregon border. It contains approximately 2160 acres,</textblock>
    <textblock>of which approximately 2.5 acres are planted to vineyards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Seiad Valley Vineyards is the only commercial grower and</textblock>
    <textblock>the only wine producer currently active within the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>viticultural area.</textblock>
    <textblock>Evidence of Name</textblock>
    <textblock>Evidence that the name of the proposed area is locally</textblock>
    <textblock>and/or nationally known as referring to the area specified</textblock>
    <textblock>in the petition includes:</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
