<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-1-00034</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>It is hereby certified that this regulation will not</textblock>
    <textblock>have a significant economic impact on a substantial number</textblock>
    <textblock>of small entities. Any benefit derived from the use of a</textblock>
    <textblock>viticultural area name is the result of the proprietor's</textblock>
    <textblock>own efforts and consumer acceptance of wines from a</textblock>
    <textblock>particular area. No new requirements are proposed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, a regulatory flexibility analysis is not</textblock>
    <textblock>required.</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980,</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Law 96-511, 44 U.S.C. chapter 35, and its</textblock>
    <textblock>implementing regulations, 5 CFR part 1320, do not apply to</textblock>
    <textblock>this notice of proposed rulemaking because no requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>to collect information is proposed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Participation</textblock>
    <textblock>ATF requests comments from all interested parties. We</textblock>
    <textblock>are particularly interested in comments concerning</textblock>
    <textblock>application of the name ``Seiad Valley'' to the area south of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Klamath River, which is drained by Grider Creek.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments received on or before the closing date will be</textblock>
    <textblock>carefully considered. Comments received after that date</textblock>
    <textblock>will be given the same consideration if it is practical to</textblock>
    <textblock>do so, but assurance of consideration cannot be given</textblock>
    <textblock>except as to comments received on or before the closing</textblock>
    <textblock>date.</textblock>
    <textblock>ATF will not recognize any comment as confidential.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments may be disclosed to the public. Any material</textblock>
    <textblock>which a commenter considers to be confidential or</textblock>
    <textblock>inappropriate for disclosure to the public should not</textblock>
    <textblock>be included in the comment. The name of the person</textblock>
    <textblock>submitting a comment is not exempt from disclosure. During</textblock>
    <textblock>the comment period, any person may request an opportunity</textblock>
    <textblock>to present oral testimony at a public hearing. However,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Director reserves the right to determine, in light of</textblock>
    <textblock>all circumstances, whether a public hearing will be held.</textblock>
    <textblock>Drafting Information</textblock>
    <textblock>The principal author of this document is Marjorie D.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ruhf, Wine and Beer Branch, Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and</textblock>
    <textblock>Firearms.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 27 CFR Part 9</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practices and procedures, Consumer</textblock>
    <textblock>protection, Viticultural areas, and Wine.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority and Issuance</textblock>
    <textblock>Title 27, Code of Federal Regulations, part 9, American</textblock>
    <textblock>Viticultural Areas, is proposed to be amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 9_AMERICAN VITICULTURAL AREAS</textblock>
    <textblock>Paragraph 1.</textblock>
    <textblock>The authority citation for part 9</textblock>
    <textblock>continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>27 U.S.C. 205.</textblock>
    <textblock>Par. 2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart C is amended by adding ยง9.148 to read</textblock>
    <textblock>as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart C_Approved American Viticultural Areas</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง9.148</textblock>
    <textblock>Seiad Valley.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Name</textblock>
    <textblock>. The name of the viticultural area described</textblock>
    <textblock>in this section is ``Seiad Valley.''</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Approved map</textblock>
    <textblock>. The appropriate map for determining</textblock>
    <textblock>the boundary of the Seiad Valley viticultural area is a</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S.G.S. 7.5 minute series topographical map of the 1:24000</textblock>
    <textblock>scale, titled ``Seiad Valley, Calif.,'' 1980.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Boundary</textblock>
    <textblock>. The Seiad Valley viticultural area is</textblock>
    <textblock>located in Siskiyou County, California. The boundary is as</textblock>
    <textblock>follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The beginning point is the intersection of the</textblock>
    <textblock>1600 foot contour line with the power transmission line</textblock>
    <textblock>north of the Klamath River, near Mile 130;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) From the beginning point, the boundary follows the</textblock>
    <textblock>1600' contour line in a generally northeasterly direction</textblock>
    <textblock>until it reaches the intersection of an unnamed light duty</textblock>
    <textblock>road and an unimproved road just west of Canyon Creek;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The boundary then follows the unimproved road</textblock>
    <textblock>north to its end, then goes east in a straight line until</textblock>
    <textblock>it reaches the 1800' contour line;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The boundary then follows the 1800' contour line</textblock>
    <textblock>in a northeasterly direction to the point, near Sawmill</textblock>
    <textblock>Gulch, where the contour line crosses Seiad Creek and turns</textblock>
    <textblock>south and west;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) The boundary continues to follow the 1800' contour</textblock>
    <textblock>line as it proceeds southwest for approximately 4.5 miles,</textblock>
    <textblock>then turns sharply south-southeast for approximately 0.3</textblock>
    <textblock>miles, until the contour line turns sharply east at a point</textblock>
    <textblock>just north of the Klamath River;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) The boundary then diverges from the 1800' contour</textblock>
    <textblock>line and proceeds south-southeast in a straight line,</textblock>
    <textblock>across the Klamath River and State route 96, until it</textblock>
    <textblock>intersects with the 1600' contour line;</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) The boundary then follows the 1600' contour line</textblock>
    <textblock>south and west, then north and west, roughly following the</textblock>
    <textblock>course of the Klamath River, until it reaches an unnamed</textblock>
    <textblock>peak 1744 feet high;</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) The boundary continues along the 1600' contour</textblock>
    <textblock>line as it diverges from the Klamath River and proceeds</textblock>
    <textblock>south, just to the east of an unnamed light duty road, to</textblock>
    <textblock>the point where that road crosses Grider Creek;</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) The boundary diverges from the contour line and</textblock>
    <textblock>proceeds west in a straight line across the road and Grider</textblock>
    <textblock>Creek until it intersects with the 1600' contour line on</textblock>
    <textblock>the west side of Grider Creek;</textblock>
    <textblock>(10) The boundary then follows the 1600' contour line</textblock>
    <textblock>north, west and north again until it reaches a point where</textblock>
    <textblock>the contour line turns west, just south of the Klamath</textblock>
    <textblock>River;</textblock>
    <textblock>(11) The boundary diverges from the 1600' contour line</textblock>
    <textblock>and proceeds in a straight line in a northeasterly</textblock>
    <textblock>direction, back to the point of beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Approved: December 28, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Daniel R. Black</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-477 Filed 01-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4810-31-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
