<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00023</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4824-8]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Final Outer Continental Shelf Air Permit Decision</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of final Outer Continental Shelf air permit.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The United States Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) hereby gives notice of the final Outer Continental Shelf air permit decision for the Chevron U.S.A. Production Company, Inc., Destin Dome Block 97 Exploratory Well. Destin Dome Block 97 is located approximately 29 miles offshore of Pensacola, Florida. After due consideration of the facts applicable to this Outer Continental Shelf source as they appear in the Administrative Record and the requirements expressed in the Clean Air Act and appropriate regulations, the Regional Administrator has determined that the Outer Continental Shelf air permit, OCS-FL-001, should be issued with the revisions incorporated since the preliminary determination announced by the previous public notice for this permit (Public Notice Date: October 3, 1993). This action constitutes EPA's final permit decision in accordance with Title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (40 CFR) ยง124.15(a). The permit will become effective as specified in this notice, provided that no timely request for review under 40 CFR 124.19 is received by EPA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person who filed comments on the draft Outer Continental Shelf permit or participated in the public hearing may petition the Environmental Appeals Board to review any condition of the permit decision. Any person who failed to file comments or failed to participate in the public hearing on the draft permit may petition for administrative review only to the extent of the changes from the draft to the final permit decision. The petition shall include a statement of the reasons supporting that review, including a demonstration that any issues being raised were raised during the public comment period (including any public hearing) to the extent required by 40 CFR Part 124 and when appropriate, a showing that the condition in question is based on a finding of fact or conclusion of law which is clearly erroneous, or an exercise of discretion or an important policy consideration.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>This action is effective February 9, 1994. The date of service of notice of this final permit decision was January 10, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The petition must be submitted to the Regional Administrator by February 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send petitions addressed to Mr. John L. Hankinson, Jr., Regional Administrator, at the EPA address in this notice (Attention: R. Scott Davis/APTMD). Copies of the documents relevant to this action are available for public inspection during normal business hours at the following locations:</textblock>
    <textblock>Region IV Library, Environmental Protection Agency, 345 Courtland Street NE, Atlanta, GA 30365.</textblock>
    <textblock>Air Resources Management Division, Florida Department of Environmental Protection, 111 South Magnolia Drive, Tallahassee, Florida 32399.</textblock>
    <textblock>West Florida Regional Library, 200 West Gregory, Pensacola, Florida 32501-4878.</textblock>
    <textblock>Orange County Library, 101 East Central Boulevard, Orlando, Florida 32801.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>R. Scott Davis, Air, Pesticides, and Toxics Management Division, U.S. EPA Region IV, 345 Courtland Street, NE, Atlanta, GA 30365. Telephone (404) 347-5014.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 5,1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Patrick M. Tobin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-617 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
