<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00019</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Tuesday</textblock>
    <textblock>January 11, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part II</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Trade Commission</textblock>
    <textblock>16 CFR Part 453</textblock>
    <textblock>Funeral Industry Practices; Final Amended Trade Regulation Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 7␣/␣Tuesday, January 11, 1994␣/␣Rules and Regulations</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL TRADE COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>16 CFR Part 453</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>Funeral Industry Practices Trade Regulation Rule</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Trade Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final amended trade regulation rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Trade Commission issues final amendments to the Funeral Industry Practices Trade Regulation Rule (hereafter ``the Rule'' or ``the original Rule''), pursuant to the review mandated by §453.10 of the Rule. That provision required that the Commission initiate a rulemaking amendment proceeding no later than four years after the effective date of the Rule to determine whether the rule should be amended or terminated.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>The amended Rule will become effective on July 19, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Requests for copies of the amended Rule and the Statement of Basis and Purpose should be sent to Public Reference Branch, room 130, Federal Trade Commission, 6th Street and Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20580.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Matthew Daynard, Division of Service Industry Practices (202-326-3291), or Carol Jennings (202-326-3010) or Sally Forman Pitofsky (202-326-3318), Division of Marketing Practices, Bureau of Consumer Protection, Federal Trade Commission, Washington, DC 20580.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The amended Rule retains the Rule's primary itemization, price and other disclosure requirements, without major, substantive modification; expressly prohibits non-declinable fees (such as so-called ``casket handling fees'' or ``basic facilities fees'') charged in addition to the non-declinable fee for basic services of funeral director and staff; deletes the affirmative telephone disclosure requirement, but retains the obligation to give price and other information to consumers who request it over the telephone; and contains a series of changes to the original Rule in the nature of fine-tuning and technical revisions designed to make the Rule more effective and to facilitate compliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>In this document, references made to material contained in the rulemaking record, and references to particular, oft-cited documents in the record, are made in the footnotes using the following abbreviations:</textblock>
    <textblock>Tr._The transcript of the public hearings (Vol. I-III).</textblock>
    <textblock>HX_Exhibits presented and accepted into the record at the hearings.</textblock>
    <textblock>R_Materials submitted by the Commission staff or interested parties, or placed on the record by the Presiding Officer. References to documents in this written (``R'') portion of the rulemaking record show the category in which the document was placed, the document number, and the internal page number of the document on which the cited reference appears. The reference number for the rulemaking record itself is 215-66.</textblock>
    <textblock>R-B-5_The Commission's official publication of the Rule and the SBP, referred to above.</textblock>
    <textblock>R-N-1_Bureau of Consumer Protection, Federal Trade Commission, Funeral Industry Practices, Mandatory Review (16 CFR Part 453):</textblock>
    <textblock>Final Staff Report to the Federal Trade Commission With Proposed Amended Trade Regulation Rule,</textblock>
    <textblock>June 1990 (hereafter cited as the ``Staff Report'' in text, ``SR'' in notes).</textblock>
    <textblock>R-O-1_The Presiding Officer's July 1990 Report (``POR'').</textblock>
    <textblock>R-A-1_The Commission's Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (``NPR'') initiating the review proceeding (53 FR 19864, May 31, 1988).</textblock>
    <textblock>R-B-2_Market Facts, Inc.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Report on the Survey of Recent Funeral Arrangers</textblock>
    <textblock>(1988) (the FTC-sponsored study of 1,004 consumers who arranged funerals between Dec. 1986 and June 1987, hereafter cited as the ``Replication Study'' in the text, or ``RS'' in notes).</textblock>
    <textblock>R-B-3_Office of Impact Evaluation, Bureau of Consumer Protection, Federal Trade Commission, Market Facts_Washington, and Dr. J. Paul Peter, University of Wisconsin,</textblock>
    <textblock>Baseline and Follow-up Studies for Evaluating the Effect of the Federal Trade Commission's Funeral Home Industry Trade Regulation Rule: Final Report,</textblock>
    <textblock>July 1982 (The FTC-sponsored study and follow-up of 1,200 consumers who arranged funerals between Nov. 1980 and May 1981, hereafter cited as the ``Baseline Study'' in the text, or ``BLS'' in notes).</textblock>
    <textblock>HX-122_February 1989, FTC Bureau of Economics staff report analyzing expenditure, selection and compliance data from the 1988 Replication Study (hereafter cited as the ``BE Report'').</textblock>
    <textblock>HX-66_1988 study, sponsored by the American Association of Retired Persons and conducted by the Gallup Organization, of 675 consumers who arranged funerals between April 1987 and Oct. 1988 (hereafter cited as the ``Gallup Study'').</textblock>
    <textblock>HX-108_Statement of Rebecca Ayers, National Research, Inc., presenting the results of a national study of 500 funeral directors.</textblock>
    <textblock>R-B-6_1985 FTC Staff publication assisting funeral providers in Rule compliance (hereafter cited as the ``Compliance Guidelines'').</textblock>
    <textblock>R-M-9_Proposed Findings of Fact, Conclusions of Law, and Recommended Decision jointly submitted by the National Funeral Directors Association and the National Selected Morticians.</textblock>
    <textblock>R-M-11_Proposed Findings of Fact, Conclusions of Law, and Recommended Decision submitted by the American Association of Retired Persons.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
