<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00071</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00040</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket Nos. AB-12 and AB-398; Sub-No. 149X and 1X]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Southern Pacific Transportation Company Abandonment Exemption in Fresno County, CA; San Joaquin Valley Railway Company Discontinuance of Service Exemption in Fresno County, CA</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interstate Commerce Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of exemption.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission exempts from the prior approval requirements of 49 U.S.C. 10903-04 the Southern Pacific Transportation Company's abandonment of and the San Joaquin Valley Railway Company's discontinuance of service over a 4.15-mile segment of the Clovis Branch rail line, from milepost 219.00 at or near the Glorietta rail station, to milepost 223.15, at or near the Cooper Avenue rail station in Fresno County, CA.</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </summary>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The Southern Pacific Transportation Company also will abandon a 4.71-mile spur track that connects to the Clovis Branch at milepost 220.9 at or near the Pinedale rail station. Under 49 U.S.C. 10907(b)(1) the Commission has no jurisdiction over that action, because the segment is a spur track.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The exemption will be effective on February 10, 1994, unless a formal expression of intent to file an offer of financial assistance is filed. Formal expressions of intent to file an offer of financial assistance under 49 CFR 1152.27(c)(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>must be filed by January 21, 1994; petitions to stay must be filed by January 26, 1994; requests for public use condition must be filed by January 31, 1994; and petitions to reopen must be filed by February 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See Exempt. of Rail Abandonment_Offers of Finan, Assist.</textblock>
    <textblock>, 4 I.C.C.2d 164 (1987).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send pleadings referring to Docket No. AB-12 (Sub-No. 149X) and Docket No. AB-398 (Sub-No. 1X) to: (1) Office of the Secretary, Case Control Branch, Interstate Commerce Commission, Washington, DC 20423; and (2) Petitioners' respresentative: Louis E. Gitomer, 919 18th Street, NW., suite 210, Washington, DC 20006.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Richard B. Felder (202) 927-5610. [TDD for hearing impaired: (202) 927-5721.]</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional information is contained in the Commission's decision. To purchase a copy of the full decision, write to, call, or pick up in person from: Dynamic Concepts, Inc., room 2229, Interstate Commerce Commission Building, Washington, DC 20423. Telephone: (202) 289-4357/4359. [Assistance for the hearing impaired is available through TDD service (202) 927-5271.]</textblock>
    <textblock>Decided:</textblock>
    <textblock>December 27, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Commission, Chairman McDonald, Vice Chairman Simmons, Commissioners Phillips and Philbin.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Sidney L. Strickland, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-611 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7035-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
