<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00078</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00046</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Documents Containing Reporting or Recordkeeping Requirements; Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of the OMB review of information collection.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The NRC has recently submitted to the OMB for review the following proposal for the collection of information under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. chapter 35).</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Type of submission, new, revision, or extension: Revision.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The title of the information collection: ``10 CFR Part 55: Operators' Licenses.''</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The form number if applicable: Not applicable.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. How often the collection is required: As necessary in order for NRC to meet its responsibilities to determine the eligibility of applicants for operators' licenses and perform a review of applications and reports for simulation facilities submitted to the NRC.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Who will be required or asked to report: Holders of and applicants for facility (i.e., nuclear power, research, and test reactor) operating licenses and individual operators' licenses.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. An estimate of the number of annual responses: 115.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. An estimate of the total number of hours needed annually to complete the requirement or request: 3,536 (approximately 944 hours of reporting burden and approximately 2,592 hours of recordkeeping burden).</textblock>
    <textblock>8. An indication of whether Section 3504(h), Public Law 96-511 applies: Not applicable.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Abstract: 10 CFR Part 55 of the NRC's regulations, ``Operators' Licenses'' specifies information and data to be provided by applicants and facility licensees so that the NRC may make determinations concerning the licensing of operators for nuclear power plants necessary to promote the health and safety of the public. The reporting and recordkeeping requirements contained in 10 CFR part 55 are mandatory for the licensees and applicants affected.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the submittal may be inspected or obtained for a fee from the NRC Public Document Room, 2120 L Street, NW. (Lower Level), Washington, DC 20555. Comments and questions should be directed to the OMB reviewer: Troy Hillier, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs (3150-0018), NEOB-3019, Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments can also be submitted by telephone at (202) 395-3084.</textblock>
    <textblock>The NRC Clearance officer is Brenda J. Shelton, (301) 492-8132.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated at Bethesda, Maryland, this 3rd day of January 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Gerald F. Cranford,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Designated Senior Official for Information Resources Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-575 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7590-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
