<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-1-00002</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-1-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Apricots: Grade Standards</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Agricultural Marketing Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>7 CFR Part 51</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. FV-92-303]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Agricultural Marketing Service, USDA.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposed rule would revise the United States Standards for Grades of Apricots. The proposal would specify definitions that do not appear in the standard but are described in the inspection handbooks and bring up to date any obsolete terms and definitions. In addition, the proposed rule will provide metric equivalents for dimensions given in terms of U.S. Customary units and contains conforming and editorial changes.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be postmarked or courier dated on or before March 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested parties are invited to submit written comments concerning this proposal. Comments must be sent to the Standardization Section, Fresh Products Branch, Fruit and Vegetable Division, Agricultural Marketing Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, P.O. Box 96456, room 2056 South Building, Washington, DC. 20090-6456. Comments should make reference to the date and page number of this issue of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>and will be made available for public inspection in the above office during regular business hours.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Thomas G. Gambill, at the above address or call (202) 720-2185.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department is issuing this rule in conformance with Executive Order 12866.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the requirements set forth in the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. 601</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>), the Administrator of the Agricultural Marketing Service (AMS) has determined that this action will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities. This proposed rule for the revision of U.S. Standards for Grades of Apricots will not impose substantial direct economic cost, recordkeeping, or personnel workload changes on small entities, and will not alter the market share or competitive position of these entities relative to large businesses. In addition, under the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946, the use of these standards is voluntary.</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposed rule has been reviewed under Executive Order 12778, Civil Justice Reform. This action is not intended to have retroactive effect. This proposed rule will not preempt any State or local laws, regulations, or policies, unless they present an irreconcilable conflict with this rule. There are no administrative procedures which must be exhausted prior to any judicial challenge to the provisions of this rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agencies periodically review existing regulations. An objective of the review is to ensure that the grade standards are serving their intended purpose, the language is clear, and the standards are consistent with AMS policy and authority.</textblock>
    <textblock>The United States Standards for Grades of Apricots became effective on May 25, 1928 and has not been revised since then. In June 1992, the Washington Apricot Marketing Committee (WAMC) requested the USDA to revise the standard. Consisting of producers from various districts throughout the State, the WAMC recommends minimum size, pack, and grade requirements each year for the Federal Marketing Order on Washington State grown apricots. Specifically, the WAMC requested that skin breaks (cuts and stem punctures), and stem pulls be changed from ``free from'' defects to ``free from damage'' or ``serious damage'' defects in the U.S. No. 1 and U.S. No. 2 grades, respectively. Such changes would have the effect of allowing these defects on fruit in various degrees without being scored against the grade (versus ``free from'' which means they are scored on sight). WAMC also suggested that the Department should make any other revisions deemed necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>AMS reviewed these issues to ascertain the need for the change proposed by WAMC as well as other technical changes or updates that the Agency believes may be helpful. Many suggestions and comments were received pertaining to a recent informal market survey by AMS. The California Apricot Advisory Board advised AMS that the changes proposed pertaining to skinbreaks and stem pulls are not warranted and would allow the export of otherwise unsaleable product.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, it would appear that there is not a widespread consensus among interested parties that skin breaks, stem punctures or similar defects should be allowed in these grades. However, in order for the Department to receive comments in a more widespread and formal manner this requested change as well as the following changes by the Department which would bring the standard up to date with current industry practices, are being proposed.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
