<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00073</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00042</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Notice of Determinations Regarding Eligibility To Apply for Worker Adjustment Assistance</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 223 of the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2273) the Department of Labor herein presents summaries of determinations regarding eligibility to apply for adjustment assistance issued during the period of December, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order for an affirmative determination to be made and a certification of eligibility to apply for adjustment assistance to be issued, each of the group eligibility requirements of section 222 of the Act must be met.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) That a significant number or proportion of the workers in the workers' firm, or an appropriate subdivision thereof, have become totally or partially separated,</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) That sales or production, or both, of the firm or subdivision have decreased absolutely, and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) That increases of imports of articles like or directly competitive with articles produced by the firm or appropriate subdivision have contributed importantly to the separations, or threat thereof, and to the absolute decline in sales or production.</textblock>
    <textblock>Negative Determinations</textblock>
    <textblock>In each of the following cases the investigation revealed that criterion (3) has not been met. A survey of customers indicated that increased imports did not contribute importantly to worker separations at the firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,135; Trinity Industries, Inc., Plant</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>70,</textblock>
    <textblock>Chicago Heights, IL</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,117; Midwest Body Corp., Paris, IL</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,239; Alda Oil and Gas, Oklahoma City, OK</textblock>
    <textblock>In the following cases, the investigation revealed that the criteria for eligibility has not been met for the reasons specified.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,152; Unisys Corp., Customer Service Engineering, Houston, TX</textblock>
    <textblock>The workers' firm does not produce an article as required for certification under Section 222 of the Trade Act of 1974.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,186; McDonnell Douglas Finance Corp., Long Beach, CA</textblock>
    <textblock>The workers' firm does not produce an article as required for certification under Section 222 of the Trade Act of 1974.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,047; E.I. DuPont De Nemours &amp; Co., DuPont Industries Imaging, Rochester, NY</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. imports of unexposed X-ray film and graphic arts film declined in the 12 month period September through August 1992-1993 compared with the same period in 1991-1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,148; Evan Picone, Inc., North Bergen, NJ</textblock>
    <textblock>Increased imports did not contribute importantly to worker separations at the firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,325; Ameripex International, Inc., Denver, CO</textblock>
    <textblock>Predominant portion of services provided by the subject firm are international in nature. Any layoffs resulting from losses in revenues in the international market are not considered import impacted under the terms of the terms of the Trade Act of 1974.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,287; American Pipeline, American Processing L.P., Goldsmith, TX.</textblock>
    <textblock>The investigation revealed that criterion (2) and criterion (3) have not been met. Sales or production did not decline during the relevant period for certification. Increases of imports of articles like or directly competitive with articles produced by the firm or appropriate subdivision have not contributed importantly to the separations or threat therefore, and the absolute decline in sales or production.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,176; Shell Pipe Line Corp., Houston, TX</textblock>
    <textblock>Increased imports did not contribute importantly to worker separations at the firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,178; Pecten Chemical Co., Houston, TX</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,179; Pecten International Co., Houston, TX</textblock>
    <textblock>Increased imports did not contribute importantly to worker separations at the firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,196; Shell Chemical Co., Houston, TX</textblock>
    <textblock>The investigation revealed that criterion (2) and criterion (3) have not been met. Sales or production did not decline during the relevant period for certification. Increases of imports of articles like or directly competitive with articles produced by the firm or appropriate subdivision have not contributed importantly to the separations or threat thereof, and the absolute decline in sales or production.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,197; Shell Oil Products, Houston, TX</textblock>
    <textblock>The investigations revealed that criterion (2) and criterion (3) have not been met. Sales or production did not decline during the relevant period for certification. Increases of imports of articles like or directly competitive with articles produced by the firm or appropriate subdivision have not contributed importantly to the separations or threat thereof, and the absolute decline in sales or production.</textblock>
    <textblock>Affirmative Determinations</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,000; Pennsylvania Optical, Reading, PA</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after August 8, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,260; Reltoc Manufacturing Co., Inc., Plant E, Wynne, AR</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after September 30, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,155 &amp; TA-W-29,155A; Reltoc Manufacturing Co., Plant C, Forest City, AR and Plant CC, Forrest City, AR</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after September 30, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,243 &amp; 29,244; Cinderella Knitting Mills, Leesport, PA and Gastonia, NC</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after November 4, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,138; Pilgrim Too Sportswear, Inc., Summit Hill, PA</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after October 7, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,184; American Cyanamid Co., Bound Brook, NJ</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after October 21, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,309; Bausch &amp; Lomb, Oakland, MD</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after November 24, 1992.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF LABOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Employment and Training Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
</doc>
