<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00095</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00019</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Preventive requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>To prevent these unfair or deceptive acts or practices, funeral providers must include on the itemized statement of funeral goods and services selected, required by §453.2(b)(5), the statement: ``If you selected a funeral that may require embalming, such as a funeral with viewing, you may have to pay for embalming. You do not have to pay for embalming you did not approve if you selected arrangements such as a direct cremation or immediate burial. If we charged for embalming, we will explain why below.''</textblock>
    <textblock>§453.6</textblock>
    <textblock>Retention of documents.</textblock>
    <textblock>To prevent the unfair or deceptive acts or practices specified in §453.2 and §453.3 of this rule, funeral providers must retain and make available for inspection by Commission officials true and accurate copies of the price lists specified in §§453.2(b) (2) through (4), as applicable, for at least one year after the date of their last distribution to customers, and a copy of each statement of funeral goods and services selected, as required by §453.2(b)(5), for at least one year from the date of the arrangements conference.</textblock>
    <textblock>§453.7</textblock>
    <textblock>Comprehension of disclosures.</textblock>
    <textblock>To prevent the unfair or deceptive acts or practices specified in §453.2 through §453.5, funeral providers must make all disclosures required by those sections in a clear and conspicuous manner. Providers shall not include in the casket, outer burial container, and general price lists, required by</textblock>
    <textblock>§§453.2(b)(2)-(4), any statement or information that alters or contradicts the information required by this Part to be included in those lists.</textblock>
    <textblock>§453.8</textblock>
    <textblock>Declaration of intent.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Except as otherwise provided in §453.2(a), it is a violation of this rule to engage in any unfair or deceptive acts or practices specified in this rule, or to fail to comply with any of the preventive requirements specified in this rule;</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The provisions of this rule are separate and severable from one another. If any provision is determined to be invalid, it is the Commission's intention that the remaining provisions shall continue in effect.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) This rule shall not apply to the business of insurance or to acts in the conduct thereof.</textblock>
    <textblock>§453.9</textblock>
    <textblock>State exemptions.</textblock>
    <textblock>If, upon application to the Commission by an appropriate state agency, the Commission determines that:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) There is a state requirement in effect which applies to any transaction to which this rule applies; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) That state requirement affords an overall level of protection to consumers which is as great as, or greater than, the protection afforded by this rule; then the Commission's rule will not be in effect in that state to the extent specified by the Commission in its determination, for as long as the State administers and enforces effectively the state requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>By direction of the Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donald S. Clark,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-393 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6750-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
