<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00096</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00059</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>D. Market Impact</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission believes that the listing and trading on the CBOE of Nasdaq Index options, including full-value and reduced-value Index LEAPS, will not adversely impact the underlying securities markets.</textblock>
    <textblock>First, as described above, the Index is broad-based and comprised of 100 stocks with no one stock dominating the Index. Second, as noted above, the stocks contained in the Index have relatively large capitalizations and are relatively actively traded. Third, the 25,000 contract position and exercise limits will serve to minimize potential manipulation and market impact concerns. Fourth, the risk to investors of contra-party non-performance will be minimized because the Index options will be issued and guaranteed by the Options Clearing Corporation just like any other standardized option traded in the United States. Fifth, existing CBOE stock index options rules and surveillance procedures will apply to Nasdaq Index options.</textblock>
    <textblock>Lastly, the Commission believes that settling expiring Nasdaq Index options (including full-value and reduced-value Index LEAPS) based on the opening prices of component securities is reasonable and consistent with the Act. As noted in other contexts, valuing expiring index options for exercise settlement purposes based on opening prices rather than closing prices may help reduce adverse effects on the securities underlying options on the Index.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is therefore ordered,</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to section 19(b)(2) of the Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>that the proposed rule change (SR-CBOE-93-42) is approved.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Commission, by the Division of Market Regulation, pursuant to delegated authority.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>23</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>In addition, the CBOE has represented that the CBOE and the Options Price Reporting Authority (``OPRA'') have the necessary systems capacity to support those new series of index options that would result from the introduction of Index options and Index LEAPS. See</textblock>
    <textblock>letter from Charles J. Henry, President and Chief Operating Officer, CBOE, to Sharon Lawson, Assistant Director, Division of Market Regulation, SEC, dated January 4, 1993 and memorandum from Joe Corrigan, Executive Director, OPRA, to Eileen Smith, CBOE, dated January 4, 1993.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>23</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>24</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Securities Exchange Act Release No. 30944, 57 FR 33376 (July 28, 1992).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>24</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>25</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(2) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>25</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>26</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 200.30-3(a)(12) (1993).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>26</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 93-622 Filed 1-10-93; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
