<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>b. Redesignating paragraph (c)(2) as paragraph (c)(1).</textblock>
    <textblock>18. Part 264 is further amended by adding §§264.4 and 264.6, to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§264.4</textblock>
    <textblock>Application to replace a Non-resident Border Crossing Card.</textblock>
    <textblock>An application for a replacement Non-Resident Border Crossing Card must be filed pursuant to §212.6(e) of this chapter. An application for a replacement Non-resident Alien Canadian Border Crossing Card must be filed on Form I-175. An application for a replacement Non-resident Mexican Border Crossing Card must be filed on Form I-190.</textblock>
    <textblock>§264.6</textblock>
    <textblock>Application for an initial or replacement Form I-94, Nonimmigrant Arrival-Departure Document, or Form I-95, Crewmen's Landing Permit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>General.</textblock>
    <textblock>An application for a new or replacement Form I-94 or replacement Form I-95 must be made on Form I-102. The application must be filed with the fee required in §103.7 of this chapter and the initial evidence required on the application form.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>An application may be approved if filed by an alien in the United States who:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Applies to replace a lost or stolen Form I-94 or Form I-95 that had been issued to him or her;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Applies to replace a mutilated Form I-94 or Form I-95 issued to him or her; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Was not issued a Form I-94 pursuant to §235.1(f)(1)(i), (iii), (iv), (v), or (vi) of this chapter, when last admitted as a nonimmigrant, has not since been issued a Form I-94, and now requires a Form I-94.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Processing.</textblock>
    <textblock>A pending application filed under paragraph (a) of this section shall be considered temporary evidence of registration. If the application is approved, the document shall be issued. There is no appeal from the denial of an application filed on Form I-102.</textblock>
    <textblock>19. In §264.5, a new paragraph (g) is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§264.5</textblock>
    <textblock>Application for a replacement Alien Registration Card.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Eligibility for a card while in deportation or exclusion proceedings.</textblock>
    <textblock>A person in exclusion proceedings shall be entitled to evidence of permanent resident status until ordered excluded. Such evidence shall be in the form of a temporary Form I-551 issued for a period sufficient to accomplish the exclusion proceedings. A person in deportation proceedings shall be entitled to evidence of permanent resident status until ordered deported or excluded. Issuance of an alien registration card to a person in exclusion or deportation proceedings, provided the person had status as a lawful permanent resident when the proceeding commenced, shall not affect those proceedings.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 292_REPRESENTATION AND APPEARANCES</textblock>
    <textblock>20. The authority citation for part 292 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>8 U.S.C. 1103, 1252b, 1362.</textblock>
    <textblock>21. In §292.4, paragraph (a), is amended by adding a new sentence at the end of the paragraph, to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§292.4</textblock>
    <textblock>Appearances.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣* A notice of appearance entered in application or petition proceedings must be signed by the applicant or petitioner to authorize representation in order for the appearance to be recognized by the Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: November 16, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Doris Meissner,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Commissioner, Immigration and Naturalization Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-392 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-10-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
