<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00024</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) invites all interested persons to nominate qualified individuals to serve as members of the National Drinking Water Advisory Council. This Advisory Council was established to provide practical and independent advice, consultation and recommendations to the Agency on the activities, functions and policies related to the implementation of the Safe Drinking Water Act as amended. The Council consists of fifteen members, including a Chairperson. Five members represent the general public; five members represent appropriate state and local agencies concerned with water hygiene and public water supply; and five members represent private organizations or groups demonstrating an active interest in the field of water hygiene and public water supply. Each member holds office for a term of three years and is eligible for reappointment. On December 15 of each year, five members complete their appointment. This notice solicits names to fill the five vacancies as of December 16, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any interested person or organization may nominate qualified individuals for membership. Nominees should be identified by name, occupation, position, address and telephone number. Nominations must include a current resume providing the nominee's background, experience, and qualifications.</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons selected for membership will receive compensation for travel and a nominal daily compensation while attending meetings.</textblock>
    <textblock>Nominations should be submitted to Charlene E. Shaw, Designated Federal Official, National Drinking Water Advisory Council, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Office of Ground Water and Drinking Water (4601), 401 M Street SW, Washington, DC 20460, no later than 30 days after publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. The agency will not formally acknowledge or respond to nominations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4824-7]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Drinking Water Advisory Council Request for Nominations</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>James R. Elder,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Ground Water and Drinking Water.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-618 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
