<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00066</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00036</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Intent To Close to Public Entry Public Lands To Protect Endangered Species Until a Suitable Permit System Is Implemented</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[AZ-024-94-4333-01]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management; Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of closure of public entry to public lands.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that portions of the Public Lands along the Gila River below Coolidge Dam in Gila County, Arizona will be closed to all forms of boating and rafting. The Gila River in this area is jointly administered by the Bureau and the San Carlos Indian Reservation. This closure will not apply to emergency response agencies conducting official business. This use restriction covers the Gila River as it crosses Public Lands from T. 3 S., R. 18 E., Section 17, downstream to the confluence of Mescal Creek and the Gila River in T. 3 S., R. 17 E., Section 29, G &amp; SR Meridian, Arizona.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>This order is effective upon signature of the authorized officer. January 1, 1994 through July 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of this use restriction is to provide protection for nesting bald eagles</textblock>
    <textblock>Haliaeetus leucocephalus.</textblock>
    <textblock>In past years, the Gila River was not navigable in this area due to water hazards. Recent flooding has opened up the river channel and facilitated a proliferation of rafting and boating in the area. The bald eagle nest is low to the ground and immediately adjacent to the river channel making it susceptible to human disturbance. To comply with the Endangered Species Act of 1973, as amended, the Bureau must not allow actions that may result in ``take'' of an endangered species without being permitted according to Section 7 of the Act. Failure by the Bureau to control public access to this area may result in disturbance to the nesting bald eagles and a violation of the Act. The Bureau will consult with the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service when a permit system is established jointly with the San Carlos Indian Reservation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Order</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that effective on the date of signature by the authorized officer of this notice, the following use restriction will be in effect on the Gila River Public Lands below Coolidge Dam until July 1, 1994, or until an opening notice is published.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. No person may boat, raft or float on the Gila River on Public Lands described below. Emergency response agencies on official business will be exempt from this order.</textblock>
    <textblock>Gila and Salt River Meridian, Arizona</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 3 S., R. 18 E.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Secs. 17, 18, 19, 29</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 3 S., R. 17 E.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Secs. 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 34</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority for this use restriction may be found in 43 CFR 8364.1d. Violations of this closure are punishable by a fine not to exceed $100,000 and/or 12 months in jail.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Gail Acheson, Area Manager, Phoenix Resource Area, 2015 West Deer Valley Road, Phoenix, AZ 85027, (602) 780-8090.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David J. Miller,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting District Manager.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-602 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-02-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
