<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00031</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Another commentor noted that transportation companies cannot board an alien passenger traveling in emergency circumstances who lacks the required documents without incurring a fine at the port of entry. The commentor recommended adding a provision to the rule which would specify the steps a carrier must take to board such a passenger without incurring a fine. This rule is not intended to expand the circumstances under which an alien may apply for a waiver of documents, only to simplify the administrative procedure for granting a waiver, and therefore the recommendation will not be incorporated into the final rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with 5 U.S.C. 605(b), the Commissioner of the Immigration and Naturalization Service certifies that this rule will not have a significant adverse economic impact on a substantial number of small entities. This rule merely reflects an agreement reached between the Department of State and the Immigration and Naturalization Service that results in a less burdensome administrative procedure. In addition, members of the public are serviced in a more expeditious manner as a result of the effect of this rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule is not significant within the meaning of section 3(f) of E.O. 12866, nor does this rule have Federalism implications warranting the preparation of a Federalism Assessment in accordance with E.O. 12612.</textblock>
    <textblock>The information collection requirement contained in this rule has been cleared by the Office of Management and Budget under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act. The OMB control number for this collection is contained in 8 CFR 299.5.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 8 CFR Part 212</textblock>
    <textblock>Aliens, Documentation, Nonimmigrant, Passport and visas, Waivers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, part 212 of chapter I of title 8 of the Code of Federal Regulations is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 212_DOCUMENTARY REQUIREMENTS: NONIMMIGRANTS; WAIVERS; ADMISSION OF CERTAIN INADMISSIBLE ALIENS; PAROLE</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 212 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>8 U.S.C. 1101, 1102, 1103, 1182, 1184, 1225, 1226, 1228, 1252; 8 CFR part 2.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. In §212.1, the first two sentences in paragraph (g) are revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§212.1</textblock>
    <textblock>Documentary requirements for nonimmigrants.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Unforeseen emergency.</textblock>
    <textblock>A visa and a passport are not required of a nonimmigrant who, either prior to his or her embarkation at a foreign port or place or at the time of arrival at a port of entry in the United States, satisfies the district director at the port of entry that, because of an unforeseen emergency, he or she is unable to present the required documents, in which case a waiver application shall be made on Form I-193. The district director may approve a waiver of documents in each case in which he or she is satisfied that the nonimmigrant cannot present the required documents because of an unforeseen emergency and the waiver would be appropriate in the circumstances. *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Doris Meissner,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Commissioner, Immigration and Naturalization Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-646 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-10-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
