<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00037</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Wild Bird Conservation Act (Act) of 1992; Possible Moratorium on Imports of Wild Birds From Indonesia and Sénégal Into the United States</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>agency:</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension of Comment Period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>summary:</textblock>
    <textblock>The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (Service) published two notices in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of November 5, 1993, announcing the receipt of petitions to impose a moratorium on the imports of wild birds from Indonesia and Sénégal into the United States, pursuant to the Wild Bird Conservation Act of 1992 (58 FR 59061 and 58 FR 59063). Through the issuance of this notice, the Service now extends the comment period on both of these petitions an additional 90 days, in order to receive as complete information as is possible concerning the status of wild bird species in Indonesia and Sénégal.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>dates:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Fish and Wildlife Service (Service) will consider comments and information received by April 11, 1994 in making a decision on this proposed action.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>addresses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments and information should be sent to: Director, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, c/o Mr. Marshall P. Jones, Chief, Office of Management Authority, 4401 N. Fairfax Dr., room 420 C, Arlington, VA 22203.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>for further information contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Susan S. Lieberman, Office of Management Authority, at the above address, telephone (703) 358-2093.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>supplementary information:</textblock>
    <textblock>The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (Service) published two notices in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of November 5, 1993, announcing the receipt of petitions to impose a moratorium on the imports of wild birds from Indonesia and Sénégal into the United States, pursuant to the Wild Bird Conservation Act of 1992 (58 FR 59061 and 58 FR 59063). The petitions were found to present sufficient information indicating that imposing a moratorium on the imports of wild birds from Indonesia and Sénégal may be warranted under the Act. The Service received requests in writing from the following to extend the comment period: Government of Indonesia, Government of Sénégal, Pet Industry Joint Advisory Council, and American Federation of Aviculture. In particular, the Governments of Indonesia and Sénégal requested additional time to fully review the petitions and prepare a response. Those written requests were received by the Service during the period of December 23-27, 1993. The Service considers these requests warranted, and through the issuance of this notice, extends the comment period on both of these petitions an additional 90 days, in order to receive as complete information as is possible concerning the status of wild bird species in both Indonesia and Sénégal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Comments Solicited</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service intends that any final decision resulting from these petitions will be as accurate and as effective as possible. Therefore, any comments or data from the public, other concerned governmental agencies, the scientific or conservation communities, trade organizations, or any other interested party concerning any aspect of the wild bird trade in Indonesia and Sénégal are hereby solicited.</textblock>
    <textblock>Author: The author of this notice is Dr. Susan S. Lieberman, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Office of Management Authority.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Notice: Wild Bird Conservation Act (WBCA) of 1992; Extension of comment period on petitions requesting moratorium on imports of Wild Birds from Indonesia and Sénégal into the United States.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard N. Smith,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-554 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-55-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
