<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00065</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-0-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(b) If a timely request for a conference has been made pursuant to 30 CFR 723.18 or 845.18, a petition for review must be filed within 30 days from service of notice by the conference officer that the conference is deemed completed.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Section 4.1152 is amended by revising paragraph (a)(2) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§4.1152</textblock>
    <textblock>Contents of petition; payment required.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If the amount of penalty is being contested based upon a misapplication of the civil penalty formula, a statement indicating how the civil penalty formula contained in 30 CFR part 723 or 845 was misapplied, along with a proposed civil penalty utilizing the civil penalty formula;</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Section 4.1154 is amended by revising paragraph (a)(2) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§4.1154</textblock>
    <textblock>Review of waiver determination.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Within 10 days of the filing of a petition under this part, petitioner may move the administrative law judge to review the granting or denial of a waiver of the civil penalty formula pursuant to 30 CFR 723.16 or 845.16.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Section 4.1157 is amended by revising paragraphs (a) and (b)(1) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§4.1157</textblock>
    <textblock>Determination by administrative law judge.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The administrative law judge shall incorporate in his decision concerning the civil penalty, findings of fact on each of the four criteria set forth in 30 CFR 723.13 or 845.13, and conclusions of law.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) If the administrative law judge finds that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A violation occurred or that the fact of violation is uncontested, he shall establish the amount of the penalty, but in so doing, he shall adhere to the point system and conversion table contained in 30 CFR 723.13 and 723.14 or 845.13 and 845.14, except that the administrative law judge may waive the use of such point system where he determines that a waiver would further abatement of violations of the Act. However, the administrative law judge shall not waive the use of the point system and reduce the proposed assessment on the basis of an argument that a reduction in the proposed assessment could be used to abate other violations of the Act; or</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Section 4.1266 is amended by revising the following phone numbers in paragraph (b)(2):</textblock>
    <textblock>§4.1266</textblock>
    <textblock>Determination on application concerning an order of cessation issued pursuant to section 521(a)(2) or section 521(a)(3) of the act.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>Alabama Field Office (also serving Georgia): 205-290-7282</textblock>
    <textblock>Illinois Field Office: 217-492-4495</textblock>
    <textblock>Indiana Field Office: 317-226-6700</textblock>
    <textblock>Kentucky Field Office: 606-233-2494</textblock>
    <textblock>Missouri Field Office (also serving Iowa, Kansas and Nebraska): 816-374-6405</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Oklahoma Field Office (also serving Arkansas, Louisiana and Texas): 918-581-6430</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Tennessee Field Office: 615-545-4103</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Wyoming Field Office (also serving Alaska, Idaho, Montana, North Dakota, Oregon, South Dakota and Washington): 307-261-5776</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>10. Section 4.1271 is amended by revising paragraph (a) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§4.1271</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of appeal.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Any aggrieved party may file a notice of appeal from an order or decision of an administrative law judge disposing of a proceeding under §§4.1160 through 4.1171, 4.1200 through 4.1205, 4.1260 through 4.1267, 4.1290 through 4.1296, and 4.1350 through 4.1356.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-601 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-79-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
