<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00011</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Marine Mammals</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), NOAA, Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Issuance of Public Display Permit No. 884.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>On Tuesday, September 21, 1993, notice was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 49024) that an application (P2Y) had been filed by Sea World, Inc. for a permit to import one adult male killer whale (</textblock>
    <textblock>Orcinus orca</textblock>
    <textblock>) identified as ``Ulysses'' from the Barcelona Zoo in Barcelona, Spain.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that on January 4, 1994, as authorized by the provisions of the Marine Mammal Protection Act (MMPA) of 1972 (16 U.S.C. 1361</textblock>
    <textblock>et. seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>) the NMFS issued a permit for the above activities subject to the special conditions set forth therein.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issuance of this permit is based on a finding that the proposed taking is consistent with the purposes and policy of the MMPA. The NMFS has determined that Sea World, Inc. offers an acceptable program for education or conservation purposes. Sea World, Inc. facilities are open the public on a regularly scheduled basis and access to these facilities is not limited or restricted other than by the charging of an admission fee.</textblock>
    <textblock>The permit is available for review by appointment in the following offices:</textblock>
    <textblock>Permits Division, Office of Protected Resources, NMFS, NOAA, 1315 East-West Highway, room 13130, Silver Spring, MD 20910 (301/713-2289);</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, Southeast Region, NMFS, NOAA, 9450 Koger Blvd., St. Petersburg, FL 33702 (813/893-3141); and</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, Southwest Region, NMFS, NOAA, 501 West Ocean Blvd., suite 4200, Long Beach, CA 90302 (310/980-4016).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William W. Fox, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Protected Resources, National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-585 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
