<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-1-00027</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>It is intended that the generic disclosure statement would specify, in an addendum on a third page, the participating jurisdictions and the specific products for which it could be used. The addendum would be updated periodically as new jurisdictions adopted the text. In the United States, it is contemplated that such risk disclosure statement, if ultimately proposed and adopted after further public comment, would satisfy only those risk disclosure obligations set forth in Commission rules 1.55 (which incorporates the risk-disclosure contained in Commission rule 30.6),</textblock>
    <textblock>the special disclosures related to futures-style margining of options permitted on certain foreign exchanges,</textblock>
    <textblock>and the special bankruptcy disclosures of Commission rule 190.10(c) related to the acceptance of non-cash margin.</textblock>
    <textblock>Approach Taken By Working Group</textblock>
    <textblock>The approach taken by the international working group with respect to risk disclosure has been to develop a draft generic statement which focuses on the major risks of trading and contains the basic generic disclosures required by most jurisdictions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thus, the approach of the working group was to eliminate much of the definitional and educational material which currently is required to be disclosed by Commission rule 33.7 and to treat options disclosure in a manner equivalent to disclosure for futures. As such, the statement is intended to focus customer attention on the risks of trading, as currently is the practice with futures risk disclosure. Further, the statement would highlight the importance of obtaining sufficient information as to the specifics of trading without attempting to address the differences from market to market.</textblock>
    <textblock>The elimination of a Commission mandated description of options trading and other educational material from the mandated risk disclosure statement does not mean, however, that firms do not have the obligation to provide all material disclosures in compliance with Commission and National Futures Association (NFA) rules.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The Commission notes in this regard that pending resolution of the Commission's determination on this draft generic risk disclosure statement, firms operating pursuant to Commission rule 30.10 relief should continue to comply with the risk disclosure requirements set forth in the relevant Commission orders and that for these purposes may continue to use the text of rule 30.6 as published prior to the 1993 revisions to Commission rules 1.55 and 30.6 (which incorporated the rule 30.6 disclosures for foreign futures into the rule 1.55 disclosures for domestic futures) (see 58 FR 17496 (April 5, 1993)).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See, e.g., CFTC Advisory No. 90-1 [1987-1990 Transfer Binder] Comm. Fut. L. Rep. (CCH) ¶24,597 (disclosure statement relating to the deferred payment of option premiums for options, superseding separate disclosure addenda required by orders concerning the London International Financial Futures Exchange (54 FR 37636 (September 12, 1989)), the International Petroleum Exchange (54 FR 50356 (December 6, 1989)), and the London Futures and Options Exchange (renamed as the London Commodity Exchange) (54 FR 50348 (December 6, 1989)); and 55 FR 14238 (April 17, 1990) (Sydney Futures Exchange).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See, e.g., Commission rule 1.55(d), which provides that:</textblock>
    <textblock>This section [requiring distribution of a risk disclosure statement] does not relieve a futures commission merchant or introducing broker from any other disclosure obligation it may have under applicable law.</textblock>
    <textblock>See also, NFA Compliance Rule 2-30 (customer information and risk disclosure).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
