<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00111</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940111-2-00070</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>East Portland Traction Company (EPTC) Waiver Petition Docket Number RSGM 93-23</textblock>
    <textblock>The EPTC seeks a permanent waiver of compliance with certain provisions of the Safety Glazing Standards, 49 CFR part 223 for three locomotives. Operations are conducted on private right-of-way with very few grade crossings at Portland, Oregon. The three locomotives, which were built between 1948 and 1952, are shared with the EPTC's affiliate Molalla Western Railway.</textblock>
    <textblock>Tulsa-Sapulpa Union Railway Company (TSU) Waiver Petition Docket Number RSGM 93-24</textblock>
    <textblock>The TSU seeks a permanent waiver of compliance with certain provisions of the Safety Glazing Standards, 49 CFR part 223 for four locomotives. The TSU operates between Tulsa and Sapulpa, Oklahoma, a distance of approximately 10 miles. The railroad states there have been no incidents involving glazing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Nobles Rock Railroad (NRRX) Waiver Petition Docket Number RSGM 93-25</textblock>
    <textblock>Rail Equipment and Transportation, Incorporated, on behalf of NRRX seeks a permanent waiver of compliance with certain provisions of the Safety Glazing Standards, 49 CFR part 223 for one locomotive. The NRRX operates 41.4 miles of track between Manly and Agate, Minnesota, and has trackage rights on 3.4 miles of Chicago and Northwestern Transportation Company track between Agate and Worthington, Minnesota. Maximum speed will be 10 mph with 1 or 2 daily trains.</textblock>
    <textblock>Hartwell Railroad Company (HRT) Waiver Petition Docket Number RSGM 93-27</textblock>
    <textblock>The HRT seeks a permanent waiver of compliance with certain provisions of the Safety Glazing Standards, 49 CFR part 223 for one locomotive. The HRT operates 10 miles of track in rural Hart County, Georgia, at a maximum speed of 10 mph. An average of two or three trains are operated per week. The railroad states there is no problem with vandalism.</textblock>
    <textblock>Beaufort and Morehead Railway, Incorporated (BMH) Waiver Petition Docket Number RSGM 93-28</textblock>
    <textblock>The BMH seeks a permanent waiver of compliance with certain provisions of the Safety Glazing Standards, 49 CFR part 223 for one locomotive. The BMH operates five days per week in a confined area of approximately one mile at Morehead City, North Carolina.</textblock>
    <textblock>Delaware-Lackawanna Railroad Company, Incorporated (DL) Waiver Petition Docket Number RSGM-93-29</textblock>
    <textblock>The DL seeks a permanent waiver of compliance with certain provisions of the Safety Glazing Standards, 49 CFR part 223 for two locomotives. The railroad operates on 58 miles of track including trackage rights on the Delaware and Hudson Railroad and Consolidated Rail Corporation, all in the general vicinity of Scranton, Pennsylvania. The ALCO C-425 locomotives are equipped with FRA glazing in the front and rear windows on both sides. The waiver is requested for the side and center front windows. The previous operator, Lackawanna Valley Railroad Corporation, reported no incidents involving glazing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC on January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Phil Olekszyk,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Associate Administrator for Safety.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-558 Filed 1-10-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-06-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
