<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00033</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given in accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act that a meeting of the Delta Region Preservation Commission will be held at 7 p.m., on Wednesday, March 16, 1994, in the Environmental Education Center, Barataria Preserve Unit, Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve, 7400 Highway 45, Marrero, Louisiana.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Delta Region Preservation Commission was established pursuant to section 907 of Public Law 95-625 (16 U.S.C. 230f), as amended, to advise the Secretary of the Interior in the selection of sites for inclusion in Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve, and in the implementation and development of a general management plan and of a comprehensive interpretive program of the natural, historic, and cultural resources of the Region.</textblock>
    <textblock>The matters to be discussed at this meeting include:</textblock>
    <textblock>_General Park Update</textblock>
    <textblock>_Lake Salvado Erosion Barrier</textblock>
    <textblock>_General Management Plan</textblock>
    <textblock>_Natural Resources Protection Program</textblock>
    <textblock>_Proposed Wildlife and Recreation Zone</textblock>
    <textblock>_Nutria Populations</textblock>
    <textblock>_Old Business</textblock>
    <textblock>_New Business</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be open to the public. However, facilities and space for accommodating members of the public are limited, and persons will be accommodated on a first-come-first-served basis. Any member of the public may file a written statement concerning the matters to be discussed with the Superintendent, Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve.</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons wishing further information concerning this meeting, or who wish to submit written statements may contact Robert Belous, Superintendent, Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve, 365 Canal Street, suite 3080, New Orleans, Louisiana 70130, Telephone 504/589-3882.</textblock>
    <textblock>Minutes of the meeting will be available for public inspection four weeks after the meeting at the office of Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 2, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Delta Region Preservation Commission; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John E. Cook,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Regional Director, Southwest Region.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3544 Filed 2-15-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-70-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
