<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00219</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>The movement of the gasoline produced using the</textblock>
    <textblock>operation to the point of fungible mixing, including any</textblock>
    <textblock>points where all or portions of the gasoline produced is</textblock>
    <textblock>accumulated in gasoline storage tanks;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)</textblock>
    <textblock>The physical lay-out of the operation;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6)</textblock>
    <textblock>The automated control system, including the method</textblock>
    <textblock>of monitoring and controlling blend properties and</textblock>
    <textblock>proportions;</textblock>
    <textblock>(7)</textblock>
    <textblock>Any sampling and analysis of gasoline that is</textblock>
    <textblock>conducted as a part of the operation, including on-line,</textblock>
    <textblock>off-line, and composite, and a description of the methods of</textblock>
    <textblock>sampling, the methods of analysis, the parameters analyzed</textblock>
    <textblock>and the frequency of such analyses, and any written,</textblock>
    <textblock>printed, or computer-stored results of such analyses,</textblock>
    <textblock>including information on the retention of such results;</textblock>
    <textblock>(8)</textblock>
    <textblock>Any sampling and analysis of gasoline produced by</textblock>
    <textblock>the operation that occurs downstream from the blending</textblock>
    <textblock>operation prior to fungible mixing of the gasoline,</textblock>
    <textblock>including any such sampling and analysis by the refiner and</textblock>
    <textblock>by any purchaser, pipeline or other carrier, or by</textblock>
    <textblock>independent laboratories;</textblock>
    <textblock>(9)</textblock>
    <textblock>Any quality assurance procedures that are carried</textblock>
    <textblock>out over the operation; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(10)</textblock>
    <textblock>Any occasion(s) during the previous three years</textblock>
    <textblock>when the refiner adjusted any physical or chemical property</textblock>
    <textblock>of any gasoline produced using the operation downstream from</textblock>
    <textblock>the operation, including the nature of the adjustment and</textblock>
    <textblock>the reason the gasoline had properties that required</textblock>
    <textblock>adjustment; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) A description of the independent audit program of</textblock>
    <textblock>the refiner's computer-controlled in-line blending operation</textblock>
    <textblock>that the refiner proposes will satisfy the requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>this paragraph (f)(4); and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Carries out an independent audit program of the</textblock>
    <textblock>refiner's computer-controlled in-line blending operation,</textblock>
    <textblock>such program to include:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) For each batch of reformulated gasoline produced</textblock>
    <textblock>using the operation, a review of the documents generated</textblock>
    <textblock>that is sufficient to determine the properties and volume of</textblock>
    <textblock>the gasoline produced;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Audits that occur no less frequently than</textblock>
    <textblock>annually;</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Reports of the results of such audits submitted to</textblock>
    <textblock>the refiner, and to EPA by the auditor no later than</textblock>
    <textblock>February 28 of each year;</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) Audits that are conducted by an auditor that meets</textblock>
    <textblock>the non-debarred criteria specified in ยง80.125 (a) and/or</textblock>
    <textblock>(d); and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Complies with any other requirements that EPA</textblock>
    <textblock>includes as part of the exemption.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Marking of conventional gasoline.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Reserved]</textblock>
    <textblock>(h)</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance audits.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any refiner, importer, and</textblock>
    <textblock>oxygenate blender of any reformulated gasoline or RBOB shall</textblock>
    <textblock>have the reformulated gasoline or RBOB it produced,</textblock>
    <textblock>imported, or blended during each calendar year audited for</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance with the requirements of this subpart D, in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with the requirements of subpart F of this part,</textblock>
    <textblock>at the conclusion of each calendar year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Exclusion from compliance calculations of gasoline</textblock>
    <textblock>received from others.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any refiner for each refinery, any</textblock>
    <textblock>oxygenate blender for each oxygenate blending facility, and</textblock>
    <textblock>any importer shall exclude from all compliance calculations</textblock>
    <textblock>the volume and properties of any reformulated gasoline that</textblock>
    <textblock>is produced at another refinery or oxygenate blending</textblock>
    <textblock>facility or imported by another importer.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง80.66</textblock>
    <textblock>Calculation of reformulated gasoline properties.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) All volume measurements required by these</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations shall be temperature adjusted to 60 degrees</textblock>
    <textblock>Fahrenheit.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
