<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force Monitoring Committee Meeting</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Interior, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice announces a meeting of the Monitoring Committee (Committee), a committee of the Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force. A number of subjects will be discussed during the Committee meeting including: continuation of the review of monitoring programs collecting data concerning nonindigenous species and further development of a pilot program to acquire data from existing monitoring programs.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Monitoring Committee will meet from 9 a.m. to 3 p.m. on Thursday, March 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Monitoring Committee meeting will be held at the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service Building, room 200A, 4401 N. Fairfax Drive, Arlington, Virginia 22203.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. James Weaver, National Fisheries Research Center, 7920 NW. 71st Street, Gainesville, Florida 32606 at (904) 378-8181.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App. I), this notice announces a meeting of the Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force Monitoring Committee established under the authority of the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 (Pub. L. 101-646, 104 Stat. 4761, 16 U.S.C. 4701</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.,</textblock>
    <textblock>November 29, 1990). Minutes of the meetings will be maintained by the Coordinator, Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force, room 840, 4401 North Fairfax Drive, Arlington, Virginia 22203 and the Monitoring Committee Chairman, National Fisheries Research Center, 7920 NW. 71st Street, Gainesville, Florida 32606 and will be available for public inspection during regular business hours, Monday through Friday within 30 days following the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Gary Edwards,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Director_Fisheries, Co-Chair, Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3559 Filed 2-15-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-55-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
