<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-1-00028</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>16. In §261.12, the introductory text is republished, paragraph (a) is revised and new paragraphs (e) through (g) are added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§261.12</textblock>
    <textblock>Forest development roads and trails.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following are prohibited:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Violating the load, weight, height, length, or width limitations prescribed by State law except by contract, special use authorization, approved plan of operations, written agreement or by order issued under §261.54 of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Operating any vehicle in violation of State law, posted sign or traffic device.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) Operating a vehicle carelessly, recklessly, or in a manner or at a speed that would endanger or be likely to endanger any person or property.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g) Operating or riding in any vehicle on a Forest development road without wearing seatbelts, if provided by the manufacturer.</textblock>
    <textblock>17. Revise §261.13 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§261.13</textblock>
    <textblock>Use of vehicles off roads.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is prohibited to operate any vehicle off Forest development, State or County roads:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Without a valid operator's license or permit in possession if required by State law.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Without an operable braking system.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) From one-half hour after sunset to one-half hour before sunrise unless equipped with working head and tail lights.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) In violation of any applicable noise emission standard established by any Federal or State agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Creating excessive or unusual smoke.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) Carelessly, recklessly, or in a manner or at speed that would endanger or be likely to endanger any person or property.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g) In a manner which damages the land or vegetative resources, or injures or unreasonably disturbs wildlife.</textblock>
    <textblock>(h) In violation of State law established for vehicles used off roads.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Without displaying a valid vehicle license or possessing a vehicle registration if required by State law.</textblock>
    <textblock>18. In §261.14, the introductory text is republished and a new paragraph (r) is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§261.14</textblock>
    <textblock>Developed recreation sites.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following are prohibited:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(r) Reserving any portion of the site for another person or party without permission of a Forest officer.</textblock>
    <textblock>19. Revise §261.15 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§261.15</textblock>
    <textblock>Admission, recreation use, and special recreation permit fees.</textblock>
    <textblock>Failure to comply with posted fee payment instructions for any fee established for admission or entrance to, or use of, a site, facility, equipment, or service furnished by the United States is prohibited. A violation of this section is an infraction and no sentence of imprisonment is authorized.</textblock>
    <textblock>20. Add a new §261.22 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§261.22</textblock>
    <textblock>Buildings used in furtherance of the administration of the National Forest System or Forest Service Programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following are prohibited in buildings owned or leased by the Forest Service:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Engaging in conduct which impedes or disrupts the performance of official duty or the safety of Government employees.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Engaging in conduct which prevents the general public from obtaining the services provided by the Government or its agents or contractors on the property.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Failing to submit packages, briefcases, or other containers for inspection, when required, prior to entrance.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Carrying, possessing, depositing, or placing firearms, other dangerous or deadly weapons, explosives, or items intended to be used to fabricate an explosive or incendiary device, unless authorized by special use authorization, contract, approved plan of operations, or Federal law or regulation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart B_Prohibitions in Areas Designated by Order</textblock>
    <textblock>21. In §261.50, revise paragraph (e)(1) as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§261.50</textblock>
    <textblock>Orders.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Persons who have specific authorization for the otherwise prohibited act or omission by virtue of a special use authorization, contract, approved plan of operations, or Federal law or regulation.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>22. In §261.53, the introductory text is republished and paragraph (a) is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§261.53</textblock>
    <textblock>Special closures.</textblock>
    <textblock>When provided by an order, it is prohibited to go into or be upon any area which is closed for the protection of:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) plants, animals, birds, fish, or shellfish.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>23. In §261.54, the introductory text is republished, paragraph (f) is removed and paragraphs (a) and (c) are revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§261.54</textblock>
    <textblock>Forest development roads.</textblock>
    <textblock>When provided by an order, the following are prohibited:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Using or possessing any type of vehicle prohibited by the order.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Using a road for commercial hauling or other commercial activities without a special use authorization or written authorization.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>24. Amend §261.58 by revising paragraphs (m) and (bb) and by adding paragraphs (dd), and (ee) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§261.58</textblock>
    <textblock>Occupancy and use.</textblock>
    <textblock>When provided by an order, the following are prohibited:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(m) Discharging or possessing a firearm, air rifle, gas gun, or other device capable of causing injury to persons or wildlife or capable of causing property damage.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(bb) Possessing an alcoholic beverage.</textblock>
    <textblock>(cc) *␣*␣*</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
