<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00007</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Central Hudson Gas &amp; Electric Corp.; Filing</textblock>
    <textblock>February 10, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 13, 1994, Central Hudson Gas &amp; Electric Corporation (CH&amp;E) tendered for filing an amendment to FERC Contract No. 26 dated August 26, 1993 between CHG&amp;E and New York State Electric and Gas Corporation (NYSEG). The amended contract provides for an increase in the facilities charge associated with investment at the Smithfield Substation due to the replacement of a motor-operated manually controlled air break switch with a supervisory controlled circuit breaker.</textblock>
    <textblock>The facilities charge increases from $57.00 per month to $2,410.00 per month and is retroactive to August 16, 1991 the date on which the circuit breaker was placed in service. The update to the facilities charge was delayed until final closure of the Work Order for the system modifications.</textblock>
    <textblock>CHG&amp;E requests waiver of the FERC advance notice requirement set forth in 18 CFR 35.11.</textblock>
    <textblock>All other provisions of FERC Contract No. 26 shall remain in effect. CHG&amp;E states that copies of the subject filing were served upon NYSEG.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rules 211 and 214 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (18 CFR 385.211 and 18 CFR 385.214). All such motions or protests should be filed on or before February 18, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-304-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3556 Filed 2-15-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
