<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00256</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Refiner and importer responsibility.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Each</textblock>
    <textblock>refiner and importer required to have its baseline verified</textblock>
    <textblock>by an auditor (per paragraph (a)(1) of this section) is</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible for utilizing an auditor for baseline</textblock>
    <textblock>verification which meets the requirements specified in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraphs (b) and (c) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A refiner's or importer's baseline submission will</textblock>
    <textblock>not be accepted until it has been verified using an auditor</textblock>
    <textblock>which meets the requirements specified in paragraphs (b) and</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Auditor responsibilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The auditor</textblock>
    <textblock>must verify that all baseline submission requirements are</textblock>
    <textblock>fulfilled. This includes, but is not limited to, the</textblock>
    <textblock>following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Verifying that all data is correctly accounted</textblock>
    <textblock>for;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Verifying that all calculations are performed</textblock>
    <textblock>correctly;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Verifying that all adjustments to the data and/or</textblock>
    <textblock>calculations to account for post-1990 data, work-in-progress,</textblock>
    <textblock>and/or extenuating or other circumstances, as</textblock>
    <textblock>allowed per §80.91, are valid and performed correctly.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The primary analyst shall prepare and sign a</textblock>
    <textblock>statement, to be included in the baseline submission of the</textblock>
    <textblock>refiner or importer, stating that:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) He/she has thoroughly reviewed the sampling</textblock>
    <textblock>methodology and baseline calculations; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) To the best of his/her knowledge, the requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>and intentions of the rulemaking are met in the baseline</textblock>
    <textblock>determination; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) He/she agrees with the final baseline parameter,</textblock>
    <textblock>volume and emission values listed in the baseline</textblock>
    <textblock>submission.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The auditor may be subject to debarment under U.S.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>1001 if it displays gross incompetency, intentionally</textblock>
    <textblock>commits an error in the verification process or</textblock>
    <textblock>misrepresents itself or information in the baseline</textblock>
    <textblock>verification.</textblock>
    <textblock>§80.93</textblock>
    <textblock>Individual baseline submission and approval.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Submission timing.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Each refiner, blender or</textblock>
    <textblock>importer shall submit two copies of its individual baseline</textblock>
    <textblock>to EPA (Fuel Studies and Standards Branch, Baseline</textblock>
    <textblock>Submission, U.S. EPA, 2565 Plymouth Rd., Ann Arbor, MI</textblock>
    <textblock>48105) not later than June 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If a refiner must collect data after December 15,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993 (per §80.91(d)(2)), it shall submit two copies of its</textblock>
    <textblock>individual baseline to EPA (per §80.93(a)(1)) by September</textblock>
    <textblock>1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)(i) All petitions required for baseline</textblock>
    <textblock>adjustments or methodology deviations will be approved or</textblock>
    <textblock>disapproved by the Director of the Office of Mobile Sources,</textblock>
    <textblock>or designee. All instances where a ``showing'' or other proof</textblock>
    <textblock>is required are also subject to approval by the Director of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Office of Mobile Sources, or designee.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Auditor-verified petitions, ``showings'' and other</textblock>
    <textblock>associated proof may be submitted to EPA (per §80.93(a)(1))</textblock>
    <textblock>prior to the official submittal of the entire baseline</textblock>
    <textblock>determination. EPA will attempt to review and approve,</textblock>
    <textblock>disapprove or otherwise comment on the petition, etc., prior</textblock>
    <textblock>to the deadline for baseline submittal.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) In the event that EPA does not comment on the</textblock>
    <textblock>petition prior to the deadline for baseline submittal, the</textblock>
    <textblock>refiner or importer must still comply with the applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>baseline submittal deadline.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) If a baseline recalculation is required per</textblock>
    <textblock>§80.91(f), documentation and recalculation of all affected</textblock>
    <textblock>baselines shall be submitted to EPA within 30 days of the</textblock>
    <textblock>previous baseline(s) becoming inaccurate due to the</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances outlined in §80.91(f).</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Submission content.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Individual baseline</textblock>
    <textblock>submissions shall include, at minimum, the information</textblock>
    <textblock>specified in this paragraph (b).</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) During its</textblock>
    <textblock>review and evaluation of the baseline submission, EPA may</textblock>
    <textblock>require a refiner or importer to submit additional</textblock>
    <textblock>information in support of the baseline determination.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Additional information which may assist EPA during</textblock>
    <textblock>its review and evaluation of the baseline may be included at</textblock>
    <textblock>the submitter's discretion.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Administrative information shall include:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Name and business address of the refiner or</textblock>
    <textblock>importer;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Name, business address and business phone number</textblock>
    <textblock>of the company contact;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Address and physical location of each refinery,</textblock>
    <textblock>terminal or import facility;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Address and physical location where documents</textblock>
    <textblock>which are supportive of the baseline determination for each</textblock>
    <textblock>facility are kept;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The chief executive officer statement shall be:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) A statement signed by the chief executive officer</textblock>
    <textblock>of the company, or designee, which states that:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The company is complying with the requirements as</textblock>
    <textblock>a refiner, blender or importer, as appropriate;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The data used in the baseline determination is the</textblock>
    <textblock>extent of the data available for the determination of all</textblock>
    <textblock>required baseline fuel parameters;</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) All calculations and procedures followed per</textblock>
    <textblock>§§80.90 through 80.93 have been done correctly;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
