<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00234</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>§80.74</textblock>
    <textblock>Record keeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>All parties in the gasoline distribution network, as</textblock>
    <textblock>described in this section, shall maintain records containing</textblock>
    <textblock>the information as required in this section. These records</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be retained for a period of five years from the date</textblock>
    <textblock>of creation, and shall be delivered to the Administrator of</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA or to the Administrator's authorized representative upon</textblock>
    <textblock>request.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>All regulated parties.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any refiner, importer,</textblock>
    <textblock>oxygenate blender, carrier, distributor, reseller, retailer,</textblock>
    <textblock>or wholesale-purchaser who sells, offers for sale,</textblock>
    <textblock>dispenses, supplies, offers for supply, stores, transports,</textblock>
    <textblock>or causes the transportation of any reformulated gasoline or</textblock>
    <textblock>RBOB, shall maintain records containing the following</textblock>
    <textblock>information:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The product transfer documentation for all</textblock>
    <textblock>reformulated gasoline or RBOB for which the party is the</textblock>
    <textblock>transferor or transferee; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For any sampling and testing on RBOB or</textblock>
    <textblock>reformulated gasoline:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The location, date, time, and storage tank or</textblock>
    <textblock>truck identification for each sample collected;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The identification of the person who collected the</textblock>
    <textblock>sample and the person who performed the testing;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The results of the tests; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The actions taken to stop the sale of any gasoline</textblock>
    <textblock>found not to be in compliance, and the actions taken to</textblock>
    <textblock>identify the cause of any noncompliance and prevent future</textblock>
    <textblock>instances of noncompliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Refiners and importers.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to other</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of this section, any refiner and importer</textblock>
    <textblock>shall, for all reformulated gasoline and RBOB produced or</textblock>
    <textblock>imported, maintain records containing the following</textblock>
    <textblock>information:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Results of the tests to determine reformulated</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline properties and characteristics specified in</textblock>
    <textblock>§80.65;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Results of the tests for the presence of the</textblock>
    <textblock>marker specified in §80.82;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The volume of gasoline associated with each of the</textblock>
    <textblock>above test results using the method normally employed at the</textblock>
    <textblock>refinery or import facility for this purpose;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) In the case of RBOB:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The results of tests to ensure that, following</textblock>
    <textblock>blending, RBOB meets applicable standards; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Each contract with each oxygenate blender to whom</textblock>
    <textblock>the refiner or importer transfers RBOB; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Compliance calculations described in §80.69(a)(8)</textblock>
    <textblock>based on an assumed addition of oxygenate;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) In the case of any refinery or importer subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>the simple model standards, the calculations used to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine the 1990 baseline levels of sulfur, T-90, and</textblock>
    <textblock>olefins, and the calculations used to determine compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>with the standards for these parameters; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) In the case of any refinery or importer subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>the complex model standards before January 1, 1998, the</textblock>
    <textblock>calculations used to determine the baseline levels of VOC,</textblock>
    <textblock>toxics, and NO</textblock>
    <textblock>x</textblock>
    <textblock>emissions performance.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Refiners, importers and oxygenate blenders of</textblock>
    <textblock>averaged gasoline.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to other requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section, any refiner, importer, and oxygenate blender</textblock>
    <textblock>who produces or imports any reformulated gasoline for which</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance with one or more applicable standard is</textblock>
    <textblock>determined on average shall maintain records containing the</textblock>
    <textblock>following information:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The calculations used to determine compliance with</textblock>
    <textblock>the relevant standards on average, for each averaging period</textblock>
    <textblock>and for each quantity of gasoline for which standards must</textblock>
    <textblock>be separately achieved; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For any credits bought, sold, traded or</textblock>
    <textblock>transferred pursuant to §80.67(h), the dates of the</textblock>
    <textblock>transactions, the names and EPA registration numbers of the</textblock>
    <textblock>parties involved, and the number(s) and type(s) of credits</textblock>
    <textblock>transferred.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Oxygenate blenders.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to other</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of this section, any oxygenate blender who</textblock>
    <textblock>blends any oxygenate with any RBOB shall, for each occasion</textblock>
    <textblock>such terminal storage tank blending occurs, maintain records</textblock>
    <textblock>containing the following information:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The date, time, location, and identification of</textblock>
    <textblock>the blending tank or truck in which the blending occurred;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The volume and oxygenate requirements of the RBOB</textblock>
    <textblock>to which oxygenate was added; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The volume, type, and purity of the oxygenate</textblock>
    <textblock>which was added, and documents which show the source(s) of</textblock>
    <textblock>the oxygenate used.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Distributors who dispense RBOB into trucks.</textblock>
    <textblock>In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition to other requirements of this section, any</textblock>
    <textblock>distributor who dispenses any RBOB into a truck used for</textblock>
    <textblock>delivering gasoline to retail outlets shall, for each</textblock>
    <textblock>occasion RBOB is dispensed into such a truck, obtain records</textblock>
    <textblock>identifying:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The name and EPA registration number of the</textblock>
    <textblock>oxygenate blender that received the RBOB; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The volume and oxygenate requirements of the RBOB</textblock>
    <textblock>dispensed.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
