<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00270</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(ii) Trace back to the batch or batches in which the</textblock>
    <textblock>non-finished-gasoline petroleum product was produced or</textblock>
    <textblock>imported. Obtain the refiner's or importer's internal</textblock>
    <textblock>laboratory analysis for each batch and compare such analysis</textblock>
    <textblock>for consistency with the product-type assigned by the</textblock>
    <textblock>refiner or importer (e.g., alkylate, isobutane, etc.), and</textblock>
    <textblock>agree that this product type is excluded from the applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>blendstock list at ยง80.102(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) In the case of a refiner or importer required to</textblock>
    <textblock>account for blendstocks produced or imported under</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง80.102(e)(2):</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Obtain listings for those tenders of non-finished-gasoline tenders classified by the refiner or importer as:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Blendstock which is included in the compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>calculations for the refinery or importer; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) All other non-finished-gasoline petroleum</textblock>
    <textblock>products;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Test the mathematical accuracy of the calculations</textblock>
    <textblock>contained in the listings under paragraph (i)(1) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Agree the listings of tenders' volumes to the</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline inventory reconciliation in paragraph (b) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Select a representative sample from the listing of</textblock>
    <textblock>blendstock tenders which are included in the compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>calculations for the refinery or importer, and for such</textblock>
    <textblock>sample:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Agree the volumes to records supporting the</textblock>
    <textblock>transfer of the tender to another person;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Review the product transfer documents for the</textblock>
    <textblock>statement indicating the blendstock has been accounted-for,</textblock>
    <textblock>and may not be included in another party's compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>calculations; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Trace back to the batch or batches in which the</textblock>
    <textblock>blendstock was produced or imported. Obtain the refiner's</textblock>
    <textblock>or importer's internal laboratory analyses for each batch</textblock>
    <textblock>and compare such analyses for consistency with the analyses</textblock>
    <textblock>results reported to EPA; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Select a representative sample from the listing of</textblock>
    <textblock>tenders of non-finished-gasoline petroleum products that are</textblock>
    <textblock>excluded from the refiner's or importer's compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>calculations, and for such sample confirm that documents</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrate the petroleum products were used for a purpose</textblock>
    <textblock>other than the production of gasoline within the United</textblock>
    <textblock>States.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง80.129</textblock>
    <textblock>Agreed upon procedures for downstream oxygenate blenders.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following are the procedures to be carried out at</textblock>
    <textblock>each oxygenate blending facility that is subject to the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of this subpart F:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Read the blenders reports filed with the EPA for</textblock>
    <textblock>the previous year as required by ยง80.75.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Obtain a material balance analysis summarizing</textblock>
    <textblock>receipts of RBOB and oxygenate to the blender, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>deliveries of reformulated gasoline from the blender.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Test the mathematical accuracy of the calculations</textblock>
    <textblock>contained in the analysis.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Agree the beginning and ending inventory to the</textblock>
    <textblock>blender's perpetual inventory records.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Agree the analysis, where applicable, to the EPA</textblock>
    <textblock>reports.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Obtain a listing of all RBOB receipts for the</textblock>
    <textblock>previous year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Test the mathematical accuracy of the volumetric</textblock>
    <textblock>calculations contained in the listing.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Agree the volumetric calculations of RBOB receipts</textblock>
    <textblock>to the calculations contained in the material balance</textblock>
    <textblock>analysis.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
