<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00025</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>2. Apportionment of Reserves to DAP</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations implementing the FMP require 20 percent of each TAC for pollock, Pacific cod, flatfish species, and the ``other species'' category be set aside in reserves for possible apportionment at a later date (ยง672.20(a)(2)(ii)). For the preceding 6 years, including 1993, NMFS has apportioned all of the reserves to DAP effective on January 1. For 1994, NMFS apportions reserves for each species category to DAP, anticipating that domestic harvesters and processors will need all the DAP amounts. Specifications of DAP shown in Table 1 reflect apportioned reserves. Under</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง672.20(d)(5)(iv), the public may submit comments on the apportionments of reserves. Comments should focus on whether, and the extent to which, operators of vessels of the United States will harvest reserve or DAP amounts during the remainder of the year and whether, and the extent to which, U.S. harvested groundfish can or will be processed by U.S. fish processors or received at sea by foreign fishing vessels.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Assignment of the Sablefish TACs to Authorized Fishing Gear Users</textblock>
    <textblock>Under ยง672.24(c), sablefish TACs for each of the regulatory areas and districts are assigned to hook-and-line and trawl gear. In the Western and Central Regulatory Areas, 80 percent of each TAC is assigned to hook-and-line gear and 20 percent to trawl gear. In the Eastern Regulatory Area, 95 percent of the TAC is assigned to hook-and-line gear and 5 percent is assigned to trawl gear. The trawl gear allocation in the Eastern Regulatory Area may only be used as bycatch to support directed fisheries for other target species. Sablefish caught in the GOA with gear other than hook-and-line or trawl gear must be treated as prohibited species and may not be retained. Table 2 shows the assignments of the 1994 sablefish TACs between hook-and-line and trawl gear.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table</textblock>
    <textblock>2._1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Sablefish TAC Specifications in the Gulf of Alaska and Assignments Thereof to Hook-And-Line and Trawl Gear</textblock>
    <textblock>[Values are in metric tons]</textblock>
    <textblock>1Area/district</textblock>
    <textblock>1TAC</textblock>
    <textblock>1Hook-and-line share</textblock>
    <textblock>1Trawl share</textblock>
    <textblock>Western</textblock>
    <textblock>2,290</textblock>
    <textblock>1,832</textblock>
    <textblock>458</textblock>
    <textblock>Central</textblock>
    <textblock>11,220</textblock>
    <textblock>8,976</textblock>
    <textblock>2,244</textblock>
    <textblock>West Yakutat</textblock>
    <textblock>4,850</textblock>
    <textblock>4,608</textblock>
    <textblock>242</textblock>
    <textblock>Southeast Outside</textblock>
    <textblock>7,140</textblock>
    <textblock>6,783</textblock>
    <textblock>357</textblock>
    <textblock>n,s</textblock>
    <textblock>Total</textblock>
    <textblock>25,500</textblock>
    <textblock>22,199</textblock>
    <textblock>3,301</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
