<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00065</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>I. Phase I Performance Standards Under the Complex Model</textblock>
    <textblock>All fuels produced during Phase I of the reformulated gasoline program must meet the VOC, toxics, and NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of the Act. Fuels certified using the complex model in Phase I must show either no increase in NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>emissions from baseline levels on a per-gallon basis as discussed in the February 1993 proposal or a 1.5% reduction from baseline levels on average as discussed in Section VII. In addition, as discussed in Section III.E., such fuels must result in either a 15% reduction in total toxics emissions from baseline levels on a per-gallon basis or a 16.5% reduction in total toxics emissions from baseline levels on average.</textblock>
    <textblock>With regard to the VOC standards, EPA considers fuels produced to meet the provisions of the simple model to be producible. Thus, as discussed in the February 1993 proposal, EPA believes it feasible to base the Phase I standards for VOC emissions on the performance of fuels that meet the Simple Model requirements, provided that this performance is more stringent than minimum performance required by the Act. EPA considers the fuels whose VOC performances were evaluated in Section IV.H to be representative of Simple Model fuels. Under the reformulated gasoline program, VOC emissions are controlled only during the high ozone season. For this reason, the VOC performance standard has been determined by the performance of the Phase I summer fuels presented in Section IV.H. Since these fuels achieve emissons reductions that equal or exceed the minimum requirements set forth in the Act, the VOC performance standard during Phase I for fuels certified under the complex model has been based on the performance of these fuels. Setting the VOC performance standards in 1998-1999 equal to this VOC performance level, which EPA believes to be a reasonable estimate of the average performance of fuels produced in 1995-1997, preserves the integrity of the two-phase program specified by Congress and is consistent with the Agreement in Principle signed in 1991.</textblock>
    <textblock>The summer VOC performance of ``typical'' high ozone season simple model reformulated gasolines according to the complex model is presented in Table IV-6. In VOC Control Region 1, the simple model fuel reduces VOC emissions by 36.6 percent for the MTBE-containing fuel (Fuel 1) and 36.8 percent for the ethanol-containing fuel (Fuel 5). Since the 1998 performance requirements in VOC Control Region 1 are to be based on the performance of typical simple model fuels, and since Fuels 1 and 5 both satisfy the simple model requirements and are considered by EPA to be representative of typical simple model fuels, EPA has set its 1998 performance standards in VOC Control Region 1 so as to permit both of these fuels to meet the 1998 performance standards. In addition, EPA considers Fuel 1 to be more representative of typical simple model fuels in VOC Control Region 1 since MTBE does not boost fuel RVP levels to the extent that ethanol does. As was discussed in the April 1992 and February 1993 proposals, EPA believes that per-gallon performance standard should be set 1.5 percentage points below the averaging performance standard. Hence high ozone season fuels certified using the complex model during Phase I of the reformulated gasoline program must provide a VOC emission reduction from baseline levels of 36.6 percent when complying on average and 35.1 percent when complying on a per-gallon basis. Similarly, high ozone season fuels certified using the complex model during Phase I in VOC Control Region 2 must provide a VOC emission reduction from baseline levels of 17.1 percent when complying on average and 15.6 percent when complying on a per-gallon basis. These standards are summarized in Table IV-7 for both VOC control regions, under averaging and per-gallon compliance. Note that a negative performance standard signifies a reduction from baseline emission levels.</textblock>
    <textblock>In summary, the per-gallon and averaging VOC performance standards under the complex model during Phase I is set by the performance of the corresponding simple model fuel when evaluated using the complex model. The toxics performance standard is set at the statutory requirement of a 15 percent reduction from baseline levels for per-gallon compliance and a 16.5 percent reduction for compliance on average. Similarly, the NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>performance standard under the complex model during Phase I must satisfy the no NO</textblock>
    <textblock>x</textblock>
    <textblock>increase requirement on a per-gallon basis, or meet a 1.5% reduction for compliance on average.</textblock>
    <textblock>V. Augmenting the Models Through Testing</textblock>
    <textblock>During the regulatory negotiation process, vehicle testing and emission modeling procedures for certifying that a gasoline complies with the NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>, toxics, and VOC requirements were discussed. Emission models such as the simple model described in Section III and the complex model described in Section IV offer several advantages over testing to determine emission effects. First, models can better reflect in-use emission effects since they can be based on the results of multiple test programs. Second, individual test programs may be intentionally or unintentionally biased due to vehicle selection, test design, and analysis methods. Third, fuel compositions tend to vary due in part to factors beyond the control of fuel suppliers such as variations in crude oil compositions and the inherent variability of refining processes. As a result, without one or more modeling options, each batch of fuel would have to be tested to ascertain its emission performance. Such levels of testing are neither desirable (because of the potential for intentional or unintentional bias in vehicle test programs) nor practical (because of the time and expense involved in vehicle testing). Fourth, models make more efficient use of scarce and expensive emission effects data than is possible otherwise. For these reasons, EPA believes that the modeling options outlined above are necessary for the reformulated gasoline program to achieve its environmental objectives and to minimize the costs of the program.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table IV-</textblock>
    <textblock>6._</textblock>
    <textblock>Performance of Typical Simple Model Fuels Under the Phase I Complex Model</textblock>
    <textblock>[Under Averaging]1</textblock>
    <textblock>1Fuel</textblock>
    <textblock>1Emission reduction versus CAAB fuel (percent)</textblock>
    <textblock>2Exhaust VOC</textblock>
    <textblock>2 Nonexhaust VOC</textblock>
    <textblock>2Total VOC</textblock>
    <textblock>2NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>2Toxics</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>7.92</textblock>
    <textblock>51.42</textblock>
    <textblock>36.57</textblock>
    <textblock>1.46</textblock>
    <textblock>27.33</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>5.35</textblock>
    <textblock>23.93</textblock>
    <textblock>17.11</textblock>
    <textblock>1.28</textblock>
    <textblock>24.57</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>0.33</textblock>
    <textblock>N/A</textblock>
    <textblock>0.33</textblock>
    <textblock>^0.21</textblock>
    <textblock>12.83</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>0.80</textblock>
    <textblock>0.00</textblock>
    <textblock>0.80</textblock>
    <textblock>0.04</textblock>
    <textblock>13.87</textblock>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
    <textblock>8.64</textblock>
    <textblock>51.42</textblock>
    <textblock>36.82</textblock>
    <textblock>1.90</textblock>
    <textblock>25.70</textblock>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
    <textblock>6.09</textblock>
    <textblock>23.93</textblock>
    <textblock>17.38</textblock>
    <textblock>1.76</textblock>
    <textblock>22.56</textblock>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
    <textblock>3.55</textblock>
    <textblock>N/A</textblock>
    <textblock>3.56</textblock>
    <textblock>0.58</textblock>
    <textblock>11.52</textblock>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
    <textblock>4.01</textblock>
    <textblock>N/A</textblock>
    <textblock>4.01</textblock>
    <textblock>0.88</textblock>
    <textblock>12.48</textblock>
    <textblock>1Performance of summer fuels (</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>s 1, 2, 5, 6) given relative to that of Clean Air Act summer baseline fuel. Performance of winter fuels (#s 3, 4, 7, 8) given relative to that of the winter baseline fuel defined in Section III.</textblock>
  </table>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table IV-</textblock>
    <textblock>7._</textblock>
    <textblock>Reformulated Gasoline Performance Standards Relative to Clean Air Act Baseline Gasoline for 1998-1999</textblock>
    <textblock>[Percent]</textblock>
    <textblock>1Emission</textblock>
    <textblock>1VOC control region 1</textblock>
    <textblock>2Average</textblock>
    <textblock>2Per gallon</textblock>
    <textblock>1VOC control region 2</textblock>
    <textblock>2Average</textblock>
    <textblock>2Per gallon</textblock>
    <textblock>VOC</textblock>
    <textblock>^36.6</textblock>
    <textblock>^35.1</textblock>
    <textblock>^17.1</textblock>
    <textblock>^15.6</textblock>
    <textblock>Toxics</textblock>
    <textblock>^16.5</textblock>
    <textblock>^15.0</textblock>
    <textblock>^16.5</textblock>
    <textblock>^15.0</textblock>
    <textblock>NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>^1.5</textblock>
    <textblock>0.0</textblock>
    <textblock>^1.5</textblock>
    <textblock>0.0</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
