<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-1-00006</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-1-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>3. Sections 800.208 and 800.210 are added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§800.208</textblock>
    <textblock>Engage in.</textblock>
    <textblock>The term</textblock>
    <textblock>engage in,</textblock>
    <textblock>as used in the phrase</textblock>
    <textblock>seeks to engage in any merger, acquisition or takeover</textblock>
    <textblock>in section 721(b), means</textblock>
    <textblock>seeks to acquire control through.</textblock>
    <textblock>§800.210</textblock>
    <textblock>Foreign government.</textblock>
    <textblock>The term foreign government</textblock>
    <textblock>means any government or body exercising governmental functions, other than the government of the United States, a State of the United States, or a political subdivision of the United States or a State. The term includes but is not limited to national, state, provincial and municipal governments, including their respective departments, agencies, government-owned enterprises and other agencies and instrumentalities.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Newly designated §800.222 is amended by revising the reference ``§800.211'' in Example 1 to read ``§800.213''.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Section 800.301 is amended by revising the third sentence in Example 1 of paragraph (b)(5) to read as follows: §800.301 Transactions that are acquisitions under Section 721.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 1. *␣*␣* Under the Articles of Incorporation of JV Corp., Corp. A through its shareholding in JV Corp. may elect a majority of the Board of Directors of JV Corp. *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Section 800.302 is amended by revising the reference ``§800.217'' in paragraph (d) introductory text to read ``§800.219''.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Section 800.401 is amended by revising ``ten copies'' in paragraph (a) to read ``thirteen copies''.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Section 800.402 is amended by revising paragraph (c)(3)(v)(A), by removing the word ``and'' at the end of paragraph (c)(5)(i), by removing the period at the end of paragraph (c)(5)(ii)(E), and replacing it with a semicolon, be adding paragraphs (c)(5)(iii) and (iv), and by adding paragraph (i) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§800.402</textblock>
    <textblock>Contents of voluntary notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) *␣*␣*</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
