<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00004</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00003</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Final Environmental Impact Statement To Assess the Impacts of Stationing Mechanized or Armored Forces at Fort Lewis, WA</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Department of the Army</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Defense, United States Army.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>As part of the worldwide reorganization of its force structure, the Army proposes to station heavy (armored or mechanized) combat units at Fort Lewis, Washington. This Final Environmental Impact Statement (FEIS) analyzes two stationing alternatives (one or two brigades) and the No Action Alternative. The One-Brigade Alternative results in approximately 4,000 additional troops and 500 tracked vehicles. Under the Two-Brigade Alternative, approximately 10,400 additional troops and 1,100 tracked vehicles would be assigned to Fort Lewis and its sub-installation, Yakima Training Center (YTC). New construction would be required to support either stationing alternative.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FEIS will be available for public review during a 30-day post-filing waiting period prior to the Army making the final decision on the stationing of mechanized and armored combat forces at Fort Lewis.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the FEIS will automatically be mailed to individuals who attended the scoping and public hearings meetings, commented during the public comment period and who requested copies. Copies will be sent to city, county, and federal officials, and civic organizations, and public libraries. Individuals not currently on the mailing list may obtain a copy of the FEIS by contacting Mr. Randall W. Hanna, Chief, Environmental and Natural Resources Division, Headquarters, I Corps and Fort Lewis, ATTN: AFZH-DEQ, Fort Lewis, Washington 98433-5000.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </address>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lewis D. Walker,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Assistant Secretary of the Army (Environmental, Safety, and Occupational Health), OASA (IL&amp;E).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3566 Filed 2-15-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3710-08-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
