<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00030</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Great Lakes Panel on Aquatic Nuisance Species; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Interior, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice announces a meeting of the Great Lakes Panel on Aquatic Nuisance Species (Great Lakes Panel), a regional committee of the Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force. A number of subjects will be discussed including: Implementation of the information/education strategy, development of the State comprehensive management plans, legislative and budget priorities, and research needs.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Great Lakes will meet from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. on Friday, March 11, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held at the Holiday Inn Madison West, 1313 John Q. Hammons Drive, Middleton, Wisconsin 53562-3500 at (608) 831-2000.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Lori Reynolds, Great Lakes Commission, The Argus Building, 400 Fourth Street, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48103 at (313) 665-9135.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App. I), this notice announces a meeting of the Great Lakes Panel on Aquatic Nuisance Species, a regional committee of the Aquatic Nuisance Species Task force established under the authority of the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 (Pub. L. 101-646, 104 Stat. 7461, 16 U.S.C. 4701</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.,</textblock>
    <textblock>November 29, 1990). Minutes of meeting will be maintained by Coordinator, Aquatic Nuisance Species Task force, room 840, 4401 North Fairfax Drive, Arlington, Virginia 22203 and the Great lakes Panel Coordinator, Great Lakes Commission, The Argus Building, 400 Fourth Street, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48103 and will be available for public inspection during regular business hours, Monday through Friday within 30 days following the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Gary Edwards,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Director_Fisheries, Co-Chair, Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3560 Filed 2-15-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-55-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
