<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00027</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>7. PSC Limits Relevant to Fully Utilized Species</textblock>
    <textblock>Under §672.20(b)(1), if NMFS determines, after consultation with the Council, that the TAC for any species or species group will be fully utilized in the DAP fishery, a groundfish PSC limit applicable to the JVP fisheries may be specified for that species or species group.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Council recommended that DAP equal TAC for each species category. Zero amounts of JVP are available. NMFS concurs with the Council's recommendation, and has not established any JVP amounts; therefore, no groundfish PSC limits under §672.20(b)(1) are necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Closures to Directed Fishing</textblock>
    <textblock>The ``proposed 1994 Initial Specifications of Groundfish and Associated Management Measures'' for the GOA (58 FR 60575, November 17, 1993) contained several closures to directed fishing for groundfish during 1994. The closures for the final specifications are listed in Table 5.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under §672.20(c)(2)(ii), the Regional Director determined that the entire TACs or allocations of TAC of some groundfish species and species groups will be needed as incidental catch to support other anticipated groundfish fisheries during 1994. The Regional Director is establishing directed fishing allowances of zero mt and prohibiting directed fishing for the remainder of the year for the fisheries listed in Table 5. Directed fishing standards for the aforementioned closures may be found at §672.20(g).</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Halibut Prohibited Species Catch (PSC) Mortality Limits</textblock>
    <textblock>Under §672.20(f)(2), annual Pacific halibut PSC limits are established and apportioned to trawl and hook-and-line gear and are established for pot gear. At its December 1993 meeting, the Council recommended that NMFS reestablish 1993 halibut PSC limits of 2,000 mt for trawl gear and 750 mt for hook-and-line gear for 1994. The hook-and-line halibut PSC limit is further apportioned between the DSR fishery (10 mt halibut mortality) and all other hook-and-line fisheries (740 mt).</textblock>
    <textblock>As in the proposed specifications, the Council recommended that pot gear be exempt from Pacific halibut PSC limits for the 1994 fishing year. The Council proposed this exemption after considering that the groundfish catch and associated halibut bycatch and mortality rates for pot gear are low (5 percent).</textblock>
    <textblock>At the September 1993 meeting, the Council recommended that NMFS prepare a rule for Secretarial approval that, if approved, would authorize separate apportionments of the trawl halibut bycatch mortality limit between trawl fisheries for the deep-water species complex (deep-water flatfish, rockfish, sablefish and arrowtooth flounder) and for the shallow-water species complex (pollock, Pacific cod, shallow-water flatfish, flathead sole, Atka mackerel, and ``other species''). At its December 1993 meeting, the Council further recommended that this action be implemented under emergency rulemaking so that it could be effective early in 1994. An emergency rule was prepared by NMFS and implemented February 7, 1994 (59 FR 6222, February 10, 1994). The emergency rule specifies trawl fishery apportionments of the 1994 GOA trawl halibut bycatch mortality limit and seasonal apportionments thereof. The emergency rule specifications supersede those set forth in this notice during the effective period of the emergency rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>NMFS concurs with the Council's recommendations listed above. The following types of information as presented in, and summarized from, the 1993 SAFE report, or as otherwise available from NMFS, Alaska Department of Fish and Game, the International Pacific Halibut Commission (IPHC) or public testimony were considered:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A)</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Halibut Bycatch in Prior Years</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table</textblock>
    <textblock>5._</textblock>
    <textblock>Closures to Directed Fishing for Total Allowable Catches Implemented by This Action</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>[Offshore = The Offshore Component; TRW = Trawl; ALL = All Gears; WG = Western Regulatory Area; CG = Central Regulatory Area; EG = Eastern Regulatory Area; GOA = Entire Gulf of Alaska]</textblock>
    <textblock>1Fishery</textblock>
    <textblock>1Component</textblock>
    <textblock>1Gear</textblock>
    <textblock>1Closed areas</textblock>
    <textblock>Atka mackerel</textblock>
    <textblock>ALL</textblock>
    <textblock>GOA</textblock>
    <textblock>Northern rockfish</textblock>
    <textblock>ALL</textblock>
    <textblock>EG</textblock>
    <textblock>Other rockfish2</textblock>
    <textblock>ALL</textblock>
    <textblock>WG,EG</textblock>
    <textblock>Pacific cod</textblock>
    <textblock>Offshore</textblock>
    <textblock>ALL</textblock>
    <textblock>WG,CG,EG</textblock>
    <textblock>Pacific ocean perch</textblock>
    <textblock>ALL</textblock>
    <textblock>WG,CG,EG</textblock>
    <textblock>Rex sole</textblock>
    <textblock>ALL</textblock>
    <textblock>WG</textblock>
    <textblock>Sablefish</textblock>
    <textblock>TRW</textblock>
    <textblock>WG,CG</textblock>
    <textblock>Shortraker/rougheye rockfish</textblock>
    <textblock>ALL</textblock>
    <textblock>WG,CG,EG</textblock>
    <textblock>Thornyhead rockfish</textblock>
    <textblock>ALL</textblock>
    <textblock>GOA</textblock>
    <textblock>1These closures to directed fishing are in addition to closures and prohibitions found in regulations at 50 CFR Part 672.</textblock>
    <textblock>2Other rockfish includes slope and demersal shelf rockfish in the WG and CG.</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
