<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00007</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Safety Zone; Illinois River</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Coast Guard</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>33 CFR Part 165</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[COTP St. Louis 94-003]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 2115-AA97</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Coast Guard, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Temporary final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard is establishing a safety zone on the Illinois River. The regulation is needed to protect tank barges from the hazards associated with ice. The regulation will restrict general navigation in the regulated area for the safety of vessel traffic and the protection of life and property along the river.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulation is effective January 25, 1994 and will terminate on March 10, 1994 unless sooner terminated by the Captain of the Port.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>LT Timothy Deal, Operations Officer, Captain of the Port, St. Louis, Missouri at (314) 539-3823.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Drafting Information</textblock>
    <textblock>The drafters of this regulation are MST1 Franz F. Karnuth, Project Officer, Marine Safety Office, St. Louis, Missouri and LCDR A. O. Denny, Project Attorney, Second Coast Guard District Legal Office.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory History</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with 5 U.S.C. 553, a notice of proposed rulemaking has not been published for this regulation and good cause exists for making it effective in less than 30 days from the date of publication. Following normal rulemaking procedures would have been impracticable. Specifically, severe weather conditions have developed hazardous icing conditions and insufficient time exists to publish a notice of proposed rulemaking. The Coast Guard deems it to be in the public's best interest to issue a regulation now as the conditions are presenting immediate hazards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Background and Purpose</textblock>
    <textblock>The hazards associated with icing conditions require immediate response to insure safe navigation and to prevent tank barge hull failure. Recent surveys of the regulated area by industry and Coast Guard representatives has established the need to impose restrictions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Evaluation</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulation is not considered a significant regulatory action under Executive Order 12866 and is not significant under Department of Transportation Regulatory Policies and Procedures (44 FR 11040; February 26, 1979), it will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities, and it contains no collection of information requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard expects the impact of this regulation to be so minimal that a Regulatory Evaluation is unnecessary. The imposed restrictions are anticipated to be of short duration. To avoid any unnecessary adverse economic impact on businesses which use the river for commercial purposes, Captain of the Port, St. Louis, Missouri will monitor the situation and will authorize entry into the closed area as conditions warrant. Changes will be announced by Marine Safety Information Radio Broadcast on VHF Marine Band Radio, Channel 22 (157.1 MHZ). Mariners may also call the Port Operations Officer, Captain of the Port, St. Louis, Missouri at (314) 539-3823 for current information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federalism Assessment</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the principles and criteria of Executive Order 12612, this regulation does not raise sufficient federalism implications to warrant the preparation of a Federalism Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Assessment</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard considered the environmental impact of this proposal and concluded that, under section 2.B.2.g.[5] of Commandant Instruction M16475.1B, this proposal is categorically excluded from further environmental documentation as an action to protect public safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 33 CFR Part 165</textblock>
    <textblock>Harbors, Marine safety, Navigation (water), Records and recordkeeping, Security measures, Waterways.</textblock>
    <textblock>Temporary Regulation</textblock>
    <textblock>In consideration of the foregoing, subpart C of part 165 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations, is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 165_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 165 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>33 U.S.C. 1231; 50 U.S.C. 191; 49 CFR 1.46 and 33 CFR 1.05-1(g), 6.04-1, 6.04-6, and 160.5.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. A temporary ยง165.T02-006 is added, to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง165.T02-006</textblock>
    <textblock>Safety zone: Upper Mississippi River.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Location.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Illinois River between mile 0.0 and 187.3 is established as a safety zone.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective dates.</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulation becomes effective on January 25, 1994 and will terminate on March 10, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The general regulations under ยง165.23 of this part which prohibit entry into the described zone without authority of the Captain of the Port apply. The Captain of the Port, St. Louis, Missouri will notify the maritime community of river conditions affecting the areas covered by this safety zone by Marine Safety Information Radio Broadcast on VHF Marine Band Radio, Channel 22 (157.1 MHZ).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Scott P. Cooper,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Commander, U.S. Coast Guard, Captain of the Port, St. Louis, Missouri.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3518 Filed 2-15-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-14-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
