<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00035</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Boston and Maine Corporation; Abandonment Exemption_Middlesex County, MA</textblock>
    <textblock>Springfield Terminal Railway Company_Discontinuance of Service Exemption; Middlesex County, MA</textblock>
    <textblock>Boston and Maine Corporation (B&amp;M) and Springfield Terminal Railway Company (ST) filed a notice of exemption under 49 CFR part 1152 Subpart F_Exempt Abandonments and Discontinuances to abandon and discontinue service over a segment of B&amp;M's rail line known as the Lowell Secondary Track, between milepost 24.27 and milepost 25.01, a distance of approximately 0.74 miles, in Lowell, Middlesex County, MA. B&amp;M seeks authority to abandon the line, and ST, which leases the line from B&amp;M, seeks authority to discontinue service over the line.</textblock>
    <textblock>B&amp;M and ST certify that: (1) No local traffic has moved over the line for at least 2 years; (2) overhead traffic, if any, has been rerouted over other lines; (3) no formal complaint filed by a user of rail service on the line (or by a state or local government entity acting on behalf of such user) regarding cessation of service over the line either is pending with the Commission or with any U.S. District Court or has been decided in favor of the complainant within the 2-year period; and (4) the requirements at 49 CFR 1105.7 (environmental reports), 49 CFR 1105.8 (historic reports), 49 CFR 1105.11 (transmittal letter), 49 CFR 1105.12 (newspaper publication),</textblock>
    <textblock>and 49 CFR 1152.50(d)(1) (notice to governmental agencies) have been met.</textblock>
    <textblock>As a condition to use of this exemption, any employee adversely affected by the abandonment or discontinuance shall be protected under</textblock>
    <textblock>Oregon Short Line R. Co._Abandonment_Goshen</textblock>
    <textblock>, 360 I.C.C. 91 (1979). To address whether this condition adequately protects affected employees, a petition for partial revocation under 49 U.S.C. 10505(d) must be filed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Provided no formal expression of intent to file an offer of financial assistance (OFA) has been received, this exemption will be effective on March 18, 1994, unless stayed pending reconsideration. Petitions to stay that do not involve environmental issues,</textblock>
    <textblock>formal expressions of intent to file an OFA under 49 CFR 1152.27(c)(2),</textblock>
    <textblock>and trail use/rail banking requests under 49 CFR 1152.29</textblock>
    <textblock>must be filed by February 28, 1994. Petitions to reopen or requests for public use conditions under 49 CFR 1152.28 must be filed by March 8, 1994, with: Office of the Secretary, Case Control Branch, Interstate Commerce Commission, Washington, DC 20423.</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of any pleading filed with the Commission should be sent to applicants' representative: Kevin J. O'Connell, Esq., Law Department, Iron Horse Park, North Billerica, MA 01862.</textblock>
    <textblock>If the notice of exemption contains false or misleading information, the exemption is void</textblock>
    <textblock>ab initio.</textblock>
    <textblock>B&amp;M and ST have filed an environmental report which addresses the effect, if any, of the abandonment and the discontinuance on the environmental and historic resources. The Section of Environmental Analysis (SEA) will issue an environmental assessment (EA) by February 18, 1994. Interested persons may obtain a copy of the EA by writing to SEA (room 3219, Interstate Commerce Commission, Washington, DC 20423) or by calling Elaine Kaiser, Chief of SEA, at (202) 927-6248. Comments on environmental and historic preservation matters must be filed within 15 days after the EA is available to the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental, historic preservation, public use, or trail use/rail banking conditions will be imposed, where appropriate, in a subsequent decision.</textblock>
    <textblock>Decided: February 3, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Commission, David M. Konschnik, Director, Office of Proceedings.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>INTERSTATE COMMERCE COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. AB-32 (Sub-No. 59X)]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. AB-355 (Sub-No. 11X)]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>B&amp;M and ST certify that they have met the newspaper publication requirement of 49 CFR 1105.7(c). The substance of the publication and certification required by that section for environmental reports is the same as that set forth at 49 CFR 1105.12.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>A stay will be issued routinely by the Commission in those proceedings where an informed decision on environmental issues (whether raised by a party or by the Commission's Section of Energy and Environment in its independent investigation) cannot be made before the effective date of the notice of exemption. See</textblock>
    <textblock>Exemption of Out-of-Service Rail Lines</textblock>
    <textblock>, 5 I.C.C.2d 377 (1989). Any entity seeking a stay involving environmental concerns is encouraged to file its request as soon as possible in order to permit this Commission to review and act on the request before the effective date of this exemption.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See</textblock>
    <textblock>Exempt. of Rail Abandonment_Offers of Finan. Assist.</textblock>
    <textblock>, 4 I.C.C.2d 164 (1987).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The Commission will accept a late-filed trail use request as long as it retains jurisdiction to do so.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Sidney L. Strickland, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3595 Filed 2-15-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7035-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
