<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00041</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Groundfish PSC Limits</textblock>
    <textblock>No PSC limits for groundfish species are specified in this action. Section 675.20(a)(6) authorizes NMFS to specify PSC limits for groundfish species or species groups for which the TAC will be completely harvested by domestic fisheries. These PSC limits apply only to JVP or TALFF fisheries. At this time, no groundfish are allocated to either JVP or TALFF and specifications of groundfish PSC limits are unnecessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>Closures to Directed Fishing</textblock>
    <textblock>Fishing for groundfish in the Bering Sea and Aleutian Islands is authorized from January 1 through December 31, with the following exceptions (ยง675.23):</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Directed fishing for yellowfin sole, ``other flatfish,'' arrowtooth flounder, and turbot is authorized from May 1, 1994 to December 31, 1994, subject to the other provisions in the BSAI regulations;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Fishing for groundfish with trawl gear in the BSAI is prohibited until January 20, 1994;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Directed fishing for pollock by the inshore and offshore components, defined at ยง675.2, is authorized from January 1, 1994, through April 15, 1994, and August 15, 1994, through the end of the fishing year;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Directed fishing for pollock under the Western Alaska Community Development Quota Program is authorized from January 1, 1994, through the end of the fishing year (ยง675.23(e)); and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Directed fishing with trawl gear in Zone 1 for rockfish, Greenland turbot, arrowtooth flounder and sablefish is closed as there is no PSC to support this fishery (Table 5).</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to these regulatory closures, the Council and NMFS annually recommend closures to directed fishing for species needed as bycatch amounts in other directed fisheries. A principal consideration for the Council in developing its 1994 TAC recommendations was ensuring that the sum of the species TACs did not exceed the maximum OY of 2 million mt. After consideration of the amount of each species category TAC that is required for bycatch in other directed fisheries, the Council and NMFS recommended that TAC amounts specified for the following species be closed to directed fishing: (1) Pacific ocean perch in the Bering Sea; (2) other red rockfish in the Bering Sea; (3) shortraker/rougheye in the Aleutian Islands; (4) other rockfish in the Bering Sea and Aleutian Islands; (5) arrowtooth flounder in the BSAI; and (6) pollock in the Bogoslof district. Species or species groups identified in Table 8 will be necessary as incidental catch to support other anticipated groundfish fisheries and TAC amounts for these species will be used for bycatch purposes only. If NMFS determines the full TAC amount will not be used as bycatch, NMFS may open a directed fishery for that species.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table</textblock>
    <textblock>8.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Closures to Directed Fishing Under 1994 Interim TACs1</textblock>
    <textblock>1Fishery (all gear)</textblock>
    <textblock>1Closed area</textblock>
    <textblock>Pollock in Bogoslof District</textblock>
    <textblock>Statistical Area 518.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pacific ocean perch</textblock>
    <textblock>Bering Sea.</textblock>
    <textblock>Shortraker/rougheye rockfish</textblock>
    <textblock>AI.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other rockfish2</textblock>
    <textblock>BSAI.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other red rockfish3</textblock>
    <textblock>Bering Sea.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rockfish, Greenland turbot/</textblock>
    <textblock>arrowtooth/sablefish</textblock>
    <textblock>Zone 1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Arrowtooth</textblock>
    <textblock>BSAI.</textblock>
    <textblock>1These closures to directed fishing are in addition to closures and prohibitions found in regulations at 50 CFR Part 675.</textblock>
    <textblock>2In the BSAI, ``Other rockfish'' includes</textblock>
    <textblock>Sebastes</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>Sebastolobus</textblock>
    <textblock>species except for Pacific ocean perchand the ``other red rockfish'' species.</textblock>
    <textblock>3``Other red rockfish'' includes shortraker, rougheye, sharpchin and northern.</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
