<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00237</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(F) The number of oxygen credits required as a result of actual total oxygen being less than compliance total oxygen;</textblock>
    <textblock>(G) The number of oxygen credits transferred to another refinery, importer, or oxygenate blending facility; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(H) The number of oxygen credits obtained from another refinery, importer, or oxygenate blending facility.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The information required by paragraph (f)(2)(i) of this section shall be reported separately for the following categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) For gasoline subject to the simple model standards:</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) Gasoline designated as VOC-controlled and non-oxygenated fuels program reformulated gasoline (OPRG);</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) Gasoline which is designated as VOC-controlled and non-OPRG;</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>) Gasoline which is designated as non-VOC-controlled and OPRG; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>) Gasoline which is designated as non-VOC-controlled and non-OPRG; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) For gasoline subject to the Phase I or Phase II complex model standards:</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) Gasoline which is designated as OPRG; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) Gasoline which is designated as non-OPRG.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The results of the compliance calculations required in ยง80.67(f) shall also be included in each report required by paragraph (f)(1) of this section, for each of the following categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) All reformulated gasoline;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Gasoline which is designated as non-OPRG; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) For gasoline subject to the simple model standards, gasoline which is designated as VOC-controlled.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>emissions performance averaging reports.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Any refiner or importer that produced or imported any reformulated gasoline or RBOB that was to meet the NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>emissions performance standard on average (``averaged reformulated gasoline'') shall submit to the Administrator, with the fourth quarterly report, a report for each refinery or importer for such averaged reformulated gasoline that was produced or imported during the previous NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>averaging period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The following information shall be reported:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The volume of averaged reformulated gasoline or RBOB in gallons;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The compliance value for NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>emissions performance; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The actual value for NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>emissions performance.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The information required by paragraph (g)(2) of this section shall be reported separately for the following categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Gasoline and RBOB which is designated as VOC-controlled; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Gasoline and RBOB which is not designated as VOC-controlled.</textblock>
    <textblock>(h)</textblock>
    <textblock>Credit transfer reports.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) As an additional part of the fourth quarterly report required by this section, any refiner, importer, and oxygenate blender shall, for each refinery, importer, or oxygenate blending facility, supply the following information for any oxygen or benzene credits that are transferred from or to another refinery, importer, or oxygenate blending facility:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The names, EPA-assigned registration numbers and facility identification numbers of the transferor and transferee of the credits;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The number(s) and type(s) of credits that were transferred; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The date(s) of transaction(s).</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For purposes of this paragraph (h), oxygen credit transfers shall be reported separately for each of the following oxygen credit types:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) For gasoline subject to the simple model standards:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) VOC controlled, oxygenated fuels program reformulated gasoline (OPRG) oxygen credits;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) VOC controlled, non-OPRG oxygen credits;</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Non-VOC controlled, OPRG oxygen credits; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) Non-VOC controlled, non-OPRG oxygen credits; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) For gasoline subject to the Phase I or Phase II complex model standards:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) OPRG oxygen credits; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Non-OPRG oxygen credits.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Covered areas of gasoline use report.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any refiner or oxygenate blender that produced or imported any reformulated gasoline that was to meet any reformulated gasoline standard on average (``averaged reformulated gasoline'') shall, for each refinery and oxygenate blending facility at which such averaged reformulated gasoline was produced submit to the Administrator, with the fourth quarterly report, a report that contains the identity of each covered area that was supplied with any averaged reformulated gasoline produced at each refinery or blended by each oxygenate blender during the previous year.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
