<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00225</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(ii) The covered area will be deemed to have failed</textblock>
    <textblock>surveys for VOC and NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>emissions performance, and survey</textblock>
    <textblock>series for benzene and oxygen, and toxic and NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>emissions</textblock>
    <textblock>performance.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>General survey requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) During the</textblock>
    <textblock>period January 1, 1995 through December 31, 1997:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Any sample taken from a retail gasoline storage</textblock>
    <textblock>tank for which the three most recent deliveries were of</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline designated as meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Simple model standards shall be considered a</textblock>
    <textblock>``simple model sample''; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Complex model standards shall be considered a</textblock>
    <textblock>``complex model sample.''</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A survey shall consist of the combination of a</textblock>
    <textblock>simple model portion and a complex model portion, as</textblock>
    <textblock>follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The simple model portion of a survey shall consist</textblock>
    <textblock>of all simple model samples that are collected pursuant to</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicable survey design in a single covered area during</textblock>
    <textblock>any consecutive seven-day period and that are not excluded</textblock>
    <textblock>under paragraph (c)(6) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The complex model portion of a survey shall</textblock>
    <textblock>consist of all complex model samples that are collected</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to the applicable survey design in a single covered</textblock>
    <textblock>area during any consecutive seven-day period and that are</textblock>
    <textblock>not excluded under paragraph (c)(6) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) (A) The simple model portion of each survey</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be representative of all gasoline certified using the</textblock>
    <textblock>simple model which is being dispensed in the covered area.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The complex model portion of each survey shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>representative of all gasoline certified using the complex</textblock>
    <textblock>model which is being dispensed in the covered area.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Beginning on January 1, 1998:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) A survey shall consist of all samples that are</textblock>
    <textblock>collected pursuant to the applicable survey design in a</textblock>
    <textblock>single covered area during any consecutive seven-day period</textblock>
    <textblock>and that are not excluded under paragraph (c)(6) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A survey shall be representative of all gasoline</textblock>
    <textblock>which is being dispensed in the covered area.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) A VOC survey, and prior to January 1, 2000, a NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>survey, shall consist of any survey conducted during the</textblock>
    <textblock>period June 1 through September 15.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) (i) A toxics, oxygen, and benzene survey</textblock>
    <textblock>series shall consist of all surveys conducted in a single</textblock>
    <textblock>covered area during a single calendar year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>survey series shall consist of all surveys</textblock>
    <textblock>conducted in a single covered area during the periods</textblock>
    <textblock>January 1 through May 31, and September 16 through December</textblock>
    <textblock>31 during a single calendar year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) (i) Each simple model sample included in a</textblock>
    <textblock>survey shall be analyzed for oxygenate type and content,</textblock>
    <textblock>benzene content, aromatic hydrocarbon content, and RVP in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with the methodologies specified in §80.46; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Each complex model sample included in a survey</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be analyzed for oxygenate type and content, olefins,</textblock>
    <textblock>benzene, sulfur, and aromatic hydrocarbons, E-200, E-300,</textblock>
    <textblock>and RVP in accordance with the methodologies specified in</textblock>
    <textblock>§80.46.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) (i) The results of each survey shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>based upon the results of the analysis of each sample</textblock>
    <textblock>collected during the course of the survey, unless the sample</textblock>
    <textblock>violates the applicable per-gallon maximum or minimum</textblock>
    <textblock>standards for the parameter being evaluated plus any</textblock>
    <textblock>enforcement tolerance that applies to the parameter (</textblock>
    <textblock>e.g.,</textblock>
    <textblock>a</textblock>
    <textblock>sample that violates the benzene per-gallon maximum plus any</textblock>
    <textblock>benzene enforcement tolerance but meets other per-gallon</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum and minimum standards would be excluded from the</textblock>
    <textblock>benzene survey, but would be included in the surveys for</textblock>
    <textblock>parameters other than benzene).</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Any sample from a survey that violates any</textblock>
    <textblock>standard under §80.41, or that constitutes evidence of the</textblock>
    <textblock>violation of any prohibition or requirement under this</textblock>
    <textblock>subpart D, may be used by the Administrator in an</textblock>
    <textblock>enforcement action for such violation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Each laboratory at which samples in a survey are</textblock>
    <textblock>analyzed shall participate in a correlation program with EPA</textblock>
    <textblock>to ensure the validity of analysis results.</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) (i) The results of each simple model VOC</textblock>
    <textblock>survey shall be determined as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) For each simple model sample from the survey, the</textblock>
    <textblock>VOC emissions reduction percentage shall be determined based</textblock>
    <textblock>upon the tested values for RVP and oxygen for that sample as</textblock>
    <textblock>applied to the VOC emissions reduction equation at</textblock>
    <textblock>§80.42(a)(1) for VOC-Control Region 1 and §80.42(a)(2) for</textblock>
    <textblock>VOC-Control Region 2;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The VOC emissions reduction survey standard</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable to each covered area shall be calculated by using</textblock>
    <textblock>the VOC emissions equation at §80.42(a)(1) with RVP=7.2 and</textblock>
    <textblock>OXCON=2.0 for covered areas located in VOC-Control Region 1</textblock>
    <textblock>and using the VOC emissions equation at §80.42(a)(2) with</textblock>
    <textblock>RVP=8.1 and OXCON=2.0 for covered areas located in VOC-Control Region 2; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) The covered area shall have failed the simple</textblock>
    <textblock>model VOC survey if the VOC emissions reduction average of</textblock>
    <textblock>all survey samples is less than VOC emissions reduction</textblock>
    <textblock>survey standard calculated under paragraph (c)(8)(i)(B) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The results of each complex model VOC emissions</textblock>
    <textblock>reduction survey shall be determined as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) For each complex model sample from the survey, the</textblock>
    <textblock>VOC emissions reduction percentage shall be determined based</textblock>
    <textblock>upon the tested parameter values for that sample and the</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate methodology for calculating VOC emissions</textblock>
    <textblock>reduction at §80.47; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The covered area shall have failed the complex</textblock>
    <textblock>model VOC survey if the VOC emissions reduction percentage</textblock>
    <textblock>average of all survey samples is less than the applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>per-gallon standard for VOC emissions reduction.</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) (i) The results of each simple model toxics</textblock>
    <textblock>emissions reduction survey series conducted in any covered</textblock>
    <textblock>area shall be determined as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) For each simple model sample from the survey</textblock>
    <textblock>series, the toxics emissions reduction percentage shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>determined based upon the tested parameter values for that</textblock>
    <textblock>sample and the appropriate methodology for calculating</textblock>
    <textblock>toxics emissions performance reduction at §80.42.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
