<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00027</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Special Concerns</textblock>
    <textblock>In its administration of the MCH Services Block Grant, the MCHB</textblock>
    <textblock>places special emphasis on improving service delivery to women and</textblock>
    <textblock>children from culturally identifiable populations who have been</textblock>
    <textblock>disproportionately affected by barriers to accessible care. This</textblock>
    <textblock>means that SPRANS projects are expected to serve and appropriately</textblock>
    <textblock>involve in project activities members of ethnoculturally distinct</textblock>
    <textblock>groups, unless there are compelling programmatic or other</textblock>
    <textblock>justifications for not doing so. The MCHB</textblock>
    <textblock>s intent is to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>that project outcomes are of benefit to culturally distinct</textblock>
    <textblock>populations and to ensure that the broadest possible</textblock>
    <textblock>representation of culturally distinct and historically underserved</textblock>
    <textblock>groups is supported through programs and projects sponsored by the</textblock>
    <textblock>MCHB.</textblock>
    <textblock>Projects supported under SPRANS are expected to be part of</textblock>
    <textblock>community-wide, comprehensive initiatives, to reflect appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>coordination of primary care and public health activities, and to</textblock>
    <textblock>target HRSA resources effectively to fill gaps in the Nation</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>health system for at-risk mothers and children. This applies</textblock>
    <textblock>especially to projects in the 15 communities in the Nation which</textblock>
    <textblock>have received grants from HRSA under the Administration</textblock>
    <textblock>s Healthy</textblock>
    <textblock>Start initiative. Grantees in these communities providing</textblock>
    <textblock>services related to activities of a Healthy Start program are</textblock>
    <textblock>expected to coordinate their projects with the Healthy Start</textblock>
    <textblock>program efforts. Healthy Start communities include: Aberdeen</textblock>
    <textblock>Area Indian Nations, NE/ND/SD; Baltimore, MD; Birmingham, AL;</textblock>
    <textblock>Boston, MA; Chicago, IL; Cleveland, OH; Detroit, MI; Lake County,</textblock>
    <textblock>IN; New Orleans, LA; New York, NY; Oakland, CA; Philadelphia, PA;</textblock>
    <textblock>Pittsburgh, PA; PeeDee Region, SC; and Washington, DC.</textblock>
    <textblock>Grants/Amounts:</textblock>
    <textblock>Up to $600,000 of SPRANS funds will be available</textblock>
    <textblock>to support up to two projects at a maximum of $300,000 per award</textblock>
    <textblock>for a one-year period. Awards are made for grant periods of up to</textblock>
    <textblock>four years.</textblock>
    <textblock>Review Criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>The following general criteria are used, as pertinent, to review</textblock>
    <textblock>and evaluate for funding all applications for SPRANS grants and</textblock>
    <textblock>cooperative agreements:</textblock>
    <textblock>_The quality of the project plan or methodology.</textblock>
    <textblock>_The need for the services, research, training or</textblock>
    <textblock>technical assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>_The cost-effectiveness of the proposed project relative</textblock>
    <textblock>to the number of persons proposed to be benefitted, served or</textblock>
    <textblock>trained, considering, where relevant, any special circumstances</textblock>
    <textblock>associated with providing care or training in various areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>_The extent to which the project will contribute to the</textblock>
    <textblock>advancement of MCH and/or CSHCN services.</textblock>
    <textblock>_The extent to which rapid and effective use of grant</textblock>
    <textblock>funds will be made by the project.</textblock>
    <textblock>_The effectiveness of procedures to collect the cost of</textblock>
    <textblock>care and service from third-party payment sources (including</textblock>
    <textblock>government agencies) which are authorized or under legal</textblock>
    <textblock>obligation to make such payment for any service (including</textblock>
    <textblock>diagnostic, preventive and treatment services).</textblock>
    <textblock>_The extent to which the project will be integrated with</textblock>
    <textblock>the administration of the Maternal and Child Health Services block</textblock>
    <textblock>grants, State primary care plans, public health, and prevention</textblock>
    <textblock>programs, and other related programs in the respective State(s).</textblock>
    <textblock>_The soundness of the project's management, considering</textblock>
    <textblock>the qualifications of the staff of the proposed project and the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant's facilities and resources.</textblock>
    <textblock>_The extent to which the project gives special emphasis to</textblock>
    <textblock>improving service delivery to women and children from culturally</textblock>
    <textblock>identifiable populations who have been disproportionately affected</textblock>
    <textblock>by barriers to accessible care and ensures that members of</textblock>
    <textblock>culturally distinct groups are appropriately represented in the</textblock>
    <textblock>activities of approved grants and cooperative agreements.</textblock>
    <textblock>_In communities with Healthy Start projects, a commitment</textblock>
    <textblock>by applicants whose projects are related to activities of a</textblock>
    <textblock>Healthy Start program to coordinate their projects with Healthy</textblock>
    <textblock>Start program efforts.</textblock>
    <textblock>_The strength of the project's plans for evaluation.</textblock>
    <textblock>_The strength of the applicant's prior experience linking</textblock>
    <textblock>health, education and social service professionals together with</textblock>
    <textblock>policy makers in State and local health and education agencies and</textblock>
    <textblock>private sector organizations to solve complex problems facing</textblock>
    <textblock>children and their families that require collaboration.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to the above criteria, other special review criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>are used to assess grants announced in this notice. As detailed</textblock>
    <textblock>in the guidance enclosed with the application packet, these</textblock>
    <textblock>special review criteria focus closely on the quality of each</textblock>
    <textblock>element of the program narrative section of the application: the</textblock>
    <textblock>problem; contributing factors; project goals; outcome objectives;</textblock>
    <textblock>methodology; tracking of project implementation; monitoring and</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluations; use of project information; capabilities of the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant; budget and justification; and the overall significance</textblock>
    <textblock>of the project.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
