<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-1-00011</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Radio Broadcasting Services; Ola, AR</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>47 CFR Part 73</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[MM Docket No. 94-8, RM-8412]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document requests comments on a petition for rule making filed on behalf of Yell County Broadcasting, requesting the allotment of FM Channel 267A to Ola,Arkansas, as that community's first local aural transmission service. Coordinates used for his proposal are 35-01-02 and 93-13-34.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be filed on or before April 4, 1994, and reply comments on or before April 19, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary, Federal Communications Commission, Washington, DC 20554. In addition to filing comments with the FCC, interested parties should serve the petitioner's counsel, as follows: Dan J. Alpert, Esq., Law Offices of Dan J. Alpert, 1250 Connecticut Avenue NW.,</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>700, Washington, DC 20036.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nancy Joyner, Mass Media Bureau, (202) 634-6530.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a synopsis of the Commission's Notice of Proposed Rule Making, MM Docket No. 94-8, adopted January 27, 1994, and released February 9, 1994. The full text of this Commission decision is available for inspection and copying during normal business hours in the FCC's Reference Center (room 239), 1919 M Street NW., Washington, DC. The complete text of this decision may also be purchased from the Commission's copy contractors, International Transcription Service, Inc., (202) 857-3800, 2100 M Street NW., suite 140, Washington, DC 20037.</textblock>
    <textblock>Provisions of the Regulatory Flexibility Act of 1980 do not apply to this proceeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>Members of the public should note that from the time a Notice of Proposed Rule Making is issued until the matter is no longer subject to Commission consideration or court review, all</textblock>
    <textblock>ex parte</textblock>
    <textblock>contacts are prohibited in Commission proceedings, such as this one, which involve channel allotments. See 47 CFR 1.1204(b) for rules governing permissible</textblock>
    <textblock>ex parte</textblock>
    <textblock>contacts.</textblock>
    <textblock>For information regarding proper filing procedures for comments, See 47 CFR 1.415 and 1.420.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 47 CFR Part 73</textblock>
    <textblock>Radio broadcasting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John A. Karousos,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Chief, Allocations Branch, Policy and Rules Division, Mass Media Bureau.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3533 Filed 2-15-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
