<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00026</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>4. Apportionments of Pollock TAC Among Regulatory Areas, Seasons, and Between Inshore and Offshore Components</textblock>
    <textblock>In the GOA, pollock is apportioned by area, season, and inshore/offshore components. Regulations at ยง672.20(a)(2)(iv) require that the TAC for pollock in the combined W/C GOA be apportioned among statistical areas Shumagin (61), Chirikof (62), and Kodiak (63) in proportion to known distributions of the pollock biomass. This measure was intended to provide spatial distribution of the pollock harvest as a sea lion protection measure. Each statistical area apportionment is further divided equally among the four quarterly reporting periods of the fishing year (Table 3). Within any fishing year, any unharvested amount of any quarterly allowance of pollock TAC is added in equal proportions to the quarterly allowance of following quarters, resulting in a sum for each quarter that does not exceed 150 percent of the initial quarterly allowance. Similarly, harvests in excess of a quarterly allowance of TAC are deducted in equal proportions from the remaining quarterly allowances of that fishing year. As defined at</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง672.23(f), directed fishing for the four quarterly allowances will start on January 1, June 1, July 1, and October 1. The Eastern Regulatory Area pollock TAC of 7,300 mt is not allocated among smaller areas, or quarters.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations at ยง672.20(a)(2)(v)(A) require that the DAP apportionment for pollock in all regulatory areas and all quarterly allowances thereof be divided into inshore and offshore components. The inshore component is apportioned 100 percent of the pollock DAP in each regulatory area after subtraction of amounts that are determined by the Regional Director to be necessary to support the bycatch needs of the offshore component in directed fisheries for other groundfish species. At this time, incidental amounts of pollock to be caught by the offshore component are unknown, and will be determined during the fishing year.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Apportionment of Pacific Cod TAC Between Inshore and Offshore Components</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations at ยง672.20(a)(2)(v)(B) require that the DAP apportionment of Pacific cod in all regulatory areas be allocated to vessels catching Pacific cod for processing by the inshore and offshore components. The inshore component is equal to 90 percent of the Pacific cod TAC in each regulatory area with 10 percent of the TAC assigned to the offshore component. Inshore and offshore allocations of the 50,400 mt Pacific cod TAC for 1994 are shown in Table 4.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. ``Other Species'' TAC</textblock>
    <textblock>The FMP specifies that the TAC amount for the ``other species'' category is calculated as 5 percent of the 1994 combined TACs for target species. For 1993, the Council recommended that ``other species'' be made available separately in each of the three regulatory areas to avoid preemption of fishing activities in the remainder of the GOA by a target fishery for Atka mackerel that developed in the Western Regulatory Area. Approval of Amendment 31, which established Atka mackerel as a separate target species, removed the necessity to apportion ``other species'' among regulatory areas in 1994. At the December 1993 meeting, the Council recommended a GOA-wide TAC of 14,504 mt for ``other species.'' As discussed above, a 1994 TAC of 5 mt for Atka mackerel in the Eastern Regulatory Area is established by NMFS, thus increasing the TAC for ``other species'' to 14,505 mt.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table</textblock>
    <textblock>3._</textblock>
    <textblock>Distribution of Pollock in the Western and Central Regulatory Areas of the Gulf of Alaska (W/CGOA); Biomass Distribution, Area Apportionments, and Quarterly Allowances. ABC for the W/C GOA Is</textblock>
    <textblock>102,000</textblock>
    <textblock>Metric Tons (mt)</textblock>
    <textblock>[Biomass distribution is based on 1990 survey data. TACs are equal to ABC. Inshore and offshore allocations of pollock are not shown. ABCs and TACs are rounded to the nearest 10 mt]</textblock>
    <textblock>1Statistical area</textblock>
    <textblock>1Biomass percent</textblock>
    <textblock>11994 TAC</textblock>
    <textblock>1Quarterly allowance</textblock>
    <textblock>Shumagin (61)</textblock>
    <textblock>21.7</textblock>
    <textblock>22,130</textblock>
    <textblock>5,532</textblock>
    <textblock>Chirikof (62)</textblock>
    <textblock>23.4</textblock>
    <textblock>23,870</textblock>
    <textblock>5,968</textblock>
    <textblock>Kodiak (63)</textblock>
    <textblock>54.9</textblock>
    <textblock>56,000</textblock>
    <textblock>14,000</textblock>
    <textblock>n,s</textblock>
    <textblock>Total</textblock>
    <textblock>100.0</textblock>
    <textblock>102,000</textblock>
    <textblock>25,500</textblock>
  </table>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table</textblock>
    <textblock>4._1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Allocation of Pacific Cod in the Gulf of Alaska; Allocations to Inshore And Offshore Components</textblock>
    <textblock>[In metric tons]</textblock>
    <textblock>1Regulatory area</textblock>
    <textblock>1TAC</textblock>
    <textblock>1Component allocation</textblock>
    <textblock>2Inshore (90%)</textblock>
    <textblock>2Offshore (10%)</textblock>
    <textblock>Western</textblock>
    <textblock>16,630</textblock>
    <textblock>14,967</textblock>
    <textblock>1,663</textblock>
    <textblock>Central</textblock>
    <textblock>31,250</textblock>
    <textblock>28,125</textblock>
    <textblock>3,125</textblock>
    <textblock>Eastern</textblock>
    <textblock>2,520</textblock>
    <textblock>2,268</textblock>
    <textblock>252</textblock>
    <textblock>n,s</textblock>
    <textblock>Total</textblock>
    <textblock>50,400</textblock>
    <textblock>45,360</textblock>
    <textblock>5,040</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
