<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00221</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>RVP and VOC emissions performance reduction</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance on average.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The VOC-controlled</textblock>
    <textblock>reformulated gasoline and RBOB produced at any refinery or</textblock>
    <textblock>imported by any importer during the period January 1 through</textblock>
    <textblock>September 15 of each calendar year which is designated for</textblock>
    <textblock>average compliance for RVP or VOC emissions performance on</textblock>
    <textblock>average must meet the standards for RVP (in the case of a</textblock>
    <textblock>refinery or importer subject to the simple model standards)</textblock>
    <textblock>or the standards for VOC emissions performance reduction (in</textblock>
    <textblock>the case of a refinery or importer subject to the complex</textblock>
    <textblock>model standards) which are applicable to that refinery or</textblock>
    <textblock>importer as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Gasoline and RBOB designated for VOC Control</textblock>
    <textblock>Region 1 must meet the standards for that Region which are</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable to that refinery or importer; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Gasoline and RBOB designated for VOC Control</textblock>
    <textblock>Region 2 must meet the standards for that Region which are</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable to that refinery or importer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) In the case of a refinery or importer subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>the simple model standards, each gallon of reformulated</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline and RBOB designated as being VOC-controlled may not</textblock>
    <textblock>exceed the maximum standards for RVP specified in §80.41(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>which are applicable to that refiner or importer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) In the case of a refinery or importer subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>the complex model standards, each gallon of reformulated</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline designated as being VOC-controlled must equal or</textblock>
    <textblock>exceed the minimum standards for VOC emissions performance</textblock>
    <textblock>specified in §80.41 which are applicable to that refinery</textblock>
    <textblock>or importer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Toxics emissions reduction and benzene compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>on average.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The averaging period for the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for benzene content and toxics emission</textblock>
    <textblock>performance is January 1 through December 31 of each year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The reformulated gasoline and RBOB produced at any</textblock>
    <textblock>refinery or imported by any importer during the toxics</textblock>
    <textblock>emissions performance and benzene averaging periods that is</textblock>
    <textblock>designated for average compliance for these parameters shall</textblock>
    <textblock>on average meet the standards specified for toxics emissions</textblock>
    <textblock>performance and benzene in §80.41 which are applicable to</textblock>
    <textblock>that refinery or importer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Each gallon of reformulated gasoline may not</textblock>
    <textblock>exceed the maximum standard for benzene content specified in</textblock>
    <textblock>§80.41 which is applicable to that refinery or importer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance on average.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The averaging</textblock>
    <textblock>period for NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>emissions performance is January 1 through</textblock>
    <textblock>December 31 of each year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The requirements of this paragraph (e) apply</textblock>
    <textblock>separately to reformulated gasoline and RBOB in the</textblock>
    <textblock>following categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) All reformulated gasoline and RBOB that is</textblock>
    <textblock>designated as VOC-controlled; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) All reformulated gasoline and RBOB that is not</textblock>
    <textblock>designated as VOC-controlled.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The reformulated gasoline and RBOB produced at any</textblock>
    <textblock>refinery or imported by any importer during the NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>averaging period that is designated for average compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>for NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>shall on average meet the standards for NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>specified in §80.41 that are applicable to that refinery or</textblock>
    <textblock>importer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Each gallon of reformulated gasoline must equal or</textblock>
    <textblock>exceed the minimum standards for NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>emissions performance</textblock>
    <textblock>specified in §80.41 which are applicable to that refinery</textblock>
    <textblock>or importer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Oxygen compliance on average.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The</textblock>
    <textblock>averaging period for the oxygen content requirements is</textblock>
    <textblock>January 1 through December 31 of each year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The requirements of this paragraph (f) apply</textblock>
    <textblock>separately to reformulated gasoline in the following</textblock>
    <textblock>categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) All reformulated gasoline;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) All reformulated gasoline that is not designated</textblock>
    <textblock>as being OPRG; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) In the case of reformulated gasoline certified</textblock>
    <textblock>under the simple model, that which is designated as VOC-</textblock>
    <textblock>controlled.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The reformulated gasoline produced at any refinery</textblock>
    <textblock>or imported by any importer during the oxygen averaging</textblock>
    <textblock>period that is designated for average compliance for oxygen</textblock>
    <textblock>shall on average meet the standards for oxygen specified in</textblock>
    <textblock>§80.41 that is applicable to that refinery or importer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The reformulated gasoline that is produced at any</textblock>
    <textblock>oxygenate blending facility by blending RBOB with oxygenate</textblock>
    <textblock>that is designated for average compliance for oxygen shall</textblock>
    <textblock>on average meet the standards for oxygen specified in</textblock>
    <textblock>§80.41 that is applicable to that oxygenate blending</textblock>
    <textblock>facility.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Each gallon of reformulated gasoline must meet the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable minimum requirements, and in the case of simple</textblock>
    <textblock>model reformulated gasoline the minimum and maximum</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements, for oxygen content specified in §80.41.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance calculation.</textblock>
    <textblock>To determine compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>with the averaged standards in §80.41, any refiner for each</textblock>
    <textblock>of its refineries at which averaged reformulated gasoline or</textblock>
    <textblock>RBOB is produced, any oxygenate blender for each of its</textblock>
    <textblock>oxygenate blending facilities at which oxygen averaged</textblock>
    <textblock>reformulated gasoline is produced, and any importer that</textblock>
    <textblock>imports averaged reformulated gasoline or RBOB shall, for</textblock>
    <textblock>each averaging period and for each portion of gasoline for</textblock>
    <textblock>which standards must be separately achieved, and for each</textblock>
    <textblock>relevant standard, calculate:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)(i) The compliance total using the following formula:</textblock>
    <textblock>where</textblock>
    <textblock>V</textblock>
    <textblock>i</textblock>
    <textblock>=the volume of gasoline batch i</textblock>
    <textblock>std=the standard for the parameter being evaluated</textblock>
    <textblock>n=the number of batches of gasoline produced or</textblock>
    <textblock>imported during the averaging period</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
  </text>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSER16FE94.007</textblock>
  </import>
</doc>
