<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00011</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-2-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the following applicants have filed with the Federal Maritime Commission applications for licenses as ocean freight forwarders pursuant to section 19 of the Shipping Act of 1984 (46 U.S.C. app. 1718 and 46 CFR Part 510).</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons knowing of any reason why any of the following applicants should not receive a license are requested to contact the Office of Freight Forwarders, Federal Maritime Commission, Washington, DC 20573.</textblock>
    <textblock>G T International, Inc., 3257 S. Del Mar Ave., Rosemead, CA 33054, Officer: Geoffrey Ren, President, Demetrio Pina, Vice President, Vilma Pina, Secretary, Raul Cabrera, Treasurer</textblock>
    <textblock>Newport Cargo Consolidated, Inc., 12533 Crenshaw Blvd., Hawthorne, CA 90250, Officers: Hae Soon Yoon, President/Stockholder, Hwa Kyung Yoon, Vice President/Stockholder</textblock>
    <textblock>Green Delta Corp., 2520 NE Broadway Street,</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>204, Minneapolis, MN 55413, Officer: Keumog L. Ahn, Corporate Executive Officer</textblock>
    <textblock>Josephine D. Mina-Saito, 29360 North Begonias Lane, Canyon Country, CA 91351, Sole Proprietor</textblock>
    <textblock>``K'' Line Air Service (U.S.A.) Inc., 144-35 157th Street, Jamaica, NY 11434, Officers: Tetsuo Shoji, President, Koichi Inouye, Executive Vice President, Yuichi Aoyagi, Secretary/Treasurer</textblock>
    <textblock>Express International Forwarders, Inc., 41501 N.W. 97th Ave., Ste. 3, Miami, FL 33172, Officers: Maura A. Paz, Director/President/Treasurer, Lild C. Barrera, Vice President/Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>Intercarga U.S.A. Corporation, 8325 N.W. 66th Street, Miami, FL 33166, Officers: Alberto Blest, President/Stockholder, Mariana De Ruiz, Treasurer/Stockholder, Carlos Salhuana, Stockholder</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Cargo, Inc., 1920 N.W. 94th Ave., Miami, FL 33172, Officers: Daniel Gamas, President/Director, John H. Shaw, Secretary/Director.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 10, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Federal Maritime Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Ocean Freight Forwarder License Applicants</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Joseph C. Polking,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3547 Filed 2-15-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6730-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
