<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-1-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(dd) Storing, placing, or leaving personal property unattended outside of developed recreation sites for more than the length of time specified by the order.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ee) Possessing, storing, or using any glass food or beverage containers.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 262_LAW ENFORCEMENT SUPPORT ACTIVITIES</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 262 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>7 U.S.C. 1011(f); 16 U.S.C. 472; 16 U.S.C. 551; 16 U.S.C. 559b-h; 40 U.S.C. 484(m); CG-B-172259.</textblock>
    <textblock>§§262.2 and 262.3</textblock>
    <textblock>[Removed]</textblock>
    <textblock>§262.1</textblock>
    <textblock>[Redesignated as §262.2]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Remove §§262.2 and 262.3, redesignate §262.1 as §262.2, and add new §§262.1 and 262.3 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§262.1</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following definitions apply to this subpart:</textblock>
    <textblock>Law Enforcement Officer</textblock>
    <textblock>means an employee of the Forest Service in other than the Criminal Investigating series, GS-1811, who is authorized by the Washington Office, Director for Law Enforcement and Investigations to conduct investigations, make arrests with or without a warrant or process, issue violation notices, execute and serve search and arrest warrants, carry firearms for law enforcement purposes, and perform other duties as directed in connection with the enforcement or administration of all laws, rules, and regulations in which the Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, is or may be a party of interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>Special Agent</textblock>
    <textblock>means an employee of the Forest Service in the Criminal Investigating series, GS-1811, who is authorized by the Chief to perform all duties conferred upon such officer under all laws and regulations administered by the Forest Service including the authority to conduct investigations, to execute and serve search and arrest warrants, to serve orders, subpoenas, or other judicial processes as directed, to carry firearms, make arrests, issue violation notices, and perform other duties as directed in connection with the enforcement or administration of all laws, rules and regulations in which the Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, is or may be a party of interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>§262.3</textblock>
    <textblock>Purchase of information or evidence in furtherance of investigations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Approval of payments.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following Forest Service officials may make or approve payments for purchase of information or evidence to further law enforcement investigations in the amount shown for each transaction as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Law Enforcement Officers</textblock>
    <textblock>up to $250.00</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Special Agents</textblock>
    <textblock>up to $500.00</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Regional Special Agents in Charge</textblock>
    <textblock>up to $1,000.00</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Director for Law Enforcement and Investigations</textblock>
    <textblock>up to $5,000.00</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Chief, for amounts exceeding</textblock>
    <textblock>$5,000.00</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) [Reserved]</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart B_Administrative Impoundments and Removals</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Revise the title of subpart B as set out above.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Amend §262.12 by revising paragraph (d) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§262.12</textblock>
    <textblock>Impounding of personal property.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) If the personal property is not redeemed on or before the date fixed for its disposition, it shall become property of the United States. Such property may be retained by the Forest Service for use in on-going management activities, sold at public sale to the highest bidder, or otherwise disposed of. When personal property is sold pursuant to this regulation, the Forest officer making the sale shall furnish the purchaser with a bill of sale or other written instrument evidencing the sale.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Revise §262.13 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§262.13</textblock>
    <textblock>Removal of obstructions.</textblock>
    <textblock>A Forest officer may remove or cause to be removed, to a more suitable place, a vehicle or other object which is an impediment or hazard to the safety, convenience, or comfort of any person, or which has been left in such a manner that it impairs or may result in the impairment of any areas of the National Forest System or other lands under Forest Service control.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 6, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David G. Unger,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Chief.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3358 Filed 2-15-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-11-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
