<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-1-00009</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-1-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Radio Broadcasting Services; Westbrook, ME</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL COMMUNICATIONS COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>47 CFR Part 73</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[MM Docket No. 93-188; RM-8278]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule; dismissal.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document dismisses a Notice of Proposed Rule Making issued in response to Buckley Broadcasting Corporation of Maine requesting the substitution of Channel 265B1 for Channel 265A at Westbrook, Maine, and modification of the license for Station WYNZ to specify the higher class channel. See 58 FR 38547, July 19, 1993. Saga Communications of New England, Inc., the current licensee of Station WYNZ, has filed an application seeking to take advantage of the Commission's new rules permitting an upgrade in facilities by the application process rather than the rule making process (BPH-930818IC). See FM Channel and Class Modification by Application, 58 FR 38534, July 19, 1993. With this action, this proceeding is terminated.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Kathleen Scheuerle, Mass Media Bureau, (202) 634-6530.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a summary of the Commission's Report and Order, MM Docket No. 93-188, adopted January 27, 1994, and released February 9, 1994. The full text of this Commission decision is available for inspection and copying during normal business hours in the Commission's Reference Center (room 239), 1919 M Street NW., Washington, DC. The complete text of this decision may also be purchased from the Commission's copy contractors, International Transcription Services, Inc., 2100 M Street NW., suite 140, Washington, DC 20037, (202) 857-3800.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 47 CFR Part 73</textblock>
    <textblock>Radio broadcasting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John A. Karousos,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Chief, Allocations Branch, Policy and Rules Division, Mass Media Bureau.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3531 Filed 2-15-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
