<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00240</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(C) Unless each gallon of such gasoline that is</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to complex model standards has a VOC and NO</textblock>
    <textblock>x</textblock>
    <textblock>emissions reduction percentage which is above the applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>minimum specified in §80.41.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) No refiner or importer may produce or import any</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline represented as reformulated or RBOB, and intended</textblock>
    <textblock>for sale or use in any covered area:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Unless such gasoline meets the definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>reformulated gasoline or RBOB; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Unless the properties of such gasoline or RBOB</textblock>
    <textblock>correspond to the product transfer documents.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) No person may manufacture and sell or distribute,</textblock>
    <textblock>or offer for sale or distribution, dispense, supply, or</textblock>
    <textblock>offer for supply, store, transport or cause the</textblock>
    <textblock>transportation of gasoline represented as conventional which</textblock>
    <textblock>does not contain at least the minimum concentration of the</textblock>
    <textblock>conventional gasoline marker specified in §80.82.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Gasoline shall be presumed to be intended for sale</textblock>
    <textblock>or use in a covered area unless:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Product transfer documentation as described in</textblock>
    <textblock>§80.77 accompanying such gasoline clearly indicates the</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline is intended for sale and use only outside any</textblock>
    <textblock>covered area; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The gasoline is contained in the storage tank of a</textblock>
    <textblock>retailer or wholesale purchaser-consumer outside any covered</textblock>
    <textblock>area.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) No person may combine any reformulated gasoline</textblock>
    <textblock>with any non-oxygenate blendstock except:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) A person that meets each requirement specified for</textblock>
    <textblock>a refiner under this subpart; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The blendstock that is added to reformulated</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline meets all reformulated gasoline standards without</textblock>
    <textblock>regard to the properties of the reformulated gasoline to</textblock>
    <textblock>which the blendstock is added.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) No person may add any oxygenate to reformulated</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline, except that oxygenate may be added to reformulated</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline that is designated as OPRG provided that such</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline is used in an oxygenated fuels program control area</textblock>
    <textblock>during an oxygenated fuels control period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) No person may combine any reformulated gasoline</textblock>
    <textblock>blendstock for oxygenate blending with any other gasoline,</textblock>
    <textblock>blendstock, or oxygenate except:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Oxygenate of the type and amount (or within the</textblock>
    <textblock>range of amounts) specified by the refiner or importer at</textblock>
    <textblock>the time the RBOB was produced or imported; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Other RBOB for which the same oxygenate type and</textblock>
    <textblock>amount (or range of amounts) was specified by the refiner or</textblock>
    <textblock>importer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) No person may combine any VOC-controlled</textblock>
    <textblock>reformulated gasoline that is produced using ethanol with</textblock>
    <textblock>any VOC-controlled reformulated gasoline that is produced</textblock>
    <textblock>using any other oxygenate during the period January 1</textblock>
    <textblock>through September 15.</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) Prior to January 1, 1998:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) No person may combine any reformulated gasoline or</textblock>
    <textblock>RBOB that is subject to the simple model standards with any</textblock>
    <textblock>reformulated gasoline or RBOB that is subject to the complex</textblock>
    <textblock>model standards, except that such gasolines may be combined</textblock>
    <textblock>at a retail outlet or wholesale purchaser-consumer facility;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) No person may combine any reformulated gasoline</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to the complex model standards that is produced at</textblock>
    <textblock>any refinery or is imported by any importer with any other</textblock>
    <textblock>reformulated gasoline that is produced at a different</textblock>
    <textblock>refinery or is imported by a different importer, unless the</textblock>
    <textblock>other refinery or importer has an identical baseline for</textblock>
    <textblock>meeting complex model standards during this period; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) No person may combine any RBOB subject to the</textblock>
    <textblock>complex model standards that is produced at any refinery or</textblock>
    <textblock>is imported by any importer with any RBOB that is produced</textblock>
    <textblock>at a different refinery or is imported by a different</textblock>
    <textblock>importer, unless the other refinery or importer has an</textblock>
    <textblock>identical baseline for meeting complex model standards</textblock>
    <textblock>during this period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(10) No person may combine any reformulated gasoline</textblock>
    <textblock>with any conventional gasoline and sell the resulting</textblock>
    <textblock>mixture as reformulated gasoline.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Liability.</textblock>
    <textblock>Liability for violations of paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) of this section shall be determined according to the</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions of §80.79.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Determination of compliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>standards listed in paragraph (a) of this section shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by use of one of the testing methodologies</textblock>
    <textblock>specified in §80.46, except that where test results using</textblock>
    <textblock>the testing methodologies specified in §80.46 are not</textblock>
    <textblock>available or where such test results are available but are</textblock>
    <textblock>in question, EPA may establish noncompliance with standards</textblock>
    <textblock>using any information, including the results of testing</textblock>
    <textblock>using methods that are not included in §80.46.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dates controls and prohibitions begin.</textblock>
    <textblock>The</textblock>
    <textblock>controls and prohibitions specified in paragraph (a) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section apply at any location other than retail outlets and</textblock>
    <textblock>wholesale purchaser-consumer facilities on or after December</textblock>
    <textblock>1, 1994, at any location on or after January 1, 1995.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
