<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00216</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940216-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(b) Alternatively, candidate vehicles may be screened</textblock>
    <textblock>for their exhaust THC emissions with the IM240 short test</textblock>
    <textblock>procedure.</textblock>
    <textblock>The results from the IM240 shall be converted</textblock>
    <textblock>into results comparable with the standard exhaust FTP as</textblock>
    <textblock>detailed in this paragraph (b) to place the vehicles within</textblock>
    <textblock>their respective emitter groups in accordance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of §80.60.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A candidate vehicle with IM240 test results &lt;0.367 grams THC per vehicle mile shall be classified as a</textblock>
    <textblock>normal emitter.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A candidate vehicle with IM240 test results "0.367 grams THC per vehicle mile shall be classified as a</textblock>
    <textblock>higher emitter.</textblock>
    <textblock>§§80.63-80.64</textblock>
    <textblock>[Reserved]</textblock>
    <textblock>§80.65</textblock>
    <textblock>General requirements for refiners, importers, and</textblock>
    <textblock>oxygenate blenders.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Date requirements begin.</textblock>
    <textblock>The requirements of this</textblock>
    <textblock>subpart D apply to all gasoline produced, imported,</textblock>
    <textblock>transported, stored, sold, or dispensed:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) At any location other than retail outlets and</textblock>
    <textblock>wholesale purchaser-consumer facilities on or after December</textblock>
    <textblock>1, 1994; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) At any location on or after January 1, 1995.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Certification of gasoline and RBOB.</textblock>
    <textblock>Gasoline or</textblock>
    <textblock>RBOB sold or dispensed in a covered area must be certified</textblock>
    <textblock>under §80.40.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Standards must be met on either a per-gallon or on</textblock>
    <textblock>an average basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Any refiner or importer, for each</textblock>
    <textblock>batch of reformulated gasoline or RBOB it produces or</textblock>
    <textblock>imports, shall meet:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Those standards and requirements it designated</textblock>
    <textblock>under paragraph (d) of this section for per-gallon</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance on a per-gallon basis; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Those standards and requirements it designated</textblock>
    <textblock>under paragraph (d) of this section for average compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>on an average basis over the applicable averaging period;</textblock>
    <textblock>except that</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Refiners and importers are not required to meet</textblock>
    <textblock>the oxygen standard for RBOB.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Any oxygenate blender, for each batch of</textblock>
    <textblock>reformulated gasoline it produces by blending oxygenate with</textblock>
    <textblock>RBOB shall, subsequent to the addition of oxygenate, meet</textblock>
    <textblock>the oxygen standard either per-gallon or average over the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable averaging period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)(i) For each averaging period, and</textblock>
    <textblock>separately for each parameter that may be met either per-gallon or on average, any refiner shall designate for each</textblock>
    <textblock>refinery, and any importer or oxygenate blender shall</textblock>
    <textblock>designate, its gasoline or RBOB as being subject to the</textblock>
    <textblock>standard applicable to that parameter on either a per-gallon</textblock>
    <textblock>or average basis. For any specific averaging period and</textblock>
    <textblock>parameter all batches of gasoline or RBOB shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>designated as being subject to the per-gallon standard, or</textblock>
    <textblock>all batches of gasoline and RBOB shall be designated as</textblock>
    <textblock>being subject to the average standard. For any specific</textblock>
    <textblock>averaging period and parameter a refiner for a refinery, or</textblock>
    <textblock>any importer or oxygenate blender, may not designate certain</textblock>
    <textblock>batches as being subject to the per-gallon standard and</textblock>
    <textblock>others as being subject to the average standard.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) In the event any refiner for a refinery, or any</textblock>
    <textblock>importer or oxygenate blender, fails to meet the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of paragraph (c)(3)(i) of this section and for</textblock>
    <textblock>a specific averaging period and parameter designates certain</textblock>
    <textblock>batches as being subject to the per-gallon standard and</textblock>
    <textblock>others as being subject to the average standard, all batches</textblock>
    <textblock>produced or imported during the averaging period that were</textblock>
    <textblock>designated as being subject to the average standard shall,</textblock>
    <textblock>ab initio,</textblock>
    <textblock>be redesignated as being subject to the per-</textblock>
    <textblock>gallon standard. This redesignation shall apply regardless</textblock>
    <textblock>of whether the batches in question met or failed to meet the</textblock>
    <textblock>per-gallon standard for the parameter in question.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Designation of gasoline.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any refiner or importer</textblock>
    <textblock>of gasoline shall designate the gasoline it produces or</textblock>
    <textblock>imports as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) All gasoline produced or imported shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>properly designated as either reformulated or conventional</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline, or as RBOB.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) All gasoline designated as reformulated or as RBOB</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be further properly designated as:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Either VOC-controlled or not VOC-controlled;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) In the case of gasoline or RBOB designated as VOC-controlled, either intended for use in VOC-Control Region 1</textblock>
    <textblock>or VOC-Control Region 2 (as defined in §80.71);</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Either oxygenated fuels program reformulated</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline, or not oxygenated fuels program reformulated</textblock>
    <textblock>gasoline. Gasoline or RBOB must be designated as oxygenated</textblock>
    <textblock>fuels program reformulated gasoline if such gasoline:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Contains more than 2.0 weight percent oxygen; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Arrives at a terminal from which gasoline is</textblock>
    <textblock>dispensed into trucks used to deliver gasoline to an</textblock>
    <textblock>oxygenated fuels control area within five days prior to the</textblock>
    <textblock>beginning of the oxygenated fuels control period for that</textblock>
    <textblock>control area;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) For gasoline or RBOB produced, imported, sold,</textblock>
    <textblock>dispensed or used during the period January 1, 1995 through</textblock>
    <textblock>December 31, 1997, either as being subject to the simple</textblock>
    <textblock>model standards, or to the complex model standards;</textblock>
  </text>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>EPA Technical Report EPA-AA-TSS-91-1. Copies may be obtained by ordering publication number PB92104405 from the National Technical Information Service, 5285 Port Royal Road, Springfield, Virginia 22161.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
