<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00065</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Potential activities that may affect the salamander and its</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat include (1) urban development over the recharge and</textblock>
    <textblock>contributing zones that may lead to contamination of the species'</textblock>
    <textblock>water supply through one or more accidental contaminant spills or</textblock>
    <textblock>chronic water quality degradation, (2) increased groundwater</textblock>
    <textblock>withdrawal leading to reduced groundwater levels and springflow</textblock>
    <textblock>(compounded if drought occurs), and (3) certain pool maintenance</textblock>
    <textblock>practices or other activities that may impact the salamander and its</textblock>
    <textblock>surface habitat (such as use of chemicals and high pressure hoses in</textblock>
    <textblock>areas occupied by salamanders and removal of substrates used for</textblock>
    <textblock>cover). Federal agency actions that may require conference and/or</textblock>
    <textblock>consultation as described in the preceding paragraph include Army</textblock>
    <textblock>Corps of Engineers involvement in projects such as the construction</textblock>
    <textblock>of roads, bridges, and dredging projects subject to section 404</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Clean Water Act (33 U.S.C. 1344</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.) and section 10 of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Rivers and Harbors Act of 1899 (33 U.S.C. 401</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.), pipeline</textblock>
    <textblock>projects, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency authorized discharges</textblock>
    <textblock>under the National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System (NPDES),</textblock>
    <textblock>and Soil Conservation Service and U.S. Housing and Urban Development</textblock>
    <textblock>projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Act and its implementing regulations found at 50 CFR 17.21</textblock>
    <textblock>set forth a series of general prohibitions and exceptions that apply</textblock>
    <textblock>to all endangered wildlife. These prohibitions, in part, make it</textblock>
    <textblock>illegal for any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United</textblock>
    <textblock>States to take (includes harass, harm, pursue, hunt, shoot, wound,</textblock>
    <textblock>kill, trap, capture, or collect; or to attempt any of these), import</textblock>
    <textblock>or export, ship in interstate commerce in the course of commercial</textblock>
    <textblock>activity, or sell or offer for sale in interstate or foreign</textblock>
    <textblock>commerce any listed species. It also is illegal to possess, sell,</textblock>
    <textblock>deliver, carry, transport, or ship any such wildlife that has been</textblock>
    <textblock>taken illegally. Certain exceptions apply to agents of the Service</textblock>
    <textblock>and State conservation agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Permits may be issued to carry out otherwise prohibited</textblock>
    <textblock>activities involving endangered wildlife species under certain</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances. Regulations governing permits are codified at 50 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>17.22 and 17.23. Such permits are available for scientific</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes, to enhance the propagation or survival of the species,</textblock>
    <textblock>and/or for incidental take in the course of otherwise lawful</textblock>
    <textblock>activities. This species is not in trade, and such permit requests</textblock>
    <textblock>are not expected.</textblock>
    <textblock>Requests for copies of the regulations regarding listed</textblock>
    <textblock>wildlife and inquiries regarding prohibitions and permits may be</textblock>
    <textblock>addressed to the Office of Management Authority, U.S. Fish and</textblock>
    <textblock>Wildlife Service, room 420C, 4401 N. Fairfax Drive, Arlington,</textblock>
    <textblock>Virginia 22203 (703/358-2104; FAX 703/358-2281).</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Comments Solicited</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service intends that any final action resulting from this</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal will be as accurate and as effective as possible.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, comments or suggestions from the public, other concerned</textblock>
    <textblock>governmental agencies, the scientific community, industry, or any</textblock>
    <textblock>other interested party concerning this proposed rule are hereby</textblock>
    <textblock>solicited. Comments particularly are sought concerning:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Biological, commercial trade, or other relevant data</textblock>
    <textblock>concerning any threat (or lack thereof) to the Barton Springs</textblock>
    <textblock>salamander;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The location of any additional populations of this</textblock>
    <textblock>species and the reasons why any habitat should or should not be</textblock>
    <textblock>determined to be critical habitat as provided by section 4 of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Act;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Additional information concerning the range,</textblock>
    <textblock>distribution, and population size of this species; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Current or planned activities in the Barton Springs</textblock>
    <textblock>segment of the Edwards Aquifer, its contributing zone, and the area</textblock>
    <textblock>around Barton Springs and possible impacts on this species resulting</textblock>
    <textblock>from these activities.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
