<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00129</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Burden Estimate:</textblock>
    <textblock>125,396 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>All owners of U.S. flag oil tankers of 150 gross tons and above and all other U.S. flag ships of 400 gross tons and above.</textblock>
    <textblock>Form(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>None.</textblock>
    <textblock>Average Burden Hours per Respondent:</textblock>
    <textblock>82 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard has submitted the requirements to OMB for review under section 3504(h) of the Paperwork Reduction Act. Persons submitting comments on the requirements should submit their comments both to OMB and to the Coast Guard where indicated under</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federalism</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard has analyzed this proposal under the principles and criteria contained in Executive Order 12612 and has determined that it does not have sufficient federalism implications to warrant the preparation of a Federalism Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environment</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard considered the environmental impact of this proposal and concluded that, under section 2B.2 of Commandant Instruction M16475.1B, this proposal is categorically excluded from further environmental documentation. This proposal is expected to contribute to the reduction of the occurrence of ship-generated oil spills in the marine environment. A Categorical Exclusion Determination is available in the docket for inspection of copying where indicated under</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 33 CFR Part 151</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedure, Oil pollution, Penalties, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Water pollution control.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set out in the preamble, the Coast Guard proposes to amend 33 CFR part 151 as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 151_VESSELS CARRYING OIL, NOXIOUS LIQUID SUBSTANCES, GARBAGE AND MUNICIPAL OR COMMERCIAL WASTE</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart A_Implementation of MARPOL 73/78</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for 33 CFR part 151, subpart A, continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>33 U.S.C. 1321(j)(1)(c) and 1903(b); Executive Order 11735; 3 CFR 1971-1975 Comp. p. 793; 49 CFR 1.46.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 151.05 is amended by adding paragraph (5) under the definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>New ship</textblock>
    <textblock>and adding a definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>Shipboard oil pollution emergency plan</textblock>
    <textblock>to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart A_Implementation of MARPOL 73/78</textblock>
    <textblock>§151.05</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>New ship</textblock>
    <textblock>means a ship_</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) For the purposes of §§151.26 through 151.28, which is delivered on or after April 4, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Shipboard oil pollution emergency plan</textblock>
    <textblock>means a plan prepared, submitted, and maintained according to the provisions of §§151.26 through 151.28 of this subpart for United States ships or maintained according to the provisions of §151.29(a) of this subpart for foreign ships operated under the authority of a country that is party to MARPOL 73/78 while in the navigable waters of the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Section 151.09 is amended by adding paragraphs (c) and (d) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§151.09</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicability.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Sections 151.26 through 151.28 apply to each United States oceangoing ship specified in paragraphs (a)(1) through (a)(4) of this section which is_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) An oil tanker of 150 gross tons and above or other ship of 400 gross tons and above; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A fixed or floating drilling rig or other platform, when not engaged in the exploration, exploitation, or associated offshore processing of seabed mineral resources.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Sections 151.26 through 151.28 do not apply to_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The ships specified in paragraph (b) of this section;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Any barge or other ship which is constructed or operated in such a manner that no oil can be discharged from any portion thereof, intentionally or unintentionally, including, but not limited to, oil discharged as the result of a casualty to the ship.</textblock>
    <textblock>§151.21</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Section 151.21(a) is amended by adding the words ``that is party to MARPOL 73/78'' in the last sentence after the word ``country''.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Sections 151.26 through 151.29 are added to read as follows:</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
