<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00019</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Government Publications Section, California State Library, 914 Capitol Mall, P.O. Box 942837 Sacramento, California 94237</textblock>
    <textblock>San Diego County Library, 5555 Overland Avenue, Building 15, San Diego, California 92123</textblock>
    <textblock>Semi Valley Public Library, 2969 Tapo Canyon Road, Semi Valley, California 93063</textblock>
    <textblock>Government Publications Department, Denver Public Library, BS/GPD, 1357 Broadway, Denver, Colorado 80203</textblock>
    <textblock>Rocky Flats Environmental Monitoring Council, 1536 Cole Boulevard, suite 150, Golden, Colorado 80401</textblock>
    <textblock>Mesa County Public Library, P.O. Box 20,000-5019, 530 College Place, Grand Junction, Colorado 81502</textblock>
    <textblock>Lakewood Branch, Jefferson County Public Library, 10200 West 20th Street, Lakewood, Colorado 80215</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Department of Energy Rocky Flats Public Reading Room, Front Range Community College Library, 3645 West 112th Avenue, Westminster, Colorado 80030</textblock>
    <textblock>Connecticut State Library, 231 Capitol Avenue, Hartford, Connecticut 06106</textblock>
    <textblock>Government Publications, Seely G. Mudd Library, Yale University, 38 Mansfield Street, New Haven, Connecticut 06520</textblock>
    <textblock>Widener University School of Law Library, P.O. Box 7475, 4601 Concord Pike, Wilmington, Delaware 19803</textblock>
    <textblock>District of Columbia Library, 6th Level, 500 Indiana Avenue, NW., Washington, D.C. 20001</textblock>
    <textblock>Freedom of Information Reading Room, U.S. Department of Energy, 1000 Independence Avenue, SW., room 1E-190, Washington, D.C. 20585</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Reading Room, Largo Public Library, 351 East Bay Drive, Largo, Florida 34640</textblock>
    <textblock>Document Section, State Library of Florida, R.A. Gray Building, 500 South Poronough, Tallahassee, Florida 82399</textblock>
    <textblock>Reese Library, Augusta College, 2500 Walton Way, Augusta, Georgia 30910</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Documents Section, Hawaii State Library, 478 South King Street, Honolulu, Hawaii 96813</textblock>
    <textblock>Boise Public Library, 715 South Capitol Boulevard, Boise, Idaho 83702</textblock>
    <textblock>Idaho State Library, 325 West State Street, Boise, Idaho 83702</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Reading Room, Idaho Operations Office, U.S. Department of Energy, 1776 Science Center Drive, Idaho Falls, Idaho 83402</textblock>
    <textblock>Idaho Falls Public Library, 457 Broadway, Idaho Falls, Idaho 83402</textblock>
    <textblock>Moscow-Latah County Library, 110 South Jefferson, Moscow, Idaho 83843</textblock>
    <textblock>Idaho National Engineering Laboratory Pocatello Office, 215 North 9th, Pocatello, Idaho 83201</textblock>
    <textblock>Pocatello Library, 612 East Clark, Pocatello, Idaho 83201</textblock>
    <textblock>Idaho National Engineering Laboratory Twin Falls Office, 1062 Blue Lakes Boulevard North, suite 106, Twin Falls, Idaho 83001</textblock>
    <textblock>Twin Falls Public Library, 434 2nd Street East, Twin Falls, Idaho 83001</textblock>
    <textblock>Chicago Operations Office, U.S. Department of Energy, 9800 South Cass Avenue, Argonne, Illinois 60439</textblock>
    <textblock>Government Publications Department, Chicago Public Library, 400 North Franklin, Chicago, Illinois 60610</textblock>
    <textblock>Reference Department, Illinois State Library, 300 South Second, Springfield, Illinois 62701</textblock>
    <textblock>Documents Section, State Library of Iowa, Historical Building, East 12th &amp; Grand, Des Moines, Iowa 50310</textblock>
    <textblock>Ashland Community College Library, University of Kentucky, 1400 College Drive, Ashland, Kentucky 41101</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Documents Section, Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives, P.O. Box 537, 300 Coffee Tree Road, Frankfort, Kentucky 40602</textblock>
    <textblock>Paducah Public Library, 555 Washington Avenue, Paducah, Kentucky 42001</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
