<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00035</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Public Service Company of Oklahoma, et al.; Electric Rate and Corporate Regulation Filings</textblock>
    <textblock>February 8, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that the following filings have been made with the Commission:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Public Service Company of Oklahoma</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-949-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 2, 1994, Public Service Company of Oklahoma and Southwestern Electric Power Company submitted for filing a revised SPP Interpool Transmission Service Tariff. The filing companies state that the purpose of the filing is to update the rates for service under the tariff. The filing companies request an effective date of February 2, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The filing companies state that copies of the filing have been served on the Public Utility Commission of Texas, the Oklahoma Corporation Commission, the Arkansas Public Service Commission, the Louisiana Public Service Commission and the New Mexico Public Utility Commission. Copies of the filing are also available for inspection in the general offices of each of the filing companies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 24, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Westchester Resco Company, L.P.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket Nos. ES94-14-000 and ES94-14-001]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 2, 1994, Westchester Resco Company (WRC) filed an application and on February 3, 1994, filed an amendment to its application under section 204 of the Federal Power Act seeking authority to guarantee refunding bonds to be issued by the County of Westchester Industrial Development Agency for refinancing bonds issued in 1982 and seeking authorization for blanket approval of all future issuance of securities and assumptions of liabilities. Also, WRC requests exemption from the Commission's competitive bidding and negotiated placement regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 24, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Stone Container Corporation, A Delaware Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. EL94-25-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 28, 1994, Stone Container Corporation (Operator) tendered for filing a Petition for Declaratory Order that the transfer of the lessee's interest in a qualifying cogeneration facility from the Operator to Carolina Power &amp; Light Company (CP&amp;L), a North Carolina corporation, will not (1) subject the Operator to Commission regulation as a ``public utility'' under section 201(e) of the Federal Power Act if the Operator continues to operate the Facility pursuant to an Operating, Maintenance and Repair Agreement between CP&amp;L and the Operator and (2) subject GELCO Corporation (GELCO) and Westinghouse Electric Corporation, as lessors, each holding an undivided interest in the Facility to regulation as ``public utilities'' under section 201(e) of the Federal Power Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 24, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Maine Yankee Atomic Power Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. EL93-22-001]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice on February 2, 1994, Maine Yankee Atomic Power Company (Maine Yankee) tendered for filing its compliance report in the above-referenced docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 22, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-949-000, et al.]</textblock>
  </rindock>
</doc>
