<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00089</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>However, for purposes of this part, the Secretary proposes</textblock>
    <textblock>to specify that with regard to the conduct of an officer or</textblock>
    <textblock>employee of a third-party servicer or a person, entity, or</textblock>
    <textblock>officer or employee of an entity with which the servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>contracts, that conduct would be a factor in determining the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer's financial responsibility only if the individual or</textblock>
    <textblock>entity is used in a capacity that involves administering any</textblock>
    <textblock>aspect of the Title IV, HEA programs. For example, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>would not hold the conduct of a custodian employed by a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer as an element in determining the servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility, if that custodian had no responsibility</textblock>
    <textblock>for administering a Title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary also proposes to specify that a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer would not be considered to be financially responsible if</textblock>
    <textblock>the servicer, or any principal or affiliate of the servicer (as</textblock>
    <textblock>those terms are defined in 34 CFR part 85), is debarred or</textblock>
    <textblock>suspended under E.O. 12549 or the FAR, or is engaging in activity</textblock>
    <textblock>that is cause under 34 CFR 85.305 or 85.405 for debarment or</textblock>
    <textblock>suspension under E.O. 12549 or the FAR.</textblock>
    <textblock>Like the proposed changes governing the past performance of</textblock>
    <textblock>individuals or organizations associated with institutions that</textblock>
    <textblock>participate in the Title IV, HEA programs and standard of conduct</textblock>
    <textblock>of participating institutions and third-party servicers, these</textblock>
    <textblock>changes are needed to establish appropriate safeguards to protect</textblock>
    <textblock>the integrity of the FFEL programs and the Federal financial</textblock>
    <textblock>interest if serious questions are raised about the honest and</textblock>
    <textblock>lawful conduct of a servicer's owners, officers, directors,</textblock>
    <textblock>employees, or affiliates whose duties involve the administration</textblock>
    <textblock>of or influence over the use of those funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under this section, a third-party servicer would be required</textblock>
    <textblock>to have an annual independent audit of its administration of the</textblock>
    <textblock>FFEL programs that examines the servicer's compliance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>Act and applicable regulations and its financial management of</textblock>
    <textblock>FFEL program activities. These requirements and audit exceptions</textblock>
    <textblock>would parallel the proposed audit requirements and exceptions</textblock>
    <textblock>under 34 CFR 668.23 (governing audit requirements for third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicers contracting with institutions to administer any aspect</textblock>
    <textblock>of the institution's participation in the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs), except that the report of the audit would have to be</textblock>
    <textblock>submitted to the Secretary within six months of the end of the</textblock>
    <textblock>audit report period. A third-party servicer's initial audit</textblock>
    <textblock>would have to cover the same period required of audits performed</textblock>
    <textblock>for third-party servicers contracting with institutions to</textblock>
    <textblock>administer any aspect of the institution's participation in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs (discussed previously in 34 CFR 668.23).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary believes that initial audits will be more useful</textblock>
    <textblock>and effective if they encompass an entire fiscal year. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary also believes that allowing servicers additional time</textblock>
    <textblock>to prepare for the implementation of these regulations would</textblock>
    <textblock>enable servicers to comply more fully with these regulations as</textblock>
    <textblock>well as defray the costs associated with an audit of a partial</textblock>
    <textblock>fiscal year and minimize the burden associated with implementing</textblock>
    <textblock>these regulations, as called for under E.O. 12866. Subsequent</textblock>
    <textblock>audits would, as required by statute, encompass the entire period</textblock>
    <textblock>since the servicer's previous audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, the Secretary proposes that the audit report</textblock>
    <textblock>would be conducted in accordance with the audit guide developed</textblock>
    <textblock>by the Inspector General of the Department of Education unless</textblock>
    <textblock>the third-party servicer is a governmental entity or nonprofit</textblock>
    <textblock>organization. A third-party servicer that is a governmental</textblock>
    <textblock>entity would be required to have an audit conducted in accordance</textblock>
    <textblock>with 31 U.S.C. 7502 and 34 CFR part 80, appendix G (pursuant to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Single Audit Act). A third-party servicer that is a</textblock>
    <textblock>nonprofit organization would be required to have an audit</textblock>
    <textblock>conducted in accordance with Office of Management and Budget</textblock>
    <textblock>Circular A-133, ``Audit of Institutions of Higher Education and</textblock>
    <textblock>Other Nonprofit Institutions,'' as incorporated in 34 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>74.61(h)(3).</textblock>
    <textblock>These proposed rules would also limit a lender's ability to</textblock>
    <textblock>enter into a contract with a third-party servicer. As explained</textblock>
    <textblock>previously in the discussion for §682.200, under this proposal, a</textblock>
    <textblock>lender may not enter into a contract with a third-party servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>that the Secretary has determined does not meet the</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability or financial responsibility standards</textblock>
    <textblock>under this section. Further, a lender that contracts with a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer would have to provide the Secretary with the</textblock>
    <textblock>name and address of the third-party servicer, and, upon request,</textblock>
    <textblock>a copy of that contract.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 682.700␣Purpose and scope, 682.701␣Definitions of</textblock>
    <textblock>terms used in this subpart, 682.702␣Effect on participation,</textblock>
    <textblock>682.703␣Informal compliance procedure, 682.704␣Emergency</textblock>
    <textblock>action, 682.705␣Suspension proceedings, 682.706␣Limitation or</textblock>
    <textblock>termination proceedings, 682.707␣Appeals in a limitation or</textblock>
    <textblock>termination proceeding, 682.708␣Evidence of mailing and receipt</textblock>
    <textblock>dates, 682.709␣Reimbursements, refunds, and offsets, 682.710␣Removal of limitation, and 682.711␣Reinstatement after</textblock>
    <textblock>termination.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to amend subpart G to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide that the Secretary would have the authority to limit,</textblock>
    <textblock>suspend, or terminate a third-party servicer's ability to</textblock>
    <textblock>contract with an eligible lender if the Secretary determines the</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer has violated any FFEL program requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 432(a)(1) of the Act authorizes the Secretary to take</textblock>
    <textblock>action against third-party servicers for any violation of any</textblock>
    <textblock>FFEL program requirement. Under these proposed regulations, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary could also take emergency action against the servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>if the Secretary receives reliable information that the servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>is in violation of applicable requirements pertaining to the</textblock>
    <textblock>lender's portfolio of loans. The procedures under which the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary could take those actions and the procedures a third-party servicer could use to appeal those actions are consistent</textblock>
    <textblock>with the long-standing procedures the Secretary uses to take</textblock>
    <textblock>those actions against a lender, and the procedures a lender may</textblock>
    <textblock>use to appeal those actions.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
