<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00051</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Endangered and Threatened Wildlife and Plants; Proposal To List the Barton Springs Salamander as Endangered</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>50 CFR Part 17</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1018-AC22</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Fish and Wildlife Service (Service) proposes to determine endangered status for the Barton Springs salamander (</textblock>
    <textblock>Eurycea sosorum</textblock>
    <textblock>), known only from Barton Springs in Zilker Park, Austin, Travis County, Texas. The primary threat to this species is contamination of the waters that feed Barton Springs due to the potential for catastrophic events (such as petroleum or chemical spills) and chronic degradation resulting from urban activities. Also of concern are disturbances to the salamander's surface habitat (the waters in Barton Springs, Eliza Pool, and Sunken Garden Springs) and reduced groundwater supplies resulting from increased groundwater withdrawal. This proposal, if made final, would implement Federal protection provided by the Act for the Barton Springs salamander.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments from all interested parties must be received by April 18, 1994. Public hearing requests must be received by April 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments and materials concerning this proposal should be sent to the State Administrator, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, 611 East 6th Street, room 407, Austin, Texas 78701. Comments and materials received will be available for public inspection, by appointment, during normal business hours at the above address.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Lisa O'Donnell, U.S. Fish and</textblock>
    <textblock>Wildlife Biologist (see</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>section) (512/482-5436).</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
