<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00015</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Army Science Board; Closed Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with Section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463), announcement is made of the following Committee Meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>Name of Committee:</textblock>
    <textblock>Army Science Board (ASB).</textblock>
    <textblock>Date of Meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>1 and 2 March 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Time of Meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>0830-1600/1 March (classified); 1300-1630/2 March (classified).</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>Fort Leavenworth, KS/1 March; Fort McPherson, GA/2 March.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agenda:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Army Science Board's Ad Hoc Study on ``Innovations in Artillery Force Structure'' will hold a meeting of the Panel Members. This meeting will be hosted by the Deputy Commanding General U.S. Army Combined Arms Command for Combat Developments (Fort Leavenworth) and the Forces Command Chief of Staff (Fort McPherson). The intent of the meeting is to present general and specific information to the panel pertaining to artillery force structure development within the U.S. Army and Forces Command. It will consist of primarily classified briefings dealing with force structure initiatives, war plans, artillery related studies and analysis, and field artillery weapons systems.</textblock>
    <textblock>This meeting will be closed to the public in accordance with Section 552b(c) of Title 5, U.S.C., specifically subparagraph (1) thereof, and Title 5, U.S.C., appendix 2, subsection 10(d). The unclassified and classified matters to be discussed are so inextricably intertwined so as to preclude opening all portions of the meeting. The ASB Administrative Officer Sally Warner, may be contacted for further information at (703) 695-0781.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Department of the Army</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Sally A. Warner,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrative Officer, Army Science Board.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3692 Filed 2-14-94; 4:14 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3710-08-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
