<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00013</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Marine Mammals</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[I.D. 020794B]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), NOAA, Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Receipt of modification to application for a scientific research permit (P557).</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that Scripps Institution of Oceanography, Institute for Geophysics and Planetary Physics, Acoustic Thermometry of Ocean Climate Program,</textblock>
    <textblock>9500 Gilman Drive, La Jolla, CA 92093-0225, has submitted a modification to an application for a permit to take marine mammals and sea turtles for purposes of scientific research.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments must be received on or before March 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The modified application and related documents are available for review upon written request or by appointment in the following offices:</textblock>
    <textblock>Permits Division, Office of Protected Resources, NMFS, 1315 East-West Highway, room 13130, Silver Spring, MD 20910 (301/713-2289);</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, Southwest Region, NMFS, NOAA, 501 West Ocean Boulevard, suite 4200, Long Beach, CA 90802-4213</textblock>
    <textblock>(310/980-4016); Coordinator, Pacific Area Office, NMFS, NOAA, 2570 Dole Street, room 106, Honolulu, HI 96822-2396 (808/955-8831).</textblock>
    <textblock>Written data or views, or requests for a public hearing on this request, should be submitted to the Director, Office of Protected Resources, NMFS, NOAA, U.S. Department of Commerce, 1315 East-West Highway, Silver Spring, MD 20910, within 30 days of the publication of this notice. Those individuals requesting a hearing should set forth the specific reasons why a hearing on this particular request would be appropriate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Concurrent with the publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, the Secretary of Commerce is forwarding copies of this modification to the application to the Marine Mammal Commission and its Committee of Scientific Advisors.</textblock>
  </address>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The subject permit is requested under the authority of the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972, as amended (16 U.S.C. 1361</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>), the Regulations Governing the Taking and Importing of Marine Mammals (50 CFR part 216), the Endangered Species Act of 1973, as amended (16 U.S.C. 1531</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>), and the regulations governing the taking, importing, and exporting of endangered fish and wildlife (50 CFR part 222).</textblock>
    <textblock>This application modification is to request incidental harassment of sea turtles, and additional species of marine mammals which have only occasionally been observed in Hawaiian waters. As described in the original permit application, permission is requested to incidentally harass marine mammals and sea turtles by a low frequency (70 Hz) sound source which will be located north of Haena, off the northern coast of Kauai, Hawaii, at a depth of 850-950m. This sound source is part of the Acoustic Thermometry of Ocean Climate (ATOC) program, and will be operated from February 1994 through December 1995, with a maximum duty cycle of 8%, to conduct research on the effects of this source on marine mammals and sea turtles. The transmission bandwidth is 20 Hz with a level of 195 dB (re: 1 uPa at 1m), and the spectrum level for the peak frequency (70 Hz) is</textblock>
    <textblock>182 dB. The effects of these transmissions on marine mammals and sea turtles will be monitored through passive acoustic tracking of Mysticetes, shore-based visual observations of marine mammals, and aerial observations and surveys of marine mammals and sea turtles.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William W. Fox, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Protected Resources, National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3579 Filed: 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
