<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00085</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00045</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[AZ-020-04-4210-05; AZA-27967]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Realty Action; Recreation and Public Purposes (R&amp;PP) Act Classification; Mohave County, AZ</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The following public lands in Mohave County, Arizona have been examined and found suitable for classification for lease or conveyance to the Chloride School District #11 under the provisions of the Recreation and Public Purposes Act, as amended (43 U.S.C. 869</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.). The Chloride School District proposes to use the lands for an elementary (kindergarten through 8th grades) school.</textblock>
    <textblock>Gila and Salt River Base and Meridian</textblock>
    <textblock>Township 25 North, Range 19 West,</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 10, W1/2SW1/4SW1/4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comprising 20.00 acres.</textblock>
    <textblock>The lands are not needed for Federal purposes. Lease or conveyance is consistent with current Bureau of Land Management land use planning and would be in the public interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>The lease/patent, when issued, will be subject to the following terms, conditions, and reservations:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Provisions of the Recreation and Public Purposes Act and to all applicable regulations of the Secretary of the Interior.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. A right-of-way for ditches and canals constructed by the authority of the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. All minerals shall be reserved to the United States, together with the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the minerals.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Those rights for road purposes granted to the Mohave County Board of Supervisors by Right-of-Way No. AZA-27254 for June Road and 7th Street.</textblock>
    <textblock>For detailed information concerning this action, contact Bill Wadsworth at the office of the Bureau of Land Management, Kingman Resource Area, 2475 Beverly Avenue, Kingman, Arizona, 86401, (602) 757-3161.</textblock>
    <textblock>Upon publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, the lands will be segregated from all other forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the general mining laws, except for lease or conveyance under the Recreation and Public Purposes Act and leasing under the mineral leasing laws. For a period of 45 days from the date of publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, interested persons may submit comments regarding the proposed lease/conveyance or classification of the lands to the District Manager, Bureau of Land Management, Phoenix District Office, 2015 West Deer Valley Road, Phoenix, Arizona 85027, (602) 780-8090.</textblock>
    <textblock>Classification Comments: Interested parties may submit comments involving the suitability of the land for a school. Comments on the classification are restricted to whether the land is physically suited for the proposal, whether the use will maximize the future use or uses of the land, whether the use is consistent with local planning and zoning, or if the use is consistent with State and Federal programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Application Comments: Interested parties may submit comments regarding the specific use proposed in the application and plan of development, whether the BLM followed proper administrative procedures in reaching the decision, or any other factor not directly related to the suitability of the land for a school.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any adverse comments will be reviewed by the State Director. In the absence of any adverse comments, the classification will become effective 60 days from the date of publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <signer>
    <textblock>G.L. Cheniae,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>District Manager.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3661 Filed 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-32-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
