<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00053</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The salamander was first observed at Sunken Garden Springs on</textblock>
    <textblock>January 12, 1993 (TPWD 1993). Five or fewer individuals have been</textblock>
    <textblock>sighted on any given visit to this outlet (Chippindale, pers. comm.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993). Biologists had speculated that the salamander occurred at</textblock>
    <textblock>Sunken Garden Springs; however, no salamanders were observed during</textblock>
    <textblock>previous surveys conducted at this location between 1987 and 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Low water levels and the presence of large rocks and sediment in the</textblock>
    <textblock>pool reportedly make searching for salamanders difficult at this</textblock>
    <textblock>location (TPWD 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>The extent to which the salamander occurs in the aquifer is</textblock>
    <textblock>unknown. However, there is currently no evidence indicating that</textblock>
    <textblock>the species' range extends beyond the immediate vicinity of Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs. Surveys of other spring outlets (including the spring</textblock>
    <textblock>outlet immediately above Barton Springs Pool) in the Barton Springs</textblock>
    <textblock>segment and other portions of the Edwards Aquifer have failed to</textblock>
    <textblock>locate additional populations (Chippindale</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993; William</textblock>
    <textblock>Russell, speleologist; Hillis; Price; Sweet; pers. comms., 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>No other species of</textblock>
    <textblock>Eurycea</textblock>
    <textblock>is known to occur in this portion of the</textblock>
    <textblock>aquifer.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Barton Springs salamander's diet is believed to consist</textblock>
    <textblock>almost entirely of amphipods (Chippindale</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993). Primary</textblock>
    <textblock>predators are believed to be fish and crayfish (Chippindale, Hillis,</textblock>
    <textblock>Price, pers. comm., 1993). Observations of larvae and females with</textblock>
    <textblock>eggs (Chippindale</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993) indicate successful breeding is</textblock>
    <textblock>occurring. The species may breed year-round (Chippindale, pers.</textblock>
    <textblock>comm., 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>The water that discharges at Barton Springs originates from</textblock>
    <textblock>the Barton Springs segment of the Edwards Aquifer (hereafter</textblock>
    <textblock>referred to as the ``Barton Springs segment''). The Barton Springs</textblock>
    <textblock>segment covers roughly 400 square kilometers (155 square miles) from</textblock>
    <textblock>southern Travis County to northern Hays County, Texas. The</textblock>
    <textblock>approximate boundaries are the ``bad water'' line to the east (where</textblock>
    <textblock>dissolved solids are less than 1,000 milligrams/l (mg/l) (1,000</textblock>
    <textblock>parts per million) in the aquifer, but greater than this to the</textblock>
    <textblock>east); the Colorado River to the north; the geologic divide between</textblock>
    <textblock>contiguous Edwards limestones overlying the aquifer and the Glen</textblock>
    <textblock>Rose limestones to the west; and a groundwater divide occurring</textblock>
    <textblock>roughly between the Onion Creek and Blanco River watersheds to the</textblock>
    <textblock>south. The area south of the southern boundary is known as the San</textblock>
    <textblock>Antonio segment of the Edwards Aquifer and drains toward San Marcos</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs. Groundwater movement from the San Antonio segment</textblock>
    <textblock>northward to the Barton Springs segment is believed to occur only</textblock>
    <textblock>during extreme drought conditions. North of the southern boundary,</textblock>
    <textblock>the water in the aquifer moves toward Barton Springs (Slade</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1986).</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs drains about 391 square kilometers (151 square</textblock>
    <textblock>miles) of the Barton Springs segment. The remaining 10 square</textblock>
    <textblock>kilometers (4 square miles) discharge at Cold and Deep Eddy Springs</textblock>
    <textblock>and are believed to be hydrologically distinct from the area</textblock>
    <textblock>discharging to Barton Springs. Cold and Deep Eddy Springs are</textblock>
    <textblock>recharged by Dry Creek and a portion of Barton Creek. About 96</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of all springflow from the aquifer discharges through Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs. The remaining 4 percent exits through intermittent</textblock>
    <textblock>springs, most of which are located in Barton Creek between Loop 360</textblock>
    <textblock>and Barton Springs. These springs flow only about 30 percent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>time and discharge up to 170 liters per second (l/s) (6 cubic feet</textblock>
    <textblock>per second (cfs)). The long-term mean discharge from Barton Springs</textblock>
    <textblock>is about 1,400 l/s (50 cfs), ranging from 283 l/s (10 cfs) to 4,700</textblock>
    <textblock>l/s (166 cfs) (Slade</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1986). The mean water temperature is</textblock>
    <textblock>20</textblock>
    <textblock>○C (68</textblock>
    <textblock>○F) (Martyn-Baker</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1992).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Barton Springs segment is divided into two major zones,</textblock>
    <textblock>the recharge zone and artesian zone. The recharge zone is that</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of the aquifer where Edwards limestones are exposed at the</textblock>
    <textblock>surface, and covers the western 79 percent (about 233 square</textblock>
    <textblock>kilometers (90 square miles)) of the aquifer. The artesian zone is</textblock>
    <textblock>confined by an impermeable layer of Del Rio clay and covers the</textblock>
    <textblock>eastern 21 percent of the aquifer. About 85 percent of all recharge</textblock>
    <textblock>is through sinkholes, fractures, and other openings in the beds of</textblock>
    <textblock>six major creeks that cross the recharge zone, including (from north</textblock>
    <textblock>to south) Barton, Williamson, Slaughter, Bear, Little Bear, and</textblock>
    <textblock>Onion creeks. The remaining 15 percent of recharge is through</textblock>
    <textblock>tributaries and direct infiltration between the creeks (Slade</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1986).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
