<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00109</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(1)(i) The gravity of an institution's or third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer's violation or failure to carry out the relevant</textblock>
    <textblock>statutory provision, regulatory provision, special arrangement,</textblock>
    <textblock>agreement, or limitation; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The gravity of the institution's or servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>misrepresentation;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The size of the institution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The size of the servicer's business, including the</textblock>
    <textblock>number of institutions and students served by the servicer;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) In the case of a violation by a third-party servicer,</textblock>
    <textblock>the extent to which the servicer can document that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution contributed to that violation; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)(i) For purposes of assessing a fine on a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, the extent to which violations are caused by repeated</textblock>
    <textblock>mechanical systemic unintentional errors.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The Secretary counts the total of violations caused by</textblock>
    <textblock>repeated mechanical systemic unintentional errors as a single</textblock>
    <textblock>violation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) In determining the gravity of the institution's or</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer's violation, failure, or misrepresentation under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (a) of this section, the designated department</textblock>
    <textblock>official, hearing official, and Secretary take into account the</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of any liability owed by the institution and any</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer that contracts with the institution, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>number of students affected as a result of that violation,</textblock>
    <textblock>failure, or misrepresentation on_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Improperly expended or unspent Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>funds received by the institution or servicer, as applicable; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Required refunds.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Upon the request of the institution or third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, the Secretary may compromise the fine.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1094)</textblock>
    <textblock>22. Section 668.93 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง668.93</textblock>
    <textblock>Limitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>A limitation may include, as appropriate to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program in question_</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A limit on the number or percentage of students</textblock>
    <textblock>enrolled in an institution who may receive Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>funds;</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) A limit, for a stated period of time, on the percentage</textblock>
    <textblock>of an institution's total receipts from tuition and fees derived</textblock>
    <textblock>from Title IV, HEA program funds;</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) A limit on the number or size of institutions with</textblock>
    <textblock>which a third-party servicer may contract;</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) A limit on the number of borrower or loan accounts that</textblock>
    <textblock>a third-party servicer may service under a contract with an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) A limit on the responsibilities that a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer may perform under a contract with an institution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) A requirement for a third-party servicer to perform</textblock>
    <textblock>additional responsibilities under a contract with an institution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(g) A requirement that an institution obtain surety, in a</textblock>
    <textblock>specified amount, to assure its ability to meet its financial</textblock>
    <textblock>obligations to students who receive Title IV, HEA program funds;</textblock>
    <textblock>(h) A requirement that a third-party servicer obtain</textblock>
    <textblock>surety, in a specified amount, to assure the servicer's ability</textblock>
    <textblock>to meet the servicer's financial obligations under a contract; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Other conditions as may be determined by the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>to be reasonable and appropriate.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1094)</textblock>
    <textblock>23. Section 668.94 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง668.94</textblock>
    <textblock>Termination.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A termination_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Ends an institution's participation in a Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program or ends a third-party servicer's eligibility to contract</textblock>
    <textblock>with any institution to administer any aspect of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation in a Title IV, HEA program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Ends the authority of a third-party servicer to</textblock>
    <textblock>administer any aspect of any institution's participation in that</textblock>
    <textblock>program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Prohibits an institution or third-party servicer, as</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable, or the Secretary from making or increasing awards</textblock>
    <textblock>under that program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Prohibits an institution or third-party servicer, as</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable, from making any other new commitments of funds under</textblock>
    <textblock>that program; and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
