<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00006</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Airworthiness Directives: Piper Aircraft Corporation PA24, PA28R, PA30, PA32R, PA32RT, PA34-200, PA34-200T, PA39, and PA44 Series Airplanes</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 39</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93-CE-61-AD]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Advance notice of proposed rulemaking (ANPRM).</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA)</textblock>
    <textblock>recently became aware of an incident in England where</textblock>
    <textblock>the left main landing gear (MLG) collapsed on a Piper</textblock>
    <textblock>Aircraft Corporation (Piper) Model PA34-200T airplane</textblock>
    <textblock>because of swivel pin failure. At that time, the FAA</textblock>
    <textblock>found no service difficulty reports on airplanes of</textblock>
    <textblock>this type design that are certificated for operation in</textblock>
    <textblock>the United States. The FAA has since reviewed service</textblock>
    <textblock>difficulty reports of all Piper airplanes that have</textblock>
    <textblock>retractable MLG with the swivel pin configuration</textblock>
    <textblock>(certain PA24, PA28R, PA30, PA32R, PA32RT, PA34-200,</textblock>
    <textblock>PA34-200T, PA39, and PA44 series airplanes), and found</textblock>
    <textblock>two incidents of cracked swivel pins. The purpose of</textblock>
    <textblock>this advance notice is to seek comments from interested</textblock>
    <textblock>persons regarding the best action (if any) to take in</textblock>
    <textblock>order to correct any possible problems with retractable</textblock>
    <textblock>MLG swivel pins. All comments and ideas will be</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluated by the FAA and the FAA will research the</textblock>
    <textblock>situation to decide whether rulemaking is needed.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before May 10,</textblock>
    <textblock>1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Submit comments in triplicate to the FAA,</textblock>
    <textblock>Central Region, Office of the Assistant Chief Counsel,</textblock>
    <textblock>Attention: Rules Docket No. 93-CE-61-AD, room 1558, 601 E. 12th Street, Kansas</textblock>
    <textblock>City, Missouri 64106. Comments may be inspected at</textblock>
    <textblock>this location between 8 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through</textblock>
    <textblock>Friday, holidays excepted.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Christina Marsh,</textblock>
    <textblock>Aerospace Engineer, FAA, Atlanta Aircraft Certification</textblock>
    <textblock>Office, 1669 Phoenix Parkway, suite 210C, Atlanta,</textblock>
    <textblock>Georgia 30349; telephone (404) 991-2910; facsimile (404) 991-3606.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments Invited</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to participate in</textblock>
    <textblock>the making of the proposed rule by submitting such</textblock>
    <textblock>written data, views, or arguments as they may desire.</textblock>
    <textblock>Communications should identify the Rules Docket number</textblock>
    <textblock>and be submitted in triplicate to the address specified</textblock>
    <textblock>above. All communications received on or before the</textblock>
    <textblock>closing date for comments, specified above, will be</textblock>
    <textblock>considered before taking action on the proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposals contained in this notice may be changed</textblock>
    <textblock>in light of the comments received.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments are specifically invited on the overall</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory, economic, environmental, and energy aspects</textblock>
    <textblock>of the proposed rule. All comments submitted will be</textblock>
    <textblock>available, both before and after the closing date for</textblock>
    <textblock>comments, in the Rules Docket for examination by</textblock>
    <textblock>interested persons. A report that summarizes each FAA-public contact concerned with the substance of this</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal will be filed in the Rules Docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Commenters wishing the FAA to acknowledge receipt</textblock>
    <textblock>of their comments submitted in response to this notice</textblock>
    <textblock>must submit a</textblock>
    <textblock>self-addressed, stamped postcard on which the following</textblock>
    <textblock>statement is made: ``Comments to Docket No. 93-CE-61-AD.'' The postcard will be date stamped and returned to</textblock>
    <textblock>the commenter.</textblock>
    <textblock>Availability of NPRMs</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person may obtain a copy of this ANPRM by</textblock>
    <textblock>submitting a request to the FAA, Central Region, Office</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Assistant Chief Counsel, Attention: Rules</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. 93-CE-61-AD, room 1558, 601 E. 12th Street,</textblock>
    <textblock>Kansas City, Missouri 64106.</textblock>
    <textblock>Discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA is currently investigating a possible</textblock>
    <textblock>unsafe condition on Piper PA24, PA28R, PA30, PA32R,</textblock>
    <textblock>PA32RT, PA34-200, PA34-200T, PA39, and PA44 series</textblock>
    <textblock>airplanes that have retractable main landing gear (MLG)</textblock>
    <textblock>with a swivel pin configuration.</textblock>
    <textblock>The MLG collapsed on a Piper Model PA34-200T</textblock>
    <textblock>airplane that is certificated for operation in England</textblock>
    <textblock>because of MLG swivel pin failure. At that time, the</textblock>
    <textblock>FAA found no service difficulty reports of this type on</textblock>
    <textblock>airplanes of this type design that are certificated for</textblock>
    <textblock>operation in the United States. The FAA has since</textblock>
    <textblock>reviewed service difficulty reports of all Piper</textblock>
    <textblock>airplanes that have retractable MLG with the swivel</textblock>
    <textblock>pin configuration (certain PA24, PA28R, PA30, PA32R,</textblock>
    <textblock>PA32RT, PA34-200, PA34-200T, PA39, and PA44 series</textblock>
    <textblock>airplanes), and found two incidents of swivel pin</textblock>
    <textblock>failure.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
