<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-0-00015</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Airworthiness Directives; McDonnell Douglas Model DC-10 Series Airplanes and Model KC-10A (Military) Airplanes</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 39</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93-NM-112-AD; Amendment 39-8815; AD 94-03-08]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This amendment supersedes an existing airworthiness directive (AD), applicable to McDonnell Douglas Model DC-10 series airplanes and Model KC-10A (military) airplanes, that currently requires certain structural modifications and inspections. This amendment requires additional structural modifications and inspections. This amendment is prompted by an evaluation by the Model DC-10 Task Group, which identified additional modifications for mandatory action. The actions specified by this AD are intended to prevent degradation in the structural capabilities of the affected airplanes. This action also reflects the FAA's decision that long-term continued operational safety should be assured by actual modification of the airframe, where feasible, rather than only repetitive inspections for known service problems.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective March 21, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The incorporation by reference of McDonnell Douglas Report No. MDC-K1571, ``DC-10/KC-10 Aging Aircraft Service Action Requirements Document,'' Revision B, dated March 24, 1993, as listed in the regulations, is approved by the Director of the Federal Register as of March 21, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The incorporation by reference of McDonnell Douglas Report No. MDC-K1571,</textblock>
    <textblock>``DC-10/KC-10 Aging Aircraft Service Action Requirements Document,'' Revision A, dated February 28, 1990, as listed in the regulations, was approved previously by the Director of the Federal Register as of September 10, 1990 (55 FR 31816, August 6, 1990).</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The service information referenced in this AD may be obtained from McDonnell Douglas Corporation, P.O. Box 1771, Long Beach, California 90801-1771, Attention: Business Unit Manager, Technical Publications_Technical Administrative Support, C1-L5B. This information may be examined at the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), Transport Airplane Directorate, Rules Docket, 1601 Lind Avenue, SW., Renton, Washington; or at the FAA, Transport Airplane Directorate, Los Angeles Aircraft Certification Office, 3229 East Spring Street, Long Beach, California; or at the Office of the Federal Register, 800 North Capitol Street NW., suite 700, Washington, DC.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Maureen Moreland, Aerospace Engineer, Airframe Branch, ANM-121L, FAA, Transport Airplane Directorate, Los Angeles Aircraft Certification Office, 3229 East Spring Street, Long Beach, California 90806-2425; telephone (310) 988-5238; fax (310) 988-5210.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>A proposal to amend part 39 of the Federal Aviation Regulations by superseding AD 90-16-04, Amendment 39-6613 (55 FR 31816, August 6, 1990), which is applicable to McDonnell Douglas Model DC-10 series airplanes and Model KC-10A (military) airplanes, was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on October 12, 1993 (58 FR 52717). The action proposed to supersede AD 90-16-04 to require additional structural modifications and inspections.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons have been afforded an opportunity to participate in the making of this amendment. Due consideration has been given to the two comments received.</textblock>
    <textblock>The commenters support the proposed rule.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
