<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00082</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00042</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[WY-040-04-4110-03]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Availability of Enron's Burly Field Enhance Oil Recovery Project Draft Environmental Impact Statement</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bureau of Land Management (BLM) announces the availability of the Draft Environmental Impact Statement for Enron Burly Field Enhanced Oil Recovery Project. The proposed project area is located in Sections 18, 19, 20 and 29 of Township 28 North, Range 133 West, 6th Principal Meridian, Sublette County, Wyoming.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on the Draft Environmental Statement must be postmarked by April 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on the Draft Environmental Statement should be sent to District Manager, Rock Springs District, Highway 191 North, P.O. Box 1869, Rock Springs, 82902, telephone 307-382-5350.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>Arlan Hiner, Area Manager, Pinedale Resource Area, 432 E. Mill Street, P.O. Box 768, Pinedale, Wyoming 82941, telephone 307-367-4358.</textblock>
    <textblock>PUBLIC HEARINGS:</textblock>
    <textblock>No hearings are presently planned. However, should public demand warrant, a hearing would be held by the BLM.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Draft Environmental Impact Statement analyses two development scenarios including a 10 acre and 20 acre spacing infill drilling program within Enron's existing Burly Field. There is potential to convert approximately 14 of the 37 proposed wells into water injection wells for enhanced oil recovery. Associated facilities include access roads, water injection and oil gathering and sales pipelines, central tank battery and an electric distribution powerline.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David J. Walter,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting State Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3580 Filed 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-22-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
