<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00052</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Service proposes to list as endangered the Barton Springs</textblock>
    <textblock>salamander (</textblock>
    <textblock>Eurycea sosorum</textblock>
    <textblock>), under the authority of the Endangered</textblock>
    <textblock>Species Act (Act) of 1973, as amended (16 U.S.C. 1531</textblock>
    <textblock>et. seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Barton Springs salamander is entirely aquatic and neotenic,</textblock>
    <textblock>meaning it does not metamorphose into a terrestrial form and retains</textblock>
    <textblock>its bright red external gills throughout life. Adults attain an</textblock>
    <textblock>average length of 6.35 centimeters (2.5 inches). This species is</textblock>
    <textblock>slender, with slightly elongate limbs and reduced eyes. Dorsal</textblock>
    <textblock>coloration varies from pale purplish-brown or gray to</textblock>
    <textblock>yellowish-cream. Irregular spacing of dorsal pigments and pigment</textblock>
    <textblock>gaps results in a mottled, ``salt and pepper'' pattern (Sweet 1978,</textblock>
    <textblock>Chippindale</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Barton Springs salamander was first collected from Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs Pool in 1946 by Bryce Brown and Alvin Flury (Chippindale</textblock>
    <textblock>et</textblock>
    <textblock>al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993, Texas Parks and Wildlife Department (TPWD) 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>Although he did not publish a formal description, Dr. Samuel Sweet</textblock>
    <textblock>(University of California at Santa Barbara) was the first to</textblock>
    <textblock>recognize the Barton Springs salamander as distinct from other</textblock>
    <textblock>central Texas</textblock>
    <textblock>Eurycea</textblock>
    <textblock>salamanders based on its restricted</textblock>
    <textblock>distribution and unique morphological and skeletal characteristics</textblock>
    <textblock>(such as its reduced eyes, elongate limbs, dorsal coloration, and</textblock>
    <textblock>reduced number of presacral vertebrae) (Sweet 1978, 1984). Formal</textblock>
    <textblock>description of the Barton Springs salamander, based on Sweet's work</textblock>
    <textblock>and genetic studies conducted by the University of Texas and TPWD</textblock>
    <textblock>(TPWD 1989, 1990, 1992), was published in June, 1993 (Chippindale</textblock>
    <textblock>et</textblock>
    <textblock>al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993). An adult male, collected from Barton Springs Pool in</textblock>
    <textblock>November, 1992, was selected to be the holotype.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Barton Springs salamander is found near three of four</textblock>
    <textblock>hydrologically connected spring outlets collectively known as Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs (Brune 1981). These three spring outlets are known as</textblock>
    <textblock>Parthenia, Eliza, and Sunken Garden springs and occur in Zilker</textblock>
    <textblock>Park, which is owned and operated by the City of Austin. No</textblock>
    <textblock>salamanders have been found at the fourth spring outlet, which is in</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Creek immediately above Barton Springs Pool (Paul Chippindale</textblock>
    <textblock>and Dr. David Hillis, University of Texas at Austin; Dr. Andrew</textblock>
    <textblock>Price, TPWD; Sweet; pers. comms., 1993). The area around the main</textblock>
    <textblock>spring outlet (Parthenia Springs) was impounded in the late 1920's</textblock>
    <textblock>to create Barton Springs Pool. Flows from Eliza and Sunken Garden</textblock>
    <textblock>springs are also retained by concrete structures, forming small</textblock>
    <textblock>pools located on either side of Barton Springs Pool. The salamander</textblock>
    <textblock>has been observed under gravel and small rocks, submerged leaves,</textblock>
    <textblock>and algae; among aquatic vegetation; and buried in organic debris,</textblock>
    <textblock>at depths of about 0.1 to 5 meters (0.3 to 16 feet) of water</textblock>
    <textblock>(Chippindale</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993, TPWD 1993). It generally does not occur</textblock>
    <textblock>on bare limestone surfaces or in silted areas (Dr. Charles Sexton,</textblock>
    <textblock>City of Austin, Environmental Conservation Services Department,</textblock>
    <textblock>unpublished data).</textblock>
    <textblock>Hundreds of individuals were estimated to occur in Eliza Pool</textblock>
    <textblock>during the 1970's (James Reddell, University of Texas at Austin,</textblock>
    <textblock>pers. comm. in Chippindale</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993). The numbers apparently</textblock>
    <textblock>declined over the next decade. Fewer than a dozen and occasionally</textblock>
    <textblock>no individuals were observed during surveys conducted in Eliza Pool</textblock>
    <textblock>between 1987 and 1992 (Chippindale</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993; TPWD 1993; Price,</textblock>
    <textblock>unpubl. data).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Barton Springs salamander was reportedly abundant among</textblock>
    <textblock>the aquatic vegetation in the deep end of Barton Springs Pool in</textblock>
    <textblock>1946 (Chippindale</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993, TPWD 1993). Between 1989 and 1991,</textblock>
    <textblock>Sexton (</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1992) reported finding salamanders on ``about one</textblock>
    <textblock>out of four [snorkeling] dives'' under rock rubble immediately</textblock>
    <textblock>adjacent to the main spring outflows. On July 28, 1992, at least 50</textblock>
    <textblock>salamanders (Hillis, pers. comm., 1993) were found over an area of</textblock>
    <textblock>roughly 400 square meters (4,300 square feet) near the spring</textblock>
    <textblock>outflows in Barton Springs Pool (TPWD 1993). Following reports of a</textblock>
    <textblock>fish kill at Barton Springs Pool on September 28, 1992 (Austin</textblock>
    <textblock>American Statesman, October 2, 1992; Daily Texan, October 13, 1992),</textblock>
    <textblock>only 10 to 11 salamanders were observed and could only be found in</textblock>
    <textblock>an area of about 5 square meters (54 square feet) in the immediate</textblock>
    <textblock>vicinity of the Parthenia Spring outflows (Chippindale</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993,</textblock>
    <textblock>TPWD 1993). Since that event, the salamander appears to be</textblock>
    <textblock>recolonizing Barton Springs Pool, which has been attributed to</textblock>
    <textblock>recent changes in pool cleaning operations (see further discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>under Factor A). At least 80 individuals were observed during a</textblock>
    <textblock>November 16, 1992, survey and about 150 individuals were seen on</textblock>
    <textblock>November 24, 1992 (Chippindale</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993, TPWD 1993).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
