<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00087</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary believes that receipt of a copy of the</textblock>
    <textblock>contract is necessary because it states the services that a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer performs for a guaranty agency. With this</textblock>
    <textblock>information, the Secretary will be better able to monitor program</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance and integrity of the guaranty agency's portfolio that</textblock>
    <textblock>the servicer is administering. These changes would parallel the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements concerning contracts between institutions and third-party servicers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note that section 552 of the Administrative Procedure Act</textblock>
    <textblock>does not require disclosure to the public, under the Freedom of</textblock>
    <textblock>Information Act (FOIA), of subject matter that is deemed to be a</textblock>
    <textblock>trade secret or is of commercial or financial interest or is of a</textblock>
    <textblock>privileged or confidential nature (note also that the entity</textblock>
    <textblock>submitting the information is responsible for identifying</textblock>
    <textblock>information that is not subject to the FOIA's disclosure</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 682.413␣Remedial actions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes</textblock>
    <textblock>to revise this section of the regulations to clarify a lender's</textblock>
    <textblock>and its third-party servicer's responsibility to pay liabilities</textblock>
    <textblock>if the servicer has not complied with FFEL program statutes or</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations with respect to services it has contracted with a</textblock>
    <textblock>lender to perform. Under this section, a third-party servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>and lender under whose contract the servicer committed the</textblock>
    <textblock>violation would be considered jointly and severally liable for</textblock>
    <textblock>paying to the Secretary any interest benefits and special</textblock>
    <textblock>allowance or any compensation the servicer has received on any</textblock>
    <textblock>loan from the lender from the date that the servicer fails to</textblock>
    <textblock>comply with any of the requirements in §682.406(a)(1)-(a)(6),</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)(9), and (a)(12), for any period when the loan has lost its</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility for reinsurance coverage as a result of the third-party servicer's actions, and for any period after it erroneously</textblock>
    <textblock>bills the Secretary for interest benefits and special allowance.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary would vigorously attempt to collect any of those</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities first from the lender and, if the lender does not</textblock>
    <textblock>repay those liabilities within 30 days or does not make</textblock>
    <textblock>arrangements satisfactory to the Secretary to repay those</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities, pursue the third-party servicer for the payment of</textblock>
    <textblock>those liabilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposed section would also clarify a guaranty agency's</textblock>
    <textblock>and its third-party servicer's responsibilities to pay</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities to the Secretary if the servicer has not complied</textblock>
    <textblock>with FFEL program statutes or regulations with respect to</textblock>
    <textblock>services that it has contracted with a guaranty agency to</textblock>
    <textblock>perform. Under this proposed provision, the Secretary would</textblock>
    <textblock>require a guaranty agency to repay to the Secretary any</textblock>
    <textblock>reinsurance payments the guaranty agency received on a loan if</textblock>
    <textblock>the third-party servicer contracting with the guaranty agency</textblock>
    <textblock>causes a loan to lose its eligibility for reinsurance. In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition to the repayment of reinsurance, if a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer makes an incomplete or incorrect statement in connection</textblock>
    <textblock>with any agreement entered into under this part or any other</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal requirement, the guaranty agency with which it has</textblock>
    <textblock>entered into a contract may be subjected by the Secretary to</textblock>
    <textblock>return payments made by the Secretary to the agency, have its</textblock>
    <textblock>payments withheld by the Secretary, or have its participation in</textblock>
    <textblock>the FFEL programs limited, suspended, or terminated. In addition</textblock>
    <textblock>to these penalties, the guaranty agency and its third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer may be fined, may be required to repay any payments the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary became obligated to make to others as a result of an</textblock>
    <textblock>incomplete or incorrect statement or violation of any Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement, or be responsible for repaying any interest</textblock>
    <textblock>benefits, special allowance, or reinsurance paid on a</textblock>
    <textblock>Consolidation loan for a violation of 34 CFR 682.206(f)(1). The</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency and its third-party servicer would be considered</textblock>
    <textblock>jointly and severally liable for any of those liabilities. The</textblock>
    <textblock>method by which the Secretary would collect any liability would</textblock>
    <textblock>parallel the proposed provisions governing the circumstances</textblock>
    <textblock>under which a lender and third-party servicer would be jointly</textblock>
    <textblock>and severally liable to the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the negotiated rulemaking sessions, the issue of third-party servicer liability generated controversy and dissension</textblock>
    <textblock>among the negotiators. With regard to liabilities assessed</textblock>
    <textblock>against a third-party servicer under the FFEL programs, many</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiators raised the same objections previously discussed in</textblock>
    <textblock>connection with liability for servicers under 34 CFR part 668.</textblock>
    <textblock>Negotiators raised an additional objection, suggesting that</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities assessed against third-party servicers under the FFEL</textblock>
    <textblock>programs are unnecessary given the ability of the Secretary to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine a loan to be uninsured and thus able to be collected</textblock>
    <textblock>directly from a lender or guaranty agency. In response to these</textblock>
    <textblock>objections, the Secretary offered the same modification of the</textblock>
    <textblock>concept of joint and several liability discussed previously in 34</textblock>
    <textblock>CFR part 668. As noted, no consensus was reached. However, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary agreed to incorporate language into these proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations to specify that the Secretary would first attempt</textblock>
    <textblock>collection from a lender or guaranty agency in the event of</textblock>
    <textblock>liability on the part of a third-party servicer. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>included this provision at the request of negotiators because the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes that this provision would not adversely impact</textblock>
    <textblock>the integrity of the FFEL programs. The Secretary specifically</textblock>
    <textblock>invites further public comment on the issue of joint and several</textblock>
    <textblock>liability for servicers contracting with lenders and guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies in order to obtain additional advice from the higher</textblock>
    <textblock>education community in the development of final regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary specifically invites public comment on</textblock>
    <textblock>whether, and how, the Secretary should hold a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer that administers FFEL programs jointly and severally</textblock>
    <textblock>liable for any violation of an FFEL program requirement by that</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer and whether any alternative less than assumption of full</textblock>
    <textblock>liability is sufficient to protect the public interest. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary notes that substantial losses have occurred in the FFEL</textblock>
    <textblock>programs due to third-party servicer violations.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
