<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00077</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In addition, this section would be amended to specify</textblock>
    <textblock>additional steps that the Secretary may take to insure the</textblock>
    <textblock>payment of any liabilities that are owed. Under this section, if</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution or third-party servicer owes funds, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>may determine that an administrative offset (as provided for</textblock>
    <textblock>under 34 CFR 30.28) is an appropriate alternative to collect</textblock>
    <textblock>those funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the case of an institution or third-party servicer that</textblock>
    <textblock>provides surety or a guarantee for the benefit of the Secretary,</textblock>
    <textblock>such as a bond or letter of credit, the Secretary may determine it is necessary to collect from that surety or guarantee before</textblock>
    <textblock>the procedures under subpart H of this part are completed, if</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances warrant.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary would collect a surety or guarantee before all</textblock>
    <textblock>available appeal procedures are completed_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Where the need to provide relief to students or borrowers</textblock>
    <textblock>affected by the institution's or third-party servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>actions, as applicable, that led to the assessment of</textblock>
    <textblock>liability, is more important than deferring collection</textblock>
    <textblock>activities until after the completion of appeal proceedings</textblock>
    <textblock>(for example, when unpaid refunds to the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs are identified, the Secretary may collect in</textblock>
    <textblock>advance of a final determination or exhaustion of appeal</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures, as the harm to students outweighs deferring</textblock>
    <textblock>collection); or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Where the conditions under which a surety or guarantee are</textblock>
    <textblock>held do not provide adequate assurances that the surety or</textblock>
    <textblock>guarantee will be available for collection through the</textblock>
    <textblock>completion of available appeal proceedings.</textblock>
    <textblock>These modifications would provide clarification in the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations of the Secretary's existing practice and authority to</textblock>
    <textblock>collect from sureties or guarantees in accordance with their</textblock>
    <textblock>terms, prior to final determinations of liabilities or exhaustion</textblock>
    <textblock>of appeal procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary also proposes to make clear that an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution is responsible for repayment of any funds owed by its</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer until those funds are repaid by the servicer. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary considers this provision necessary because an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution is always responsible for the actions of its agents.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes that if a determination is made to</textblock>
    <textblock>assess a liability against a third-party servicer, the servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>would be required to notify each institution under whose contract</textblock>
    <textblock>the servicer was assessed a liability of the Secretary's</textblock>
    <textblock>determination. The servicer would also be required to notify</textblock>
    <textblock>every institution that contracts with the servicer for the same</textblock>
    <textblock>service that the Secretary determined a liability is owed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Final consensus on this particular language was not reached</textblock>
    <textblock>as negotiators believed that this provision essentially requires</textblock>
    <textblock>the notification of all institutions with which a servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>contracts. Negotiators objected to a notice being provided to</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions that a servicer contracts with that would not be</textblock>
    <textblock>directly affected by a determination from the Secretary to assess</textblock>
    <textblock>liability. A number of negotiators opposed this language on the</textblock>
    <textblock>ground that such a blanket notification unnecessarily damages a</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer's reputation among unaffected institutions. However,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary believes that an institution that contracts with a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer should be informed of determinations by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education that the institution's servicer is</textblock>
    <textblock>improperly administering the Title IV, HEA programs, especially</textblock>
    <textblock>given the potential liability exposure to the institution. These</textblock>
    <textblock>notification requirements would arise only if the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>determines that a third-party servicer owes a liability based on</textblock>
    <textblock>an audit finding, after providing the institution or third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer an opportunity to respond to an audit report response. By limiting the requirement for notice provided by a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer to institutions receiving the same service for which a</textblock>
    <textblock>liability was assessed, the Secretary believes that he has</textblock>
    <textblock>responded to any legitimate concerns raised by the negotiators.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.25 Contracts between an institution and a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to redesignate ยง668.25, governing loss of institutional eligibility, as ยง668.26</textblock>
    <textblock>and to add a new ยง668.25 that would establish minimum</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for contracts between an institution and a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer. Proposed ยง668.25 would allow an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to contract with a servicer to administer aspects of</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution's participation in a Title IV, HEA program only</textblock>
    <textblock>to the extent that the servicer's eligibility to contract with</textblock>
    <textblock>that institution has not been limited, suspended, or terminated</textblock>
    <textblock>under the proceedings in Subpart G (as proposed to be amended).</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, under these proposed regulations, a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer is considered eligible to contract with an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>to administer aspects of the institution's participation in a</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program to the extent that the servicer is not</textblock>
    <textblock>found to exhibit indicators of questionable past performance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Indicators of questionable past performance would be_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A limitation, suspension, or termination action by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary against the servicer within the preceding five</textblock>
    <textblock>years;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
