<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00116</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Special review of third-party servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary may review a third-party servicer to determine that it</textblock>
    <textblock>meets the administrative capability and financial responsibility</textblock>
    <textblock>standards in this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) In response to a request from the Secretary, the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer shall provide evidence to demonstrate that it meets the</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability and financial responsibility standards</textblock>
    <textblock>in this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The servicer may also provide evidence of why</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative action is unwarranted if it is unable to</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrate that it meets the standards of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Based on the review of the materials provided by the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, the Secretary determines if the servicer meets the</textblock>
    <textblock>standards in this part. If the servicer does not, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>may initiate an administrative proceeding under subpart G.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Past performance of third-party servicer or persons</textblock>
    <textblock>affiliated with servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notwithstanding paragraph (b) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, a third-party servicer is not financially responsible</textblock>
    <textblock>if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) (i) The servicer; its owner, majority shareholder, or</textblock>
    <textblock>chief executive officer; any person employed by the servicer in a</textblock>
    <textblock>capacity that involves the administration of a Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program or the receipt of Title IV, HEA program funds; any</textblock>
    <textblock>person, entity, or officer or employee of an entity with which</textblock>
    <textblock>the servicer contracts in a capacity that involves the</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of a Title IV, HEA program or the receipt of</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program funds has been convicted of, or has pled</textblock>
    <textblock>nolo contendere</textblock>
    <textblock>or guilty to, a crime involving the acquisition,</textblock>
    <textblock>use, or expenditure of Federal, State, or local government funds,</textblock>
    <textblock>or has been administratively or judicially determined to have</textblock>
    <textblock>committed fraud or any other material violation of law involving</textblock>
    <textblock>such funds, unless_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The funds that were fraudulently obtained, or</textblock>
    <textblock>criminally acquired, used, or expended have been repaid to the</textblock>
    <textblock>United States, and any related financial penalty has been paid;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The persons who were convicted of, or pled</textblock>
    <textblock>nolo</textblock>
    <textblock>contendere</textblock>
    <textblock>or guilty to, a crime involving the acquisition, use,</textblock>
    <textblock>or expenditure of the funds are no longer incarcerated for that</textblock>
    <textblock>crime; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) At least five years have elapsed from the date of the</textblock>
    <textblock>conviction,</textblock>
    <textblock>nolo contendere</textblock>
    <textblock>plea, guilty plea, or administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>or judicial determination; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The servicer, or any principal or affiliate of the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer (as those terms are defined in 34 CFR part 85), is_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Debarred or suspended under Executive Order</textblock>
    <textblock>(E.O.) 12549 or the Federal Acquisition Regulations (FAR),</textblock>
    <textblock>48 CFR part 9, subpart 9.4; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Engaging in any activity that is a cause under</textblock>
    <textblock>34 CFR 85.305 or 85.405 for debarment or suspension under</textblock>
    <textblock>E.O. 12549 or the FAR, 48 CFR part 9, subpart 9.4; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Upon learning of a conviction, plea, or administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>or judicial determination described in paragraph (d)(1) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, the servicer does not promptly remove the person,</textblock>
    <textblock>agency, or organization from any involvement in the</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of the servicer's participation in Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs, including, as applicable, the removal or elimination of</textblock>
    <textblock>any substantial control, as determined under 34 CFR 668.13, over</textblock>
    <textblock>the servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Independent audits.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A third-party servicer shall</textblock>
    <textblock>arrange for an independent audit of its administration of the</textblock>
    <textblock>FFEL program loan portfolio unless_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The servicer contracts with only one lender or guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agency; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The audit of that lender's or guaranty agency's FFEL</textblock>
    <textblock>programs involves every aspect of the servicer's administration</textblock>
    <textblock>of those FFEL programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The audit must_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Examine the servicer's compliance with the Act and</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable regulations;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Examine the servicer's financial management of its</textblock>
    <textblock>FFEL program activities;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Be conducted in accordance with the standards for</textblock>
    <textblock>audits issued by the United States General Accounting Office's</textblock>
    <textblock>(GAO's) Standards for Audit of Governmental Organizations,</textblock>
    <textblock>Programs, Activities, and Functions. Procedures for audits are</textblock>
    <textblock>contained in an audit guide developed by and available from the</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Inspector General of the Department of Education; and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
