<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00088</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Under these proposed regulations, the Secretary would follow</textblock>
    <textblock>the fine proceedings contained in 34 CFR part 668, subpart G, in</textblock>
    <textblock>imposing a fine against a third-party servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 682.414␣Records, reports, and inspection</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for guaranty agency programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes to amend this section to make a third-party servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibilities under this part conform to currently existing</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations with respect to a guaranty agency's obligation to</textblock>
    <textblock>maintain current records. Under this provision, a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer acting as an agent for a guaranty agency would be</textblock>
    <textblock>required to maintain current, complete, and accurate records for</textblock>
    <textblock>all loans that it services for that agency. These records would</textblock>
    <textblock>have to be updated at least once every 10 business days. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary is proposing this provision to ensure that a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer with which a guaranty agency contracts is</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible for maintaining accurate records.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 682.416␣Requirements for third-party servicers and</textblock>
    <textblock>lenders contracting with third-party servicers.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes to add a new section to the FFEL program regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>that would set forth administrative and financial standards that</textblock>
    <textblock>a third-party servicer would be required to meet in order to be</textblock>
    <textblock>an eligible third-party servicer with which a lender or guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agency may contract for purposes of its responsibilities under</textblock>
    <textblock>the FFEL programs. Under these proposed regulations, a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer would be considered to be administratively</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible if it provides the services for which it has</textblock>
    <textblock>contracted to perform in accordance with the Federal laws and</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations that govern the FFEL programs, has business systems</textblock>
    <textblock>that are capable of meeting those requirements and has adequate</textblock>
    <textblock>personnel who are knowledgeable about the FFEL programs. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary is proposing these standards because he believes that</textblock>
    <textblock>these are the minimum administrative standards that an agent or</textblock>
    <textblock>entity must meet to demonstrate satisfactorily to the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>that it is capable of performing FFEL program services in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with applicable statutes and regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to apply the standards governing</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility under 34 CFR 668.13(c), (d), (g), and</textblock>
    <textblock>(h), governing the financial responsibility of institutions and</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicers contracting with those institutions, to a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer that administers any aspect of the FFEL</textblock>
    <textblock>programs under a contract with a guaranty agency or lender, for</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>During the negotiated rulemaking sessions, the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>standards governing financial responsibility of third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicers and institutions generated disagreement among the</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiators. The Secretary intends that the financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility standards in this section would parallel, as</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable, similar standards of financial responsibility for</textblock>
    <textblock>participating institutions that the Secretary intends to publish</textblock>
    <textblock>in proposed regulations to be published shortly after these.</textblock>
    <textblock>When published, this future NPRM will provide commenters with the</textblock>
    <textblock>opportunity to comment on financial responsibility standards</textblock>
    <textblock>governing both third-party servicers and institutions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes these standards to ensure that a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer would not be able to maintain a contract</textblock>
    <textblock>with a lender or guaranty agency to administer any aspect of the</textblock>
    <textblock>lender's or guaranty agency's FFEL program unless that servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>periodically demonstrates to the Secretary the ability to meet</textblock>
    <textblock>its financial obligations with that lender or guaranty agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further, these standards would ensure that the servicer can</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrate that it is financially stable and will be able to</textblock>
    <textblock>meet these obligations in the future. The Secretary believes</textblock>
    <textblock>that these standards are necessary because the financial failure</textblock>
    <textblock>of a third-party servicer could have an enormous impact on the</textblock>
    <textblock>FFEL programs that could create substantial losses for the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal taxpayer.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under these proposed rules, the Secretary would, as</textblock>
    <textblock>determined necessary, conduct a special review of a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer to determine if it meets the administrative capability</textblock>
    <textblock>and financial responsibility standards proposed in this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>If the Secretary conducts that review, the servicer would be</textblock>
    <textblock>required to provide evidence to the Secretary that it meets these</textblock>
    <textblock>standards. Based on the review of the materials required by this</textblock>
    <textblock>section the Secretary could initiate a limitation, suspension, or</textblock>
    <textblock>termination action against the servicer. If the servicer is</textblock>
    <textblock>unable to demonstrate that it meets the established standards for</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability and financial responsibility, the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer could provide evidence to the Secretary demonstrating</textblock>
    <textblock>that the limitation, suspension, or termination action is</textblock>
    <textblock>unwarranted. This latter provision was added at the request of</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiators to govern situations where a third-party servicer may</textblock>
    <textblock>not be able to meet the defined standards proposed in this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, but the servicer still considers itself to be</textblock>
    <textblock>administratively capable and financially responsible. This</textblock>
    <textblock>provision would allow a third-party servicer the opportunity to</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrate to the Secretary that it is still administratively</textblock>
    <textblock>capable and financially responsible.</textblock>
    <textblock>This section would provide that a third-party servicer is</textblock>
    <textblock>not financially responsible under this section if the servicer,</textblock>
    <textblock>or the servicer's owner, majority shareholder, or chief executive</textblock>
    <textblock>officer is determined to have a questionable past performance.</textblock>
    <textblock>The past performance criteria in this section would parallel</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed requirements under 34 CFR 668.12 (implementing statutory</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements governing the past performance of persons or</textblock>
    <textblock>organizations associated with institutions that participate in</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs) and under 34 CFR 668.82 (governing the</textblock>
    <textblock>standard of conduct of institutions and third-party servicers for</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of the Title IV, HEA programs). Furthermore, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary proposes to apply this provision to any person employed</textblock>
    <textblock>by the servicer or any person, entity, or any officer or employee</textblock>
    <textblock>of an entity that the servicer contracts with whose past</textblock>
    <textblock>performance is also questionable. In addition, in order to</textblock>
    <textblock>remain financially responsible, if a third-party servicer learns</textblock>
    <textblock>of such a conviction or determination, the servicer would have to</textblock>
    <textblock>take immediate action to safeguard the Title IV, HEA programs, as</textblock>
    <textblock>explained previously in the discussion concerning §668.82.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
