<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00080</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00040</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Information Collection Submitted to the Office of Management and Budget for Review Under the Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposal for the collection of information listed below has been submitted to the Office of Management and Budget for approved under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. chapter 35). Copies of the proposed information collection requirement and related forms and explanatory material may be obtained by contacting the Bureau's Clearance Officer at the phone number listed below. Comments and suggestions on the requirement should be made directly to the Bureau's Clearance Office and to the Office of Management and Budget Paperwork Reduction Project (1004-0074), Washington, DC 20503, telephone 202-395-7340.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Oil and Gas Geothermal Resources Leasing</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB Approval Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>1004-0074</textblock>
    <textblock>Abstract:</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondents supply information which will be used to determine the highest qualified bonus bid submitted for a competitive oil and gas or geotermal lease (Form 3000-2) and enable the Bureau of the Land Management to complete environmental reviews in compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (Form 3200-9). The information supplied allows the Bureau of Land Management to determine whether a bidder is qualified to hold a lease and to conduct geothermal resource operations under the terms of the Mineral Leasing Act of 1920 and the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970.</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau Form Numbers:</textblock>
    <textblock>3000-2, 3200-9</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency:</textblock>
    <textblock>On occasion</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of Respondent:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals, small businesses, and oil companies</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Completion Time:</textblock>
    <textblock>2 hrs</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Responses:</textblock>
    <textblock>443</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Burden Hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>886</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau Clearance Officer:</textblock>
    <textblock>(Alternate) Marsha Harley 202-452-5019.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 8, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[WO-610-4140-01-24]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Hillary A. Oden,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Director, Energy and Mineral Resources.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3646 Filed 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-84-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
