<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00005</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Initiation of Antidumping and Countervailing Duty Administrative Reviews</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>International Trade Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>International Trade Administration/Import Administration, Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of initiation of antidumping and countervailing duty administrative reviews.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Commerce has received requested to conduct administrative review of various antidumping and countervailing duty orders, findings and suspension agreements with January anniversary dates. In accordance with the Commerce Regulations, we are initiating those administrative reviews.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 17, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Holly A. Kuga, Office of Antidumping Compliance, International Trade Administration, U.S. Department of Commerce, Washington, DC 20230, telephone: (202) 482-2104.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Commerce (the Department) has received timely requests, in accordance with §§353.22(a) and 355.22(a) of the Department's regulations, for administrative reviews of various antidumping and countervailing duty orders, findings, and suspension agreements with January anniversary dates.</textblock>
    <textblock>Initiation of Reviews</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with §§353.22(c) and 355.22(c) of the Department's regulations, we are initiating administrative reviews of the following antidumping and countervailing duty orders, findings, and suspension agreements. We intend to issue the final results of these reviews not later than January 31, 1995.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
