<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00061</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00031</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>_The extent to which the project gives special emphasis</textblock>
    <textblock>to the issues identified in the Special Concerns section of this</textblock>
    <textblock>notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>_The likelihood of success of the applicant's proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>strategies for promoting coordination and collaboration between</textblock>
    <textblock>separate centers providing different resource capacities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Eligible Applicants</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications for funding will be accepted from States and</textblock>
    <textblock>accredited schools of medicine. Applications which involve more</textblock>
    <textblock>than a single State will also be accepted. In developing the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed project, applicants must seek the participation and</textblock>
    <textblock>support of local or regional trauma centers and other interested</textblock>
    <textblock>entities within the State, such as local government and health and</textblock>
    <textblock>medical organizations in the private sector. If the applicant is</textblock>
    <textblock>a school of medicine, the application must be endorsed by the</textblock>
    <textblock>State. The State's endorsement must acknowledge that the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant has consulted with the State and that the State has been</textblock>
    <textblock>assured that the applicant will work with the State on the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed project.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any State (or medical school within that State) may apply for any</textblock>
    <textblock>category or subcategory of grant, subject to the following</textblock>
    <textblock>considerations based on equitable geographic distribution of EMSC</textblock>
    <textblock>funds, differences in purpose among EMSC grant categories, and</textblock>
    <textblock>variation among States in EMSC program progress:</textblock>
    <textblock>•For Category (1) Planning Grants, States (or medical schools</textblock>
    <textblock>within those States) that have received prior EMSC implementation</textblock>
    <textblock>grants may not apply for planning grants.</textblock>
    <textblock>•For Category (2)(A) Implementation Grants, applications from</textblock>
    <textblock>States (and medical schools within those States) that have not</textblock>
    <textblock>previously received EMSC program funds, or that have received only</textblock>
    <textblock>partial support under this program as part of a regional alliance,</textblock>
    <textblock>will receive preference for funding in this subcategory. This</textblock>
    <textblock>means that approved applications from States (and medical schools</textblock>
    <textblock>within those States) with no or very limited prior EMSC program</textblock>
    <textblock>support will be funded ahead of approved applications from outside</textblock>
    <textblock>this group.</textblock>
    <textblock>•For Category (2)(B) System Enhancement Grants, States (and</textblock>
    <textblock>medical schools within States) that have previously received EMSC</textblock>
    <textblock>funds may apply for a system enhancement grant, as long as they</textblock>
    <textblock>will not also be receiving implementation funds during the project</textblock>
    <textblock>period of the systems enhancement grant. States that have not</textblock>
    <textblock>previously received EMSC funds are advised to apply first for</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation category funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>•For Category (3) Targeted Issues Grants, eligibility is not</textblock>
    <textblock>affected by receipt of other EMSC funding.</textblock>
    <textblock>•For Category (4) Resource Capacity Cooperative Agreements,</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility is not affected by receipt of other EMSC funding.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications will not be considered for both Category (1) State</textblock>
    <textblock>Planning Grants and Category (2)(A) Implementation Grants</textblock>
    <textblock>simultaneously from the same State. Funding of an application for</textblock>
    <textblock>a planning grant or for either subcategory of State Systems Grant</textblock>
    <textblock>bars a State from future competitions for that category or</textblock>
    <textblock>subcategory. Although funding of a Category (3) Targeted Issue</textblock>
    <textblock>Grant does not preclude a State (or medical school) from applying</textblock>
    <textblock>for other categories of EMSC funding, applicants should taken care</textblock>
    <textblock>to avoid overlap in proposed project activities and associated</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal support for the separate categories.</textblock>
    <textblock>Allowable Costs</textblock>
    <textblock>The MCHB may support reasonable and necessary costs of EMSC</textblock>
    <textblock>Demonstration Grant projects within the scope of approved</textblock>
    <textblock>projects. Allowable costs may include salaries, equipment and</textblock>
    <textblock>supplies, travel, contracts, consultants, and others, as well as</textblock>
    <textblock>indirect costs as negotiated and certified. The MCHB adheres to</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative standards reflected in the Code of Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations, 45 CFR part 92 and 45 CFR part 74.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
