<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00092</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(iii) Financial and compliance auditing.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Mailing of documents prepared by the institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) Warehousing of records; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Notwithstanding the exclusions referred to in paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) of this definition, include any activity comprised of any</textblock>
    <textblock>function described in paragraph (1) of this definition.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1088)</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Section 668.11 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.11</textblock>
    <textblock>Scope.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) This subpart establishes standards that an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>must meet in order to participate in any Title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Noncompliance with these standards by an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>already participating in any Title IV, HEA program or with</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable standards in this subpart by a third-party servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>that contracts with the institution may subject the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>or servicer, or both, to proceedings under subpart G of this</textblock>
    <textblock>part. These proceedings may lead to any of the following</textblock>
    <textblock>actions:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) An emergency action.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The imposition of a fine.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The limitation, suspension, or termination of the</textblock>
    <textblock>participation of the institution in a Title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The limitation, suspension, or termination of the</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility of the servicer to contract with any institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>administer any aspect of the institution's participation in a</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1094)</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Section 668.12, as proposed to be amended in a Notice of</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Rulemaking published on July 10, 1992 (57 FR 30830), is</textblock>
    <textblock>further amended by removing the period at the end of proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>redesignated paragraph (b)(2)(iv)(B) and adding, in its place, a</textblock>
    <textblock>semi-colon and adding new paragraphs (b)(2)(v) and (b)(2)(vi) to</textblock>
    <textblock>read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.12</textblock>
    <textblock>Institutional participation agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) That it is liable for all_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Improperly spent or unspent funds received under the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs, including any funds administered by a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Refunds that the institution or its servicer may be</textblock>
    <textblock>required to make; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) That it will not knowingly_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Employ in a capacity that involves the administration</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Title IV, HEA programs or the receipt of funds under those</textblock>
    <textblock>programs, an individual who has been convicted of, or has pled</textblock>
    <textblock>nolo contendere</textblock>
    <textblock>or guilty to, a crime involving the acquisition,</textblock>
    <textblock>use, or expenditure of Federal, State, or local government funds,</textblock>
    <textblock>or has been administratively or judicially determined to have</textblock>
    <textblock>committed fraud or any other material violation of law involving</textblock>
    <textblock>those funds;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Contract with an institution or third-party servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>that has been terminated under section 432 of the HEA for a</textblock>
    <textblock>reason involving the acquisition, use, or expenditure of Federal,</textblock>
    <textblock>State, or local government funds, or that has been</textblock>
    <textblock>administratively or judicially determined to have committed fraud</textblock>
    <textblock>or any other material violation of law involving those funds; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Contract with or employ any individual, agency, or</textblock>
    <textblock>organization that has been, or any of whose officers or employees</textblock>
    <textblock>have been_</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) Convicted of, or pled</textblock>
    <textblock>nolo contendere</textblock>
    <textblock>or guilty to, a</textblock>
    <textblock>crime involving the acquisition, use, or expenditure of Federal,</textblock>
    <textblock>State or local government funds; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) Administratively or judicially determined to have</textblock>
    <textblock>committed fraud or any other material violation of law involving</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal, State, or local funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Section 668.13 as amended by the regulations published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on June 8, 1993 (58 FR 32201) (effective date pending) is amended by removing paragraphs (c)(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>and (g); redesignating paragraph (c)(5) as (c)(4) and</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraphs (h) through (j) as paragraphs (g) through (i),</textblock>
    <textblock>respectively; adding the word ``or'' after the semi-colon in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (c)(3); and revising redesignated paragraph (c)(4),</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (d)(3), and redesignated paragraphs (g) introductory</textblock>
    <textblock>text and (h) to read as follows:</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
