<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00090</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12866</textblock>
    <textblock>These proposed regulations have been reviewed in accordance</textblock>
    <textblock>with Executive Order 12866. Under the terms of the order the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary has assessed the potential costs and benefits of this</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory action.</textblock>
    <textblock>The potential costs associated with the proposed regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>are those resulting from statutory requirements and those</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by the Secretary to be necessary for administering the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs effectively and efficiently. Burdens</textblock>
    <textblock>specifically associated with information collection requirements,</textblock>
    <textblock>if any, are identified and explained elsewhere in this preamble</textblock>
    <textblock>under the heading</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>In assessing the potential costs and benefits_both</textblock>
    <textblock>quantitative and qualitative_of these proposed regulations, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary has determined that the benefits of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations justify the costs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary has also determined that this regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>action does not unduly interfere with State, local, and tribal</textblock>
    <textblock>governments in the exercise of their governmental functions.</textblock>
    <textblock>To assist the Department in complying with the specific</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of Executive Order 12866, the Secretary invites</textblock>
    <textblock>comment on whether there may be further opportunities to reduce</textblock>
    <textblock>any potential costs or increase potential benefits resulting from</textblock>
    <textblock>these proposed regulations without impeding the effective and</textblock>
    <textblock>efficient administration of the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act Certification</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary certifies that these proposed regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>would not have a significant economic impact on a substantial</textblock>
    <textblock>number of small entities. The small entities that would be</textblock>
    <textblock>affected by these regulations are small institutions of higher</textblock>
    <textblock>education; small organizations that contract with educational</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions to administer aspects of the institutions'</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the Title IV, HEA programs; and small</textblock>
    <textblock>organizations that contract with lenders or guaranty agencies to</textblock>
    <textblock>administer aspects of the lenders' or agencies' participation in</textblock>
    <textblock>the FFEL programs. However, the regulations would not have a</textblock>
    <textblock>significant economic impact on these small entities because the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations would not impose excessive regulatory burdens or</textblock>
    <textblock>require unnecessary Federal supervision. The regulations would</textblock>
    <textblock>impose minimal requirements to ensure the proper expenditure of</textblock>
    <textblock>program funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 668.13, 668.23, 668.25, 668.90, 668.96, 668.113,</textblock>
    <textblock>682.414, 682.416, and 682.711 contain information collection</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements. As required by the Paperwork Reduction Act of</textblock>
    <textblock>1980, the Department of Education will submit a copy of these</textblock>
    <textblock>sections to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for its</textblock>
    <textblock>review. (44 U.S.C. 3504(h))</textblock>
    <textblock>Educational institutions that are public or nonprofit</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions or businesses or other for-profit institutions may</textblock>
    <textblock>participate in the Title IV, HEA programs. State entities,</textblock>
    <textblock>nonprofit institutions, businesses or other for-profit</textblock>
    <textblock>organizations, or individuals may contract with educational</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions to administer aspects of the institutions'</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the programs and may contract with lenders and</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agencies to administer aspects of the lenders' and</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies' participation in the FFEL programs. Individuals may</textblock>
    <textblock>apply for student financial assistance under the programs. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education needs and uses the information to enable</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary to determine whether the States, institutions,</textblock>
    <textblock>organizations, businesses, and individuals comply with the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for eligibility and participation in the programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual public reporting and recordkeeping burden contained</textblock>
    <textblock>in the collection of information proposed in these regulations is</textblock>
    <textblock>estimated to be 2,786 hours, including the time for searching</textblock>
    <textblock>existing data sources, gathering and maintaining the data needed,</textblock>
    <textblock>completing and reviewing the collection of information, and</textblock>
    <textblock>submitting materials.</textblock>
    <textblock>Organizations and individuals desiring to submit comments on</textblock>
    <textblock>the information collection requirements should direct them to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, OMB, room 3002, New</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503; Attention:</textblock>
    <textblock>Daniel J. Chenok.</textblock>
    <textblock>Invitation to Comment</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to submit comments and</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendations regarding these proposed regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>All comments submitted in response to these proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations will be available for public inspection, during and</textblock>
    <textblock>after the comment period, in room 4318, Regional Office</textblock>
    <textblock>Building 3, 7th and D Streets, SW., Washington, DC, between</textblock>
    <textblock>the hours of 8:30 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through Friday of</textblock>
    <textblock>each week except Federal holidays.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
