<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00084</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 668.92␣Fines.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add</textblock>
    <textblock>references to third-party servicers in this section to conform to</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed changes governing the imposition of fines in other</textblock>
    <textblock>sections of this subpart.</textblock>
    <textblock>This section would also be amended to provide for the</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration of the size of the servicer's business (including</textblock>
    <textblock>the number of institutions and student accounts served by the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer) in determining the amount of a fine against a servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>This provision would be similar to the provision already in place</textblock>
    <textblock>in this section that requires consideration of the size of an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution in determining the amount of a fine against the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution. The Secretary also proposes to take into account,</textblock>
    <textblock>in the case of a violation by a third-party servicer, the degree</textblock>
    <textblock>to which the servicer can provide evidence that the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>contributed to that violation and the extent to which repeated</textblock>
    <textblock>mechanical systemic unintentional errors contributed to that</textblock>
    <textblock>violation. For purposes of this section, repeated mechanical</textblock>
    <textblock>systemic unintentional errors would be counted as a single</textblock>
    <textblock>violation. This provision was requested by non-Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiators to cover cases where errors in computer systems</textblock>
    <textblock>result in multiple violations. The Secretary proposes to adopt</textblock>
    <textblock>these measures in the interest of fairness to a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer in cases where a minor programming error leads to</textblock>
    <textblock>hundreds or thousands of violations. While the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>believes that all resulting losses should be compensated for by</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution or servicer, fines need not be unduly multiplied.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary specifically invites comment on whether this</textblock>
    <textblock>provision is sufficiently specific and not excessively broad and</textblock>
    <textblock>effectively balances the Federal interest in ensuring compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>with the realities of computer processing.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary also proposes to provide for the consideration</textblock>
    <textblock>of the amount of liability owed by an institution or third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer on the misuse of Title IV, HEA program funds or refunds</textblock>
    <textblock>in determining the gravity of the institution's or servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>violation, as applicable, of a Title IV requirement. The number</textblock>
    <textblock>of students affected by the violation also would be a</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration in that determination. The Secretary intends these</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions to serve as guidelines for evaluating the gravity of a</textblock>
    <textblock>violation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.93␣Limitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add</textblock>
    <textblock>references to third-party servicers in this section to conform to proposed changes governing the imposition of limitations in other</textblock>
    <textblock>sections of this subpart. The Secretary also proposes that a</textblock>
    <textblock>limitation on a third-party servicer's eligibility to contract</textblock>
    <textblock>with institutions to administer any aspect of an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the Title IV, HEA programs could include a limit</textblock>
    <textblock>on the number or size of institutions with which the servicer may</textblock>
    <textblock>contract, the number of accounts (borrower or loan accounts) that</textblock>
    <textblock>the servicer may service under contract, an increase or reduction</textblock>
    <textblock>in the responsibilities allowed or required of the servicer under</textblock>
    <textblock>a contract, or a requirement for the servicer to obtain surety</textblock>
    <textblock>assuring the servicer's ability to meet financial obligations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary believes that these limitations are necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>to address the probable causes of improprieties in which a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer might engage. By limiting the number or</textblock>
    <textblock>size of institutions or accounts that a third-party servicer may</textblock>
    <textblock>serve (including, for example, requiring the servicer to transfer</textblock>
    <textblock>existing accounts back to the institution) the Secretary may</textblock>
    <textblock>address a problem involving the servicer's overextended</textblock>
    <textblock>resources. By limiting the responsibilities performed by the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer under a contract, the Secretary may restrict the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer's administration to a particular Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>while prohibiting the servicer from administering another</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program for which the servicer's past performance</textblock>
    <textblock>has been inadequate. By imposing additional responsibilities</textblock>
    <textblock>under a third-party servicer's contract, the Secretary may</textblock>
    <textblock>require the servicer to use additional safeguards before awarding</textblock>
    <textblock>or disbursing Title IV, HEA program funds or delivering Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Stafford or Federal SLS loan proceeds.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
