<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00058</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Oil pipeline ruptures also represent a potential source of</textblock>
    <textblock>groundwater contamination. Three oil pipelines run roughly parallel</textblock>
    <textblock>to each other across the Barton Springs segment and its contributing</textblock>
    <textblock>zone and cross Barton Creek near the Hays/Travis county line. Two</textblock>
    <textblock>of these lines ruptured within the recharge zone during the 1980's,</textblock>
    <textblock>about 13 kilometers (8 miles) south of Barton Springs. These two</textblock>
    <textblock>spills constitute the largest spills reported from Hays and Travis</textblock>
    <textblock>counties between 1986 and 1992 (TWC, unpubl. data). The first major</textblock>
    <textblock>spill occurred in 1986, about 270 meters (300 yards) from Slaughter</textblock>
    <textblock>Creek, when an oil pipeline was severed during a construction</textblock>
    <textblock>operation and released about 366,000 liters (96,600 gallons) of oil.</textblock>
    <textblock>The equipment necessary to contain the spill was on-site at the time</textblock>
    <textblock>the spill occurred (Russell 1987), and about 91 percent of the spill</textblock>
    <textblock>was recovered (Rose 1986). The second pipeline break occurred in</textblock>
    <textblock>1987 near the first spill site and released over 185,000 liters</textblock>
    <textblock>(49,000 gallons) of oil. According to the TWC database, more than</textblock>
    <textblock>97 percent of this spill was recovered (TWC, unpubl. data).</textblock>
    <textblock>Although the effects of these two spills on the Barton Springs</textblock>
    <textblock>salamander are unknown, similar spills that are not immediately</textblock>
    <textblock>remediated could adversely impact the salamander and its habitat.</textblock>
    <textblock>Peter Rose (1986), a geologist who has studied the effects of</textblock>
    <textblock>pipeline oil spills on the Edwards Aquifer, has estimated that oil</textblock>
    <textblock>spills of 160,000 liters (42,000 gallons) or more pose a</textblock>
    <textblock>``reasonable danger'' of entering and contaminating the Edwards</textblock>
    <textblock>Aquifer. ``Free oil entering an unconfined aquifer would be</textblock>
    <textblock>expected to spread and travel in the direction of water flow,</textblock>
    <textblock>emerging eventually at springs *␣*␣*'' (Rose 1986). Oil is highly</textblock>
    <textblock>toxic to aquatic life (Pyastolova and Danilova 1987). A study of</textblock>
    <textblock>the effects of oil on the sharp-snouted frog (</textblock>
    <textblock>Rana arvalis</textblock>
    <textblock>) showed</textblock>
    <textblock>that ``the presence of crude oil in an aquatic environment, even in</textblock>
    <textblock>small amounts (0.05 ml/l) exerts an unfavorable influence on both</textblock>
    <textblock>embryonic and larval development'' of the frog, including increased</textblock>
    <textblock>mortality and appearance of deformities (Pyastolova and Danilova</textblock>
    <textblock>1987). Because of physiological similarities among amphibian</textblock>
    <textblock>larvae, the Barton Springs salamander may exhibit similar or</textblock>
    <textblock>possibly more severe reactions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The conveyance and treatment of sewage in the watershed,</textblock>
    <textblock>particularly in the recharge zone, may also result in the impairment</textblock>
    <textblock>of local water quality and negative effects to the Barton Springs</textblock>
    <textblock>salamander. In 1982, high levels of fecal coliform bacteria at</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs were attributed to a sewerline leak upstream from</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs Pool. While fecal coliform bacteria are believed to</textblock>
    <textblock>be harmless, they may indicate the presence of other organisms that</textblock>
    <textblock>are pathogenic to aquatic life (Slade</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1986), some of which</textblock>
    <textblock>may pose a threat to salamanders and/or their prey base. The USGS</textblock>
    <textblock>has stated that because ``there are many sewerlines near the</textblock>
    <textblock>springs, fecal coliform contamination of the springs may be a</textblock>
    <textblock>recurring problem'' (Slade</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1986). There are over 145</textblock>
    <textblock>kilometers (90 miles) of wastewater lines in the recharge zone of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Barton Springs segment (Maureen McReynolds, City of Austin Water</textblock>
    <textblock>and Wastewater Utility, pers. comm., 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>Once an aquifer is contaminated, it can be very difficult to</textblock>
    <textblock>remediate. TDA (1987) maintains that ``contaminated groundwater can</textblock>
    <textblock>be extremely difficult and expensive, and in some cases even</textblock>
    <textblock>impossible, to clean up. The only way to maintain groundwater</textblock>
    <textblock>quality is to prevent contamination in the first place.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Regarding the effects of oil pipeline spills on the Edwards Aquifer,</textblock>
    <textblock>``*␣*␣* for all practical purposes, once spilled oil has been</textblock>
    <textblock>introduced into a cavernous carbonate aquifer, only time and nature</textblock>
    <textblock>can take care of the cleanup job'' (Rose 1986).</textblock>
    <textblock>Major contaminant spills that are not quickly remediated could</textblock>
    <textblock>enter the aquifer and contaminate the waters feeding Barton Springs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response times to hazardous materials spills vary, depending on</textblock>
    <textblock>several factors, including detection capability, location and size</textblock>
    <textblock>of the spill, weather conditions, whether or not the spill is</textblock>
    <textblock>reported, and the party performing the cleanup. Generally, cleanup</textblock>
    <textblock>is initiated within several hours following detection of a spill,</textblock>
    <textblock>but many weeks may be necessary to complete the effort. In some</textblock>
    <textblock>cases in Travis County, cleanup of leaking storage tanks was not</textblock>
    <textblock>initiated until two months following leak detection (Philip</textblock>
    <textblock>Winsborough, TWC, pers. comm., 1993). In other cases, such as the</textblock>
    <textblock>oil pipeline ruptures that occurred within the recharge zone,</textblock>
    <textblock>cleanup was initiated the same day the spill was detected and</textblock>
    <textblock>completed the following day.</textblock>
    <textblock>Chronic water quality degradation of the aquifer resulting</textblock>
    <textblock>from increasing urban activities (including roadway, residential,</textblock>
    <textblock>commercial, and industrial development) may also lead to</textblock>
    <textblock>contamination of the waters feeding Barton Springs (see also</textblock>
    <textblock>discussion under Factor D). Because of the characteristics of karst</textblock>
    <textblock>aquifers discussed in the Background section, Barton Springs is</textblock>
    <textblock>believed to be ``heavily influenced by the quality and quantity of</textblock>
    <textblock>runoff,'' particularly in the recharge zone (City of Austin 1991).</textblock>
    <textblock>A report by USGS (Veenhuis and Slade 1990) on the relationship</textblock>
    <textblock>between urbanization and surface water quality in several streams</textblock>
    <textblock>throughout the Austin area (10 of 18 sample sites were along streams</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Barton Springs segment and its contributing zone)</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrates that increases in impervious cover can lead to large</textblock>
    <textblock>increases in pollutant runoff. This is indicated in several streams</textblock>
    <textblock>with increased levels of suspended solids, biochemical oxygen</textblock>
    <textblock>demand, total organic carbon, total nitrogen, total phosphorus,</textblock>
    <textblock>fecal-group bacteria, inorganic trace elements, and synthetic</textblock>
    <textblock>compounds. A preliminary review of water quality data for 15 wells</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Barton Springs segment also suggests that increasing</textblock>
    <textblock>impervious cover has resulted in increased concentrations of certain</textblock>
    <textblock>water quality constituents in the groundwater, including total</textblock>
    <textblock>nitrogen and total phosphorus (USGS 1992). These changes in</textblock>
    <textblock>groundwater quality may indicate future water quality changes at</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs as development increases across the recharge and</textblock>
    <textblock>contributing zones.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
