<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00061</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>D.</textblock>
    <textblock>The inadequacy of existing regulatory mechanisms.</textblock>
    <textblock>No</textblock>
    <textblock>existing rules or regulations specifically require protection of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs salamander or its habitat. The salamander is not</textblock>
    <textblock>included on the TPWD's list of threatened and endangered species,</textblock>
    <textblock>and thus the species is not afforded protection by that agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>Several individuals who provided comments on the 90-day finding</textblock>
    <textblock>stated that existing state and local regulations are sufficient to</textblock>
    <textblock>mitigate potential water quality threats resulting from development</textblock>
    <textblock>activities in the Barton Springs segment and contributing zone.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, while there are many existing rules and regulations in</textblock>
    <textblock>place that will likely contribute positively to water quality and</textblock>
    <textblock>quantity, there are no assurances that they are adequate to protect</textblock>
    <textblock>the salamander and its habitat. Furthermore, whether the existing</textblock>
    <textblock>rules and regulations can provide long-term protection of the</textblock>
    <textblock>quality and quantity of the waters feeding Barton Springs is</textblock>
    <textblock>unknown.</textblock>
    <textblock>There are few measures in place to prevent the risk of</textblock>
    <textblock>hazardous material spills across the recharge and contributing</textblock>
    <textblock>zones. No regulations prohibit the transportation of hazardous</textblock>
    <textblock>materials across the Barton Springs segment (Tom Word, Texas</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Transportation (TxDOT), pers. comm., 1993), and few</textblock>
    <textblock>existing roads have water quality control structures (such as</textblock>
    <textblock>hazardous materials traps, sediment basins, and filters) to protect</textblock>
    <textblock>against non-point-source pollution and chemical spills (Shyra Darr,</textblock>
    <textblock>Travis County Public Improvements and Transportation Department</textblock>
    <textblock>(PITD),</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993; Barnett,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993; Roland Gamble,</textblock>
    <textblock>TxDOT,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993). Travis County and TxDOT have agreed to</textblock>
    <textblock>install water quality devices on new State and county roadway</textblock>
    <textblock>construction projects in the recharge zone (Barnett,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993;</textblock>
    <textblock>David Pimentel, PITD,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993; Gamble,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>However, no program is currently in place to retrofit these</textblock>
    <textblock>water quality control structures on existing roadways in the Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs segment (Barnett,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993). In addition, the</textblock>
    <textblock>effectiveness of these water quality control structures has not yet</textblock>
    <textblock>been determined (Gamble,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>The major regulations affecting water quality in the Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs segment include the Edwards Rules (31 Texas Administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>Code, Chapter 313), which are promulgated and enforced by the TWC,</textblock>
    <textblock>and the City of Austin's water quality protective ordinances</textblock>
    <textblock>(Williamson Creek Ordinance (1980), Barton Creek Watershed Ordinance</textblock>
    <textblock>(1981), Lower Watersheds Ordinance (1981), Comprehensive Watersheds</textblock>
    <textblock>Ordinance (1986), ``Composite Ordinance'' (1991), and the ``Save Our</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs'' (``SOS'') Ordinance (1992)). These ordinances are only</textblock>
    <textblock>implemented within Austin's city limits and five-mile</textblock>
    <textblock>extra-territorial jurisdiction, which is about a third of the entire</textblock>
    <textblock>area affecting Barton Springs. Each ordinance includes impervious</textblock>
    <textblock>cover limitations, development setbacks from water quality zones,</textblock>
    <textblock>erosion control measures, restricted or prohibited development on</textblock>
    <textblock>steep slopes, and other water quality protective measures. However,</textblock>
    <textblock>none of the ordinances include retrofit provisions for existing</textblock>
    <textblock>developments or land use regulations (Barnett,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>Furthermore, the ordinances can be rendered ineffective by variance</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions and exemptions. The SOS Ordinance requires greater</textblock>
    <textblock>impervious cover limitations, further development restrictions in</textblock>
    <textblock>the water quality zones of Barton Creek, and limitations of</textblock>
    <textblock>exemptions from the ordinance provisions, and will attempt to reduce</textblock>
    <textblock>the risk of accidental contamination (Barnett,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Edwards Rules regulate construction-related activities on</textblock>
    <textblock>the recharge zone that may ``alter or disturb the topographic,</textblock>
    <textblock>geologic, or existing recharge characteristics of a site'' as well</textblock>
    <textblock>as any other activity ``which may pose a potential for contaminating</textblock>
    <textblock>the Edwards Aquifer,'' including sewage collection systems and</textblock>
    <textblock>hazardous materials storage tanks. The Edwards Rules regulate</textblock>
    <textblock>construction activities through review of Water Pollution Abatement</textblock>
    <textblock>Plans (WPAPs). The WPAPs do not require site-specific water quality</textblock>
    <textblock>performance standards for developments over the recharge zone nor do</textblock>
    <textblock>they address land use, impervious cover limitations, or retrofitting</textblock>
    <textblock>for developments existing prior to the implementation of the Rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Travis County was not incorporated into the Rules until March,</textblock>
    <textblock>1990; Hays County was incorporated in 1984.) The WPAPs also do not</textblock>
    <textblock>regulate development activities in the aquifer's contributing zone.</textblock>
    <textblock>As yet, the Edwards Rules do not include a comprehensive plan to</textblock>
    <textblock>address the effects of cumulative impacts on water quality in the</textblock>
    <textblock>aquifer.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
