<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00060</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Another threat to the salamander is the degradation of its</textblock>
    <textblock>surface habitat, particularly at Barton Springs Pool and Eliza Pool.</textblock>
    <textblock>Following reports of a fish kill in Barton Springs Pool on September</textblock>
    <textblock>28, 1992 (Austin American Statesman, October 2, 1992; Daily Texan,</textblock>
    <textblock>October 13, 1992), the salamander's surface range contracted from</textblock>
    <textblock>about a 400 square meter (4,300 square foot) area to about a 5</textblock>
    <textblock>square meter (50 square foot) area immediately around the outflow of</textblock>
    <textblock>the spring (see discussion in Background). The fish kill has been</textblock>
    <textblock>attributed to the improper application of chlorine used to clean</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs Pool (Chippindale et al. 1993, TPWD 1993). Previous</textblock>
    <textblock>fish kills, although rare events, have also occurred at Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs Pool (Robert Sapronyi, City of Austin Parks and Recreation</textblock>
    <textblock>Department, pers. comm., 1992). Other cleaning procedures and park</textblock>
    <textblock>operations that may have had adverse impacts on the salamander and</textblock>
    <textblock>its surface habitat include lowering the water levels in Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs Pool and Eliza Pool for cleaning, use of high pressure fire</textblock>
    <textblock>hoses in areas where salamanders are found, and removal of aquatic</textblock>
    <textblock>vegetation from Eliza Pool. Runoff from the area above Eliza Pool,</textblock>
    <textblock>which includes a maintenance area and concession stand for the</textblock>
    <textblock>Zilker Eagle train, may also have contributed to the decline in</textblock>
    <textblock>numbers of salamanders found at this location.</textblock>
    <textblock>Following the September 28 fish kill, the City of Austin</textblock>
    <textblock>discontinued the use of chlorine to clean Barton Springs Pool and</textblock>
    <textblock>Eliza Pool. The City of Austin is continuing to revise its pool</textblock>
    <textblock>maintenance practices in order to protect the salamander and its</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat, as well as maintain a safe environment for swimmers</textblock>
    <textblock>(Camille Barnett, City of Austin,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993). Cleaning</textblock>
    <textblock>practices at Eliza Pool and other park operations near this pool are</textblock>
    <textblock>also being reevaluated.</textblock>
    <textblock>Another change that has been observed at Barton Springs is the</textblock>
    <textblock>loss of aquatic vascular plants in Barton Springs Pool, where</textblock>
    <textblock>salamanders were reportedly abundant in 1946. The plants</textblock>
    <textblock>disappeared during the late 1980's (Chippindale et al. 1993). The</textblock>
    <textblock>cause of the disappearance is unknown and may be due to changes in</textblock>
    <textblock>water quality originating upstream (such as increased turbidity),</textblock>
    <textblock>certain pool maintenance operations, and/or other factors. Aquatic</textblock>
    <textblock>plants are important because they provide cover where salamanders</textblock>
    <textblock>can hide from predators. Amphipods and other invertebrates that</textblock>
    <textblock>form the diet of salamanders also depend on aquatic vegetation</textblock>
    <textblock>(Hillis and Chippindale 1992).</textblock>
    <textblock>Reduced water levels in the Barton Springs segment could also</textblock>
    <textblock>adversely impact the Barton Springs salamander. The volume of</textblock>
    <textblock>springflow is self-regulated by the level of water in the aquifer.</textblock>
    <textblock>Discharge decreases as water storage in the aquifer drops, which</textblock>
    <textblock>historically has been due primarily to the lack of recharging rains</textblock>
    <textblock>rather than groundwater withdrawal for public consumption (Slade et</textblock>
    <textblock>al. 1986). Reduced aquifer levels may lead to the movement of water</textblock>
    <textblock>with high levels of total dissolved solids from the ``bad water''</textblock>
    <textblock>zone to the freshwater zone of the Barton Springs segment, including</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs (Slade et al. 1986). The increased concentration of</textblock>
    <textblock>dissolved solids resulting from this encroachment of ``bad water''</textblock>
    <textblock>could have negative impacts on the plants and animals associated</textblock>
    <textblock>with Barton Springs. Reduced groundwater levels would also increase</textblock>
    <textblock>the concentration of pollutants in the aquifer.</textblock>
    <textblock>The potential for ``bad water'' encroachment is increased with</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) pumpage of the aquifer and (b) extended low recharge or low flow</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions (Slade et al. 1986). Barton Springs lies near the ``bad</textblock>
    <textblock>water'' line. Under low flow conditions, Barton Springs and a well</textblock>
    <textblock>near the ``bad water'' line (YD-58-50-216) show increased dissolved</textblock>
    <textblock>solid concentrations, particularly sodium and chloride, indicating</textblock>
    <textblock>that some encroachment of ``bad water'' has occurred at Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs in the past (Slade et al. 1986).</textblock>
    <textblock>According to the Barton Springs/Edwards Aquifer Conservation</textblock>
    <textblock>District (BS/EACD) (1990), pumpage from the aquifer has increased in</textblock>
    <textblock>recent years, resulting in decreased discharges from Barton Springs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The USGS has stated that groundwater withdrawal in the area is</textblock>
    <textblock>expected to increase because of further urbanization in outlying</textblock>
    <textblock>areas of Austin. Currently, discharge from the Barton Springs</textblock>
    <textblock>segment (withdrawal plus springflow) is roughly equal to recharge.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thus, an increase in groundwater withdrawal is likely to cause a</textblock>
    <textblock>decrease in the quantity of water in the aquifer and discharge from</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs (Slade et al. 1986). Based on the current population</textblock>
    <textblock>projection, water demands could almost double by the year 2000 (from</textblock>
    <textblock>about 470 hectare-meters/year (3,800 acre-feet/year) in 1982 to</textblock>
    <textblock>about 760 hectare-meters/year (6,200 acre-feet/year)) (Slade et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1986).</textblock>
    <textblock>B.</textblock>
    <textblock>Overutilization for commercial, recreational, scientific,</textblock>
    <textblock>or educational purposes.</textblock>
    <textblock>No threat from overutilization of this</textblock>
    <textblock>species is known to exist at this time. Several citizens have</textblock>
    <textblock>expressed concern over impacts to the salamander from recreational</textblock>
    <textblock>use of Barton Springs Pool for swimming. However, no evidence</textblock>
    <textblock>exists to indicate that swimming in Barton Springs Pool poses a</textblock>
    <textblock>threat to the salamander population. Provided that pool maintenance</textblock>
    <textblock>activities do not adversely impact the salamander and its habitat</textblock>
    <textblock>(see discussion under Factor A), swimming at Barton Springs Pool is</textblock>
    <textblock>not likely to disturb the salamander.</textblock>
    <textblock>C.</textblock>
    <textblock>Disease or predation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Certain naturally occurring</textblock>
    <textblock>populations as well as captive individuals of</textblock>
    <textblock>Eurycea neotenes</textblock>
    <textblock>have</textblock>
    <textblock>shown symptoms of redleg, a bacterial (</textblock>
    <textblock>Aeromonas</textblock>
    <textblock>sp.) infection</textblock>
    <textblock>(Sweet 1978). The Barton Springs salamander may also be susceptible</textblock>
    <textblock>to this disease, although no diseases or parasites of the Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs salamander have been reported. Primary predators of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs salamander are believed to be fish and crayfish;</textblock>
    <textblock>however, no information exists to indicate that predation poses a</textblock>
    <textblock>major threat to this species.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
