<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-0-00018</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(2) Modification in accordance with paragraph (f) of this AD terminates the individual inspection requirements of the applicable service bulletin.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) Prior to reaching the incorporation thresholds listed in the SARD, Revision B, or within four years after the effective date of this AD, whichever occurs later, accomplish the structural modifications specified in the service bulletins listed in Table 2.2 of the SARD, Revision B.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note 6:</textblock>
    <textblock>The service bulletin revision levels listed under ``Recommended Modification'' in Table 2.2 of the SARD, Revision B, are acceptable revisions for modifications accomplished prior to the effective date of this AD.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note 7:</textblock>
    <textblock>The modifications required by this paragraph do not terminate the inspection requirements of any other AD unless that AD specifies that any such modification constitutes terminating action for the inspection requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g) An alternative method of compliance or adjustment of the compliance time that provides an acceptable level of safety may be used if approved by the Manager, Los Angeles ACO, FAA, Transport Airplane Directorate. Operators shall submit their requests through an appropriate FAA Principal Maintenance Inspector, who may add comments and then send it to the Manager, Los Angeles ACO.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note 8:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information concerning the existence of approved alternative methods of compliance with this AD, if any, may be obtained from the Los Angeles ACO.</textblock>
    <textblock>(h) Special flight permits may be issued in accordance with FAR 21.197 and 21.199 to operate the airplane to a location where the requirements of this AD can be accomplished.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The inspections, and modification shall be done in accordance with McDonnell Douglas Report No. MDC-K1571, ``DC-10/KC-10 Aging Aircraft Service Action Requirements Document,'' Revision A, dated February 28, 1990; or McDonnell Douglas Report No. MDC K1571, ``DC-10/KC-10 Aging Aircraft Service Action Requirements Document'', Revision B, dated March 24, 1993, which contains the following list of effective pages:</textblock>
    <textblock>The incorporation by reference of McDonnell Douglas Report No. MDC K1571,</textblock>
    <textblock>``DC-10/KC-10 Aging Aircraft Service Action Requirements Document'', Revision B, dated March 24, 1993, is approved by the Director of the Federal Register in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552(a) and 1 CFR part 51. The incorporation by reference of McDonnell Douglas Report No. MDC-K1571, ``DC-10/KC-10 Aging Aircraft Service Action Requirements Document,'' Revision A, dated February 28, 1990, was approved previously by the Director of the Federal Register in accordance 5 U.S.C. 552(a) and 1 CFR part 51 as of September 10, 1990 (55 FR 31816, August 6, 1990). Copies may be obtained from McDonnell Douglas Corporation, P.O. Box 1771, Long Beach, California 90801-1771, Attention: Business Unit Manager, Technical Publications_Technical Administrative Support, C1-L5B. Copies may be inspected at the FAA, Transport Airplane Directorate, 1601 Lind Avenue, SW., Renton, Washington; or at the FAA, Transport Airplane Directorate, Los Angeles Aircraft Certification Office, 3229 East Spring Street, Long Beach, California; or at the Office of the Federal Register, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., suite 700, Washington, DC.</textblock>
    <textblock>(j) This amendment becomes effective on March 21, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Renton, Washington, on January 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Page No.</textblock>
    <textblock>1Revision sym shown on page</textblock>
    <textblock>1Date shown on page</textblock>
    <textblock>Pages xiii and xiv</textblock>
    <textblock>(Not shown on these pages)</textblock>
    <textblock>March 24, 1993.</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Darrell M. Pederson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Manager,</textblock>
    <textblock>Transport Airplane Directorate,</textblock>
    <textblock>Aircraft Certification Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2412 Filed 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
