<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00007</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Discussions with operators that utilize these type</textblock>
    <textblock>airplanes under 14 CFR part 135 reveal that regular</textblock>
    <textblock>maintenance inspections require inspections in this</textblock>
    <textblock>area every 200 hours time-in-service (TIS), and that</textblock>
    <textblock>there have been no problems with the retractable MLG</textblock>
    <textblock>swivel pins.</textblock>
    <textblock>The inspection procedures in Piper's maintenance</textblock>
    <textblock>manual of the referenced airplanes calls for inspecting</textblock>
    <textblock>the MLG assembly every 100 hours TIS. The inspection</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures do not specifically address a teardown</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection of this assembly. At this time, the FAA has</textblock>
    <textblock>determined that there is no basis to establish a</textblock>
    <textblock>threshold or repetitive teardown inspection interval of</textblock>
    <textblock>this assembly based on the information obtained.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order to adequately make a determination as to</textblock>
    <textblock>what type of action to take (if any), the FAA is</textblock>
    <textblock>issuing this advance notice of proposed rulemaking</textblock>
    <textblock>(ANPRM) to provide an opportunity for the general</textblock>
    <textblock>public to participate in the decision whether to</textblock>
    <textblock>initiate rulemaking. Interested persons are encouraged</textblock>
    <textblock>to provide information that describes what they</textblock>
    <textblock>consider the best action (if any) to be taken to</textblock>
    <textblock>correct the possible problem. In this regard, the FAA</textblock>
    <textblock>is especially interested in comments and viewpoints on</textblock>
    <textblock>the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. How often do you have the retractable MLG</textblock>
    <textblock>swivel pins inspected and in what detail, i.e., visual,</textblock>
    <textblock>dye penetrant, etc.?</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Does the checklist in the procedures you</textblock>
    <textblock>utilize during the MLG swivel pin inspections include</textblock>
    <textblock>removal of the swivel pins?</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Have you ever replaced the swivel pin?</textblock>
    <textblock>a. If so, please list the hours TIS replaced</textblock>
    <textblock>and the reason why for each instance?</textblock>
    <textblock>b. If not, how many hours TIS have you</textblock>
    <textblock>accumulated on your airplane?</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Do you feel that the current inspection</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements are adequate, i.e., 14 CFR part 43, your</textblock>
    <textblock>checklist, Piper's maintenance manual, etc.? Please</textblock>
    <textblock>list any specific recommendations that you may have</textblock>
    <textblock>concerning current or future inspection requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Please include the model and serial number of</textblock>
    <textblock>your airplane, and the part number of the retractable</textblock>
    <textblock>MLG swivel pin with this correspondence.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Please provide any other information that you</textblock>
    <textblock>feel is pertinent in helping the FAA determine what</textblock>
    <textblock>type of action (if any) needs to be taken.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following figure (Figure 1) depicts the</textblock>
    <textblock>retractable MLG assembly, including the swivel pin.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Kansas City, Missouri, on February 11, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-U</textblock>
  </billing>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEP17fe94.002</textblock>
  </import>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-C</textblock>
  </billing>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Mickael K. Dahl,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Manager, Small Airplane Directorate, Aircraft Certification Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3575 Filed 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
