<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00075</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>These provisions would expand the factors of financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility of an institution to take into consideration</textblock>
    <textblock>substantial control over both other existing institutions (as opposed to only defunct institutions) and third-party servicers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 498(e) of the HEA clearly contemplates this expansion.</textblock>
    <textblock>Furthermore, these requirements are needed for the same reasons</textblock>
    <textblock>that similar requirements recently were adopted for persons with</textblock>
    <textblock>substantial control over defunct institutions. A person might be</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible for incurring liabilities for Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>violations because of his or her substantial control over</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicers or other institutions. The person could,</textblock>
    <textblock>nevertheless, have the same level of control over a participating</textblock>
    <textblock>institution while avoiding responsibility for repayment of those</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities. These requirements are intended to prevent those</textblock>
    <textblock>persons from continuing to participate either directly or</textblock>
    <textblock>indirectly in the Title IV, HEA programs without assuming</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility for their prior actions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary also proposes technical changes to this</textblock>
    <textblock>section to remove as factors of financial responsibility the</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration of matters that would instead be included in</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.12 as conditions for participation in the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs, for the reasons given in the discussion of that</textblock>
    <textblock>section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.23␣Audits, records, and examination.</textblock>
    <textblock>The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary proposes to specify that in addition to current</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements, an institution would be required to cooperate with</textblock>
    <textblock>a guaranty agency in whose program the institution participates</textblock>
    <textblock>and the State postsecondary review entity designated under</textblock>
    <textblock>subpart 1 of part H of Title IV of the HEA, in the conduct</textblock>
    <textblock>of audits, investigations, and program reviews. These requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>would clarify existing responsibilities to be accountable to</textblock>
    <textblock>authorized persons or organizations for the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>activities with respect to the sound management of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs. The Secretary further proposes to apply</textblock>
    <textblock>these requirements to a third-party servicer that contracts with</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution to administer any aspect of that institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in a Title IV, HEA program. This change would</textblock>
    <textblock>merely clarify existing responsibilities of a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, as an agent of an institution, to be accountable and</textblock>
    <textblock>provide access to authorized persons for the servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>activities on behalf of the institution's participation in a</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add a requirement that a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer that administers funds or determines student</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility under contract with an institution would be required</textblock>
    <textblock>to have prepared, at least annually, a compliance audit of all</textblock>
    <textblock>aspects of the servicer's administration of the participation in</textblock>
    <textblock>the Title IV, HEA programs of each institution with which the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer contracts. (This requirement would be satisfied by an</textblock>
    <textblock>audit report submitted in accordance with the Single Audit Act or</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Management and Budget Circular A-133.) This</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement is necessitated by section 487(c)(1)(C) of the HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary, however, believes that the contractual</textblock>
    <textblock>obligations of some third-party servicers do not necessitate</textblock>
    <textblock>audits of the servicers' activities. Accordingly, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes to require annual audits to be performed only by those</textblock>
    <textblock>servicers that administer funds or determine student eligibility</textblock>
    <textblock>on behalf of institutions. The consequences of the activities of</textblock>
    <textblock>those servicers to the integrity of the Title IV, HEA programs</textblock>
    <textblock>justify stricter accountability to the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, the Secretary proposes certain additional</textblock>
    <textblock>exceptions to the annual audit requirement in the discussion that</textblock>
    <textblock>follows. A third-party servicer that is required to have an</textblock>
    <textblock>audit performed would be excused from the annual audit</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement if that servicer contracts with only one</textblock>
    <textblock>participating institution and if that servicer's administration</textblock>
    <textblock>of a Title IV, HEA program would still be covered fully in that</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's compliance audit. (In proposed regulations to be</textblock>
    <textblock>published shortly after these, the Secretary intends to propose</textblock>
    <textblock>to excuse certain institutions from having an annual audit</textblock>
    <textblock>performed. If an institution were to be excused from an audit</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement, the activities of that institution's third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer would not be fully covered, and thus the servicer would</textblock>
    <textblock>be required to have an audit performed to meet the requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section). This provision would not harm the integrity of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Title IV, HEA programs as the servicer's activities still</textblock>
    <textblock>would be covered fully by the submission of an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>A third-party servicer that is required to have an audit</textblock>
    <textblock>performed and that contracts with more than one participating</textblock>
    <textblock>institution could have performed, to meet the requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section, a single comprehensive compliance audit that covers all of the servicer's activities for all of the institutions that</textblock>
    <textblock>the servicer contracts with for Title IV, HEA program purposes,</textblock>
    <textblock>if the audit is conducted in such a way as to satisfy each</textblock>
    <textblock>individual audit requirement and if the audit covers all aspects</textblock>
    <textblock>of the servicer's administration of the participation in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs of all institutions with which the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer contracts. The Secretary believes that, by allowing</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicers to have one inclusive audit performed,</textblock>
    <textblock>instead of many individual audits, the burden associated with</textblock>
    <textblock>these regulations would be reduced (regulatory burden reduction</textblock>
    <textblock>is an objective under Executive Order (E.O.) 12866).</textblock>
    <textblock>Furthermore, the Secretary does not believe that this provision</textblock>
    <textblock>would in any way affect the soundness of the information required</textblock>
    <textblock>by these regulations.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
