<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00056</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00031</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Subcategory (B): system enhancement grants.</textblock>
    <textblock>System enhancement grants will fund activities that represent the</textblock>
    <textblock>next logical step or steps to take in institutionalizing EMSC</textblock>
    <textblock>activities within the State EMS system and achieving program goals</textblock>
    <textblock>outlined in this announcement and further elaborated in the 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>Institute of Medicine Report to Congress entitled Emergency</textblock>
    <textblock>Medical Services for Children. (A copy of the Executive Summary of</textblock>
    <textblock>this report will be enclosed with the application kit. The full</textblock>
    <textblock>report is available for $49.95 from National Academy Press, 2101</textblock>
    <textblock>Constitution Avenue, NW., Box 285, Washington, DC 20055.) For</textblock>
    <textblock>example, funding might be used to improve linkages between local</textblock>
    <textblock>and regional or State agencies, to develop pediatric standards for</textblock>
    <textblock>a region, or to assure effective field triage of the child in</textblock>
    <textblock>physical or emotional crisis to appropriate facilities and/or</textblock>
    <textblock>other resources. Activities implemented under prior EMSC program</textblock>
    <textblock>funding but not completed or made self-sustaining during the</textblock>
    <textblock>original implementation project period will not be considered</textblock>
    <textblock>suitable. States that have previously received EMSC funds may</textblock>
    <textblock>apply for a system enhancement grant, as long as they will not</textblock>
    <textblock>also be receiving implementation grant funds during the project</textblock>
    <textblock>period of the systems enhancement grant. Grants of up to $150,000</textblock>
    <textblock>are anticipated for the first year, with grants of up to $100,000</textblock>
    <textblock>for the second year.</textblock>
    <textblock>Category (3): Targeted Issues Grants</textblock>
    <textblock>The third funding category is that of targeted issues grants on</textblock>
    <textblock>topics of importance to EMSC. These grants are intended to</textblock>
    <textblock>address specific, focused issues related to the development of</textblock>
    <textblock>EMSC capacity, with the potential to serve as national or regional</textblock>
    <textblock>models. Proposals in this category must have a well conceived</textblock>
    <textblock>methodology to evaluate the impact of the activity. The Director</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Maternal and Child Health Bureau (MCHB) will judge the</textblock>
    <textblock>acceptability of projects proposed in this category. Prospective</textblock>
    <textblock>applicants are urged to contact EMSC program staff well in advance</textblock>
    <textblock>of submitting their formal applications, so that the work of</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal development can be avoided if the proposed project is</textblock>
    <textblock>judged to be inappropriate for submission in this category.</textblock>
    <textblock>Priorities for this category have been chosen from topics</textblock>
    <textblock>recommended by the 1993 Institute of Medicine Report on EMSC.</textblock>
    <textblock>Priorities and examples include:</textblock>
    <textblock>_Education and Training. For this priority, proposals</textblock>
    <textblock>are sought which develop or evaluate education or training geared</textblock>
    <textblock>to improving EMS providers' ability to address underdeveloped</textblock>
    <textblock>elements in EMSC. They may relate to particular areas of</textblock>
    <textblock>attention, such as the psychosocial aspects of EMSC, or to</textblock>
    <textblock>particular populations that are underserved or isolated.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposals focusing on underserved or isolated populations of</textblock>
    <textblock>children might target the needs of Native Americans, Native</textblock>
    <textblock>Alaskans, or Native Hawaiians, adolescents, developmentally</textblock>
    <textblock>disabled, mentally ill, homeless, or children living in rural</textblock>
    <textblock>areas or inner cities. Educational programs might also be</textblock>
    <textblock>developed for particular groups, such as parents, volunteers,</textblock>
    <textblock>caretakers, teachers, firefighters, medical control or medical</textblock>
    <textblock>dispatch personnel. Assessment of the effectiveness of the</textblock>
    <textblock>training, using appropriate outcome measures, is a key objective</textblock>
    <textblock>for proposals in this category. Proposals are expected to</textblock>
    <textblock>incorporate existing materials whenever possible; however,</textblock>
    <textblock>innovations in media or instructional techniques are encouraged.</textblock>
    <textblock>Projects could include the conversion of previously developed</textblock>
    <textblock>teaching materials to interactive video format, the development of</textblock>
    <textblock>curricula or training exercises to promote improved EMS management</textblock>
    <textblock>of psychosocial crises, or the utilization of multidisciplinary</textblock>
    <textblock>seminars or study groups to enhance collaboration on pediatric</textblock>
    <textblock>emergency care between primary and specialty providers.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
