<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00144</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(b) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Until February 1, 1998, a 121.5/243.0 MHz EPIRB meeting §25.26-30(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Until February 1, 1998, a 121.5/243.0 MHz EPIRB meeting §25.26-30(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>4. By revising §25.26-10 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§25.26-10</textblock>
    <textblock>Uninspected passenger vessels and vessel assistance towing vessels.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) After (one year after date of publication of the final rule in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>), each owner or operator of an uninspected passenger vessel or vessel assistance towing vessel 11 meters (36 feet) or more in length, shall ensure that the vessel does not operate more than 3 nautical miles from the coastline or more than 4.8 Km (3 statute miles) from the coastline of the Great Lakes, except as provided for in paragraphs (b) and (c) of this section, unless it has on board_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A float-free, automatically activated Category 1 406 MHz EPIRB stowed in a manner so that it will float free if the vessel sinks; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Until August 1, 1998, a 121.5/243.0 MHz EPIRB meeting §25.26-30(b) of this subpart.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) After (one year after date of publication of the final rule in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>), the owner or operator of an uninspected passenger vessel or assistance towing vessel less than 11 meters (36 feet) in length, or an uninspected passenger vessel or assistance towing vessel 11 meters (36 feet) or more in length which has a builder's certification that the vessel is constructed with inherently buoyant material to keep the flooded vessel afloat, shall ensure that the vessel does not operate 3 nautical miles from the coastline or beyond 4.8 Km (3 statute miles) from the coastline of the Great Lakes, except as provided for in paragraph (c) of this section, unless it has_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A manually activated Category 2 406 MHz EPIRB installed in a readily accessible location at or near the principal steering station; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A float-free, automatically activated Category 1 406 MHz EPIRB installed in a readily accessible location at or near the principal steering station; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) A float-free, automatically activated Category 1 406 MHz EPIRB installed in a manner so that it will float free if the vessel capsizes or sinks; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Until August 1, 1998, a 121.5/243.0 MHz EPIRB meeting §25.26-30(b) of this subpart.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) A vessel identified in paragraphs (a) and (b) is not required to carry an EPIRB between one hour before sunrise and one hour before sunset if it_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Operates between 3 and 20 minutes from shore and is equipped with an operable VHF radio capable of transmitting and receiving on channels 6, 13, 16, and 22A and operates within the VHF radio range of at least 1 VHF coast station (same as sea area A1 as defined in 47 CFR 80.1069) or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Operates more than 20 miles from shore ``in company'' with at least one other vessel at all times and each vessel is equipped with an operable VHF radio capable of transmitting and receiving on channels 6, 13, 16, and 22A.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. By revising the section heading and paragraphs (a) introductory text, (a)(2), (b) introductory text and (b)(3) of §25.26-20 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§25.26-20</textblock>
    <textblock>Other self-propelled uninspected commercial vessels.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) After March 10, 1994, the owner or operator of a self-propelled uninspected commercial vessel 11 meters (36 feet) or more in length, other than a vessel under §25.26-5 or §25.26-10 or under paragraph (b) of this section shall ensure that the vessel does not operate more than 3 nautical miles from the coastline or more than 4.8 Km (3 statute miles) from the coastline of the Great Lakes unless it has on board_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Until February 1, 1998, a 121.5/243.0 MHz EPIRB meeting §25.26-30(a) of this subpart.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) After March 10, 1994, the owner or operator of a self-propelled uninspected commercial vessel 11 meters (36 feet) or more in length, or 11 meters (36 feet) or more in length which has a builder's certification that the vessel is constructed with sufficient inherently buoyant material to keep the flooded vessel afloat, shall ensure that the vessel does not operate more than 3 nautical miles from the coastline or more than 4.8 Km (3 statute miles) from the coastline of the Great Lakes, unless it has installed in a readily accessible location at or near the principal steering station_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Until February 1, 1998, a 121.5/243.0 MHz EPIRB meeting §25.26-30(a) of this subpart.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. By revising §25.26-30 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§25.26-30</textblock>
    <textblock>121.5/243.0 MHz EPIRBs.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A 121.5/243.0 MHz EPIRB manufactured after October 1, 1988, may be used to meet certain requirements of §25.26-5 and §25.26-20, if the EPIRB is operable and was installed on the vessel on or before April 26, 1993. The EPIRB must be a Class A EPIRB, or a Class B EPIRB which is watertight, self-buoyant, and stable in a floating position to properly transmit a distress signal.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) A 121.5/243.0 MHz EPIRB manufactured after October 1, 1988, may be used to meet the requirements of §25.26-10 of this part, if the EPIRB is operable and was installed on the vessel on or before [date 45 days after date of publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of the final rule]. The EPIRB must be a Class A EPIRB, or a Class B EPIRB which is watertight, self-buoyant, and stable in a floating position to properly transmit a distress signal.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
