<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00103</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(g) The expiration, modification, or revocation of an</textblock>
    <textblock>emergency action against an institution or third-party servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>does not bar subsequent emergency action against that institution</textblock>
    <textblock>on grounds other than those specifically identified in the notice</textblock>
    <textblock>imposing the prior emergency action. Separate grounds may</textblock>
    <textblock>include violation by an institution or third-party servicer of an</textblock>
    <textblock>agreement or limitation imposed or resulting from the prior</textblock>
    <textblock>emergency action.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1094)</textblock>
    <textblock>13. Section 668.84 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง668.84</textblock>
    <textblock>Fine proceedings.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Scope and consequences.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The Secretary may impose</textblock>
    <textblock>a fine of up to $25,000 per violation on a participating</textblock>
    <textblock>institution or third-party servicer that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Violates any statutory provision of or applicable to</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV of the HEA, any regulatory provision prescribed under</textblock>
    <textblock>that statutory authority, or any applicable special arrangement,</textblock>
    <textblock>agreement, or limitation; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Substantially misrepresents the nature of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) In the case of an institution, its educational program,</textblock>
    <textblock>its financial charges, or the employability of its graduates; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) In the case of a third-party servicer, as applicable,</textblock>
    <textblock>the educational program, financial charges, or employability of</textblock>
    <textblock>the graduates of any institution that contracts with the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If the Secretary begins a fine proceeding against a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer, the Secretary also may begin a fine,</textblock>
    <textblock>limitation, suspension, or termination proceeding against any</textblock>
    <textblock>institution under whose contract a third-party servicer commits</textblock>
    <textblock>the violation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A designated department official</textblock>
    <textblock>begins a fine proceeding by sending the institution or servicer,</textblock>
    <textblock>as applicable, a notice by certified mail, return receipt</textblock>
    <textblock>requested. In the case of a fine proceeding against a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer, the official also sends the notice to each</textblock>
    <textblock>institution that is affected by the alleged violations identified</textblock>
    <textblock>as the basis for the fine action, and, to the extent possible, to</textblock>
    <textblock>each institution that contracts with the servicer for the same</textblock>
    <textblock>service affected by the violation. This notice_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Informs the institution or servicer of the Secretary's</textblock>
    <textblock>intent to fine the institution or servicer, as applicable, and</textblock>
    <textblock>the amount of the fine and identifies the alleged violations that</textblock>
    <textblock>constitute the basis for the action;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Specifies the proposed effective date of the fine,</textblock>
    <textblock>which is at least 20 days from mailing of the notice of intent;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Informs the institution or servicer that the fine</textblock>
    <textblock>will not be effective on the date specified in the notice if the</textblock>
    <textblock>designated department official receives from the institution or</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, as applicable, by that date a written request for a</textblock>
    <textblock>hearing or written material indicating why the fine should not be</textblock>
    <textblock>imposed; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) In the case of a fine proceeding against a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, informs each institution that is affected by the</textblock>
    <textblock>alleged violations of the consequences of the action to the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
