<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00076</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>A third-party servicer would be required to have an audit</textblock>
    <textblock>performed at least once every two years if the servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>administers less than $1,000,000 under the Title IV, HEA programs</textblock>
    <textblock>for the period covered by the audit, or if the servicer's most</textblock>
    <textblock>recently submitted audit report did not contain any material</textblock>
    <textblock>deficiencies and was submitted in a timely fashion. Also, a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer would not be required to have an audit</textblock>
    <textblock>performed for any year in which the servicer administers less</textblock>
    <textblock>than $250,000 under the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary is proposing these Title IV, HEA program fund</textblock>
    <textblock>thresholds, for purposes of exceptions to the audit requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section, on the assumption that a large amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program funds are not at risk in the case of a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer that administers less than $250,000 during</textblock>
    <textblock>the audit period. Similarly, the Secretary believes that a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer administering less than $1,000,000 in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs during the audit period or whose most</textblock>
    <textblock>recently submitted audit report revealed no abnormal practices or</textblock>
    <textblock>material discrepancies in the servicer's administration of those</textblock>
    <textblock>funds, provided that the audit report was submitted in a timely</textblock>
    <textblock>fashion, would not be likely to endanger those funds. By</textblock>
    <textblock>proposing these exceptions to the audit requirements of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, and thus limiting the scope of these provisions, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes that the Department of Education will be able</textblock>
    <textblock>to concentrate on those third-party servicers that pose the</textblock>
    <textblock>greatest financial risk to the Title IV, HEA programs; these</textblock>
    <textblock>exceptions also reduce the administrative burden on those</textblock>
    <textblock>qualifying for the exemptions. The threshold amounts were</textblock>
    <textblock>extrapolated from similar exemptions to audit submission</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for institutions under the Single Audit Act</textblock>
    <textblock>($100,000 and $25,000) and increased by a factor of ten in order</textblock>
    <textblock>to cover third-party servicer activities because these entities</textblock>
    <textblock>generally contract with multiple clients and thus would</textblock>
    <textblock>administer greater amounts of Title IV, HEA program funds than</textblock>
    <textblock>any single institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>These provisions are intended to parallel similar audit</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for institutions (in proposed regulations to be</textblock>
    <textblock>published shortly after these). The intent is to minimize the</textblock>
    <textblock>burden associated with these regulations, both to the servicing</textblock>
    <textblock>industry and to the Federal Government, as called for under E.O.</textblock>
    <textblock>12866. The Secretary believes that these exceptions would not</textblock>
    <textblock>harm the integrity of the audit oversight that Congress intended</textblock>
    <textblock>under section 487(c)(1)) of the HEA. Under that section and</textblock>
    <textblock>these regulations, the Secretary retains the authority to require</textblock>
    <textblock>any third-party servicer to have an audit performed on an annual</textblock>
    <textblock>basis if the Secretary believes it is necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>This section would be amended to provide that the servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>first audit would cover the servicer's first full fiscal year</textblock>
    <textblock>after the effective date of these regulations and any period on</textblock>
    <textblock>or after the effective date of these regulations up to the</textblock>
    <textblock>beginning of the servicer's first full fiscal year. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes that initial audits will be more useful and</textblock>
    <textblock>effective if they encompass an entire fiscal year. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>also believes that allowing servicers additional time to prepare</textblock>
    <textblock>for the implementation of these regulations would enable</textblock>
    <textblock>servicers to comply more fully with these regulations as well as</textblock>
    <textblock>defray the costs associated with an audit of a partial fiscal</textblock>
    <textblock>year. Subsequent audits would, as required by statute, encompass</textblock>
    <textblock>the entire period since the servicer's previous audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>A third-party servicer that is required to have an audit</textblock>
    <textblock>performed would be required to submit that audit to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education's Inspector General by the deadlines</textblock>
    <textblock>established in the audit guide developed by the Department's</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Inspector General. The Secretary also proposes to</textblock>
    <textblock>apply the statutory requirements of section 487(c) of the HEA to</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicers such that the results of these audits would</textblock>
    <textblock>be made available to the appropriate authorities, as detailed in</textblock>
    <textblock>the discussion at the beginning of this section. (The Secretary intends to propose similar requirements for institutions required</textblock>
    <textblock>to have an audit performed in proposed regulations to be</textblock>
    <textblock>published shortly after these).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.24␣Audit exceptions and repayments.</textblock>
    <textblock>The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary proposes to extend to a third-party servicer the</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions governing audit exceptions and determinations of audit</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities that currently apply to institutions. These</textblock>
    <textblock>modifications would simply reflect the Secretary's current</textblock>
    <textblock>practice under this section as applied to a third-party servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, an institution or a third-party servicer would have</textblock>
    <textblock>an opportunity to demonstrate within 45 days (35 days is mandated</textblock>
    <textblock>under the current regulations) of the Secretary's notification</textblock>
    <textblock>that the expenditure or compliance was proper. The Secretary is</textblock>
    <textblock>proposing 45 days to make the response period consistent with</textblock>
    <textblock>other reporting requirements in this part.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
