<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00057</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00031</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>_Data and Information System Management. For this</textblock>
    <textblock>priority, proposals are sought which reflect an understanding of</textblock>
    <textblock>the uses to which data are to be applied (e.g., patient care,</textblock>
    <textblock>quality assessment, resource allocation, research, etc.) and of</textblock>
    <textblock>the questions they are to answer. Projects should reflect</textblock>
    <textblock>familiarity with efforts of NHTSA, HRSA, the Centers for Disease</textblock>
    <textblock>Control and Prevention (CDC), and the EMSC program to develop</textblock>
    <textblock>national uniform data sets, if appropriate to the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>project. States are encouraged to develop EMS data systems which</textblock>
    <textblock>include all the elements of a national uniform data set and are</textblock>
    <textblock>capable of describing the nature of EMS provided to children.</textblock>
    <textblock>Demonstrations of linkage of data sources to provide an optimal</textblock>
    <textblock>picture of EMS furnished to children is one example of a proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>project under this priority; such proposals would be expected to</textblock>
    <textblock>show considerable familiarity with previous linkage efforts by the</textblock>
    <textblock>above organizations and others. Another example is the</textblock>
    <textblock>improvement of the quality of data that relate mechanisms of</textblock>
    <textblock>injury to assigned E-codes.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Communications. For this priority, proposals are</textblock>
    <textblock>sought which take advantage of new telecommunications technologies</textblock>
    <textblock>to improve EMS for children. Proposals could promote access to</textblock>
    <textblock>``911'' or ``enhanced 911'' emergency telephone systems. For example,</textblock>
    <textblock>projects might use the ``Make the Right Call'' campaign on a</textblock>
    <textblock>statewide basis, with modifications that include educating the</textblock>
    <textblock>public_including children_about when to access EMS services</textblock>
    <textblock>for children; such projects would be expected to incorporate a</textblock>
    <textblock>well conceived evaluation of the impact of such a campaign.</textblock>
    <textblock>Alternatively, proposals could promote the use of advanced</textblock>
    <textblock>technologies to improve care for children. For example, projects</textblock>
    <textblock>might use new technology to improve communications among health</textblock>
    <textblock>care facilities, linking hospitals, health care agencies and/or</textblock>
    <textblock>providers; or to educate various categories of providers by</textblock>
    <textblock>providing on-line pediatric medical control via new technology.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposals are also sought which evaluate, describe, analyze, or</textblock>
    <textblock>improve the pattern of EMS communications, dispatcher protocols,</textblock>
    <textblock>or on-line medical control as they affect the care of children or</textblock>
    <textblock>in relationship to pediatric utilization of emergency medical</textblock>
    <textblock>services. This priority has been developed in cooperation with</textblock>
    <textblock>HRSA's Trauma Care Systems Planning and Development Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Violence and Injury Prevention. For this priority,</textblock>
    <textblock>activities could include advocacy, education, training, or</textblock>
    <textblock>curriculum development, especially in the development of programs</textblock>
    <textblock>which expand the role of EMS personnel in prevention of injury,</textblock>
    <textblock>interpersonal violence, or youth-on-youth violence. Innovative</textblock>
    <textblock>strategies to link EMS personnel with law enforcement personnel,</textblock>
    <textblock>primary care providers, and community resources are sought.</textblock>
    <textblock>Examples are programs to reduce children's access to firearms or</textblock>
    <textblock>to educate children about the use of seatbelts or bicycle helmets.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further examples include the use of EMS personnel as</textblock>
    <textblock>trainer/educators, advocates, and organizers for community based</textblock>
    <textblock>violence prevention initiatives in schools and other settings</textblock>
    <textblock>serving youth, such as recreation centers, detention centers, or</textblock>
    <textblock>youth employment centers; or the use of EMS records to study the</textblock>
    <textblock>characteristics of violence or for education about the</textblock>
    <textblock>consequences of violence. Violence and injury prevention</textblock>
    <textblock>initiatives might also focus on enhancing preparation of EMS</textblock>
    <textblock>personnel for providing initial attention and arranging</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate follow-up when there are violent, destructive,</textblock>
    <textblock>damaging, or hurtful behaviors, or when there are injury-risking</textblock>
    <textblock>behaviors, such as combined drinking and driving, substance abuse,</textblock>
    <textblock>or attempted suicide by intentional overdosing on drugs.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Psychosocial/Behavioral. Proposals are sought for this</textblock>
    <textblock>priority focusing on strategies to reduce the emotional toll of</textblock>
    <textblock>childhood emergencies on the child, family, and/or providers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Examples include development and evaluation of techniques to</textblock>
    <textblock>increase the sensitivity of EMS personnel to psychosocial issues</textblock>
    <textblock>affecting children, adolescents, and their families and enhance</textblock>
    <textblock>EMS provider skills, knowledge, and crisis intervention capability</textblock>
    <textblock>in dealing with these issues; development and evaluation of</textblock>
    <textblock>approaches and techniques for assisting EMS personnel in dealing</textblock>
    <textblock>with child and family crises arising from abuse, neglect, sexual</textblock>
    <textblock>assault, or noncompliant and other high risk behaviors; or</textblock>
    <textblock>activities that foster greater synergy between primary care and</textblock>
    <textblock>mental health specialty personnel in dealing with psychosocial</textblock>
    <textblock>aspects of EMSC.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
