<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00100</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(A) Discontinue the affiliation; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Remove the principal from responsibility for any aspect</textblock>
    <textblock>of the administration of an institution's or servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A violation for a reason contained in paragraph (e)(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section is grounds for terminating_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The institution's participation in any Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The servicer's eligibility to contract with any</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to administer any aspect of the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in any Title IV, HEA program. The violation is</textblock>
    <textblock>also grounds for terminating, under this subpart, the</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in any Title IV, HEA program of any institution</textblock>
    <textblock>under whose contract the servicer committed the violation, if</textblock>
    <textblock>that institution knew or should have known of the violation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)(1) The debarment of a participating institution or</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer, as applicable, under E.O. 12549 or the FAR,</textblock>
    <textblock>48 CFR part 9, subpart 9.4, by the Department of Education or another</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal agency from participation in Federal programs, under</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures that comply with 5 U.S.C. 554-557 (formal adjudication</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements under the Administrative Procedure Act), terminates,</textblock>
    <textblock>for the duration of the debarment_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The institution's participation in any Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The servicer's eligibility to contract with any</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to administer any aspect of the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in any Title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)(i) The suspension of a participating institution or</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer, as applicable, under E.O. 12549 or the FAR,</textblock>
    <textblock>48 CFR part 9, subpart 9.4, by the Department of Education or another</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal agency from participation in Federal programs, under</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures that comply with 5 U.S.C. 554-557, suspends_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The institution's participation in any Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The servicer's eligibility to contract with any</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to administer any aspect of the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in any Title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A suspension under this paragraph lasts for a period</textblock>
    <textblock>of 60 days, beginning on the date of the suspending official's</textblock>
    <textblock>decision, except that the suspension may last longer if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The institution or servicer, as applicable, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary, agree to an extension of the suspension; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The Secretary begins a limitation or termination</textblock>
    <textblock>proceeding against the institution or servicer, as applicable,</textblock>
    <textblock>under this subpart before the 60th day of the suspension.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: E.O. 12549 (3 CFR, 1987 Comp., p. 189), 12689 (3 CFR, 1989 Comp., p. 235); 20 U.S.C. 1070,</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1082(a)(1) and (h)(1), 1094(c)(1) (D) and (H), and 3474)</textblock>
    <textblock>12. Section 668.83 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง668.83</textblock>
    <textblock>Emergency action.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Under an emergency action, the Secretary may_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Withhold Title IV, HEA program funds from a</textblock>
    <textblock>participating institution or its students, or from a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, as applicable;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)(i) Withdraw the authority of the institution or</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, as applicable, to commit, disburse, deliver, or cause</textblock>
    <textblock>the commitment, disbursement, or delivery of Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program funds; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Withdraw the authority of the institution or servicer,</textblock>
    <textblock>as applicable, to commit, disburse, deliver, or cause the</textblock>
    <textblock>commitment, disbursement, or delivery of Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>funds except in accordance with a particular procedure; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)(i) Withdraw the authority of the servicer to administer</textblock>
    <textblock>any aspect of any institution's participation in any</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Withdraw the authority of the servicer to administer</textblock>
    <textblock>any aspect of any institution's participation in any</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program except in accordance with a particular</textblock>
    <textblock>procedure.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)(1) An initiating official begins an emergency action</textblock>
    <textblock>against an institution or third-party servicer by sending the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution or servicer a notice by registered mail, return</textblock>
    <textblock>receipt requested. In an emergency action against a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, the official also sends the notice to each institution</textblock>
    <textblock>that contracts with the servicer. The official also may transmit</textblock>
    <textblock>the notice by other, more expeditious means if practical.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
