<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00083</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>With respect to fine proceedings against third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicers, the Secretary proposes to amend §668.84 to specify</textblock>
    <textblock>under the procedures for fine proceedings that a designated</textblock>
    <textblock>department official notifies each institution that is affected by</textblock>
    <textblock>the alleged violations identified as the basis for the fine</textblock>
    <textblock>proceeding. To the extent possible, the official also notifies</textblock>
    <textblock>each institution that contracts with the servicer for the same</textblock>
    <textblock>service affected by the alleged violation. This change would</textblock>
    <textblock>parallel the notification requirements that the Secretary has</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed under §668.24(b). As explained in the prior discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>regarding notification requirements under §668.24(b), there was</textblock>
    <textblock>no consensus during negotiated rulemaking on this proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>provision. Some negotiators opposed this requirement on the</textblock>
    <textblock>grounds previously noted. In addition, §§668.85 and 668.86 would</textblock>
    <textblock>require the official to notify each institution that contracts</textblock>
    <textblock>with a third-party servicer under a suspension, limitation, or</textblock>
    <textblock>termination proceeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>Fine, limitation, suspension, and termination proceedings</textblock>
    <textblock>would all require the official to include in the notice to a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer the consequences of the action to the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution, including that the Secretary may fine, limit,</textblock>
    <textblock>suspend, or terminate the institution, as applicable. Given the</textblock>
    <textblock>potential consequences to an institution, the Secretary deems it</textblock>
    <textblock>proper to provide notice to each institution that could be</textblock>
    <textblock>affected of the Secretary's intent to seek a sanction against the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, whether the Secretary also intends to seek a sanction</textblock>
    <textblock>against the institution or not. Even if the Secretary does not</textblock>
    <textblock>begin a fine, limitation, suspension, or termination proceeding</textblock>
    <textblock>against an institution, the Secretary believes that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution should be kept informed of the status of any proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>sanction against the institution's servicer. Imposition of the</textblock>
    <textblock>sanction could have an effect on the institution's participation</textblock>
    <textblock>in a Title IV, HEA program. Further, the Secretary believes that</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution should be informed if its servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of a Title IV, HEA program is called into</textblock>
    <textblock>question. That information would permit the institution to make</textblock>
    <textblock>informed judgments about the institution's continued use of the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, and take corrective action prior to the outcome of any</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative proceeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 668.87␣Prehearing Conference and 668.88 Hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add references to third-party servicers</textblock>
    <textblock>to conform to the proposed changes in the scope of this subpart.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.89␣Authority and responsibilities of the</textblock>
    <textblock>hearing official.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to amend this section</textblock>
    <textblock>to make clear that a hearing official is bound by all applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>statutes and regulations. This change would codify in the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations the existing responsibility of the hearing official.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.90␣Initial and final decisions_Appeals.</textblock>
    <textblock>This</textblock>
    <textblock>section would be amended to add references to third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicers to conform to the proposed changes in the scope of this</textblock>
    <textblock>subpart. In addition, paragraph (a)(3) of this section would be</textblock>
    <textblock>amended to reflect changes proposed under §§668.12 and 668.82</textblock>
    <textblock>dealing with the past performance of individuals, agencies, or</textblock>
    <textblock>organizations that are affiliated with an institution, including,</textblock>
    <textblock>as applicable, third-party servicers.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add a new restriction on a hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>official's authority to modify a proposed sanction against an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution or third-party servicer. If a designated department</textblock>
    <textblock>official brings a termination action against an institution or</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer for engaging in fraud, and a hearing official finds that</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution or servicer has engaged in fraud, the hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>official must uphold the termination. The examples of fraud</textblock>
    <textblock>listed in this section are the same as those proposed for §668.83</textblock>
    <textblock>concerning emergency action.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary believes that if an institution or third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer engages in fraud involving a Title IV, HEA program, the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation in the program should be terminated</textblock>
    <textblock>or the servicer's eligibility to contract with an institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>administer any aspect of that institution's participation in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs, as applicable, should be terminated. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary does not believe that a lesser sanction that permits</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution or servicer to continue to participate in the</textblock>
    <textblock>program or in the case of a third-party servicer to be eligible</textblock>
    <textblock>to contract, is a sufficient safeguard against the likely abuse</textblock>
    <textblock>of Title IV, HEA program funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to amend paragraph (c)(1) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section so that in a fine, limitation, or termination proceeding,</textblock>
    <textblock>the hearing official's initial decision automatically becomes the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's final decision in 30 days (20 days is mandated under</textblock>
    <textblock>the current regulations) after the initial decision is issued and</textblock>
    <textblock>received by both parties unless that initial decision is</textblock>
    <textblock>questioned before the Secretary. The Secretary is proposing</textblock>
    <textblock>these new timeframes to make them consistent with other reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements in this part. The Secretary does not believe that a</textblock>
    <textblock>ten-day difference in an institution's or servicer's right to</textblock>
    <textblock>appeal an initial decision would unduly affect the integrity of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary also proposes to make technical changes in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (a)(3)(iv) of this section to correct typographical</textblock>
    <textblock>errors that inadvertently appeared in final regulations published</textblock>
    <textblock>in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on July 31, 1991 (56 FR 36698).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.91␣Filing of requests for hearings and appeals;</textblock>
    <textblock>confirmation of mailing and receipt dates.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes to add references to third-party servicers to conform to</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed changes in the scope of this subpart.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
