<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00054</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The watersheds of the six creeks upstream (west) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>recharge zone span about 684 square kilometers (264 square miles).</textblock>
    <textblock>This area is referred to as the contributing zone and includes</textblock>
    <textblock>portions of Travis, Hays, and Blanco counties. The recharge and</textblock>
    <textblock>contributing zones make up the total area that provides water to the</textblock>
    <textblock>aquifer, which equals about 917 square kilometers (354 square miles)</textblock>
    <textblock>(Slade</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1986).</textblock>
    <textblock>Based on streamflow studies, Onion Creek and Barton Creek</textblock>
    <textblock>contribute the greatest percentages of total recharge to the aquifer</textblock>
    <textblock>(34 percent and 28 percent, respectively). Williamson, Slaughter,</textblock>
    <textblock>Bear, and Little Bear creeks each contribute 12 percent or less to</textblock>
    <textblock>total recharge. Owing to the amount of recharge contributed by</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Creek and its proximity to Barton Springs, this creek has a</textblock>
    <textblock>greater impact on the water quality at the springs than any other</textblock>
    <textblock>recharge source in the Barton Springs segment (Slade</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1986).</textblock>
    <textblock>The potential of the Edwards Aquifer to rapidly transmit large</textblock>
    <textblock>volumes of water with little filtration makes it highly susceptible</textblock>
    <textblock>to pollution (Slade</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1986). The Edwards Aquifer is a</textblock>
    <textblock>``karst'' aquifer, characterized by subsurface features such as</textblock>
    <textblock>caves, sinkholes, and other conduits. The aquifer is made up of</textblock>
    <textblock>limestones that have high localized permeability and porosity.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dissolution of calcium carbonate along faults and fractures in the</textblock>
    <textblock>bedrock forms solution channels similar to an underground network of</textblock>
    <textblock>pipes. Because these subsurface ``pipes'' are not uniformly</textblock>
    <textblock>distributed, groundwater movement in the aquifer is highly variable,</textblock>
    <textblock>being rapid in areas where the ``pipes'' are large and extensive and</textblock>
    <textblock>slow where permeability and porosity are low. Transmissivity (the</textblock>
    <textblock>rate at which groundwater is transmitted through the aquifer) values</textblock>
    <textblock>for the Barton Springs segment have been estimated at 0.3 to 4,000</textblock>
    <textblock>square meters (3 to 47,000 square feet) per day and tend to increase</textblock>
    <textblock>as one moves northward toward the springs (Slade</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1985).</textblock>
    <textblock>Karst aquifers are also more prone to pollution than other</textblock>
    <textblock>aquifers because few materials (such as sand, gravel, and organic</textblock>
    <textblock>matter) are present to filter out pollutants (U.S. Environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>Protection Agency (EPA) 1990). Furthermore, waters entering from</textblock>
    <textblock>the surface receive little filtration from the typically thin soils</textblock>
    <textblock>overlying the aquifer (Slade</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1986). As a result, increasing</textblock>
    <textblock>urban development over the area supplying recharge waters to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs segment can threaten water quality within the</textblock>
    <textblock>aquifer. The Texas Water Commission (TWC) has identified the</textblock>
    <textblock>Edwards Aquifer as being one of the most sensitive aquifers in Texas</textblock>
    <textblock>to groundwater pollution (TWC 1989; Margaret Hart, TWC,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1991).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Barton Springs salamander has been a Category 2 candidate</textblock>
    <textblock>species on the Service's candidate notices of review since December</textblock>
    <textblock>30, 1982 (47 FR 58454; September 18, 1985-50 FR 37958; January 6,</textblock>
    <textblock>1989-54 FR 554; and November 21, 1991-56 FR 58804), meaning that</textblock>
    <textblock>information then available indicated that a proposal to determine</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered or threatened status was possibly appropriate, but</textblock>
    <textblock>conclusive data on biological vulnerability and threats were not</textblock>
    <textblock>then available to support such a proposal. Through publication of</textblock>
    <textblock>the candidate notices, the Service requests any additional status</textblock>
    <textblock>information that may be available. On January 22, 1992, the Service</textblock>
    <textblock>received a petition from Dr. Mark Kirkpatrick and Ms. Barbara Mahler</textblock>
    <textblock>to list the Barton Springs salamander. The Service evaluated this</textblock>
    <textblock>petition and on November 25, 1992, determined that the petition</textblock>
    <textblock>presented information on threats indicating that the requested</textblock>
    <textblock>action may be warranted. A notice of that finding was published in</textblock>
    <textblock>the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 11, 1992 (57 FR 58779). The</textblock>
    <textblock>Service continued its status review of the species and solicited</textblock>
    <textblock>information regarding the status of the salamander. Although the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice requested that comments be submitted by</textblock>
    <textblock>January 11, 1993, the Service sent out numerous notification letters</textblock>
    <textblock>indicating that it recognized additional time may be needed and</textblock>
    <textblock>requesting that pertinent information be submitted by February 10,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993. This proposed rule constitutes the final finding on the</textblock>
    <textblock>petitioned action for the Barton Springs salamander.</textblock>
    <textblock>Summary of Comments and Recommendations</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service received 205 letters from individuals and agencies</textblock>
    <textblock>providing information and comments on the petition and the 90-day</textblock>
    <textblock>finding. Of the letters received, 104 were form letters stating</textblock>
    <textblock>opposition to listing, 80 were other letters opposing listing, 14</textblock>
    <textblock>supported listing, and 7 were neutral. Some of the letters provided</textblock>
    <textblock>additional new, substantive information, which was considered in</textblock>
    <textblock>making a final determination on the petition. Major comments of a</textblock>
    <textblock>similar nature or point are grouped into a number of general issues</textblock>
    <textblock>and are presented and discussed here.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 1:</textblock>
    <textblock>Several commenters requested that the Service delay</textblock>
    <textblock>or preclude listing the Barton Springs salamander because too little</textblock>
    <textblock>is known about the salamander's biology, including factors such as</textblock>
    <textblock>its range, population size and status, dietary needs, predators,</textblock>
    <textblock>longevity, reproductive success, and sensitivity to contaminants and</textblock>
    <textblock>other water quality constituents.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The known range of the Barton Springs salamander is</textblock>
    <textblock>based on the most recent information available, including status</textblock>
    <textblock>surveys conducted by the University of Texas at Austin and TPWD</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to section 6 of the Act, and through personal communication</textblock>
    <textblock>with biologists who conducted surveys at other springs in central</textblock>
    <textblock>Texas. No new information was provided to contradict the finding</textblock>
    <textblock>that the salamander is endemic to the immediate vicinity of Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs. Regarding other aspects of the species' biology, such as</textblock>
    <textblock>its population status, the Act requires a species to be determined</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered or threatened if one or more of the five factors</textblock>
    <textblock>described in section 4(a)(1) causes it to qualify under the Act's</textblock>
    <textblock>definition. Absolute population number may not be as significant in</textblock>
    <textblock>determining whether a species is endangered or threatened as</textblock>
    <textblock>knowledge that the species' entire range is threatened and cannot be</textblock>
    <textblock>preserved (see Factor A, ``The present or threatened destruction,</textblock>
    <textblock>modification, or curtailment of its habitat or range,'' and Factor</textblock>
    <textblock>D, ``The inadequacy of existing regulatory mechanisms''). Although</textblock>
    <textblock>there are still biological questions regarding the Barton Springs</textblock>
    <textblock>salamander, the Service believes that the available scientific</textblock>
    <textblock>information is sufficient for status determination and strongly</textblock>
    <textblock>supports the need to designate the salamander as an endangered</textblock>
    <textblock>species. The data that support this conclusion are presented and</textblock>
    <textblock>discussed in the ``Summary of Factors Affecting the Species''</textblock>
    <textblock>section of this rule, particularly under Factor A (loss of habitat).</textblock>
    <textblock>Available information on the sensitivity of the salamander and its</textblock>
    <textblock>prey base (amphipods) to water quality deterioration is discussed</textblock>
    <textblock>under Factors A and E (``Other natural or manmade factors affecting</textblock>
    <textblock>its continued existence''). Once a species becomes listed as</textblock>
    <textblock>threatened or endangered, section 4(f) of the Act directs the</textblock>
    <textblock>Service to develop and implement a recovery plan for that species.</textblock>
    <textblock>Recovery is the process by which the decline of a listed species is</textblock>
    <textblock>arrested or reversed, and threats to its survival are eliminated or</textblock>
    <textblock>neutralized, so that its long-term survival in nature can be</textblock>
    <textblock>ensured. Further research is very often an essential component of</textblock>
    <textblock>recovery plans. The Service envisions that conducting research on</textblock>
    <textblock>the salamander's biology and other factors, such as those mentioned</textblock>
    <textblock>in this comment, will be an important part of the recovery process</textblock>
    <textblock>for this species (see Available Conservation Measures).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
