<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00093</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00053</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that, on November 12, 1993, pursuant to Section 6(a) of the National Cooperative Research and Production Act of 1993, 15 U.S.C. 4301</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>(``the Act''), Microelectronics and Computer Technology Corporation (``MCC'') has filed written notifications simultaneously with the Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission disclosing changes in its membership. The notifications were filed for the purpose of extending the Act's provisions limiting the recovery of antitrust plaintiffs to actual damages under specified circumstances. Specifically, the changes are as follows: (1) Ceridian Corporation, Bloomington, MN, and Paramex Systems Corporation, Salt Lake City, UT, have agreed to become participants in MCC's Adaptive Beam Forming Technology Study; and (2) Raytheon Company, Lexington, MA, has agreed to become a participant in MCC's Mixed Signal Open Systems Project.</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 21, 1984, MCC filed its original notification pursuant to Section 6(a) of the Act. The Department of Justice published a notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to Section 6(b) of the Act on January 17, 1985 (50 FR 2633).</textblock>
    <textblock>The last notification was filed with the Department on September 15, 1993. A notice was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to Section 6(b) of the Act on October 28, 1993 (58 FR 58019).</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice Pursuant to the National Cooperative Research and Production Act of 1993_Microelectronics and Computer Technology Corporation</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Joseph H. Widmar,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director of Operations, Antitrust Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3658 Filed 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
