<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00038</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00023</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>4. Gordonsville Energy, L.P.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket Nos. EL94-20-000, QF92-166-003 and QF92-167-003]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 13, 1994, Gordonsville Energy, L.P. (Gordonsville) tendered for filing a Petition for Waiver of the Commission's Regulations under the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (PURPA). Gordonsville petitions the Commission to waive the ownership requirements for qualifying cogeneration facilities as set forth in ยง292.206(b), 18 CFR 292.206(b) of the Commission's Regulations implementing Section 201 of PURPA, as amended, with respect to Gordonsville's one hundred percent (100%) ownership interest in two natural gas and oil-fired qualifying cogeneration facilities located in Gordonsville, Virginia.</textblock>
    <textblock>The notice originally issued in this proceeding on January 28, 1994, is amended to reference Docket Nos. QF92-166-003 and QF92-167-003.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 28, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Southern California Edison Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER93-576-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 2, 1994, Southern California Edison Company submitted supplemental information regarding its filing in the above-captioned docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 22, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Pennsylvania Power &amp; Light Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-945-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 1, 1994, Pennsylvania Power &amp; Light Company (PP&amp;L), tendered for filing a proposed change in rate levels of certain electric resale schedules presently on file with the Commission. The proposed change will decrease base rate revenues from jurisdictional sales and service to the specified utility and municipal resale customers (municipal utilities). PP&amp;L requests an effective date of February 1, 1994, the date negotiated by PP&amp;L and the municipal utilities. PP&amp;L states that all the municipal utilities concerned have agreed to the filed rate schedule changes.</textblock>
    <textblock>PP&amp;L states that copies of the filing were served on the municipal utilities concerned as well as the Pennsylvania Public Utility Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 22, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-946-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 1, 1994, Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation (Niagara Mohawk) tendered for filing with the Commission a signed Service Agreement between Niagara Mohawk and the New York Power Authority (NYPA) for sales of system capacity and/or energy or resource capacity and/or energy under Niagara Mohawk's proposed Power Sales Tariff in Docket No. ER93-313-000. Niagara Mohawk filed its Power Sales Tariff on January 11, 1993 and requested an effective date of March 13, 1993 for the Tariff. Niagara Mohawk requests an effective date for this Service Agreement of February 1, 1994, the date of filing with FERC.</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of this filing has been served upon NYPA and the New York State Public Service Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 22, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. IES Utilities Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-947-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 1, 1994, IES Utilities Inc. (IESU), tendered for filing a Notice of Succession, wherein IESU stated it had adopted all existing rate schedules of Iowa Southern Utilities Company (ISU) and Iowa Electric Light and Power Company (IE) on file with the Commission. Effective December 31, 1993, ISU merged into IE and the name of the surviving corporation was changed to IES Utilities Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the filing was served upon all jurisdictional customers of IESU.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 22, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
