<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00081</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00041</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The proposal for the collection of information listed below has been submitted to the Office of Management and Budget for approval under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. chapter 35). Copies of the proposed information collection requirement and related forms and explanatory material may be obtained by contacting the Bureau of Land Management's (BLM) Clearance Office at the phone number listed below. Comments and suggestions on the requirement should be made directly to the BLM's Clearance Officer and to the Office of Management and Budget, Paperwork Reduction Project (1004-0042), Washington, DC 20503, telephone 202-395-7340.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Protection, Management, and Control of Wild Free-Roaming Horses and Burros, 43 CFR 4700.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB Approval Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>1004-0042.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abstract:</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondents furnish documentation about the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Removal of wild horses and burros from private land (non-form item).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Qualifications of applicants related to adoption of 1 to 4 wild horses or burros (Form 4710-10).</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Qualifications of applicants related to adoption of 5 or more wild horses or burros (non-form item).</textblock>
    <textblock>The request for removal of animals from private land is necessary to determine the need for removing wild horses and burros from these lands. The documentation about adoption allows the BLM to determine if an applicant will be given the opportunity to adopt wild horses or burros. Adoption applicants provide information about their qualifications and capability to provide humane care and treatment for wild horses and burros under conditions specified by Federal regulations. Applicants for adoption of more than 4 wild horses or burros are requested to provide additional information related to their capability to provide proper care for the number of wild horses or burros requested.</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau Form Numbers:</textblock>
    <textblock>Application for Adoption of Wild Horse(s) and Burro(s), Form 4710-10.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency:</textblock>
    <textblock>On occasion.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Landowners requesting the BLM to remove wild horses or burros from their property and applicants desiring to adopt wild horses or burros.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Completion Time:</textblock>
    <textblock>.165 hours per response.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>32,380.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Burden Hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>5,376.</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau Clearance Officer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Marsha A. Harley 202-452-5014.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 19, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[NV-960-4370-01-241B]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Information Collection Submitted to the Office of Management and Budget for Review Under the Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>J. David Almand,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Deputy Asstistant Director, Land and Renewable Resources.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3647 Filed 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-84-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
