<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00055</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Issue 2:</textblock>
    <textblock>Several individuals questioned the taxonomic status</textblock>
    <textblock>of the salamander, asserting that it is still an undescribed species</textblock>
    <textblock>and may be part of the central Texas salamander (</textblock>
    <textblock>Eurycea neotenes</textblock>
    <textblock>)</textblock>
    <textblock>complex.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Formal description of the salamander as a distinct</textblock>
    <textblock>species has withstood peer-review and was published in June, 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>(see discussion in the Background section).</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 3:</textblock>
    <textblock>Several commenters stated that water quality data at</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs show no demonstrable deterioration, despite</textblock>
    <textblock>development immediately upstream from the springs, much of which</textblock>
    <textblock>occurred prior to implementation of water quality controls.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service recognizes that, other than high levels</textblock>
    <textblock>of fecal-group bacteria and turbidity immediately following storm</textblock>
    <textblock>events, water quality at Barton Springs is considered to be very</textblock>
    <textblock>good. However, only about 3 to 4 percent of the recharge and</textblock>
    <textblock>contributing zones is currently developed. As urban development</textblock>
    <textblock>over the recharge and contributing zones increases, the threat of</textblock>
    <textblock>water quality degradation from point-source and non-point-source</textblock>
    <textblock>pollution will increase. The threat of increased urbanization over</textblock>
    <textblock>these areas and impacts on water quality in the aquifer and at</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs are discussed in Factor A.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 4:</textblock>
    <textblock>Most commenters opposed to the listing stated that</textblock>
    <textblock>existing State and local rules and regulations are adequate to</textblock>
    <textblock>protect the salamander and its habitat from groundwater degradation</textblock>
    <textblock>and depletion.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>This issue is presented and discussed in Factor D.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service recognizes that there are several rules and regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>aimed at protecting water quality and quantity within the aquifer,</textblock>
    <textblock>and that these rules and regulations will provide some benefits to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Barton Springs salamander if adequately enforced. However, no</textblock>
    <textblock>information was presented to show that these existing rules and</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations will ensure long-term protection of water quality and</textblock>
    <textblock>quantity at Barton Springs and will be adequate to protect the</textblock>
    <textblock>salamander and its habitat. Furthermore, there are no assurances</textblock>
    <textblock>that the existing rules and regulations will remain in place and be</textblock>
    <textblock>enforced. Regarding water quantity, the Barton Springs/Edwards</textblock>
    <textblock>Aquifer Conservation District (BS/EACD) has limited enforcement</textblock>
    <textblock>authority and does not regulate 30 to 40 percent of the total volume</textblock>
    <textblock>that is pumped from the Barton Springs segment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 5:</textblock>
    <textblock>Several individuals expressed concern that listing</textblock>
    <textblock>the salamander could impose restrictions on the recreational use of</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs Pool.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>This issue is discussed under Factor B</textblock>
    <textblock>(``Overutilization for commercial, recreational, scientific, or</textblock>
    <textblock>educational purposes''). There is currently no evidence suggesting</textblock>
    <textblock>that swimming in Barton Springs Pool will adversely impact the</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs salamander. The Service maintains the position that</textblock>
    <textblock>if pool maintenance activities are conducted in such a way as to</textblock>
    <textblock>avoid impacting the salamander and its habitat (such as avoiding the</textblock>
    <textblock>application of chemicals and the use of high pressure fire hoses to</textblock>
    <textblock>clean areas inhabited by salamanders), then activities associated</textblock>
    <textblock>with swimming at Barton Springs Pool should not disturb the</textblock>
    <textblock>salamander.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 6:</textblock>
    <textblock>The salamander has persisted despite past droughts,</textblock>
    <textblock>low springflows, and pollution events over the aquifer and its</textblock>
    <textblock>contributing zone and at Barton Springs (elevated fecal coliform</textblock>
    <textblock>bacteria and turbidity).</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service acknowledges that these events have</textblock>
    <textblock>occurred and that the frequency of such events is likely to increase</textblock>
    <textblock>with increasing development over the aquifer and its contributing</textblock>
    <textblock>zone. Although the salamander has survived these past events, the</textblock>
    <textblock>point at which declining water quality and quantity would cause</textblock>
    <textblock>extinction of the salamander is uncertain. Amphibians in general</textblock>
    <textblock>are highly sensitive to changes in water chemistry, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>salamander's restricted range makes it especially vulnerable to</textblock>
    <textblock>water quality deterioration. A major pollution event has the</textblock>
    <textblock>potential of eliminating the entire species and/or its prey base.</textblock>
    <textblock>Amphipods, which comprise most of the salamander's diet, are</textblock>
    <textblock>especially sensitive to water pollution (see discussion in Factor</textblock>
    <textblock>E).</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 7:</textblock>
    <textblock>A few commenters stated that the threat of declining</textblock>
    <textblock>aquifer levels is not substantial at Barton Springs and, in any</textblock>
    <textblock>event, no demonstrable evidence exists that lowered aquifer levels</textblock>
    <textblock>will cause a threat to the continued existence of the salamander.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>This issue is addressed in Factor A. Although the</textblock>
    <textblock>Service recognizes that cessation of flows is not likely at Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs in the near future, increased groundwater withdrawal and</textblock>
    <textblock>resulting reduced flows are expected due to increasing urbanization</textblock>
    <textblock>over the aquifer. Reduced aquifer levels may lead to the</textblock>
    <textblock>encroachment of the ``bad water'' line and increased concentrations</textblock>
    <textblock>of pollutants in the aquifer.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
