<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00094</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(4) Is a member of the board of directors, the chief</textblock>
    <textblock>executive officer, or other executive officer of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The institution or servicer; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) An entity that holds at least a 25 percent ownership</textblock>
    <textblock>interest in the institution or servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Section 668.23 is amended by redesignating</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (c)(3) as paragraph (c)(3)(i), revising paragraphs (b)</textblock>
    <textblock>and (c)(1), adding paragraph (c)(3) (ii) through (vi) and</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (c)(4)(iii), revising paragraph (c)(5), adding a new</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (c)(6), and revising paragraph (e) and the authority</textblock>
    <textblock>citation to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.23</textblock>
    <textblock>Audits, records, and examinations.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)(1) An institution that participates in any Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA program shall cooperate with an independent auditor, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary, the Department of Education's Inspector General, and</textblock>
    <textblock>the Comptroller General of the United States, or their authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>representatives, a guaranty agency in whose program the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution participates, and the State postsecondary review</textblock>
    <textblock>entity designated under subpart 1 of part H of Title IV of the</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA, in the conduct of audits, investigations, and program</textblock>
    <textblock>reviews authorized by law.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A third-party servicer shall cooperate with an</textblock>
    <textblock>independent auditor, the Secretary, the Department of Education's</textblock>
    <textblock>Inspector General, and the Comptroller General of the United</textblock>
    <textblock>States, or their authorized representatives, a guaranty agency in</textblock>
    <textblock>whose program the institution contracting with the servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>participates, and the State postsecondary review entity</textblock>
    <textblock>designated under subpart 1 of part H of Title IV of the HEA, in</textblock>
    <textblock>the conduct of audits, investigations, and program reviews</textblock>
    <textblock>authorized by law.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The institution's or servicer's cooperation must</textblock>
    <textblock>include_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Providing timely access, for examination and copying,</textblock>
    <textblock>to the records (including computerized records) required by the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable regulations and to any other pertinent books,</textblock>
    <textblock>documents, papers, computer programs, and records;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Providing reasonable access to personnel associated</textblock>
    <textblock>with the institution's or servicer's administration of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs for the purpose of obtaining relevant</textblock>
    <textblock>information. In providing reasonable access, the institution or</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer may not_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Refuse to supply any relevant information;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Refuse to permit interviews with those personnel that</textblock>
    <textblock>do not include the presence of representatives of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's or servicer's management; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Refuse to permit interviews with those personnel that</textblock>
    <textblock>are not tape recorded by the institution or servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)(1)(i) An institution that participates in the FDSL,</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Perkins Loan, FWS, FSEOG, Federal Stafford Loan, Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>PLUS, Federal SLS, Federal Pell Grant, or PAS programs shall have</textblock>
    <textblock>performed a compliance audit of that program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A third-party servicer that administers funds or</textblock>
    <textblock>determines student eligibility shall have a compliance audit</textblock>
    <textblock>performed of every aspect of the servicer's administration of the</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the Title IV, HEA programs of each institution</textblock>
    <textblock>with which the servicer has a contract, unless_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The servicer contracts with only one participating</textblock>
    <textblock>institution; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The audit of that institution's participation involves</textblock>
    <textblock>every aspect of the servicer's administration of that</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) To meet the requirements of paragraph (c)(1)(ii) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section, a third-party servicer that contracts with more</textblock>
    <textblock>than one participating institution may submit a single compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>audit report that covers every aspect of the servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of the participation in the Title IV, HEA programs</textblock>
    <textblock>for each institution with which the servicer contracts.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The audit required under paragraph (c)(1) (i) or (ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section must be conducted by an independent auditor in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with the general standards and the standards for</textblock>
    <textblock>audits in the U.S. General Accounting Office's (GAO's) Standards</textblock>
    <textblock>for Audit of Governmental Organizations, Programs, Activities,</textblock>
    <textblock>and Functions.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) *␣*␣*</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
