<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00130</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00074</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>13. Compensate for wetland impacts caused by the development of the Proposed Action Alternative through the creation of approximately 25 acres of new wetlands. (scoped originally)</textblock>
    <textblock>14. An additional 1,500 flights annually beyond those originally forecasted but with a greater number of stage three aircraft. This is based on UPS's proposal to initiate an air cargo operation at Greater Rockford Airport. (new)</textblock>
    <textblock>An informational workshop and Public Hearing will be held from 3 p.m. to 8 p.m. on Tuesday, March 22, 1994 in the Auditorium and Classroom of the Operations &amp; Public Safety Center at Greater Rockford Airport, 60 Airport Drive, Rockford, Illinois. Comments on the Draft Environmental Assessment are invited from Federal, State, and local agencies, and all other interested parties to provide additional opportunity for scoping comments and to insure that a full range of issues and alternatives related to the proposed projects and actions are addressed and all issues identified. Comments may be provided in writing and/or orally at the Public Hearing or submitted in writing either to the FAA at the address provided above or to Mr. Frederick C. Ford, Executive Director, Greater Rockford Airport, 3600 Airport Drive, P.O. Box 5063, Rockford, Illinois 61125-0063. All comments received by April 6, 1994 will be considered in preparation of the Airport Sponsor's Final Environmental Assessment. Comments received after the close of the comment period, but prior to the FAA's environmental fining will be considered by the FAA to the extent practical. The FAA will issue a Final Environmental Document that includes corrections, clarifications and responses to comments on the Draft Environmental Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the Draft Environmental Assessment are available for review at the following locations:</textblock>
    <textblock>Airport Manager's Office, Greater Rockford Airport Authority, 3600 Airport Drive, Rockford, Illinois 61125-0063</textblock>
    <textblock>Rockford City Clerk's Office, Rockford City Hall, 1201 Broadway, Rockford, Illinois</textblock>
    <textblock>Winnebago County Courthouse, County Clerk's Office, 400 West State, Rockford, Illinois</textblock>
    <textblock>Rockford Public Library, 215 North Wyman, Rockford, Illinois</textblock>
    <textblock>Illinois Department of Transportation, Division of Aeronautics, One Langhorne Drive, Capitol Airport, Springfield, Illinois</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, Chicago Airports District Office, 2300 East Devon Avenue, Des Plaines, Illinois 60018</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Des Plaines, Illinois on February 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Louis H. Yates,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Chicago Airports District Office, FAA, Great Lakes Region.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3621 Filed 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
