<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00139</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00080</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>III. Selection Process</textblock>
    <textblock>A. A school that has been selected to participate in the Direct Loan Program for the 1994-1995 academic year, and an eligible school that applied to participate in the program for that year but was not selected, need not submit an application for the 1995-1996 academic year.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. By June 15, 1994, the Secretary will select schools from all applications received by March 30, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. If the loan volume of the selected schools represents less than 40 percent of the new student loan volume for the 1995-1996 academic year, the Secretary will select additional schools from applications submitted by July 1, 1994. The Secretary will select these schools by September 15, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>D. If the loan volume of all selected schools represents less than 40 percent of the new student loan volume for the 1995-1996 academic year, the Secretary will select additional schools from applications submitted by October 1, 1994. The Secretary will select these schools by November 15, 1994. (20 U.S.C. 1087a</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>)</textblock>
    <textblock>Solicitation of Applications for Participation in the Direct Loan Program_1995-1996 Academic Year</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose of program:</textblock>
    <textblock>To provide loans to enable a student or parent to pay the costs of the student's attendance at a postsecondary school. Under the Direct Loan Program, loan capital is provided directly to student and parent borrowers by the Federal Government rather than through private lenders.</textblock>
    <textblock>Eligible applicants</textblock>
    <textblock>: Colleges, universities, graduate and professional schools, and vocational and technical schools that meet the definition of an eligible institution under section 435(a) of the HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Deadlines for transmittal of applications:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 30, 1994; July 1, 1994; and October 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>For information contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Barbara Ragon, U.S. Department of Education, 400 Maryland Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20202-5162. Telephone: (202) 708-8242. Individuals who use a telecommunications device for the deaf (TDD) may call the Federal Information Relay Service (FIRS) at 1-800-877-8339 between 8 a.m. and 8 p.m., Eastern time, Monday through Friday.</textblock>
    <textblock>Application form and instructions:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary has developed an application form for a school to use to apply to participate in the Direct Loan Program. A copy of the application form is included as an Appendix to this notice. On this form, the signature of the President or Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of the institution is required.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a school desires to participate in both the FFEL Program and the Direct Loan Program, it must include an estimate of the percentage of the institution's anticipated new student loan volume that will be made under the Direct Loan Program. In addition, an applying school must indicate whether it is willing to participate in the Direct Loan Program electronically.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a school is applying as part of a consortium, it must indicate the exact names of all schools in the consortium and the name of the destination point (school or outside entity) for the consortium.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order to be considered for participation in the 1995-1996 academic year, a school must complete the application and submit it to the address below as soon as possible, but no later than the final deadline date.</textblock>
    <textblock>A school may mail or fax the application to: U.S. Department of Education, Office of Postsecondary Education, ROB-3, Federal Direct Loan Task Force, room 4025, 400 Maryland Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20202-5162, FAX: (202) 260-6718, (202) 260-6705, or (202) 260-6706.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Number 84.268, Federal Direct Student Loan Program)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard W. Riley,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of Education.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4000-01-P-M</textblock>
  </billing>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:Graphicsen17fe94.000</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:Graphicsen17fe94.001</textblock>
  </import>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3583 Filed 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4000-01-C</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
