<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00072</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The following summarizes the major changes in this notice of</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rulemaking (NPRM):</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 668_Student Assistance General Provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.1␣Scope.</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 668 governs the administration</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Title IV, HEA programs by an institution and provides for</textblock>
    <textblock>various enforcement measures against institutions for any</textblock>
    <textblock>violations of program requirements by the institution or its</textblock>
    <textblock>agents. A third-party servicer, as an agent of an institution,</textblock>
    <textblock>must currently apply the requirements of part 668 to administer</textblock>
    <textblock>properly the Title IV, HEA programs on behalf of an institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to specify that the requirements of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Student Assistance General Provisions regulations would be</textblock>
    <textblock>applied to a third-party servicer (as proposed to be defined in</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.2) to the extent that the servicer administers any aspect of</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution's participation in a Title IV, HEA program. This</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal would enable the Secretary, for the first time, to</textblock>
    <textblock>directly oversee the conduct of third-party servicers. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary also proposes to make clear that although the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>would hold a third-party servicer responsible for compliance with</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable regulations, an institution that contracts with the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer always remains responsible for the servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance. This clarification merely restates the Department of</textblock>
    <textblock>Education's long-standing policy and requirements with respect to</textblock>
    <textblock>institutional responsibility.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.2␣General definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>These proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations would incorporate the statutory definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer in section 481(f) of the HEA. Under that</textblock>
    <textblock>definition (as amended by the Higher Education Technical Amendments of 1993 (Pub. L. 103-208), enacted on December 20,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993), a third-party servicer is an ``individual, or any State, or</textblock>
    <textblock>private, profit or nonprofit organization'' that contracts with an</textblock>
    <textblock>eligible institution to administer any aspect of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation in a Title IV, HEA program. The</textblock>
    <textblock>statutory definition includes additional elements applicable to a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer's administration of the FFEL programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>These aspects of the definition are addressed in a subsequent</textblock>
    <textblock>discussion on 34 CFR part 682.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary also proposes to include as part of the</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of third-party servicer examples of services which a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer could provide to an institution that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary considers to constitute the administration of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation in a Title IV, HEA program. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes that examples are necessary to alert those</textblock>
    <textblock>individuals and organizations that contract with an eligible</textblock>
    <textblock>institution of the specific activities that would be subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>the requirements proposed in these regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The examples that the Secretary proposes to include in the</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of third-party servicer are primarily examples that</textblock>
    <textblock>show an obvious relationship to the administration of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs. The Secretary proposes these examples to</textblock>
    <textblock>specifically detail which activities unequivocally constitute the</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of an institution's participation in the Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA programs. While these examples are not all-inclusive, they</textblock>
    <textblock>do provide a baseline to judge other activities that could be</textblock>
    <textblock>deemed an aspect of the administration of an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary also proposes to include another set of</textblock>
    <textblock>examples that the Secretary believes do not constitute the</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of an institution's participation in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs. For example, the Secretary does not</textblock>
    <textblock>consider the activity of publishing ability-to-benefit (ATB)</textblock>
    <textblock>tests to be a third-party servicer activity because publishers of</textblock>
    <textblock>ATB tests do not contract with institutions and under the statute</textblock>
    <textblock>would not fall within the definition of a third-party servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>As another example, the Secretary does not consider</textblock>
    <textblock>performing activities as a Multiple Data Entry Processor (MDE) to</textblock>
    <textblock>be included in the scope of third-party servicer activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>While an MDE could be considered to administer certain aspects of</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution's participation in the Title IV, HEA programs, an</textblock>
    <textblock>MDE is bound by other Department of Education requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, the Secretary does not believe it necessary to</textblock>
    <textblock>separately regulate MDE activities as part of these proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>In general, the Secretary also proposes to exclude auditing</textblock>
    <textblock>activities from the scope of these regulations. Entities</textblock>
    <textblock>performing audits are required to be impartial and independent</textblock>
    <textblock>entities with no vested interest in the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further, while auditors provide services needed to comply with</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA requirements, their services are not directly</textblock>
    <textblock>connected to the day-to-day administration of Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>assistance. The Secretary, therefore, believes that auditing</textblock>
    <textblock>activities should not be included in the scope of these</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other proposed examples classified as being outside the</textblock>
    <textblock>scope of these regulatory requirements simply reinforce the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's belief that certain activities performed by a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer that do not substantially affect the</textblock>
    <textblock>delivery of Title IV, HEA program aid do not constitute the</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of an institution's participation in the Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA programs, (for example, contracting to warehouse records).</textblock>
    <textblock>As a result of deliberations during the negotiated</textblock>
    <textblock>rulemaking sessions, Federal and non-Federal negotiators</textblock>
    <textblock>concluded that it was not necessary to include or exclude</textblock>
    <textblock>computer services or software providers from the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of third-party servicer or the examples provided. The</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiators concluded that computer software and computer</textblock>
    <textblock>services are simply technological means to assist in carrying out</textblock>
    <textblock>specific administrative functions. Accordingly, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>invites public comment on whether an individual, State, or</textblock>
    <textblock>organization providing computer software and services represented</textblock>
    <textblock>to satisfy Title IV, HEA program requirements should specifically</textblock>
    <textblock>be included in what the Secretary considers to constitute a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer's administration of an eligible</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation in a Title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
