<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00096</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(i) If an institution or third-party servicer has posted</textblock>
    <textblock>surety or has provided a third-party guarantee and the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>questions expenditures or compliance with applicable requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>and identifies liabilities, then the Secretary may determine that</textblock>
    <textblock>deferring recourse to the surety or guarantee is not appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>because_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The need to provide relief to students or borrowers</textblock>
    <textblock>affected by the act or omission giving rise to the liability</textblock>
    <textblock>outweighs the importance of deferring collection action until</textblock>
    <textblock>completion of available appeal proceedings; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The terms of the surety or guarantee do not provide</textblock>
    <textblock>complete assurance that recourse to that protection will be fully</textblock>
    <textblock>available through the completion of available appeal proceedings;</textblock>
    <textblock>or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The Secretary may determine that an administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>offset to collect the funds owed under the procedures of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section is appropriate under 34 CFR 30.28.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) If, under the proceedings in subpart H, liabilities</textblock>
    <textblock>asserted in the notification against the institution or</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer are upheld, the institution or third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer shall repay those funds at the direction of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary within 30 days of the final determination under</textblock>
    <textblock>subpart H of this part unless_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The Secretary permits a longer repayment period; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The Secretary determines that earlier collection</textblock>
    <textblock>action is appropriate pursuant to paragraph (c)(2) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) An institution is held responsible for any liability</textblock>
    <textblock>owed by the institution's third-party servicer for a violation</textblock>
    <textblock>incurred in servicing any aspect of that institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the Title IV, HEA programs and remains</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible for that amount until that amount is repaid in full.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1094)</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Section 668.25 is redesignated as ยง668.26 and a new</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง668.25 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง668.25</textblock>
    <textblock>Contracts between an institution and a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) An institution may enter into a written contract with a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer for the administration of any aspect of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation in any Title IV, HEA program only to</textblock>
    <textblock>the extent that the servicer's eligibility to contract with the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution has not been limited, suspended, or terminated under</textblock>
    <textblock>the proceedings of subpart G of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Subject to the provisions of paragraph (d) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, a third-party servicer is eligible to enter into a</textblock>
    <textblock>written contract with an institution for the administration of</textblock>
    <textblock>any aspect of the institution's participation in any</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program only to the extent that the servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility to contract with the institution has not been</textblock>
    <textblock>limited, suspended, or terminated under the proceedings of</textblock>
    <textblock>subpart G of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) In a contract with an institution, a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer shall agree to_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Comply with all statutory provisions of or applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>to Title IV of the HEA, all regulatory provisions prescribed</textblock>
    <textblock>under that statutory authority, and all applicable special</textblock>
    <textblock>arrangements, agreements, limitations, suspensions, and</textblock>
    <textblock>terminations, including the requirement to use any funds that the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer administers under any Title IV, HEA program and any</textblock>
    <textblock>interest or other earnings thereon solely for the purposes</textblock>
    <textblock>specified in and in accordance with that program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Refer to the Office of Inspector General of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education for investigation of any information</textblock>
    <textblock>indicating there is reasonable cause to believe that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution might have engaged in fraud or other criminal</textblock>
    <textblock>misconduct in connection with the institution's administration of</textblock>
    <textblock>any Title IV, HEA program or an applicant for Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program assistance might have engaged in fraud or other criminal</textblock>
    <textblock>misconduct in connection with his or her application. Examples</textblock>
    <textblock>of the type of information that must be referred are_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) False claims by the institution for Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program assistance;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) False claims of independent student status;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) False claims of citizenship;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Use of false identities;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
