<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00032</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>DOE Response to Recommendation 93-6 of the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board; Maintaining Access to Nuclear Weapons Expertise</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Energy.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice and request for public comment.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 315(b) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended, 42 U.S.C. 2286d(b), the Department of Energy (DOE) hereby publishes notice of a response of the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) to Recommendation 93-6 of the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board, published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 23, 1993, (58 FR 68123) concerning access to nuclear weapons expertise.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments, data, views, or arguments concerning the Secretary's response are due on or before March 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send comments, data, views, or arguments concerning the Secretary's response to: Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board, 625 Indiana Avenue NW., suite 700, Washington, DC 20004.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Victor H. Reis, Assistant Secretary for Defense Programs, Department of Energy, 1000 Independence Avenue SW., Washington, DC 20585.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on February 2, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Mark B. Whitaker,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Departmental Representative to the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Honorable John T. Conway,</textblock>
    <textblock>Chairman,</textblock>
    <textblock>Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board, 625 Indiana Avenue NW., Suite 700, Washington, DC 20004</textblock>
    <textblock>Dear Mr. Conway: The Department of Energy fully accepts Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board Recommendation 93-6, Maintaining Access to Nuclear Weapons Expertise.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department shares your concern of ensuring capability to safely conduct nuclear weapons testing operations at the Nevada Test Site and to safely dismantle nuclear weapons at the Pantex Site. To meet this challenge, the Department must identify and maintain access to the critical skills of nuclear weapons scientists, engineers, and technicians. Where access to skills in the future is uncertain, the Department must find ways to capture knowledge, so safe dismantlement procedures can be developed and utilized and safe testing operations can be conducted.</textblock>
    <textblock>The forthcoming Implementation Plan for Recommendation 93-6 will capitalize on activities that have already been initiated and provide a structured approach for ensuring the continued safe conduct of operations at Pantex and the Nevada Test Site.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣Sincerely,</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Hazel R. O'Leary.</textblock>
  </signer>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3643 Filed 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
