<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00055</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00031</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Program Background and Objectives</textblock>
    <textblock>The Emergency Medical Services for Children statute (Section 1910</textblock>
    <textblock>of the PHS Act, as amended) establishes a program of two-year</textblock>
    <textblock>grants to States, through a State-designated agency, or to an</textblock>
    <textblock>accredited medical school within the State, for projects for the</textblock>
    <textblock>expansion and improvement of emergency medical services for</textblock>
    <textblock>children who need treatment for trauma or critical illness. For</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of this grant program, the term ``State'' includes the 50</textblock>
    <textblock>States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Virgin Islands, the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, American</textblock>
    <textblock>Samoa, the Republic of Palau, the Republic of the Marshall</textblock>
    <textblock>Islands, and the Federated States of Micronesia. The term ``school</textblock>
    <textblock>of medicine'' is defined as having the same meaning as set forth in</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 799(1)(A) of the PHS Act (42 U.S.C. 295p(1)(A)).</textblock>
    <textblock>``Accredited'' in this context has the same meaning as set forth in</textblock>
    <textblock>section 799(1)(E) of the PHS Act (42 U.S.C. 295p(1)(E)). It is</textblock>
    <textblock>the intent of this grant program to stimulate further development</textblock>
    <textblock>or expansion of ongoing efforts in the States to reduce the</textblock>
    <textblock>problems of life-threatening pediatric trauma and critical</textblock>
    <textblock>illness. The Department does not intend to award grants which</textblock>
    <textblock>would duplicate grants previously funded under the Emergency</textblock>
    <textblock>Medical Services Systems Act of 1972 or which would be used simply</textblock>
    <textblock>to increase the availability of emergency medical services funds</textblock>
    <textblock>allotted to the State under the Preventive Health Services Block</textblock>
    <textblock>Grant.</textblock>
    <textblock>Funding Categories</textblock>
    <textblock>There will be four categories of competition for funding this</textblock>
    <textblock>year: State planning grants, State systems grants, targeted issue</textblock>
    <textblock>grants, and resource capacity grants. States may apply for only</textblock>
    <textblock>one of the first two categories, but are not restricted in</textblock>
    <textblock>applying for the last two categories.</textblock>
    <textblock>Category (1): State Planning Grants</textblock>
    <textblock>Planning grants are intended for States that have never received</textblock>
    <textblock>an EMSC grant and that are not at a stage of readiness to initiate</textblock>
    <textblock>a full-scale implementation project. States (or medical schools</textblock>
    <textblock>within those States) that have not received prior EMSC</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation grants are the only applicants eligible for this</textblock>
    <textblock>category. Planning grants are designed to enable a State to</textblock>
    <textblock>assess needs and develop a strategy to begin to address those</textblock>
    <textblock>needs. Funds may be used to hire staff to assist in the</textblock>
    <textblock>assessment of EMSC needs of the State; obtain technical assistance</textblock>
    <textblock>from national, State, regional or local resources; help formulate</textblock>
    <textblock>a State plan for the integration of EMSC services into the</textblock>
    <textblock>existing State EMS plan; and plan a more comprehensive grant</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal based upon a needs assessment performed during the</textblock>
    <textblock>planning grant project period. A comprehensive approach,</textblock>
    <textblock>addressing physical, psychological, and social aspects of EMSC</textblock>
    <textblock>along the continuum of care, should be reflected. An ongoing working relationship with Federal EMSC program staff and resource</textblock>
    <textblock>center staff, beginning with the initiation of a planning grant</textblock>
    <textblock>application, is strongly encouraged. Budget requests in this</textblock>
    <textblock>category should not exceed $50,000, The project period is for one</textblock>
    <textblock>year only, with no renewal. Applications in this category are due</textblock>
    <textblock>earlier than other categories. The application deadline is</textblock>
    <textblock>March 25, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Category (2): State Systems Grants</textblock>
    <textblock>This category of grants has two subcategories: implementation</textblock>
    <textblock>grants and system enhancement grants. Proposals for State systems</textblock>
    <textblock>grants may be framed within the context of the changing conditions</textblock>
    <textblock>of health care delivery anticipated under health care reform.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subcategory (A): implementation grants.</textblock>
    <textblock>Implementation grants will improve the capacity of a State's</textblock>
    <textblock>Emergency Medical Services program to address the particular needs</textblock>
    <textblock>of children. Implementation grants are used to assist States in</textblock>
    <textblock>integrating research-based knowledge and state-of-the-art systems</textblock>
    <textblock>development approaches into the existing State EMS/trauma systems</textblock>
    <textblock>using the experience and products of previous EMSC grantees.</textblock>
    <textblock>Grants of up to $250,000 per award for each twelve month budget</textblock>
    <textblock>period are anticipated. Project periods are up to two years. Up</textblock>
    <textblock>to five grants will be awarded. For this competition, we intend</textblock>
    <textblock>to fund applications from States (and medical schools within those</textblock>
    <textblock>States) that have not as yet received support, or that have</textblock>
    <textblock>received only partial support under this program as part of a</textblock>
    <textblock>regional alliance. This means that approved applications from</textblock>
    <textblock>States (and medical schools within those States) with no or very</textblock>
    <textblock>limited prior EMSC program support will be funded before approved</textblock>
    <textblock>applications from outside this group. Applications will not be</textblock>
    <textblock>accepted for both planning grants and implementation grants</textblock>
    <textblock>simultaneously from the same State.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
