<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00147</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Therefore, it is proposed that 48 CFR parts 9, 15, and 42 be amended as set forth below:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for 48 CFR parts 9, 15, and 42 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>40 U.S.C. 486(c); 10 U.S.C. chapter 137; and 42 U.S.C. 2473(c).</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 9_CONTRACTOR QUALIFICATIONS</textblock>
    <textblock>9.104-1</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 9.104-1, paragraph (c) is amended by adding the words ``and subpart 42.15'' at the end.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Section 9.105-1, paragraph (c) introductory text, is revised as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>9.105-1</textblock>
    <textblock>Obtaining information.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The contracting officer shall consider relevant past performance information (see subpart 42.15) in making determinations of responsibility or nonresponsibility. In addition, the contracting officer should use the following sources of information to support such determinations:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 15_CONTRACTING BY NEGOTIATION</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Section 15.605, paragraph (b) is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>15.605</textblock>
    <textblock>Evaluation factors.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)(1) The evaluation factors that apply to an acquisition and the relative importance of those factors are within the broad discretion of agency acquisition officials except that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Price or cost to the Government shall be included as an evaluation factor in every source selection.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Past performance shall be evaluated in all competitively negotiated acquisitions expected to exceed $100,000, unless the contracting officer documents in the contract file the reasons why past performance should not be evaluated. Past performance may be evaluated in competitively negotiated acquisitions estimated at $100,000 or less at the discretion of the contracting officer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Quality shall be addressed in every source selection. In evaluation factors, quality may be expressed in terms of technical excellence, management capability, personnel qualifications, prior experience, and schedule compliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Any other relevant factors, such as cost realism, may also be included.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Section 15.608 is amended in the introductory text of paragraph (a) by removing the parenthetical phrase ``(as conveyed by the proposal)'', and by adding paragraph (a)(3) as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>15.608</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposal evaluation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)␣*␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Past performance evaluation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Past performance information should be used in assessing performance risk. The assessment of performance risk should consider the relative merits of the offeror's prior experience and performance as compared to that of other competing offerors. The number and severity of an offeror's problems, the effectiveness of corrective actions taken, the offeror's overall work record, and the age and relevance of past performance information should be considered at the time it is used.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Past performance information may be obtained from a variety of sources, including private firms. The source and type of past performance information to be included in the evaluation is within the broad discretion of agency acquisition officials and should be tailored to the circumstances of each procurement. Evaluations of contractor performance prepared in accordance with subpart 42.15 are one source of performance information which may be used.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) firms shall be allowed to compete for contracts even though they lack a history of relevant past performance.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 42_CONTRACT ADMINISTRATION</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Section 42.302 is amended by adding paragraph (b)(11) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>42.302</textblock>
    <textblock>Contract administration functions.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)␣*␣*␣*</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
