<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00064</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00032</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Potential applicants may obtain a copy of Healthy People 2000 (Full Report; Stock No. 017-001-00474-0) or Healthy People 2000 (Summary Report; Stock No. 017-001-00473-1) through the Superintendent of Documents, Government Printing Office, Washington, DC 20402-9325 (Telephone (202) 783-3238).</textblock>
    <textblock>Education and Service Linkage</textblock>
    <textblock>As part of its long-range planning, HRSA will be targeting its efforts to strengthening linkages between U.S. Public Health Service education programs and programs which provide comprehensive primary care services to the underserved.</textblock>
    <textblock>Review Criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>The review of applications will take into consideration the following criteria:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The degree to which the project plan adequately provides for meeting the requirements set forth in the regulations;</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The potential effectiveness of the project in carrying out the purposes of section 750 of the PHS Act and 42 CFR part 57, subparts H-I;</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The capability of the applicant to carry out the proposed project;</textblock>
    <textblock>4. The local, regional and national needs the project proposes to serve;</textblock>
    <textblock>5. The adequacy of the project's plan for placing graduates in health professional shortage areas;</textblock>
    <textblock>6. The soundness of the fiscal plan for assuring effective use of grant funds;</textblock>
    <textblock>7. The potential of the project to continue on a self-sustaining basis after the period of grant support; and</textblock>
    <textblock>8. The adequacy of the project's plan to develop and use methods designed to attract and maintain minority and disadvantaged students to train as</textblock>
    <textblock>physician assistants.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other Considerations</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, the following funding factors may be applied in determining the funding of approved applications:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Funding preference is defined as the funding of a specific category or group of applications ahead of other categories or groups of approved applications, such as competing continuation projects ahead of new projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Funding priority is defined as the favorable adjustment of aggregate review scores when applications meet specified objective criteria.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is not required that applicants request consideration for a funding factor. Applications which do not request consideration for a funding factor will be reviewed and given full consideration for funding.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
