<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00107</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(iv) In a limitation, suspension, or termination proceeding</textblock>
    <textblock>commenced on the grounds described in §668.15(b)(1), if the</textblock>
    <textblock>hearing official finds that an institution's Federal Stafford</textblock>
    <textblock>loan and Federal SLS cohort default rate, as defined in</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.15(f), meets the conditions specified in §668.15(b)(1) for</textblock>
    <textblock>initiation of limitation, suspension, or termination proceedings,</textblock>
    <textblock>the hearing official finds that the sanction sought by the</textblock>
    <textblock>designated department official is warranted, except that the</textblock>
    <textblock>hearing official finds that no sanction is warranted if the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution demonstrates that it has acted diligently to</textblock>
    <textblock>implement the default reduction measures described in Appendix D</textblock>
    <textblock>to this part;</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) In a termination action taken against an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>or third-party servicer based on the grounds that the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>or servicer failed to comply with the requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.23(c)(4), if the hearing official finds that the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>or servicer failed to meet those requirements, the hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>official finds that the termination is warranted;</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) In a termination action against an institution based</textblock>
    <textblock>on the grounds that the institution is not financially</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible under §668.13(c)(4), the hearing official finds that</textblock>
    <textblock>the termination is warranted unless the institution demonstrates</textblock>
    <textblock>that all applicable conditions described in §668.13(d)(3) have</textblock>
    <textblock>been met; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(vii) In a termination action against an institution or</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer on the grounds that the institution or</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, as applicable, engaged in fraud involving the</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of any Title IV, HEA program, the hearing official</textblock>
    <textblock>finds that the termination action is warranted if the hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>official finds that the institution or servicer, as applicable,</textblock>
    <textblock>engaged in that fraud. Examples of fraud include_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Falsification of any document received from a student</textblock>
    <textblock>or pertaining to a student's eligibility for assistance under a</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Falsification, including false certifications, of any</textblock>
    <textblock>document submitted by the institution or servicer to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education;</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Falsification, including false certifications, of any</textblock>
    <textblock>document used for or pertaining to_</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) The legal authority of an institution to provide</textblock>
    <textblock>postsecondary education in the State in which the institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>located; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) The accreditation or preaccreditation of an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>or any of the institution's educational programs or locations;</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) Falsification, including false certifications, of any</textblock>
    <textblock>document submitted to a guaranty agency under the Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Stafford Loan, Federal PLUS, and Federal SLS programs, an</textblock>
    <textblock>independent auditor, an eligible institution, or a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer;</textblock>
    <textblock>(E) Falsification of any document submitted to a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer by an institution or to an institution by a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer pertaining to the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in a Title IV, HEA program; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(F) Falsification, including false certifications, of any</textblock>
    <textblock>document pertaining to the performance of any loan collection</textblock>
    <textblock>activity, including activity that is not required by the HEA or</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable program regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The hearing official bases findings of fact only on</textblock>
    <textblock>evidence considered at the hearing and on matters given judicial</textblock>
    <textblock>notice. If a hearing is conducted solely through written</textblock>
    <textblock>submissions, the parties must agree to findings of fact.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)(1) In a suspension proceeding, the Secretary reviews</textblock>
    <textblock>the hearing official's initial decision and issues a final</textblock>
    <textblock>decision within 20 days after the initial decision. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary adopts the initial decision unless it is clearly</textblock>
    <textblock>unsupported by the evidence presented at the hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The Secretary notifies the institution or servicer and,</textblock>
    <textblock>in the case of a suspension proceeding against a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, each institution that contracts with the servicer of</textblock>
    <textblock>the final decision. If the Secretary suspends the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation or servicer's eligibility, the suspension takes</textblock>
    <textblock>effect on the later of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The day that the institution or servicer receives the</textblock>
    <textblock>notice; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The date specified in the designated department</textblock>
    <textblock>official's original notice of intent to suspend the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation or servicer's eligibility.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
