<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00121</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(d) If the presiding officer's initial decision would limit</textblock>
    <textblock>or terminate the lender's or servicer's eligibility, it does not</textblock>
    <textblock>take effect pending the appeal unless the Secretary determines</textblock>
    <textblock>that a stay of the date it becomes effective would seriously and</textblock>
    <textblock>adversely affect the FFEL programs or student or parent</textblock>
    <textblock>borrowers.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1080, 1082, 1085, 1094)</textblock>
    <textblock>48. Section 682.708 is amended by revising paragraph (b) to</textblock>
    <textblock>read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§682.708</textblock>
    <textblock>Evidence of mailing and receipt dates.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) If a lender or third-party servicer refuses to accept a</textblock>
    <textblock>notice mailed under this subpart, the Secretary considers the</textblock>
    <textblock>notice as being received on the date that the lender or servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>refuses to accept the notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1080, 1082, 1085, 1094)</textblock>
    <textblock>49. Section 682.709 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§682.709</textblock>
    <textblock>Reimbursements, refunds, and offsets.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) As part of a limitation or termination proceeding, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary, or a designated Departmental official, may require a</textblock>
    <textblock>lender or third-party servicer to take reasonable corrective</textblock>
    <textblock>action to remedy a violation of applicable laws, regulations,</textblock>
    <textblock>special arrangements, agreements, or limitations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The corrective action may include payment to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary or recipients designated by the Secretary of any funds,</textblock>
    <textblock>and any interest thereon, that the lender, or, in the case of a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer, the servicer or the lender that has a</textblock>
    <textblock>contract with a third-party servicer, improperly received,</textblock>
    <textblock>withheld, disbursed, or caused to be disbursed. A third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer may be held liable up to the amounts specified in</textblock>
    <textblock>§682.413(a)(2).</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) If a final decision requires a lender, a lender that</textblock>
    <textblock>has a contract with a third-party servicer, or a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer to reimburse or make any payment to the Secretary, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary may, without further notice or opportunity for a</textblock>
    <textblock>hearing, proceed to offset or arrange for another Federal agency</textblock>
    <textblock>to offset the amount due against any interest benefits, special</textblock>
    <textblock>allowance, or other payments due to the lender, the lender that</textblock>
    <textblock>has a contract with the third-party servicer, or the third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer. A third-party servicer may be held liable up to the</textblock>
    <textblock>amounts specified in §682.413(a)(2).</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1080, 1082, 1094)</textblock>
    <textblock>50. Section 682.710 is amended by revising paragraphs (a),</textblock>
    <textblock>(b), and (d) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§682.710</textblock>
    <textblock>Removal of limitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A lender or third-party servicer may request removal of</textblock>
    <textblock>a limitation imposed by the Secretary in accordance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations in this subpart at any time more than 12 months after</textblock>
    <textblock>the date the limitation becomes effective.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The request must be in writing and must show that the</textblock>
    <textblock>lender or servicer has corrected any violations on which the</textblock>
    <textblock>limitation was based.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)(1) If the Secretary denies the request or establishes</textblock>
    <textblock>other limitations, the lender or servicer, upon request, is given</textblock>
    <textblock>an opportunity to show why all limitations should be removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A lender or third-party servicer may continue to</textblock>
    <textblock>participate in the FFEL programs, subject to any limitation</textblock>
    <textblock>imposed by the Secretary under paragraph (c)(3) of this section,</textblock>
    <textblock>pending a decision by the Secretary on a request under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (d)(1) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1080, 1082, 1085, 1094)</textblock>
    <textblock>51. Section 682.711 is amended by revising paragraphs (a),</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)(1), (b)(2), (e), and the authority citation following the</textblock>
    <textblock>section to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§682.711</textblock>
    <textblock>Reinstatement after termination.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A lender or third-party servicer whose eligibility has</textblock>
    <textblock>been terminated by the Secretary in accordance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations in this subpart may request reinstatement of its</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility at any time more than 18 months after the date the</textblock>
    <textblock>termination becomes effective.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The lender or servicer has corrected any violations on</textblock>
    <textblock>which the termination was based; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The lender or servicer meets all requirements for</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)(1) If the Secretary denies the lender's or servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>request or allows reinstatement subject to limitations, the</textblock>
    <textblock>lender or servicer, upon request, is given an opportunity to show</textblock>
    <textblock>why its eligibility should be reinstated and all limitations</textblock>
    <textblock>removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A lender or third-party servicer whose eligibility to</textblock>
    <textblock>participate in the FFEL programs is reinstated subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>limitations imposed by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (d)(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section, may participate in those programs, subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>those limitations, pending a decision by the Secretary on a</textblock>
    <textblock>request under paragraph (e)(1) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1080, 1082, 1085, 1094)</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3422 Filed 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4000-01-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
