<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00120</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00066</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Documents Containing Reporting or Recordkeeping Requirements: Office of Management and Budget Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of the Office of Management and Budget review of information collection.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) has recently submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for review the following proposal for the collection of information under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. chapter 35).</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Type of submission, new, revision, or extension: Extension.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The title of the information collection: 10 CFR Part 60_Disposal of High-Level Radioactive Wastes in Geologic Repositories</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The form number if applicable: Not applicable.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. How often the collection is required: The information need only be submitted one time.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Who will be required or asked to report: States or Indian Tribes, or their representatives, requesting consultation with the NRC staff regarding review of a potential high-level waste repository site, or wishing to participate in a license review for a potential repository.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. An estimate of the annual number of responses: 8</textblock>
    <textblock>7. An estimate of the total number of hours needed annually to complete the requirement or request: An average of 40 hours per response for consultation requests, 80 hours per response for license review participation proposals, and 1 hour per response for statements of representative authority. The total burden for all responses is estimated to be 244 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. An indication of whether Section 3504(h), Public Law 96-511 applies: Not applicable.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Abstract: 10 CFR part 60 requires States and Indian Tribes to submit certain information to the NRC if they request consultation with the NRC staff concerning review of a potential repository site or wish to participate in a license review for a potential repository. Representatives of States or Indian Tribes must submit a statement of their authority to act in such representative capacity. The information submitted by the States and Indian Tribes is used by the director of the Office of Nuclear Material Safety and Safeguards as a basis for decisions about the commitment of NRC staff resources to the consultation and participation efforts.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the submittal may be inspected or obtained for a fee from the NRC Public Document Room, 2120 L Street, NW. (Lower Level), Washington, DC.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments and questions may be directed by mail to the OMB reviewer: Troy Hillier, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs (3150-0127), NEOB-3019, Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments may also be communicated by telephone at (202) 395-3084.</textblock>
    <textblock>The NRC Clearance officer is Brenda Jo. Shelton, (301) 492-8132.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated at Bethesda, Maryland, this 8th day of February 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Gerald F. Cranford,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Designated Senior Official for Information Resources Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3589 Filed 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7590-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
