<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00108</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(3) A suspension may not exceed 60 days unless a designated</textblock>
    <textblock>department official begins a limitation or termination proceeding</textblock>
    <textblock>under this subpart before the expiration of that period. In that</textblock>
    <textblock>case, the period may be extended until a final decision is issued</textblock>
    <textblock>in that proceeding according to paragraph (c) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)(1) In a fine, limitation, or termination proceeding,</textblock>
    <textblock>the hearing official's initial decision automatically becomes the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's final decision 30 days after the initial decision is</textblock>
    <textblock>issued and received by both parties unless, within that 30-day</textblock>
    <textblock>period, the institution or servicer, as applicable, or the</textblock>
    <textblock>designated department official appeals the initial decision to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)(i) A party may appeal the hearing official's initial</textblock>
    <textblock>decision by submitting to the Secretary, within 30 days after the</textblock>
    <textblock>party receives the initial decision, a brief or other written</textblock>
    <textblock>statement that explains why the party believes that the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>should reverse or modify the decision of the hearing official.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) At the time the party files its appeal submission, the</textblock>
    <textblock>party shall provide a copy of that submission to the opposing</textblock>
    <textblock>party.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The opposing party shall submit its brief or other</textblock>
    <textblock>responsive statement to the Secretary, with a copy to the</textblock>
    <textblock>appellant, within 30 days after the opposing party receives the</textblock>
    <textblock>appellant's brief or written statement.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The appealing party may submit proposed findings of</textblock>
    <textblock>fact or conclusions of law. However, the proposed findings of</textblock>
    <textblock>fact must be supported by_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The evidence introduced into the record at the hearing;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Stipulations of the parties if the hearing consisted of</textblock>
    <textblock>written submissions; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Matters that may be judicially noticed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) Neither party may introduce new evidence on appeal.</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) The initial decision of the hearing official imposing</textblock>
    <textblock>a fine or limiting or terminating the institution's participation</textblock>
    <textblock>or servicer's eligibility does not take effect pending the</textblock>
    <textblock>appeal.</textblock>
    <textblock>(vii) The Secretary renders a final decision. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary may delegate to a designated department official the</textblock>
    <textblock>functions described in paragraph (c)(2) (vii) through (ix) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(viii) In rendering a final decision, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>considers only evidence introduced into the record at the hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>and facts agreed to by the parties if the hearing consisted only</textblock>
    <textblock>of written submissions and matters that may be judicially</textblock>
    <textblock>noticed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ix) If the hearing official finds that a termination is</textblock>
    <textblock>warranted pursuant to paragraph (a)(3) of this section, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary affirms that decision. In any other case, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary may affirm, modify, or reverse the initial decision, or</textblock>
    <textblock>may remand the case to the hearing official for further</textblock>
    <textblock>proceedings consistent with the Secretary's decision. If the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary affirms the initial decision without issuing a</textblock>
    <textblock>statement of reasons, the Secretary adopts the opinion of the</textblock>
    <textblock>hearing official as the decision of the Secretary. If the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary modifies, remands, or reverses the initial decision, in</textblock>
    <textblock>whole or in part, the Secretary's decision states the reasons for</textblock>
    <textblock>the action taken.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1082, 1094)</textblock>
    <textblock>20. Section 668.91 is amended by revising the heading; and revising paragraphs (a)(1), (a)(2), (b) heading, (b)(1), (b)(2) introductory text, and (c) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.91</textblock>
    <textblock>Filing of requests for hearings and appeals;</textblock>
    <textblock>confirmation of mailing and receipt dates.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A request by an institution or third-party servicer for</textblock>
    <textblock>a hearing or show-cause opportunity, other material submitted by</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution or third-party servicer in response to a notice of</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed action under this subpart, or an appeal to the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>under this subpart must be filed with the designated department</textblock>
    <textblock>official by hand-delivery, mail, or facsimile transmission.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Documents filed by facsimile transmission must be</textblock>
    <textblock>transmitted to the designated department official identified,</textblock>
    <textblock>either in the notice initiating the action, or, for an appeal, in</textblock>
    <textblock>instructions provided by the hearing official, as the individual</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible to receive them. A party filing a document by</textblock>
    <textblock>facsimile transmission must confirm that a complete and legible</textblock>
    <textblock>copy of the document was received by the Department of Education,</textblock>
    <textblock>and may be required by the designated department official to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide a hard copy of the document.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Confirmation of mailing and receipt dates.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The</textblock>
    <textblock>mailing date of a notice from a designated department official</textblock>
    <textblock>initiating an action under this subpart is the date evidenced on</textblock>
    <textblock>the original receipt of mailing from the U.S. Postal Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The date on which a request for a show-cause</textblock>
    <textblock>opportunity, a request for a hearing, other material submitted in</textblock>
    <textblock>response to a notice of action under this subpart, a decision by</textblock>
    <textblock>a hearing official, or a notice of appeal is received is, as</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable_</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Refusals.</textblock>
    <textblock>If an institution or third-party servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>refuses to accept a notice mailed under this subpart, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary considers the notice as being received on the date that</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution or servicer refuses to accept the notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1094)</textblock>
    <textblock>21. Section 668.92 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.92</textblock>
    <textblock>Fines.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) In determining the amount of a fine, the designated</textblock>
    <textblock>department official, hearing official, and Secretary take into</textblock>
    <textblock>account_</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
