<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00064</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 4(a)(3) of the Act, as amended, requires that, to the</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum extent prudent and determinable, the Secretary propose</textblock>
    <textblock>critical habitat at the time the species is proposed to be</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered or threatened. The Service's listing regulations at 50</textblock>
    <textblock>CFR 424.12(a)(1) specify that designation of critical habitat is not</textblock>
    <textblock>prudent when such designation would not be beneficial to the</textblock>
    <textblock>species. The Service finds that designation of the springs occupied</textblock>
    <textblock>by the Barton Springs salamander as critical habitat would not be</textblock>
    <textblock>prudent because it would not provide a conservation benefit to the</textblock>
    <textblock>species, and would actually be detrimental to the species by</textblock>
    <textblock>suggesting a misleadingly restricted view of its true conservation</textblock>
    <textblock>needs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Designation of Barton Springs as critical habitat would not</textblock>
    <textblock>provide a conservation benefit to the Barton Springs salamander</textblock>
    <textblock>beyond benefits provided by listing and the subsequent evaluation of</textblock>
    <textblock>activities under section 7 of the Act for possible jeopardy to the</textblock>
    <textblock>species. In the Service's section 7 regulations at 50 CFR 402, the</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of ``jeopardize the continuing existence'' includes ``to</textblock>
    <textblock>reduce appreciably the likelihood of both the survival and recovery</textblock>
    <textblock>of the listed species,'' and ``adverse modification'' is defined as</textblock>
    <textblock>``a direct or indirect alteration that appreciably diminishes the</textblock>
    <textblock>value of critical habitat for both the survival and recovery of a</textblock>
    <textblock>listed species.'' Because the species is endemic to such a highly</textblock>
    <textblock>localized area, actions that appreciably diminish water quality and</textblock>
    <textblock>quantity at Barton Springs would be fully evaluated for their</textblock>
    <textblock>effects on the salamander through analysis of whether the actions</textblock>
    <textblock>would be likely to jeopardize the continuing existence of the</textblock>
    <textblock>species. Any action that would appreciably diminish the value, in</textblock>
    <textblock>quality or quantity, of flows from Barton Springs would also reduce</textblock>
    <textblock>appreciably the likelihood of survival and recovery of the Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs salamander. The analysis for possible jeopardy applied to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Barton Springs salamander would therefore be identical to the</textblock>
    <textblock>section 7 analysis for determining adverse modification or</textblock>
    <textblock>destruction of critical habitat; no distinction between jeopardy and</textblock>
    <textblock>adverse modification for activities impacting the waters of Barton</textblock>
    <textblock>Springs can be made at this time. Application of section 7 relative</textblock>
    <textblock>to critical habitat would therefore not add measurable protection to</textblock>
    <textblock>the species beyond what is achievable through review for jeopardy.</textblock>
    <textblock>Designation of the springs and their immediate environment as</textblock>
    <textblock>critical habitat would actually be detrimental to conservation</textblock>
    <textblock>efforts for the Barton Springs salamander, because it would promote</textblock>
    <textblock>the misconception that the Barton Springs are the only areas</textblock>
    <textblock>important to the conservation of the species. Conservation efforts</textblock>
    <textblock>for the species must address a wide variety of federally funded or</textblock>
    <textblock>authorized activities (summarized in the ``Available Conservation</textblock>
    <textblock>Measures'' section of this proposed rule) that affect the quality</textblock>
    <textblock>and quantity of water available to the species through their effects</textblock>
    <textblock>on the recharge sources and aquifer that supply water to the habitat</textblock>
    <textblock>of the salamander. Nearly all of these activities will occur beyond</textblock>
    <textblock>the immediate vicinity of Barton Springs, and some will occur</textblock>
    <textblock>several miles away. Designation of Barton Springs as critical</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat would be misleading in implying to federal agencies whose</textblock>
    <textblock>activities may affect the Barton Springs salamander that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Service's concern for the species is limited only to activities</textblock>
    <textblock>taking place at the springs occupied by the species. Designation of</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs as critical habitat would therefore not be prudent.</textblock>
    <textblock>Available Conservation Measures</textblock>
    <textblock>Conservation measures provided to species listed as endangered</textblock>
    <textblock>or threatened under the Act include recognition, recovery actions,</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for Federal protection, and prohibitions against</textblock>
    <textblock>certain practices. Recognition through listing encourages and</textblock>
    <textblock>results in conservation actions by Federal, State, and private</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies, groups, and individuals. The Act provides for possible</textblock>
    <textblock>land acquisition and cooperation with the States and requires that</textblock>
    <textblock>recovery actions be carried out for all listed species. The</textblock>
    <textblock>protection required of Federal agencies and the prohibitions against</textblock>
    <textblock>taking and harm are discussed, in part, below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Conservation and management of the Barton Springs salamander</textblock>
    <textblock>is likely to involve removing threats to the survival of the</textblock>
    <textblock>salamander, including (1) protecting the quality of springflow from</textblock>
    <textblock>Barton Springs by implementing comprehensive programs to control and</textblock>
    <textblock>reduce point sources and non-point sources of pollution throughout</textblock>
    <textblock>the Barton Springs segment of the Edwards Aquifer, (2) minimizing the</textblock>
    <textblock>likelihood of pollution events that would affect groundwater</textblock>
    <textblock>quality, (3) continuing to protect groundwater and springflow</textblock>
    <textblock>quantity by implementing water conservation and drought contingency</textblock>
    <textblock>plans throughout the Barton Springs segment, and (4) continuing to</textblock>
    <textblock>examine and implement pool cleaning practices and other park</textblock>
    <textblock>operations that protect and perpetuate the salamander's surface</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat and population. It is also anticipated that listing will</textblock>
    <textblock>encourage research on the Barton Springs salamander's distribution</textblock>
    <textblock>within the aquifer and critical aspects of its biology (e.g.,</textblock>
    <textblock>longevity, natality, sources of mortality, feeding ecology, and</textblock>
    <textblock>sensitivity to contaminants and other water quality constituents).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 7(a) of the Act, as amended, requires Federal agencies</textblock>
    <textblock>to evaluate their actions with respect to any species that is</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed or listed as endangered or threatened and with respect to</textblock>
    <textblock>its critical habitat, if any is being designated. Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>implementing this interagency cooperation provision of the Act are</textblock>
    <textblock>codified at 50 CFR part 402. Section 7(a)(4) requires Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies to confer with the Service on any action that is likely to</textblock>
    <textblock>jeopardize the continued existence of a species proposed for listing</textblock>
    <textblock>or result in destruction or adverse modification of proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>critical habitat. If a species is listed subsequently, section</textblock>
    <textblock>7(a)(2) requires Federal agencies to ensure that activities they</textblock>
    <textblock>authorize, fund, or carry out are not likely to jeopardize the</textblock>
    <textblock>continued existence of such a species or to destroy or adversely</textblock>
    <textblock>modify its critical habitat. If a Federal action may affect a</textblock>
    <textblock>listed species or its critical habitat, the responsible Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>agency must enter into formal consultation with the Service.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
