<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00128</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00073</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 10, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The above named national securities exchange has filed applications with the Securities and Exchange Commission (``Commission'') pursuant to section 12(f)(1)(B) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and Rule 12f-1 thereunder for unlisted trading privileges in the following securities:</textblock>
    <textblock>Grangers Exploration, Ltd.</textblock>
    <textblock>Common Stock, $.01 Par Value (File No. 7-11994)</textblock>
    <textblock>Playtex Products, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>Common Stock, $.01 Par Value (File No. 7-11995)</textblock>
    <textblock>Emerging Markets Infrastructure Fund</textblock>
    <textblock>Common Stock $.001 Par Value (File No. 7-11996)</textblock>
    <textblock>Aztar Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Common Stock, $.01 Par Value (File No. 7-11997)</textblock>
    <textblock>Alliance World Dollar Fund</textblock>
    <textblock>Common Stock, $.01 Par Value (File No. 7-11998)</textblock>
    <textblock>Blackrock 2001 Term Trust</textblock>
    <textblock>Common Stock, No Par Value (File No. 7-11999)</textblock>
    <textblock>Grupo Casa Autry S.A. de C.V.</textblock>
    <textblock>American Depositary Shares, No Par Value (File No. 7-12000)</textblock>
    <textblock>Grupo Mexicano de Desarrollo S.A. de C.V.</textblock>
    <textblock>American Depositary Shares, No Par Value (File No. 7-12001)</textblock>
    <textblock>J&amp;L Specialty Steel, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>Common Stock, $.01 Par Value (File No. 7-12002)</textblock>
    <textblock>These securities are listed and registered on one or more other national securities exchange and are reported in the consolidated transaction reporting system.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to submit on or before March 4, 1994, written data, views and arguments concerning the above-referenced application. Persons desiring to make written comments should file three copies thereof with the Secretary of the Securities and Exchange Commission, 450 5th Street, NW., Washington, DC 20549. Following this opportunity for hearing, the Commission will approve the application if it finds, based upon all the information available to it, that the extensions of unlisted trading privileges pursuant to such applications are consistent with the maintenance of fair and orderly markets and the protection of investors.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Commission, by the Division of Market Regulation, pursuant to delegated authority.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Self-Regulatory Organizations; Applications for Unlisted Trading Privileges; Notice and Opportunity for Hearing; Boston Stock Exchange, Inc.</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jonathan G. Katz,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3627 Filed 2-16-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
