<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00031</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(i) All elements of information for all transactions required to be maintained, except the time that the transaction was executed, before the close of business on the day specified in a request for such transaction information; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The time that each of such transactions were executed, within 15 calendar days after receipt of a specific request for such information.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)</textblock>
    <textblock>Unidentified large traders.</textblock>
    <textblock>With respect to transactions effected directly or indirectly by or through the account of a person that a registered broker or dealer knows or has reason to know is a large trader, all elements of information for all transactions required to be maintained and such person's name, address, date that the account was opened, and tax identification number(s) shall be reported.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Supervisory safe harbor.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the purposes of this section, a registered broker or dealer shall not be deemed to know or have reason to know that a person is a large trader if it establishes policies and procedures reasonably designed to assure compliance with the identification requirements of this section and does not have actual knowledge that a person is a large trader. Policies and procedures shall be deemed to satisfy this section, if they include:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Systems reasonably designed to detect and identify persons that have not complied with the identification requirements of this section, which such broker-dealer knows or has reason to know is a large trader, based upon transactions effected through an account or a group of accounts, that may be identified as a large trader, based on account name, tax identification number, or other information readily available to such broker-dealer; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Systems reasonably designed to inform large traders of their obligations to file Form 13H and disclose large trader status under this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Exemptions.</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Comprehensive.</textblock>
    <textblock>The identification, recordkeeping, and reporting requirements of this section shall not apply to any registered broker or dealer that does not carry accounts for itself or others, and:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Is registered as a specialist or option market maker by a national securities exchange;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Is a member or allied member of a national securities exchange that exclusively executes transactions on the floor of such national securities exchange; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Is registered as a market maker by a national securities association to the extent that it effects transactions in its capacity as a registered market maker.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Reporting requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>The reporting requirements of this section shall not apply to:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Transactions for the account of a specialist or option market maker registered by a national securities exchange, effected in its capacity as a registered specialist or option market maker;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Transactions for the account of a market maker registered by a national securities association, effected in its capacity as a registered market maker; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Any broker or dealer that does not carry accounts for itself or others.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Written requests.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission may, upon written application, exempt from the provisions of this section, either unconditionally or on specified terms and conditions, any person, large trader, broker or dealer, or class of transactions for which the Commission determines that application of this section is not necessary or appropriate in the public interest, for the protection of investors, or otherwise in furtherance of the purposes of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 249_FORMS, SECURITIES EXCHANGE ACT OF 1934</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The authority citation for part 249 continues to read in part as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78a,</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.,</textblock>
    <textblock>unless otherwise noted;</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>4. By adding ยง249.327 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง249.327</textblock>
    <textblock>Form 13H, information required of large traders pursuant to section 13(h) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and rules thereunder.</textblock>
    <textblock>This form shall be used by persons that are large traders required to furnish identifying information to the Commission pursuant to section 13(h)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (15 U.S.C. 78m(h)(1)) and Rule 13h-1(b)) thereunder (ยง240.13h-1(b) of this chapter).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 9, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix A will not appear in the Code of Federal Regulations.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEP17FE94.005</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEP17FE94.006</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEP17FE94.007</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEP17FE94.008</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEP17FE94.009</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEP17FE94.010</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEP17FE94.011</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEP17FE94.012</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEP17FE94.013</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEP17FE94.014</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEP17FE94.015</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEP17FE94.016</textblock>
  </import>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-C</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
