<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00085</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 668.94␣Termination.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add</textblock>
    <textblock>references to third-party servicers in this section to conform to</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed changes governing termination proceedings in other</textblock>
    <textblock>sections of this subpart. The Secretary proposes to specify that</textblock>
    <textblock>a termination of a third-party servicer's eligibility to contract</textblock>
    <textblock>with an institution to administer a Title IV, HEA program ends</textblock>
    <textblock>the authority of the servicer to administer that program under</textblock>
    <textblock>any existing contract between an institution and the servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, if a third-party servicer's eligibility is</textblock>
    <textblock>terminated, the servicer would be required to return to each</textblock>
    <textblock>institution (or otherwise dispose of according to the Secretary's</textblock>
    <textblock>instructions) any funds received by the servicer under that</textblock>
    <textblock>program for that institution or the institution's students. The</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer also would be required to return to the institution all</textblock>
    <textblock>records pertaining to the servicer's administration of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation in that program.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary believes that the termination of a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer's eligibility to contract with an institution should be</textblock>
    <textblock>treated like the termination of an institution's participation in</textblock>
    <textblock>a Title IV, HEA program. Not only should new contracts with an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution be prohibited, but the servicer's existing activities</textblock>
    <textblock>involving the administration of that program also should cease.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further, a third-party servicer may possess unexpended funds</textblock>
    <textblock>under that program for an institution's students at the time that</textblock>
    <textblock>termination takes effect. The servicer should be required to</textblock>
    <textblock>return those funds to the institution so that those students may</textblock>
    <textblock>receive their aid. The return of records to the institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>needed because of the recordkeeping requirements that the various</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program requirements that the various Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program regulations apply to institutions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.95␣Reimbursements, refunds, and offsets.</textblock>
    <textblock>This</textblock>
    <textblock>section would be amended to add references to third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicers to conform to the proposed changes in the scope of this</textblock>
    <textblock>subpart.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.96␣Reinstatement after termination.</textblock>
    <textblock>The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary proposes to add references to third-party servicers to</textblock>
    <textblock>conform to proposed changes in the scope of this subpart. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary also proposes to eliminate the provision that permits</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution to apply for reinstatement of its participation</textblock>
    <textblock>after three months if the institution's participation has been</textblock>
    <textblock>terminated for engaging in substantial misrepresentation. Like</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions whose participation is terminated for other</textblock>
    <textblock>violations, the institution would be able to apply for</textblock>
    <textblock>reinstatement only after 18 months from the date of the</textblock>
    <textblock>termination, unless the institution also was debarred or</textblock>
    <textblock>suspended under E.O. 12549 or the Federal Acquisition Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>(FAR), 48 CFR subpart 9.4. The Secretary further proposes to</textblock>
    <textblock>extend these criteria to apply to a termination of a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer's eligibility to contract with an institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>administer any aspect of the institution's participation in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs if the basis for that termination was</textblock>
    <textblock>engaging in substantial misrepresentation.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Title IV, HEA programs are most effective only if</textblock>
    <textblock>students, other members of the public, and governmental and other</textblock>
    <textblock>bodies can rely on the honesty of the representations of an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution or the institution's agents. The harm that</textblock>
    <textblock>substantial misrepresentation does to the integrity of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs, to those who rely on the programs to help</textblock>
    <textblock>meet educational costs, and to the taxpayers who pay for the</textblock>
    <textblock>programs should carry equal weight with the harm done by any</textblock>
    <textblock>other violation of a Title IV, HEA program requirement. If an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation or third-party servicer's eligibility</textblock>
    <textblock>is terminated because the institution or servicer engaged in</textblock>
    <textblock>substantial misrepresentation, the consequence of that</textblock>
    <textblock>termination should be no less than the consequence of a</textblock>
    <textblock>termination for other reasons.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.97␣Removal of limitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes to provide that an institution may not apply for removal</textblock>
    <textblock>of a limitation before the later of (1) 12 months from the</textblock>
    <textblock>effective date of the limitation, or (2) the expiration of a</textblock>
    <textblock>debarment or suspension under E.O. 12549 or the FAR, 48 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>subpart 9.4. Parallel to the requirement for institutions, a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer would be able to apply for removal of a</textblock>
    <textblock>limitation only after 12 months from the date of the limitation,</textblock>
    <textblock>unless the servicer was also debarred or suspended.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
