<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00028</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>V. Effects on Competition and Regulatory Flexibility Analysis</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 23(a) of the Exchange Act</textblock>
    <textblock>80</textblock>
    <textblock>requires that the Commission, when proposing rules under the Exchange Act, consider the effects on competition of such rules, if any, and balance any anti-competitive impact against the regulatory benefits gained in terms of furthering the purposes of the Exchange Act. The Commission is of the view that the Rule will not result in any burden on competition that is not necessary or appropriate in furtherance of the purposes of the Exchange Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the requirements of the Regulatory Flexibility Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>81</textblock>
    <textblock>the Commission previously prepared an Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis (``IRFA''), concerning the proposed rule. The IRFA indicated that the proposed rule may impose some additional costs on small broker-dealers, small investment advisers, and small investors. The Commission has prepared a revised IRFA that details the changes to the proposed rule found in the reproposed rule. The Commission believes that the reproposed rule has been structured in a manner that further minimizes the costs of the reproposed system and fulfills the requirements of the Market Reform Act and section 13(h) of the Exchange Act. A copy of the revised IRFA may be obtained from Cameron D. Smith, Staff Attorney, Division of Market Regulation, Securities and Exchange Commission, 450 Fifth Street NW., Washington, DC 20549, (202) 272-5418.</textblock>
    <textblock>VI. List of Subjects in 17 CFR Parts 240 and 249</textblock>
    <textblock>Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Securities.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the foregoing, title 17, chapter II of the Code of Federal Regulations is proposed to be amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 240_GENERAL RULES AND REGULATIONS, SECURITIES EXCHANGE ACT OF 1934</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 240 continues to read in part as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 77c, 77d, 77g, 77j, 77s, 77eee, 77ggg, 77nnn, 77sss, 77ttt, 78c, 78d, 78i, 78j, 78</textblock>
    <textblock>l</textblock>
    <textblock>, 78m, 78n, 78o, 78p, 78s, 78w, 78x, 78</textblock>
    <textblock>ll</textblock>
    <textblock>(d), 79q, 79t, 80a-20, 80a-23, 80a-29, 80a-37, 80b-3, 80b-4 and 80b-11, unless otherwise noted.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>2. By adding ยง240.13h-1 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง240.13h-1</textblock>
    <textblock>Large trader reporting system.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of this section_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The term</textblock>
    <textblock>large trader</textblock>
    <textblock>means every person who, for an account that he owns or controls, effects transactions for the purchase or sale of any publicly traded security or securities by use of any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce or of the mails, or of any facility of a national securities exchange, directly or indirectly by or through a registered broker or dealer in an aggregate amount equal to or in excess of the identifying activity level.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The term</textblock>
    <textblock>person</textblock>
    <textblock>shall mean those persons and entities specified in Section 3(a)(9) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, two or more persons acting as a partnership, limited partnership, syndicate, or other group, but does not include a foreign central bank, and also includes such persons, entities, partnerships, or groups acting as a trustee.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The term</textblock>
    <textblock>account</textblock>
    <textblock>or</textblock>
    <textblock>accounts</textblock>
    <textblock>means each proprietary and customer account maintained or carried by a registered broker or dealer, which is disclosed or undisclosed to such broker or dealer as to ownership, and for which books and records are required to be made and kept in accordance with the provisions of ยง240.17a-3.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>Ownership.</textblock>
    <textblock>An account of a person shall be deemed to be owned or under common ownership of the person in whose name an account is maintained, or a custodian or nominee that maintains an omnibus account or accounts otherwise undisclosed as to ownership, and any other person who has more than a 10 percent financial interest in the equity in the account or accounts of such person.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)</textblock>
    <textblock>Control.</textblock>
    <textblock>An account of a person shall be deemed to be controlled or under the common control of the owner of such account, and any other person that has received or been assigned full or limited investment discretion from the owner of such account. For purposes of this section:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The term</textblock>
    <textblock>full discretionary investment authority</textblock>
    <textblock>means the discretion to enter orders for an account owned by another person, for the purchase or sale of any publicly traded security or securities, of any size, and at any time or price, without prior instruction or approval of the owner of such account; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The term</textblock>
    <textblock>limited discretionary investment authority</textblock>
    <textblock>means the discretion to enter orders for an account owned by another person, for the purchase or sale of any publicly traded security or securities, limited only to the price or time of execution, upon the express prior instruction or approval of the owner of such account.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) The term</textblock>
    <textblock>publicly traded security</textblock>
    <textblock>means any equity security, option on an equity security, or an option on a group or index of equity securities (or based on the value thereof) listed, or admitted to unlisted trading privileges, on a national securities exchange and all other national market system securities as defined in ยง240.11Aa2-1.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78w(a) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>80</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>5 U.S.C. 604 (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>81</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
