<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00095</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(ii) The servicer shall have an audit performed at least</textblock>
    <textblock>once every year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Notwithstanding paragraph (c)(3)(ii) of this section,</textblock>
    <textblock>the servicer shall have an audit performed at least once every</textblock>
    <textblock>two years if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The servicer administers less than $1,000,000 under the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs for the period covered by the audit; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The servicer had no material exceptions identified in</textblock>
    <textblock>the servicer's most recently submitted audit report and that</textblock>
    <textblock>report was submitted in a timely fashion.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The servicer is not required to have an audit</textblock>
    <textblock>performed for any year in which the servicer administers less</textblock>
    <textblock>than $250,000 under the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) The servicer's first audit must cover the servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>activities for its first full fiscal year beginning after July 1,</textblock>
    <textblock>1994, and include any period from that date to the beginning of</textblock>
    <textblock>the first full fiscal year. Each subsequent audit that the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer has performed must cover the servicer's activities for</textblock>
    <textblock>the entire period of time since the servicer's preceding audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) Notwithstanding paragraph (c)(3)(iii) of this section,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary may, as the Secretary deems necessary, request any</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer to have an audit performed on an annual</textblock>
    <textblock>basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The servicer shall submit its audit to the Department</textblock>
    <textblock>of Education's Inspector General in accordance with the deadlines</textblock>
    <textblock>established in audit guides developed by the Department of</textblock>
    <textblock>Education's Office of Inspector General.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)(i) An institution or third-party servicer that has an</textblock>
    <textblock>audit conducted in accordance with this section shall_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Give the Secretary and the Inspector General access to</textblock>
    <textblock>records or other documents necessary to review the audit; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Include in any arrangement with an individual or firm</textblock>
    <textblock>conducting an audit described in this section a requirement that</textblock>
    <textblock>the individual or firm shall give the Secretary and the Inspector</textblock>
    <textblock>General access to records or other documents necessary to review</textblock>
    <textblock>the audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A third-party servicer shall give the Secretary and</textblock>
    <textblock>the Inspector General access to records or other documents</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to review an institution's audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) An institution shall give the Secretary and the</textblock>
    <textblock>Inspector General access to records or other documents necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>to review a third-party servicer's audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) The Secretary may require the institution or servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>to provide, upon request, to cognizant guaranty agencies and</textblock>
    <textblock>eligible lenders under the FFEL programs, State agencies,</textblock>
    <textblock>nationally recognized accrediting agencies, and State</textblock>
    <textblock>postsecondary review entities designated under Subpart 1 of</textblock>
    <textblock>part H of Title IV of the HEA, the results of any audit conducted</textblock>
    <textblock>under this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Upon written request, an institution or third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer shall give the Secretary access to all Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program and fiscal records, including records reflecting</textblock>
    <textblock>transactions with any financial institution with which the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution or servicer deposits or has deposited any</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1088, 1094, 1099c, 1141 and section 4 of</textblock>
    <textblock>Pub. L. 95-452, 92 Stat. 1101-1109)</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Section 668.24 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.24</textblock>
    <textblock>Audit exceptions and repayments.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)(1) If, as a result of a Federal audit or an audit</textblock>
    <textblock>performed at the direction of an institution or third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer, an expenditure made by the institution or servicer or</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution's or servicer's compliance with an applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement (including the lack of proper documentation), is</textblock>
    <textblock>questioned, the Secretary notifies the institution or servicer of</textblock>
    <textblock>the questioned expenditure or compliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If the institution or servicer believes that the</textblock>
    <textblock>questioned expenditure or compliance was proper, the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>or servicer shall notify the Secretary in writing of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's or servicer's position and the reasons for that</textblock>
    <textblock>position.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The institution's or servicer's response must be</textblock>
    <textblock>certified as to accuracy and completeness by an independent</textblock>
    <textblock>auditor in accordance with the general standards and the</textblock>
    <textblock>standards for audits in the U.S. General Accounting Office's</textblock>
    <textblock>(GAO's) Standards for Audit of Governmental Organizations,</textblock>
    <textblock>Programs, Activities, and Functions and must be received by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary within 45 days of the date of the Secretary's</textblock>
    <textblock>notification to the institution or servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)(1) Based on the audit finding and the institution's or</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer's response, the Secretary determines the</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of liability, if any, owed by the institution or servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>and instructs the institution or servicer as to the manner of</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If the Secretary determines that a third-party servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>owes a liability for its administration of an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs, the servicer shall notify each</textblock>
    <textblock>institution under whose contract the servicer owes a liability of</textblock>
    <textblock>the determination. The servicer shall also notify every</textblock>
    <textblock>institution that contracts with the servicer for the same service</textblock>
    <textblock>that the Secretary determined that a liability was owed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)(1) An institution or third-party servicer that must</textblock>
    <textblock>repay funds under the procedures in this section shall repay</textblock>
    <textblock>those funds at the direction of the Secretary within 45 days of</textblock>
    <textblock>the date of the Secretary's notification, unless_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The institution or servicer files an appeal under the</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures established in subpart H of this part; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The Secretary permits a longer repayment period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Notwithstanding paragraphs (b) and (c)(1) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section_</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
