<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00021</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the Delaware River Basin Commission will hold a public hearing on Wednesday, February 23, 1994. The hearing will be part of the Commission's regular business meeting which is open to the public and scheduled to begin at 1 p.m. in the Goddard Conference Room of the Commission's offices at 25 State Police Drive, West Trenton, New Jersey.</textblock>
    <textblock>An informal conference among the Commissioners and staff will be open for public observation at 9:30 a.m. at the same location and will include discussions concerning Basinwide hydrologic conditions; the Christina River drought management plan; Pennsylvania municipal compliance with DRBC water conservation plumbing fixture requirements and contracts to receive and expend funds in connection with the scenic rivers water quality monitoring program and a nonpoint source management study of the Musconetcong watershed.</textblock>
    <textblock>The subjects of the hearing will be as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications for Approval of the Following Projects Pursuant to Article 10.3, Article 11 and/or Section 3.8 of the Compact</textblock>
    <textblock>1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Merrill Creek Owners Group (MCOG) D-77-110 CP (Amendment 4).</textblock>
    <textblock>A Resolution to include an additional designated unit (Metropolitan Edison Company's Portland Unit 5, an oil/gas fueled combustion turbine electric generating unit) to the list of designated units which is incorporated in the MCOG docket. Table A (Revision 4), attached to the Resolution, replaces Table A (Revision 3).</textblock>
    <textblock>2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Carolyn R. Wilson D-83-4 RENEWAL.</textblock>
    <textblock>An application for the renewal of a ground water withdrawal project, formerly approved under the name of Edith Raughley, to supply up to 18.9 million gallons (mg)/30 days of water to the applicant's supplemental agricultural irrigation system from Well Nos. 1(Home Farm) and 2(Wilson Farm). Commission approval on June 27, 1984 was limited to nine years. The applicant requests that the total withdrawal from all wells remain limited to 18.9 mg/30 days. The project is located in Kent County, Delaware.</textblock>
    <textblock>3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Willingboro Municipal Utilities Authority D-87-42 CP RENEWAL.</textblock>
    <textblock>An application for the renewal of a ground water withdrawal project to supply up to 60.48 mg/30 days of water to the applicant's distribution system from Well No. 11. Commission approval on October 26, 1988 was limited to five years. The applicant requests that the total withdrawal from all wells remain limited to 300 mg/30 days. The project is located in Willingboro Township, Burlington County, New Jersey.</textblock>
    <textblock>4.</textblock>
    <textblock>City of Dover D-88-71 CP RENEWAL.</textblock>
    <textblock>An application for the renewal of a ground water withdrawal project to supply up to 300 mg/30 days of water to the applicant's distribution system from Well Nos. 1 through 14. Commission approval on December 14, 1988 was limited to five years. The applicant requests that the total withdrawal from all wells remain limited to 300 mg/30 days. The project is located in the City of Dover, Kent County, Delaware.</textblock>
    <textblock>5.</textblock>
    <textblock>Citgo Asphalt Refining Company D-91-34.</textblock>
    <textblock>A surface water withdrawal project for provision of up to 0.156 million gallons per day (mgd) of water for steam generation and other uses at the applicant's asphalt refining facility. The applicant proposes to withdraw water from Mantua Creek adjacent to the refinery located near the confluence of Mantua Creek with the Delaware River, in West Deptford Township, Gloucester County, New Jersey.</textblock>
    <textblock>6.</textblock>
    <textblock>Borough of Richland D-92-1 CP.</textblock>
    <textblock>An application for approval of a ground water withdrawal project to supply up to 1.3 mg/30 days of water to the applicant's distribution system from existing Well No. 5, and to retain the existing withdrawal limit from all wells of 5.2 mg/30 days. The project is located in Millcreek Township, Lebanon County, Pennsylvania.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DELAWARE RIVER BASIN COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Commission Meeting and Public Hearing</textblock>
  </doctitle>
</doc>
