<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00086</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>These changes are necessary to conform to the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>changes in the scope of this subpart. The Secretary would</textblock>
    <textblock>include the length of a debarment or suspension action as a</textblock>
    <textblock>criterion to apply for removal of a limitation to protect the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs, the beneficiaries of those programs, and</textblock>
    <textblock>the Federal Government from potential effects of doing business</textblock>
    <textblock>with irresponsible entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 668.111␣Scope and purpose, 668.112␣Definitions,</textblock>
    <textblock>668.113␣Request for review, 668.114␣Notification of hearing,</textblock>
    <textblock>and 668.116␣Hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add references</textblock>
    <textblock>to a third-party servicer to these sections to parallel</textblock>
    <textblock>institutional appeal procedures and thus establish procedures for</textblock>
    <textblock>a third-party servicer to appeal a final audit determination or</textblock>
    <textblock>final program review determination. The proposed procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>generally would be parallel to the procedures already established</textblock>
    <textblock>that govern appeals by an institution of a final audit</textblock>
    <textblock>determination or final program review determination. Under</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.116(e), the Secretary proposes to expand the types of</textblock>
    <textblock>evidence that an institution or servicer requesting review of the</textblock>
    <textblock>final audit or final program review determination may submit to a</textblock>
    <textblock>hearing official to include Department of Education program</textblock>
    <textblock>review reports and work papers for program reviews and</textblock>
    <textblock>institutional or servicer records and other materials (including</textblock>
    <textblock>records and other materials of institutions with which the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer has contracts) provided to the Department in response to</textblock>
    <textblock>a program review. The Secretary also proposes to notify all</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions with which a third-party servicer contracts of final</textblock>
    <textblock>audit report or final program review determinations. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes that an institution that contracts with a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer should be kept informed of any activities</textblock>
    <textblock>between the servicer and the Department that might affect the</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of the institution's participation in a Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.123␣Collection.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to</textblock>
    <textblock>modify this section to conform to the proposed changes to</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.24.</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 682_Federal Family Education Loan Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 682.200␣Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to</textblock>
    <textblock>amend the definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>lender</textblock>
    <textblock>to exclude from the definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>an ``eligible lender'' any lender that (1) is debarred or suspended</textblock>
    <textblock>under E.O. 12549 or the FAR, (2) has principals or affiliates so</textblock>
    <textblock>debarred or suspended, (3) is an affiliate of any person so</textblock>
    <textblock>debarred or suspended, or (4) employs to administer or assist in</textblock>
    <textblock>the administration of FFEL program funds any person so debarred</textblock>
    <textblock>or suspended. The effect of these proposed changes would be</textblock>
    <textblock>automatically to exclude a debarred or suspended lender from</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the FFEL programs for the duration of the</textblock>
    <textblock>debarment or suspension. A guaranty agency would thus be</textblock>
    <textblock>prohibited from guaranteeing a new loan made by the lender during</textblock>
    <textblock>this period.</textblock>
    <textblock>Like the proposed changes governing the standard of conduct</textblock>
    <textblock>of participating educational institutions and third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicers under 34 CFR 668.82, these changes are needed to</textblock>
    <textblock>establish appropriate safeguards to protect the integrity of the</textblock>
    <textblock>FFEL programs and the Federal financial interest if serious</textblock>
    <textblock>questions are raised about the honesty and lawfulness of the</textblock>
    <textblock>conduct of a lender's owners, officers, directors, management,</textblock>
    <textblock>employees, or affiliates whose duties involve the administration</textblock>
    <textblock>of or influence over the use of those funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to amend this section to expand on</textblock>
    <textblock>the statutory definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>in the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations to clarify its applicability in the FFEL programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under that definition, a third-party servicer is an individual or</textblock>
    <textblock>organization that contracts with a lender or guaranty agency to</textblock>
    <textblock>administer any aspect of the lender's or guaranty agency's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the FFEL programs, including any applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>function described in the definition of third-party servicer in</textblock>
    <textblock>34 CFR part 668. The Secretary believes that by including the</textblock>
    <textblock>statutory definition as well as a reference to the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of third-party servicer under 34 CFR part 668, that</textblock>
    <textblock>individuals or organizations that contract with a lender or</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency to administer any aspect of the lender's or</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency's participation in the FFEL programs will be able</textblock>
    <textblock>to determine the applicability of these regulations to</textblock>
    <textblock>themselves.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 682.401␣Basic Program Agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes to revise this section of the regulations to clarify a</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency's responsibilities if it enters into a contract</textblock>
    <textblock>with a third-party servicer. As discussed previously under</textblock>
    <textblock>§682.200, the Secretary proposes to prohibit a guaranty agency</textblock>
    <textblock>from entering into a contract with a third-party servicer that</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary has determined is not financially responsible or</textblock>
    <textblock>has been determined by the Secretary to have not complied with</textblock>
    <textblock>the statutes and regulations that govern the FFEL programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under this proposed provision, a guaranty agency would be</textblock>
    <textblock>required to provide to the Secretary the names and addresses of</textblock>
    <textblock>any third-party servicer with which the agency contracts and, if</textblock>
    <textblock>requested by the Secretary, a copy of that contract. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary is proposing to require submission by the agency of the</textblock>
    <textblock>name and address of any third-party servicer with which the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency contracts, and, upon request, the contract, to assist the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary in carrying out his responsibilities to monitor the</textblock>
    <textblock>performance of third-party servicers.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
