<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00033</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-2-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of the Deputy Secretary</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Contract Reform Team: Notice of Availability of the Report of the Contract Reform Team</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Energy (DOE).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Contract Reform Team, which was established last year by the Secretary of Energy to conduct a comprehensive review of the Department's contracting practices, has completed its work and provided its recommendations to the Secretary. This notice announces the availability of the Report of the Contract Reform Team (Report) and requests the views of the public on the recommendations contained in the Report. The Department will proceed with implementation of the recommendations following an opportunity to consider the views of DOE employees and the public on the Report's recommendations.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES AND ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the Report may be purchased from the Superintendent of Documents, U.S. Government Printing Office. The publication's number is 061-000-00801-2, and its cost is $11.00. Telephone orders should be directed to: Superintendent of Documents, U.S. Government Printing Office, Washington, DC 20402, (202) 783-3238, FAX (202) 512-2233, Monday through Friday between the hours of 8 a.m. and 4 p.m., eastern time. Mail orders should be directed to: U.S. Government Printing Office, P.O. Box 371954, Pittsburgh, PA 15250-7954.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Report also is available for inspection in DOE Public Reading Rooms at Headquarters and in the eight Operations Offices. The locations and telephone numbers of these Reading Rooms are:</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Department of Energy, Public Reading Room, room 1G-051, 1000 Independence Avenue SW, Washington, DC 20585, (202) 586-6020, Attn: Denise Diggin</textblock>
    <textblock>Albuquerque</textblock>
    <textblock>National Atomic Museum, 20358 Wyoming Boulevard SE, Kirkland Air Force Base, NM 87117, (505) 845-4378, Attn: Diane Zepeda</textblock>
    <textblock>Chicago</textblock>
    <textblock>Chicago Operations Office, Public Reading Room, 9800 South Cass Avenue, Argonne, IL 60439, (708) 252-2010, Attn: Joan L. Redding</textblock>
    <textblock>Idaho</textblock>
    <textblock>Idaho Operations Office, Public Reading Room, 1776 Science Center Drive, Idaho Falls, ID 83415, (208) 526-1144, Attn: Gail Wilmore</textblock>
    <textblock>Nevada</textblock>
    <textblock>Nevada Operations Office, Public Reading Room, 2753 South Highland Drive, Las Vegas, NV 89109, (702) 295-1459, Attn: Charlotte Santilli</textblock>
    <textblock>Oak Ridge</textblock>
    <textblock>Oak Ridge Operations Office, Public Reading Room, Federal Building, 200 Administration Road, Oak Ridge, TN 37830, (615) 576-1216, Attn: Jane Greenwalt</textblock>
    <textblock>Richland</textblock>
    <textblock>Richland Operations Office, Public Reading Room, room 130 West, 100 Sprout Road, Richland, WA 99352, (509) 376-8583, Attn: Terri Traub</textblock>
    <textblock>Oakland</textblock>
    <textblock>Oakland Operations Office, 1301 Clay Street, Oakland, CA 94612, (510) 637-1794, Attn: Lauren McNair</textblock>
    <textblock>Savannah River</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Department of Energy, Public Reading Room, University of South Carolina-Aiken, 171 University Parkway, Second Floor Library, Aiken, SC 29801, (803) 725-2889, Attn: James M. Gaver.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments on the Report should be sent to: The Office of the Deputy Secretary, Attention: Contract Reform Team, U.S. Department of Energy, Forrestal Building, 1000 Independence Avenue SW, room 7B-252, Washington, DC 20585. Comments must be received no later than March 21, 1994 and should not exceed ten double-spaced, single-sided typed pages. To facilitate review, an original and two copies of the comments should be provided.</textblock>
  </date>
</doc>
