<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940217-0-00019</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940217-0-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Airworthiness Directives; Fokker Model F28 Mark 0100 Series Airplanes</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 39</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93-NM-107-AD; Amendment 39-8824; AD 94-04-06]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This amendment adopts a new airworthiness directive (AD), applicable to certain Fokker Model F28 Mark 0100 series airplanes, that requires replacement of the existing ground/flight microswitches located in the main landing gear with improved microswitches, and installation of an anti-skid system ON/OFF switch in the flight compartment. This amendment is prompted by an incident involving loss of braking, which was caused by mechanical ground/flight microswitches that froze while in the flight position. The actions specified by this AD are intended to prevent loss of braking below 40 miles per hour, when the anti-skid system is activated.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective March 21, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The incorporation by reference of certain publications listed in the regulations is approved by the Director of the Federal Register as of March 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The service information referenced in this AD may be obtained from Fokker Aircraft USA, Inc., 1199 North Fairfax Street, Alexandria, Virginia 22314. This information may be examined at the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), Transport Airplane Directorate, Rules Docket, 1601 Lind Avenue, SW., Renton, Washington; or at the Office of the Federal Register, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., suite 700, Washington, DC.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Timothy Dulin, Aerospace Engineer, Standardization Branch, ANM-113, FAA, Transport Airplane Directorate, 1601 Lind Avenue, SW., Renton, Washington 98055-4056; telephone (206) 227-2141; fax (206) 227-1320.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>A proposal to amend part 39 of the Federal Aviation Regulations to include an airworthiness directive (AD) that is applicable to certain Fokker Model F28 Mark 0100 series airplanes was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on September 1, 1993 (58 FR 46139). That action proposed to require replacement of the existing left- and right-hand ground/flight microswitches with new, improved microswitches at the MLG downlock, temperature sensor, and anti-skid harness positions. The proposed rule would also require installation of an anti-skid system ON/OFF switch in the flight compartment, for certain airplanes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons have been afforded an opportunity to participate in the making of this amendment. Due consideration has been given to the comments received.</textblock>
    <textblock>One commenter supports the proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Air Transport Association (ATA) of America, on behalf of one of its members, requests withdrawal of the proposal. The commenter notes that the proposed replacement and installation has already been accomplished on all 14 airplanes affected by this proposal in the U.S.-registered fleet. Therefore, the commenter does not believe that an AD is necessary. The commenter also asserts that issuance of the proposal would only add to an administrative paperwork burden. The FAA does not agree. Issuance of this AD is necessary to ensure accomplishment of the requirements on any affected airplane currently of foreign registry that is purchased by a U.S. operator and placed on the U.S. register in the future. The FAA has determined that issuance of this AD should only result in a minor administrative burden, since the required actions have already been accomplished.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
