<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00096</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(A) A guaranty agency shall notify the Secretary immediately</textblock>
    <textblock>whenever it becomes aware of reliable information indicating a</textblock>
    <textblock>participating school may have closed. The designated agency in</textblock>
    <textblock>the state in which the school is located shall promptly</textblock>
    <textblock>investigate whether the school has closed, and whether a</textblock>
    <textblock>teach-out of the closed school's program was made available to</textblock>
    <textblock>students, and report the results of its investigation to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary no later than 30 days after receiving the information.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) If a guaranty agency determines (or is informed by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary) that a participating school has closed, it shall,</textblock>
    <textblock>within 30 days of making that determination or being informed by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary, notify all lenders participating in its program to</textblock>
    <textblock>suspend collection efforts against individuals with respect to</textblock>
    <textblock>loans made for attendance at the closed school, if the student to</textblock>
    <textblock>whom (or on whose behalf) a loan was made was enrolled at the</textblock>
    <textblock>school on the closing date or withdrew not more than 90 days</textblock>
    <textblock>prior to the date the school closed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Within 30 days after receiving notice from the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>that a school has closed, a guaranty agency shall review its</textblock>
    <textblock>records of loans that it holds and identify all borrowers (or</textblock>
    <textblock>students) who appear to have been enrolled at the closed school</textblock>
    <textblock>on the closing date or who withdrew not more than 90 days prior</textblock>
    <textblock>to the date the school closed. If the guaranty agency knows the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower's address, it shall, within 30 days after identifying a</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower under paragraph (d) of this section, mail a discharge</textblock>
    <textblock>application and an explanation of the information that must be</textblock>
    <textblock>included in the sworn statement (which may be combined) to the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower. The application shall inform the borrower of the</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures and eligibility criteria for obtaining a discharge.</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) If the guaranty agency determines that a borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>identified in paragraph (d)(6)(ii)(C) of this section does not</textblock>
    <textblock>qualify for a discharge, the agency shall notify the borrower in</textblock>
    <textblock>writing of that determination and the reasons for it within 30</textblock>
    <textblock>days after receiving the borrower's completed application and</textblock>
    <textblock>sworn statement.</textblock>
    <textblock>(E) A borrower's request for discharge may not be denied</textblock>
    <textblock>solely on the basis of failing to meet any time limits set by the</textblock>
    <textblock>lender, guaranty agency, or the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Lender responsibilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) If the lender is notified</textblock>
    <textblock>by a guaranty agency or the Secretary, or receives information it</textblock>
    <textblock>believes to be reliable from another source indicating that the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower may be eligible for a loan cancellation under paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) of this section, the lender shall immediately suspend any</textblock>
    <textblock>efforts to collect from the borrower on any loan received for the</textblock>
    <textblock>program of study for which the loan was made (but may continue to</textblock>
    <textblock>receive borrower payments), and, within 30 days of receiving the</textblock>
    <textblock>information or notification, inform the borrower of the</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures for requesting a discharge.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) If the borrower fails to submit the written request and</textblock>
    <textblock>sworn statement described in paragraph (d)(3) of this section</textblock>
    <textblock>within 60 days of being notified of that option, the lender shall</textblock>
    <textblock>resume collection and shall be deemed to have exercised</textblock>
    <textblock>forbearance of payment of principal and interest from the date</textblock>
    <textblock>the lender suspended collection activity. The lender may</textblock>
    <textblock>capitalize, in accordance with 682.202(b), any interest accrued</textblock>
    <textblock>and not paid during that period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The lender shall file a closed school claim with the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency in accordance with ยง682.402(g) no later than 60</textblock>
    <textblock>days after the lender receives the borrower's written request and</textblock>
    <textblock>sworn statement described in paragraph (d)(3) of this section. If</textblock>
    <textblock>a lender receives a payment made by or on behalf of the borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>on the loan after the lender files a claim on the loan with the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency, the lender shall forward the payment to the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency within 30 days of its receipt. The lender shall</textblock>
    <textblock>assist the guaranty agency and the borrower in determining</textblock>
    <textblock>whether the borrower is eligible for discharge of the loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Within 30 days after receiving reimbursement from the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency for a closed school claim, the lender shall</textblock>
    <textblock>notify the borrower that the loan obligation has been discharged,</textblock>
    <textblock>and request that all credit bureaus to which it previously</textblock>
    <textblock>reported the status of the loan delete all adverse credit history</textblock>
    <textblock>assigned to the loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>False certification by a school of a student's</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility to borrow.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>General.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary reimburses the</textblock>
    <textblock>holder of a loan received by a borrower on or after January 1,</textblock>
    <textblock>1986, and discharges the borrower's obligation with respect to</textblock>
    <textblock>the loan in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (e) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section, if the borrower's (or the student for whom a parent</textblock>
    <textblock>received a PLUS loan) eligibility to receive the loan was falsely</textblock>
    <textblock>certified by an eligible school. For purposes of a false</textblock>
    <textblock>certification discharge, the term ``borrower'' includes all</textblock>
    <textblock>endorsers on a loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Relief available pursuant to discharge.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Discharge</textblock>
    <textblock>under paragraph (e) of this section relieves the borrower of an</textblock>
    <textblock>existing obligation to repay the loan and any charges imposed or</textblock>
    <textblock>costs incurred by the holder with respect to the loan that the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower is otherwise obligated to pay.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A discharge of a loan under paragraph (e) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section qualifies the borrower for reimbursement of amounts paid</textblock>
    <textblock>voluntarily or through enforced collection on a loan obligation</textblock>
    <textblock>discharged under paragraph (e) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) A borrower who has defaulted on a loan discharged</textblock>
    <textblock>under paragraph (e) of this section is not regarded as in default</textblock>
    <textblock>on the loan after discharge, and is eligible to receive</textblock>
    <textblock>assistance under the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) A discharge of a loan under paragraph (e) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section is reported by the loan holder to all credit reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies to which the holder previously reported the status of</textblock>
    <textblock>the loan, so as to delete all adverse credit history assigned to</textblock>
    <textblock>the loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Borrower eligibility for discharge.</textblock>
    <textblock>A borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>qualifies for discharge of a loan under paragraph (e) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section if the borrower submits to the holder of the loan a</textblock>
    <textblock>written request and a sworn statement. The statement need not be</textblock>
    <textblock>notarized, but must be made by the borrower under penalty of</textblock>
    <textblock>perjury, and, in the statement, the borrower shall state_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Whether the student has made a claim with respect to the</textblock>
    <textblock>school's false certification with any third party, such as the</textblock>
    <textblock>holder of a performance bond or a tuition recovery program, and</textblock>
    <textblock>if so, the amount of any payment received by the borrower (or</textblock>
    <textblock>student) or credited to the borrower's loan obligation;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) That the borrower (or the student for whom a parent</textblock>
    <textblock>received a PLUS loan)_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Received the proceeds of a loan on or after January 1,</textblock>
    <textblock>1986 to attend a school;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Was admitted to that school on the basis of ability to</textblock>
    <textblock>benefit from its training and did not meet the applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for admission on the basis of ability to benefit as</textblock>
    <textblock>described in paragraph (e)(8) of this section;</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Was certified by the school on the application for the</textblock>
    <textblock>loan as an eligible student; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) Withdrew from the school and did not find employment in</textblock>
    <textblock>the occupation for which the program was intended to provide</textblock>
    <textblock>training, or completed the training program for which the loan</textblock>
    <textblock>was made and made a reasonable attempt to obtain employment in</textblock>
    <textblock>the occupation for which the program was intended to provide</textblock>
    <textblock>training, and_</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) Was not able to find employment in that occupation; or</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
