<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00098</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00065</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>H. A. Hooks-855; A-879.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-879 described as follows: Beginning at the Northwest corner of A-879; Thence, Easterly 300 feet along the North line of A-879; Thence Southeasterly, approximately 1100 feet, along the westerly gradient boundary of said Village Creek; Thence, Westerly, 100 feet, along the North line of the M. M. Bradley survey, A-7; Thence, Southerly, 4200 feet, along the east line of said A-879; Thence, Southerly, approximately 4000 feet, along the westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>58</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 700 feet, along the South line of said A-879; Thence, N. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○18</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W., 1000 feet; Thence, along the Westerly line of said A-879 the following 4 courses: 1. N. 82</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>’58</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 800 feet; 2. N. 07</textblock>
    <textblock>○04</textblock>
    <textblock>02</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 56 feet; 3. N. 82</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>58</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 108 feet; 4. N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○02</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 6600 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the South line of A-879, at a point which lies N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>58</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2000 feet from the Northwest corner of the D. C. Montgomery survey, A-39; Thence, Northeasterly, approximately 4000 feet, along the easterly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, Southerly, 2800 feet, along the East line of said A-879; Thence, S. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>58</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1100 feet, along the South line of said A-879, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>W. Weiss-9; A-634.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-634 described as follows: Beginning on the East line of said A-634 at a point which lies S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○02</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 3800 feet from the Northeast corner of A-634; Thence, along the easterly line of A-634, the following 4 courses: 1. S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○02</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2800 feet; 2. S. 82</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>58</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 107 feet; 3. S. 07</textblock>
    <textblock>○04</textblock>
    <textblock>02</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 56 feet; 4. S. 82</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>58</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 800 feet; Thence, N. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○18</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1500 feet; Thence, N. 30</textblock>
    <textblock>○19</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1700 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning at the Northeast corner of A-634; Thence, S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○02</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1500 feet, along the East line of A-634; Thence, N. 51</textblock>
    <textblock>○34</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2350 feet; Thence, N. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○47</textblock>
    <textblock>33</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1762 feet, along the North line of A-634, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>M. M. Bradley; A-7.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-7 described as follows: Beginning at the Northwest corner of A-7; Thence, East, 100 feet along the North line of A-7, Thence, Southeasterly and Southwesterly approximately 5000 feet along the westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, Northerly 4200 feet along the east line of A-7 to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the South line of said A-7, at a point which lies N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>58</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 3100 feet from the Northwest corner of the D. C. Montgomery survey, A-39; Thence, Northerly, 2800 feet, along the West line of said A-7; Thence, Northeasterly, approximately 1000 feet, along the easterly, gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, N. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○06</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 900 feet, Thence, S. 18</textblock>
    <textblock>○46</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2900 feet; Thence, S. 36</textblock>
    <textblock>○02</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 969.16 feet; Thence, S. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>58</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 600 feet, along the south line of A-7, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>A. E. Spellenberg-35; A-459.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of said A-459 described as follows: Beginning on the North line of said A-459, at a point which lies N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○20</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2600 feet from the Northwest corner of said A-459; Thence, N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○20</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1950 feet, along the North line of said A-459; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 2000 feet, along the westerly gradient boundary of said Village Creek; Thence, S. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○47</textblock>
    <textblock>33</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2050 feet, along the South line of said A-459; Thence, N. 51</textblock>
    <textblock>○34</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2000 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>A. E. Spellenberg-36; A-458.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of said A-458 described as follows: Beginning on the North line of said A-458 at a point which lies N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○20</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2550 feet from the Northwest corner of said A-458; Thence, N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○20</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1800 feet, along the North line of said A-458; Thence, Southwesterly, Northerly and Southeasterly, approximately 4500 feet, along the westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○20</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1950 feet, along the South line of said A-458; Thence, N. 51</textblock>
    <textblock>○34</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2325 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>F. McCafferty-38; A-397.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
