<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00100</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(h)</textblock>
    <textblock>Payment of death, disability, closed school, false</textblock>
    <textblock>certification, and bankruptcy claims by the guaranty agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) In the case of a closed school claim, the guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agency shall document its determination that the student was</textblock>
    <textblock>unable to complete the educational program as a result of the</textblock>
    <textblock>school's closure. On the same date that it pays a closed school</textblock>
    <textblock>claim to the lender, the agency shall pay the borrower an amount</textblock>
    <textblock>equal to the amount paid on the loan by or on behalf of the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower, less any school tuition refunds or payments received by</textblock>
    <textblock>the holder or the borrower from a tuition recovery fund,</textblock>
    <textblock>performance bond, or other third-party source.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) In the case of a false certification claim, the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency shall document its determination that the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower is eligible for cancellation under paragraph (e) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section. On the same date that it pays a false certification</textblock>
    <textblock>claim to the lender, the agency shall pay the borrower an amount</textblock>
    <textblock>equal to the amount paid on the loan by or on behalf of the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower, less any school tuition refunds or payments received by</textblock>
    <textblock>the holder or the borrower from a tuition recovery fund,</textblock>
    <textblock>performance bond, or other third-party source.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The amount of loss payable on a closed school claim or</textblock>
    <textblock>on a false certification claim is equal to the sum of the</textblock>
    <textblock>remaining principal balance and interest accrued on the loan,</textblock>
    <textblock>collection costs incurred by the lender and applied to the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower's account within 30 days of the date those costs were</textblock>
    <textblock>actually incurred, and unpaid interest determined in accordance</textblock>
    <textblock>with paragraph (h)(3) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) During the period before the claim is filed, not to</textblock>
    <textblock>exceed the period provided for in paragraph (g)(2) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section for filing the claim.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) During a period not to exceed 30 days following the</textblock>
    <textblock>receipt date by the lender of a claim returned by the guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agency for additional documentation necessary for the claim to be</textblock>
    <textblock>approved by the guaranty agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Response by a guaranty agency to plans proposed under</textblock>
    <textblock>Chapters 11, 12, and 13.</textblock>
    <textblock>The guaranty agency shall take the</textblock>
    <textblock>following actions when a petition for relief in bankruptcy under</textblock>
    <textblock>Chapters 11, 12, or 13 is filed:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The agency shall monitor the debtor's performance under</textblock>
    <textblock>a confirmed plan. If the debtor fails to make payments required</textblock>
    <textblock>under the plan or seeks but does not demonstrate entitlement to</textblock>
    <textblock>discharge under 11 U.S.C. 1328(b), the agency shall oppose any</textblock>
    <textblock>requested discharge or move to dismiss the case if the costs of</textblock>
    <textblock>litigation together with the costs incurred for objections to the</textblock>
    <textblock>plan are not reasonably expected to exceed one-third of the</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of the loan to be discharged under the plan.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
