<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00085</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In general, participants at the regional meetings and the</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiations recognized that grounds for cancellation of a loan</textblock>
    <textblock>obligation under section 437 of the HEA should include a case</textblock>
    <textblock>where a student was unable to obtain employment after attending</textblock>
    <textblock>the school, and the school had falsely certified that the student</textblock>
    <textblock>had the ability to benefit from the school's training. This kind</textblock>
    <textblock>of falsification is both part of the loan certification process</textblock>
    <textblock>and results in a student being left without needed skills.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, the proposed regulations focus on the school's false</textblock>
    <textblock>representation that the student had the ability to benefit as the</textblock>
    <textblock>grounds for cancellation under this new provision.</textblock>
    <textblock>The statute and regulations have addressed the ability-to-benefit requirement for many years, and the proposed regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>reflect both the legal elements of that requirement and some</textblock>
    <textblock>enforcement perspectives developed in implementing it. For</textblock>
    <textblock>example, the school has always been required to test the ability</textblock>
    <textblock>to benefit only of those applicants who did not have a high</textblock>
    <textblock>school diploma, and the school therefore does not certify</textblock>
    <textblock>anything regarding the ability to benefit of high school</textblock>
    <textblock>graduates. Since 1987, students who had a general education</textblock>
    <textblock>diploma, or obtained one after enrolling, and students who lacked</textblock>
    <textblock>both a GED and a high school diploma but completed an</textblock>
    <textblock>institutionally prescribed remedial education program, have been</textblock>
    <textblock>deemed by Congress to have the ability to benefit, and the rule</textblock>
    <textblock>would incorporate that congressional judgement.</textblock>
    <textblock>The regulations therefore would generally permit relief in</textblock>
    <textblock>the case of a student whom the school was required to test for</textblock>
    <textblock>ability to benefit, but either failed to test at all, or tested</textblock>
    <textblock>in disregard of the requirements for proper use of the test</textblock>
    <textblock>adopted. Schools have a continuing legal obligation to</textblock>
    <textblock>administer tests, subject to criteria developed by the school's</textblock>
    <textblock>accreditor, in compliance with test protocols. These criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>and protocols may include requirements related both to the</textblock>
    <textblock>accuracy of the test results as to the individual tested and to</textblock>
    <textblock>the continuing development and validation of the test mechanism.</textblock>
    <textblock>Non-compliance with testing requirements may warrant</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative sanctions against the school, but a false</textblock>
    <textblock>certification claim under this provision requires the Department</textblock>
    <textblock>to determine a different question.</textblock>
    <textblock>A false certification claim depends not on whether the</textblock>
    <textblock>school met all its obligations with regard to testing, but on</textblock>
    <textblock>whether a test already given lacks credibility as a measure of</textblock>
    <textblock>the student's ability to benefit so that the Department should,</textblock>
    <textblock>in the absence of other evidence, regard the student as lacking</textblock>
    <textblock>that ability. The Secretary expects that practical, specific</textblock>
    <textblock>standards will be needed to help identify those deviations from</textblock>
    <textblock>testing requirements that support an inference that the student</textblock>
    <textblock>lacked ability to benefit. For example, use of photocopied</textblock>
    <textblock>versions of tests by the school or test administrator may violate</textblock>
    <textblock>the requirements of the test publisher, but may have no direct</textblock>
    <textblock>effect on the accuracy of the assessment of the student's ability</textblock>
    <textblock>to benefit. Use of an indefensibly low cutoff score by the</textblock>
    <textblock>school on an ability-to-benefit test does not discredit an</textblock>
    <textblock>assessment of the ability of those students who score above a</textblock>
    <textblock>legitimate cutoff score, such as those now published by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary. Similarly, minor deviations from required time limits</textblock>
    <textblock>may have little effect on the validity of the test results. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary intends to address these practical considerations in</textblock>
    <textblock>the final regulations, and invites public comment on the content</textblock>
    <textblock>of those standards or guidelines.</textblock>
    <textblock>In applying these standards, moreover, the Secretary has</textblock>
    <textblock>consistently recognized that a student may actually have the</textblock>
    <textblock>ability to benefit from the school's training even though the</textblock>
    <textblock>school does not test that student's ability or does so</textblock>
    <textblock>improperly. The proposed regulations therefore recognize that a</textblock>
    <textblock>student who actually obtains employment in the occupation for</textblock>
    <textblock>which the school's program was designed to prepare him or her had</textblock>
    <textblock>the actual ability to benefit from that training without regard</textblock>
    <textblock>to whether the school falsified its test of ability to benefit.</textblock>
    <textblock>A student not properly tested for ability to benefit who</textblock>
    <textblock>nevertheless completes the program of instruction can reasonably</textblock>
    <textblock>be considered to have found the training consistent with his or</textblock>
    <textblock>her aptitude, and the proposed regulations would provide for</textblock>
    <textblock>cancellation only if the a student had unsuccessfully tried to</textblock>
    <textblock>find employment in the occupation for which the program was</textblock>
    <textblock>designed to prepare him or her. Conversely, a student not</textblock>
    <textblock>properly tested who withdraws from the course can be reasonably</textblock>
    <textblock>regarded as having found the training not consistent with his or</textblock>
    <textblock>her aptitude, and the proposed regulations grant relief to this</textblock>
    <textblock>kind of student (or a parent PLUS borrower who borrowed on behalf</textblock>
    <textblock>of the student) unless the student actually obtained employment</textblock>
    <textblock>in that occupation.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
