<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00086</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Consistent with the approach that the student's ability to</textblock>
    <textblock>benefit should be evaluated realistically, the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations would recognize that those individuals admitted on</textblock>
    <textblock>the basis of their ability to benefit who met one or more of the</textblock>
    <textblock>several statutory requirements would nevertheless be regarded as</textblock>
    <textblock>not having had that ability if they had a physical, mental, or</textblock>
    <textblock>personal impediment to employment in, or performance of the</textblock>
    <textblock>physical duties of, the occupation for which the program was</textblock>
    <textblock>designed. Individuals with certain kinds of criminal records or</textblock>
    <textblock>a history of mental illness may be barred from some positions for</textblock>
    <textblock>which the school proposed to train them, and these students could</textblock>
    <textblock>not benefit from the training even if they successfully completed</textblock>
    <textblock>a test sanctioned by both the industry and school's accrediting</textblock>
    <textblock>agency. Other students may lack the physical ability to perform</textblock>
    <textblock>a job for which their grades on an industry and accreditor-approved test might otherwise show an ability to perform. Both</textblock>
    <textblock>kinds of students would qualify (or qualify the parent PLUS</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower) for relief under these regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>A number of other kinds of falsification were considered as</textblock>
    <textblock>potential grounds for discharge of the loan under this provision,</textblock>
    <textblock>including a school's acceptance of a student into an ineligible</textblock>
    <textblock>program, but they were not adopted in these proposed regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>As explained earlier, the statute uses fairly precise language to</textblock>
    <textblock>describe the grounds for discharge under this provision, and that</textblock>
    <textblock>language, by authorizing discharge where there has been a false</textblock>
    <textblock>certification ``by the eligible institution,'' does not authorize</textblock>
    <textblock>relief where the falsity relates to the eligibility of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution itself. Thus, although misrepresentations regarding</textblock>
    <textblock>the school's financial or administrative capability, including</textblock>
    <textblock>the school's placement services or the quality of the school's</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities, faculty, or equipment, may well have induced the</textblock>
    <textblock>individual to enroll at the school, those representations are not</textblock>
    <textblock>part of the process of ``certification'' of the student's</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility to borrow, tend to constitute claims that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution was in fact not an ``eligible institution,'' and are</textblock>
    <textblock>not the kind of representations for which this statute authorizes</textblock>
    <textblock>relief. These proposed regulations therefore do not treat</textblock>
    <textblock>falsifications by the institution about itself as grounds for</textblock>
    <textblock>discharge.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the vocational schools that are the primary focus of</textblock>
    <textblock>this statutory provision, representations about the eligibility</textblock>
    <textblock>of the institution include representations about the eligibility</textblock>
    <textblock>of its programs, and, under the statute and regulations, the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution is virtually defined in terms of the programs it</textblock>
    <textblock>offers. 20 U.S.C. 1088 (1992); 34 CFR 600.7, 668.7(a)(2)(v).</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, because the statute confines relief precisely to</textblock>
    <textblock>instances of false certifications regarding the eligibility of</textblock>
    <textblock>the student, not on representations that would tend to show that</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution itself was not eligible, the Secretary does not</textblock>
    <textblock>believe that the statute authorizes relief where the alleged</textblock>
    <textblock>misrepresentation goes to the eligibility of the program in which</textblock>
    <textblock>the student was enrolled. For these reasons, relief under the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations would not permit a borrower to secure</textblock>
    <textblock>cancellation by challenging the eligibility of the program or the</textblock>
    <textblock>school itself, but would require a demonstration by the student</textblock>
    <textblock>that the school failed to test (or tested improperly) his or her</textblock>
    <textblock>ability to benefit and that he or she did not secure employment</textblock>
    <textblock>in the occupation for which the school stated its program was</textblock>
    <textblock>designed to prepare the student.</textblock>
    <textblock>Bankruptcy Claims</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 437(a) of the HEA as amended by the Higher Education</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendments of 1992 allowed a lender to submit and receive payment</textblock>
    <textblock>on a bankruptcy claim on the date on which the borrower filed for</textblock>
    <textblock>relief in bankruptcy, an action that ``stays collection'' of the</textblock>
    <textblock>loan, rather than when the loan was discharged, as under prior</textblock>
    <textblock>law. The proposed regulations submitted to the negotiation</textblock>
    <textblock>process would have revised current regulations as needed to</textblock>
    <textblock>implement this change. Other features of current bankruptcy</textblock>
    <textblock>claim processing were to remain unchanged. Section 2(c)(63) of</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Law 103-208 reinstated standards for payment of bankruptcy</textblock>
    <textblock>claims consistent with those now found in FFEL Program</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations at 34 CFR 682.402(d)(5); pursuant to section 5 of</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Law 103-208, this most recent change took effect as if</textblock>
    <textblock>enacted as part of the 1992 amendments. Any regulations needed</textblock>
    <textblock>to implement this change, moreover, are not subject to negotiated</textblock>
    <textblock>rulemaking requirements of section 492. To implement the new law,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary is here withdrawing those proposals found in 34 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>682.402(f)(5) and (g)(2) (iv) and (v) as presented to the</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiators prior to the enactment of Public Law 103-208, and will</textblock>
    <textblock>leave in effect the provisions of current 34 CFR 682.402(d)(5),</textblock>
    <textblock>redesignated here as ยง682.402(g)(5), and current</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง682.402(e)(2)(ii), redesignated here as ยง682.402(g)(2)(iv).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
