<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00111</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00065</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the South line of said A-701 at a point which lies N. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 520.29 feet from the Southeast corner of said A-701; Thence, N. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 750 feet along the South line of said A-701; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 1100 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the South line of said A-701 at a point which lies N. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2120.29 feet, from the Southeast corner of said A-701; Thence, N. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 500 feet, along the South line of said A-701; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 900 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the South line of said A-701 at a point which lies N. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 3270.29 feet from the Southeast corner of said A-701; Thence, N. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 350 feet, along the South line of said A-701; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 800 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Andreas Morales; A-52.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-52 described as follows: Beginning on the Southeasterly line of said A-52 at a point which lies S. 67</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 4400 feet from the Easterly most corner of said A-52; Thence N. 54</textblock>
    <textblock>○24</textblock>
    <textblock>31</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 848.66 feet, along the North right-of-way line of Farm Road 943; Thence, N. 23</textblock>
    <textblock>○49</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 700 feet; Thence, N. 05</textblock>
    <textblock>○25</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2300 feet; Thence, N. 39</textblock>
    <textblock>○32</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2700 feet; Thence, N. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○56</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1540 feet; Thence, N. 63</textblock>
    <textblock>○10</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 625 feet; Thence, S. 65</textblock>
    <textblock>○25</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 175 feet; Thence, N. 24</textblock>
    <textblock>○35</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1350 feet; Thence, S. 63</textblock>
    <textblock>○43</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2050 feet; Thence, N. 52</textblock>
    <textblock>○51</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2600 feet; Thence, S. 63</textblock>
    <textblock>○14</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1825 feet; Thence, N. 63</textblock>
    <textblock>○23</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1925 feet, along the North right-of-way line of Farm Road 943; Thence, N. 59</textblock>
    <textblock>○53</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 3250 feet, along the North right-of-way line of Farm Road 943; Thence, N. 65</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 3700 feet along the Northwesterly line of said A-52; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 21,000 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek; Thence, S. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 350 feet along the Northeasterly line of said A-52; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 900 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek; Thence, S. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 500 feet along the Northeasterly line of said A-52; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 1000 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek; Thence, S. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 750 feet, along the Northeasterly line of said A-52; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 500 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek; Thence, S. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 50.29 feet, along the Northeasterly line of said A-52; Thence, southeasterly, approximately 8100 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek; Thence, S. 67</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1800 feet, along the southerly line of said A-52, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning at the most Northerly corner of said A-52; Thence, S. 27</textblock>
    <textblock>○46</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2100 feet; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 2500 feet, along the northerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek; Thence, N. 65</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 3000 feet along the Northwesterly line of said A-52, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the Northeasterly line of A-52 at a point which lies N. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W., 9000 feet; from the most Easterly corner of said A-52; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 900 feet, along the northerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek; Thence, S. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 450 feet, along the Northeasterly line of said A-52, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the Northeasterly line of said A-52 at a point which lies N. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W., 7650 feet; from the most Easterly corner of said A-52; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 1000 feet, along the northerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek; Thence, S. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 650 feet, along the Northeasterly line of A-52, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the Northeasterly line of said A-52 at a point which lies N. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W., 6530 feet; from the most Easterly corner of said A-52; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 500 feet, along the northerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek; Thence, S. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 170 feet, along the Northeasterly line of said A-52, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning at the most Easterly corner of said A-52; Thence, S. 67</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W., 2600 feet, along the Southerly line of said A-52; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 8000 feet, along the Northerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek; Thence, S. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 6279.71 feet, along the Northeasterly line of said A-52, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
