<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00061</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Small Entity Impact</textblock>
    <textblock>In compliance with the Regulatory Flexibility Act, the agencies have evaluated the effects of this action on small entities. Based on the evaluation, we certify that this rule will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities. States will be recipients of any funds awarded under the regulation and, accordingly, the preparation of a Regulatory Flexibility Analysis is unnecessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Impacts</textblock>
    <textblock>The agencies have also analyzed this action for the purpose of the National Environmental Policy Act. The agencies have determined that this action would not have any effect on the human environment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federalism Assessment</textblock>
    <textblock>This action has been analyzed in accordance with the principles and criteria contained in Executive Order 12612 and it has been determined that it has no federalism implication that warrants the preparation of a federalism assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The requirement relating to this proposal, that each State must submit a highway safety plan to receive section 402 grant funds, is considered to be an information collection requirement, as that term is defined by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) in 5 CFR part 1320. Accordingly, these requirements have been submitted to and approved by OMB, pursuant to the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. 3501</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>). These requirements have been approved through 11/30/95; OMB No. 2127-0501. This NPRM would establish no new information collection requirement, as that term is defined by the OMB in 5 CFR part 1320.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 23 CFR Part 1205</textblock>
    <textblock>Grant programs, Highway safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>In consideration of the foregoing, the agencies propose to amend 23 CFR part 1205 as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 1205_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 1205 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>23 U.S.C. 402; delegations of authority at 49 CFR 1.48 and 1.50.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. In §1205.3, paragraph (a)(7) is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§1205.3</textblock>
    <textblock>Identification of National Priority Program Areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Speed enforcement.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued on January 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rodney E. Slater,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator, Federal Highway Administration.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Howard M. Smolkin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Executive Director, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-445 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-59-P-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
