<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00077</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>§75.563</textblock>
    <textblock>Restricted indirect cost rate_programs covered.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a grantee decides to charge indirect costs to a program that has a statutory requirement prohibiting the use of Federal funds to supplant non-Federal funds, the grantee shall use a restricted indirect cost rate computed under 34 CFR 76.564-76.569.</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>20 U.S.C. 1221e-3(a)(1) and 3474)</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Sections 75.564 through 75.568 are removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. A new §75.564 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§75.564</textblock>
    <textblock>Reimbursement of indirect costs.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Reimbursement of indirect costs is subject to the availability of funds and statutory or administrative restrictions. The extent to which indirect costs are reimbursed is a matter for determination between the Secretary and the grantee.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The application of the rates and the determination of the direct cost base by a grantee must be in accordance with the indirect cost rate agreement approved by the grantee's cognizant Federal agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Indirect cost reimbursement is not allowable under grants for_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Fellowships and similar awards if Federal financing is exclusively in the form of fixed amounts such as scholarships, stipend allowances, or the tuition and fees of an institution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Construction grants;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Grants to individuals;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Grants to organizations located outside the territorial limits of the United States;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Grants to Federal organizations; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Grants in support of conferences.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Indirect cost reimbursement on grants received under programs with statutory restrictions or other limitations on indirect costs must be made in accordance with the restrictions in 34 CFR 76.564-76.569.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Under programs with matching or cost-sharing requirements, indirect costs that are unallowable as charges to Federal funds may not be used to satisfy matching or cost-sharing requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) Indirect costs for a group of eligible parties (see §§75.127-75.129) are limited to the amount derived by applying the rate of the applicant, or a restricted rate when applicable, to the grant in keeping with the terms of the applicant's indirect cost rate agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>20 U.S.C. 1221e-3(a)(1) and 3474)</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 76_STATE-ADMINISTERED PROGRAMS</textblock>
    <textblock>9. The authority citation for part 76 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>20 U.S.C. 1221e-3(a)(1), 2831(a), 2974(b), and 3474, unless otherwise noted.</textblock>
    <textblock>10. Section 76.560 is amended by revising paragraph (b), adding new paragraphs (c) and (d), and revising the authority citation at the end of the section, to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§76.560</textblock>
    <textblock>General indirect cost rates; exceptions.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) A grantee must have a current indirect cost rate agreement to charge indirect costs to a grant. To obtain an indirect cost rate, a grantee must submit an indirect cost proposal to the cognizant Federal agency and negotiate an indirect cost rate agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The Secretary may establish a temporary indirect cost rate for a grantee that does not have an indirect cost rate agreement with its cognizant Federal agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) The Secretary accepts an indirect cost rate negotiated by a grantee's cognizant Federal agency, but may establish a restricted indirect cost rate for a grantee to satisfy the statutory requirements of certain programs administered by the Department.</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>20 U.S.C. 1221e-3(a)(1), 2831(a), 2974(b), and 3474)</textblock>
    <textblock>11. Section 76.563 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§76.563</textblock>
    <textblock>Restricted indirect cost rate_programs covered.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 76.564-76.569 apply to agencies of State and local governments, and their subgrantees, that are grantees under programs with a statutory requirement prohibiting the use of Federal funds to supplant non-Federal funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>20 U.S.C. 1221e(a)(1), 2831(a), 2974(b), and 3474)</textblock>
    <textblock>12. A new §76.564 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§76.564</textblock>
    <textblock>Restricted indirect cost rate_formula.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) An indirect cost rate for a grant covered by §76.563 or 34 CFR 75.563 is determined by the following formula:</textblock>
    <textblock>Restricted indirect cost rate=(General management costs + Fixed costs)</textblock>
    <textblock>(Other expenditures)</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) General management costs, fixed costs, and other expenditures must be determined under §§76.565-76.567.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Under the programs covered by §76.563, a subgrantee of an agency of a State or a local government (as those terms are defined in 34 CFR 80.3) or a grantee subject to 34 CFR 75.563 that is not a State or local government agency may use_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) An indirect cost rate computed under paragraph (a) of this section; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) An indirect cost rate of eight percent unless the Secretary determines that the subgrantee or grantee would have a lower rate under paragraph (a) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Indirect costs that are unrecovered as a result of these restrictions may not be charged directly or be charged to another Federal award.</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>20 U.S.C. 1221e-3(a)(1), 2831(a), 2974(b), and 3474)</textblock>
    <textblock>13. A new §76.565 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§76.565</textblock>
    <textblock>General management costs_restricted rate.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) As used in §76.564,</textblock>
    <textblock>general management costs</textblock>
    <textblock>means the costs of activities that are for the direction and control of the grantee's affairs that are organization-wide. The term organization-wide does not include divisional administration or other activities that are limited to one activity, one component of the grantee, one subject, one phase of operations, or other single responsibility.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
