<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00100</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00065</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the Northerly right-of-way line of Texas State Highway No. 327 at a point which lies S. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○21</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 150 feet; N. 66</textblock>
    <textblock>○14</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2000 feet; S. 44</textblock>
    <textblock>○39</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1000 feet; S. 05</textblock>
    <textblock>○03</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 500 feet; S. 71</textblock>
    <textblock>○40</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1550 feet; N. 84</textblock>
    <textblock>○52</textblock>
    <textblock>22</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 7450 feet from the Southeast corner of said A-35; Thence, N. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○21</textblock>
    <textblock>W. 1300 feet; Thence, S. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○44</textblock>
    <textblock>W. 3750 feet; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○52</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2600 feet; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 13,500 feet along the westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 66</textblock>
    <textblock>○14</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1200 feet, along the North right-of-way line of Texas State Highway 327, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Jacob Hall; A-31.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of said A-31 described as follows: Beginning on the North line of said A-31 at a point which lies N. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2800 feet from the Northwest corner of said A-31; Thence, N. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 400 feet, along the North line of said A-31; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 15,500 feet, along the westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 950 feet, along the South line of said A-31; Thence, N. 05</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 850 feet; Thence, N. 29</textblock>
    <textblock>○21</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 900 feet; Thence, N. 07</textblock>
    <textblock>○46</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 550 feet; Thence, N. 41</textblock>
    <textblock>○02</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 900 feet; Thence, N. 26</textblock>
    <textblock>○10</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1750 feet; Thence, N. 00</textblock>
    <textblock>○14</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1100 feet; Thence, N. 10</textblock>
    <textblock>○31</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1650 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the South line of said A-31 at a point which lies N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2750 feet from the Northwest corner of the L. De Lesslie Survey, A-35; Thence, Easterly, approximately 2600 feet, along the Southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1700 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Henry Binns; A-6.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of said A-6 described as follows: Beginning on the South line of said A-6 at a point which lies N. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 5850 feet from the Southwest corner of said A-6; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○10</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1125 feet; Thence, S. 85</textblock>
    <textblock>○46</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 600 feet, along the South right-of-way line of the A.T. and S.F. Railroad; Thence, Southerly, approximately 2000 feet, along the westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 500 feet, along the south line of said A-6, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning at a point of intersection of the Westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek with the North right-of-way line of A. T. and S. F. Railroad which lies N. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 5850 feet; N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○10</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1125 feet; S. 85</textblock>
    <textblock>○46</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 600 feet and N. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○14</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 400 feet from the Southwest corner of said A-6; Thence, N. 85</textblock>
    <textblock>○46</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 600 feet; Thence, N. 01</textblock>
    <textblock>○09</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1800 feet; Thence, N. 11</textblock>
    <textblock>○57</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1750 feet; Thence, 1400.85 feet; Thence, N. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○15</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1400 feet, along the South right-of-way line of Farm Road 418; Thence, Southerly, approximately 10,000 feet, along the westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the North line of said A-6 at a point which lies N. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○42</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 4300 feet from the Northwest corner of A-6; Thence, N. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○42</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2100 feet, along the North line of A-6; Thence, Southerly, approximately 1000 feet, along the westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence S. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○51</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2300 feet, along the North right-of-way line of Farm Road 418; Thence, S. 73</textblock>
    <textblock>○47</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 400 feet, continuing along said North right-of-way line; Thence, N. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○23</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 600 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the North line of said A-6 at a point which lies N. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○42</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 6550 feet, from the Northwest corner of A-6; Thence, N. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○42</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 766 feet; Thence, S. 32</textblock>
    <textblock>○14</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 693 feet; Thence, S. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○51</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 500 feet, along the Northerly right-of-way line of Farm Road 418; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 1000 feet, along the easterly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Hampton; A-30.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of said A-30 described as follows: Beginning on the North line of said A-30 at a point which lies N. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>29</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 5400 feet, from the Northwest corner of said A-30; Thence, N. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>29</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1300 feet, along the North line of said A-30; Thence, Southwesterly, approximately 14,000 feet along the westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○42</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1100 feet; Thence, N. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○23</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1500 feet; Thence, N. 16</textblock>
    <textblock>○22</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1306.04 feet; Thence, N. 41</textblock>
    <textblock>○32</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1500 feet; Thence, N. 68</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1100 feet; Thence, N. 11</textblock>
    <textblock>○23</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2000 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the South line of A-30 at a point which lies N. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○42</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 5600 feet from the Northwest corner of the Henry Binns survey, A-6; Thence, N. 05</textblock>
    <textblock>○20</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 900 feet; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 1500 feet, along the westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○42</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 800 feet, along the South line of said A-30, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
