<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00174</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00102</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>2. Effluent discharges are prohibited during periods when new water is allowed to enter the plant site. Additionally, there shall be no discharge as a result of the intake of new water.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Hydraulic Removal of Overburden</textblock>
    <textblock>During the term of this permit, no wastewater discharges are authorized except as specified below.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Effluent Limitations. a. The volume of wastewater which may be discharged shall not exceed the volume of infiltration, drainage and mine drainage waters which is in excess of the make-up water required for operation of the hydraulicking process.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. The wastewater discharged shall not exceed the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Effluent discharges are prohibited during periods when new water is allowed to enter the plant site. Additionally, there shall be no discharge as a result of the intake of new water.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Suction Dredging</textblock>
    <textblock>1. At any point in the receiving stream 500 feet downstream of the dredge's discharge point, the maximum allowable increase in turbidity over the natural receiving stream turbidity while operating is 5 NTUs.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. A visual increase in turbidity (any cloudiness or muddiness) 500 feet downstream of the suction dredge during operations would be considered a violation of the 5 NTU limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. If noticeable turbidity does occur 500 feet downstream of the work site, operation of the suction dredge must decrease or cease so that a violation as defined above does not exist.</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Monitoring Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Mechanical Operations and Hydraulic Removal of Overburden. a. During the period beginning on the effective date of this permit and lasting until the expiration date, the following monitoring shall be conducted:</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Visual Inspection. The Permittee shall institute a comprehensive visual inspection program to facilitate proper operation and maintenance of the recycle system and the wastewater treatment system. The Permittee shall conduct an inspection of the site once per day during the mining season. The Permittee shall maintain records of all information resulting from any visual inspections. These records shall include, but are not limited to, an evaluation of the condition of all water control devices such as diversion structures and berms and all solids retention structures such as berms, dikes, pond structures, and dams. The records shall also include an assessment of the presence of sediment buildup within the settling ponds. The Permittee shall examine all ponds for the occurrence of short circuiting.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Turbidity Monitoring. The Permittee shall monitor the turbidity values of the effluent stream and the background turbidity values of the receiving stream then compare the two samples. The sample results shall be reported on the Annual Discharge Monitoring Report (DMR). The Permittee shall take one sample at a point that is representative of the discharge prior to entering the receiving stream. The Permittee shall take another sample above the discharge point at a location that is considered to be the ``natural'' background of the receiving stream as defined in permit part V.I. Both samples shall be taken within a reasonable time frame. Monitoring shall be conducted in accordance with accepted analytical procedures. See attachment 1 for sampling protocol.</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Arsenic Monitoring. Arsenic samples shall be representative of the discharge and shall be taken at a point prior to entering the receiving stream. Arsenic samples taken to determine ``natural'' background shall be representative of the receiving water upstream from any man-made disturbances. Monitoring shall be conducted in accordance with accepted analytical procedures. The Permittee shall report the sample results on the Annual DMR. See attachment 2 for sampling protocol.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Effluent characteristic</textblock>
    <textblock>1Instantaneous maximum</textblock>
    <textblock>Settleable Solids</textblock>
    <textblock>0.2 ml/L.</textblock>
    <textblock>Turbidity</textblock>
    <textblock>5 NTU above natural background.</textblock>
    <textblock>Arsenic, Total Recoverable</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) 0.18 μg/L</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) natural background.*</textblock>
    <textblock>*See Part II.D.4. for details.</textblock>
  </table>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Effluent characteristic</textblock>
    <textblock>1Monitoring location</textblock>
    <textblock>1Monitoring frequency</textblock>
    <textblock>1Sample type</textblock>
    <textblock>Settleable Solids (ml/L)</textblock>
    <textblock>Effluent</textblock>
    <textblock>Once per day each day of discharge</textblock>
    <textblock>Grab.</textblock>
    <textblock>Turbidity (NTU)</textblock>
    <textblock>Effluent natural background</textblock>
    <textblock>Once per season</textblock>
    <textblock>Grab.</textblock>
    <textblock>Arsenic (μg/L) Total recoverable</textblock>
    <textblock>Effluent natural background*</textblock>
    <textblock>Once per season</textblock>
    <textblock>Grab.**</textblock>
    <textblock>Flow (gpm)</textblock>
    <textblock>Effluent</textblock>
    <textblock>(***)</textblock>
    <textblock>Instantaneous.</textblock>
    <textblock>*Only when choosing Option (2).</textblock>
    <textblock>**Analyzed by EPA Method 206.2 with a detection limit of 1 μg/L.</textblock>
    <textblock>***See Part II.D.1.f. for details.</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
