<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00133</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00081</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Penetrators, Inc., Midland and Houston, Texas; Negative Determination on Reconsideration</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 13, 1993, the Department issued an Affirmative Determination Regarding Application for Reconsideration for workers and former workers of the subject firm. This notice was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 27, 1993 (58 FR 68440).</textblock>
    <textblock>The former workers stated that the workers produced crude oil and natural gas and should be certified.</textblock>
    <textblock>New findings on reconsideration show that the workers perform downhole drilling and stimulation services to rejuvenate new and existing oil wells. These services are provided to unaffiliated production firms in the oil and gas industry. The predominate portion of their services is performed on old wells. Only a small portion of their work is performed on new wells. Accordingly, the workers do not meet the on-site requirements for drilling exploration services necessary for a worker group certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further, the price of oil is not a worker group eligibility criterion for certification under the Trade Act of 1974. Accordingly, a decline in the price of crude oil, in itself, would not form a basis for a worker group certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Trade Act was not intended to provide TAA benefits to everyone who is in some way affected by increased imports but only to those who experienced a decline in sales or production and employment and an increase in imports of like or directly competitive products which contributed importantly to declines in sales or production and employment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Conclusion</textblock>
    <textblock>After reconsideration, I affirm the original notice of negative determination of eligibility to apply for adjustment assistance to workers and former workers of Penetrators, Inc., in Midland, Texas and Houston, Texas.</textblock>
    <textblock>Signed at Washington, DC, this 4th day of January 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Employment and Training Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[TA-W-29,065, TA-W-29,066]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Robert O. Deslongchamps,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Legislation &amp; Actuarial Services, Unemployment Insurance Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-990 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4510-30-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
