<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00053</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department appreciates the difficulties of enforcing the</textblock>
    <textblock>standards when multiple zones exist in a single State. Accordingly, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department has specifically listed those local governments in the higher wind</textblock>
    <textblock>zones in each State. Depending on the facts surrounding the sale of a</textblock>
    <textblock>manufactured home, both the manufacturer and the dealer will be responsible</textblock>
    <textblock>for assuring that the home will be in compliance with the standards by siting</textblock>
    <textblock>the home in the proper zone. The State Administrative Agencies (SAAs) will be</textblock>
    <textblock>informed of the changes resulting from this rule and will assist the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department in discovering homes that are sited in noncompliance with these</textblock>
    <textblock>standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Anchoring and Tie-Downs</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>The change in lease communities could be revolutionary, as</textblock>
    <textblock>homes become more permanent in nature (122) and homes are taxed more as real,</textblock>
    <textblock>rather than personal, property. Generally, lessors are required to restore</textblock>
    <textblock>the site to its original condition when they move. This requirement, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>relocation of utility connections, would be made more difficult with more</textblock>
    <textblock>permanent foundations. In addition, the FHA Title II allowance for</textblock>
    <textblock>installation would not be sufficient for the additional costs of permanent</textblock>
    <textblock>foundations (146, and others).</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department has evaluated these comments and has removed</textblock>
    <textblock>the design requirement for a permanent foundation. However, the Department</textblock>
    <textblock>remains concerned that some form of strengthened tiedown system may be</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to protect homes adequately in high wind areas. Thus, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department will be reviewing the issue of permanent foundations and other</textblock>
    <textblock>strengthened anchoring systems in conjunction with regulatory action on wind</textblock>
    <textblock>resistant design and construction requirements for the remainder of the</textblock>
    <textblock>country.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>The impact of the new Wind Standards can be adversely effected</textblock>
    <textblock>if there is inadequate enforcement and monitoring of the placement of homes to</textblock>
    <textblock>assure that only homes that have been designed for the wind load requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Zone are permitted to be sited. There is a need for better local</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection; the home is only as good as its anchoring system (149). There is</textblock>
    <textblock>compelling evidence that much of the damage from Hurricane Andrew was</textblock>
    <textblock>attributable to the lax enforcement of State and local building codes,</textblock>
    <textblock>including anchoring requirements, rather than to inadequate standards (80,</textblock>
    <textblock>122). Similarly, the main problem with manufactured homes is the proper</textblock>
    <textblock>installation of anchoring equipment, which the Department cannot regulate</textblock>
    <textblock>(100).</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Although the use of tiedowns was widespread in the areas</textblock>
    <textblock>affected by Hurricane Andrew, indicating some attempt to comply with codes,</textblock>
    <textblock>the tiedowns generally performed very poorly. None of the tiedowns observed</textblock>
    <textblock>was certified in accordance with code requirements. The Department is</textblock>
    <textblock>reviewing the authority to regulate installation of manufactured homes and is</textblock>
    <textblock>exploring ways to encourage States and localities to adopt and enforce more</textblock>
    <textblock>stringent anchoring requirements. The Department also is reviewing</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate methods, including a disclosure requirement, to inform consumers</textblock>
    <textblock>about the installation of the home in a manner that achieves the highest wind</textblock>
    <textblock>protection performance for the home's design.</textblock>
    <textblock>Meanwhile, the Department will be contacting the Governors of all</textblock>
    <textblock>States, and in particular States where the wind risk is the greatest, to</textblock>
    <textblock>advise the Governors of the changes in the wind standards and the need for</textblock>
    <textblock>each State to establish installation standards and a system of enforcement and</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>Typical ground anchors performed adequately in Hurricane</textblock>
    <textblock>Andrew (14</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>-17</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>, 73</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>, 88</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>, and others). If given enough time, ground</textblock>
    <textblock>anchor manufacturers can develop an anchoring system that is comparable to a</textblock>
    <textblock>permanent foundation system (29).</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>With very few exceptions, manufactured homes in the path of</textblock>
    <textblock>Hurricane Andrew were destroyed by the resulting wind forces. The lack of</textblock>
    <textblock>adequate attachment of single or double-wide units to ground anchors was a</textblock>
    <textblock>major factor in loss of units. The chassis of some units could be found some</textblock>
    <textblock>distance away from their original site. However, in some cases the anchors</textblock>
    <textblock>did hold the floor of the unit down while the ``box'' of the structure was torn</textblock>
    <textblock>away by the high winds. For this reason, there is justification for</textblock>
    <textblock>increasing the strength of the structure by this final rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>The effective date of these new requirements will now be at least 180</textblock>
    <textblock>days from today. The Department agrees that innovative anchoring systems</textblock>
    <textblock>comparable to permanent foundations systems can be developed; however, anchor</textblock>
    <textblock>manufacturers are cautioned regarding the resistance capacity of auger-type</textblock>
    <textblock>anchors presently used for installing manufactured homes, when those anchors</textblock>
    <textblock>are subject to high winds and ensuing saturated soil conditions. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Department's tests show substantially less resistance than required by 24 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>3280.306(f), even when tested under dry soil conditions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>Substantially increased siting requirements would be a problem</textblock>
    <textblock>especially for retirees in land-lease communities and for minority owners who</textblock>
    <textblock>reside on ``heir property'' and cannot secure clear title to their site (672).</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Alternative anchoring systems that are expected to provide</textblock>
    <textblock>the required resistance to high wind forces are already available in the</textblock>
    <textblock>market. The Department believes that if siting requirements are increased by</textblock>
    <textblock>State and local governments, the manufactured housing industry will likely</textblock>
    <textblock>develop ways to accommodate siting in land-lease communities.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
