<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00084</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00053</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Extension of Comment Period for the Draft Supplemental Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement on the Federal Aid in Sport Fish Restoration and Federal Aid in Wildlife Restoration Programs</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>A Notice of Availability pertaining to the draft document was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on November 1, 1993, (58 FR 58347). The comment period has been extended in response to requests of several parties for more time.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments will be accepted through March 2, 1994. This is a 45-day extension beyond the previously announced date of January 17, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be sent to U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Division of Federal Aid, 1849 C Street, NW. (Mail Stop 140 Arlington Square), Washington, DC 20240.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Columbus H. Brown, Chief, Division of Federal Aid, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, 140 Arlington Square, 4401 North Fairfax Drive, Arlington, Virginia, 22203. Telephone (703) 358-2156.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service is reviewing the operation and management of its Federal Aid in Sport Fish and Wildlife Restoration Programs into the next century. This Supplemental Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement is being prepared to supplement the Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement published in 1978.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies are available at the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Division of Federal Aid, 4401 North Fairfax Drive, Arlington, Virginia, room 140 during normal working hours. Telephone (703) 358-2156.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 6, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Bruce Blanchard,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Director, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-949 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-55-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
