<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00097</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) Obtained employment in that occupation only after</textblock>
    <textblock>receiving additional training that was not provided by the school</textblock>
    <textblock>that certified the loan;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) That the borrower agrees to provide upon request by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary or the Secretary's designee, other documentation</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonably available to the borrower, that demonstrates, to the</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfaction of the Secretary or the Secretary's designee, that</textblock>
    <textblock>the student meets the qualifications in paragraph (e) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) That the borrower agrees to cooperate with the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary or the Secretary's designee in enforcement actions in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with paragraph (e)(4) of this section, and to transfer</textblock>
    <textblock>any right to recovery against a third party in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (e)(5) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>Cooperation by borrower in enforcement actions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) In</textblock>
    <textblock>any judicial or administrative proceeding brought by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary or the Secretary's designee to recover for amounts</textblock>
    <textblock>discharged under paragraph (e) of this section or to take other</textblock>
    <textblock>enforcement action with respect to the conduct on which those</textblock>
    <textblock>claims were based, a borrower who requests or receives a</textblock>
    <textblock>discharge under paragraph (e) of this section must cooperate with</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary or the Secretary's designee. At the request of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary or the Secretary's designee, and upon the Secretary's</textblock>
    <textblock>or the Secretary's designee's tendering to the borrower the fees</textblock>
    <textblock>and costs as are customarily provided in litigation to reimburse</textblock>
    <textblock>witnesses, the borrower shall_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Provide testimony regarding any representation made by</textblock>
    <textblock>the borrower to support a request for discharge; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Produce any documentation reasonably available to the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower with respect to those representations and any sworn</textblock>
    <textblock>statement required by the Secretary with respect to those</textblock>
    <textblock>representations and documents.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The Secretary revokes the discharge, or denies the</textblock>
    <textblock>request for discharge, of a borrower who_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Fails to provide testimony, sworn statements, or</textblock>
    <textblock>documentation to support material representations made by the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower to obtain the discharge; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Provides testimony, a sworn statement, or documentation</textblock>
    <textblock>that does not support the material representations made by the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower to obtain the discharge.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)</textblock>
    <textblock>Transfer to the Secretary of right of recovery against</textblock>
    <textblock>third parties.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Upon discharge under paragraph (e) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, the borrower is deemed to have assigned to and</textblock>
    <textblock>relinquish in favor of the Secretary any right to a loan refund</textblock>
    <textblock>(up to the amount discharged) that the borrower (or student) may</textblock>
    <textblock>have, by contract or applicable law with respect to the loan or</textblock>
    <textblock>the enrollment agreement for the program for which the loan was</textblock>
    <textblock>received, against the school, its principals, affiliates and</textblock>
    <textblock>their successors, its sureties, and any private or public fund.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The provisions of paragraph (e) of this section apply</textblock>
    <textblock>notwithstanding any provision of State law that would otherwise</textblock>
    <textblock>restrict transfer of those rights by the borrower (or student),</textblock>
    <textblock>limit or prevent a transferee from exercising those rights, or</textblock>
    <textblock>establish procedures or a scheme of distribution that would</textblock>
    <textblock>prejudice the Secretary's ability to recover on those rights.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting</textblock>
    <textblock>or foreclosing the borrower's (or student's) right to pursue</textblock>
    <textblock>legal and equitable relief regarding disputes arising from</textblock>
    <textblock>matters otherwise unrelated to the loan discharged.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6)</textblock>
    <textblock>Guaranty agency responsibilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Upon receipt of a</textblock>
    <textblock>false certification discharge claim filed by a lender, or a</textblock>
    <textblock>request submitted by a borrower with respect to a loan held by</textblock>
    <textblock>the guaranty agency, the agency shall review the borrower's</textblock>
    <textblock>request and supporting sworn statement in the light of</textblock>
    <textblock>information available from the records of the agency and from</textblock>
    <textblock>other sources, including other guaranty agencies, state</textblock>
    <textblock>authorities, and cognizant accrediting associations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) In the case of a claim filed by a lender_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) If the guaranty agency determines that the borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfies the requirements for discharge under paragraph (e) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section, it shall pay the claim in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง682.402(h) not later than 90 days after the agency received the</textblock>
    <textblock>claim; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) If, after examining the documentation in the claim file</textblock>
    <textblock>and considering relevant information available from other</textblock>
    <textblock>sources, the guaranty agency determines that the borrower does</textblock>
    <textblock>not qualify for a discharge, the agency shall, not later than 90</textblock>
    <textblock>days after the agency received the claim, return the claim to the</textblock>
    <textblock>lender with an explanation of the reasons for its determination.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) In the case of a request submitted by a borrower with</textblock>
    <textblock>respect to a loan held by the agency_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) If the guaranty agency determines that the borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfies the requirements for discharge under paragraph (e) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section, it shall notify the borrower not later than 90 days</textblock>
    <textblock>after the agency received the borrower's request; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) If, after examining the documentation provided by the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower and considering relevant information available from</textblock>
    <textblock>other sources, the guaranty agency determines that the borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>does not qualify for a discharge, the agency shall notify the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower of the reasons for its determination not later than 90</textblock>
    <textblock>days after the agency received the borrower's request.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) If the guaranty agency receives information it believes</textblock>
    <textblock>to be reliable indicating that the borrower may be eligible for a</textblock>
    <textblock>cancellation of a loan under paragraph (e) of this section held</textblock>
    <textblock>by the agency, the agency shall immediately suspend any efforts</textblock>
    <textblock>to collect from the borrower on any loan received for the program</textblock>
    <textblock>of study for which the loan was made (but may continue to receive</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower payments), and inform the borrower of the procedures for</textblock>
    <textblock>requesting a discharge.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
