<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00095</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(iii) Nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting</textblock>
    <textblock>or foreclosing the borrower's (or student's) right to pursue</textblock>
    <textblock>legal and equitable relief regarding disputes arising from</textblock>
    <textblock>matters otherwise unrelated to the loan discharged.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6)</textblock>
    <textblock>Guaranty agency responsibilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable to the period prior to the effective date of this</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) If a loan subject to paragraph (d) of this section was</textblock>
    <textblock>received for attendance at a school with a closure date after</textblock>
    <textblock>January 1, 1986 but prior to August 29, 1994, the loan may be</textblock>
    <textblock>discharged in accordance with the procedures specified in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (d)(6)(i) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) If a loan subject to paragraph (d) of this section was</textblock>
    <textblock>discharged in part in accordance with the Secretary's ``Closed</textblock>
    <textblock>School Policy'' as authorized by section IV of Bulletin 89-G-159,</textblock>
    <textblock>the guaranty agency shall initiate the discharge of the remaining</textblock>
    <textblock>balance of the loan not later than September 28, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) A guaranty agency shall review its records and identify</textblock>
    <textblock>all schools that appear to have closed after January 1, 1986 and</textblock>
    <textblock>prior to August 29, 1994, and shall identify all borrowers (or</textblock>
    <textblock>students) who appear to have been enrolled on the school closure</textblock>
    <textblock>date or who withdrew not more than 90 days prior to the closure</textblock>
    <textblock>date.</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) If a guaranty agency determines (or is informed by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary) that a participating school has closed, it shall,</textblock>
    <textblock>within 30 days of making that determination or being informed by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary, notify all lenders participating in its program to</textblock>
    <textblock>suspend collection efforts against individuals with respect to</textblock>
    <textblock>loans made for attendance at the closed school, if the student to</textblock>
    <textblock>whom (or on whose behalf) a loan was made, was enrolled at the</textblock>
    <textblock>school on the closing date, or withdrew not more than 90 days</textblock>
    <textblock>prior to the date the school closed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(E) If a loan identified under paragraph (d)(6)(i)(C) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section is held by the guaranty agency as a defaulted loan</textblock>
    <textblock>and the borrower's current address is known, the guaranty agency</textblock>
    <textblock>shall, within 30 days after identifying a borrower under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (d)(6)(i)(C) of this section, mail a discharge</textblock>
    <textblock>application that meets the requirements of paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)(6)(ii)(C) of this section to the borrower.</textblock>
    <textblock>(F) If a loan identified under paragraph (d)(6)(i)(C) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section is held by the guaranty agency as a defaulted loan</textblock>
    <textblock>and the borrower's current address is unknown, the agency shall,</textblock>
    <textblock>by August 29, 1995, further refine the list of borrowers whose</textblock>
    <textblock>loans are potentially subject to discharge under paragraph (d) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section by consulting with representatives of the closed</textblock>
    <textblock>school, the school's licensing agency, accrediting agency, and</textblock>
    <textblock>other appropriate parties. Upon learning the borrower's new</textblock>
    <textblock>address, the guaranty agency shall, within 30 days, mail a</textblock>
    <textblock>discharge application to the borrower.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Procedures applicable to the period beginning on or</textblock>
    <textblock>after the effective date of this regulation.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
