<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00039</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Kathryn M. Petersen, License Coordinator, Pacific Gas and Electric Company, 201 Mission Street, room 1012, P.O. Box 770000, Mail P10A, San Francisco, CA 94177, (415) 973-4054.</textblock>
    <textblock>i. FERC Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Héctor M. Pérez at (202) 219-2843.</textblock>
    <textblock>j.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of Project:</textblock>
    <textblock>The existing project consists of: (1) the 5.6-foot-high, 64-foot-long gunite faced rock-wall and concrete buttress Angels Diversion Dam; (2) the Upper Angels Canal, approximately 2.5 miles long, to Ross Reservoir; (3) the 100-acre-feet gross storage capacity Ross Reservoir and a 44-foot-high and 710-foot-long earthfill, masonry, and rock structure dam; (5) the Lower Angels Canal, approximately 3.3 miles long; (6) the Angels Forebay with a gross storage capacity of 2 acre-feet; (7) the 8,624-foot-long Angels Penstock; (8) a powerhouse with an installed capacity of 1,400 kW; and (9) other appurtenances.</textblock>
    <textblock>k. Under §4.32(b)(7) of the Commission's regulations (18 CFR), if any resource agency, Indian Tribe, or person believes that the applicant should conduct an additional scientific study to form an adequate factual basis for a complete analysis of the application on its merits, they must file a request for the study with the Commission, not later than 60 days after the application is filed, and must serve a copy of the request on the applicant.</textblock>
    <textblock>5 a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Application:</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendment of License.</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Project No:</textblock>
    <textblock>1835-100.</textblock>
    <textblock>c.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date Filed:</textblock>
    <textblock>October 28, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>d.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nebraska Public Power District.</textblock>
    <textblock>e.</textblock>
    <textblock>Name of Project:</textblock>
    <textblock>North Platte/Keystone Diversion Dam.</textblock>
    <textblock>f.</textblock>
    <textblock>Location:</textblock>
    <textblock>On the North and South Platte Rivers, Nebraska.</textblock>
    <textblock>g.</textblock>
    <textblock>Filed Pursuant to:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 23(b) of the Federal Power Act, 16 U.S.C. 817(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>h.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. R. L. Peterson, Nebraska Public Power District, P.O. Box 310, North Platte, NE 69103 (308) 532-9200.</textblock>
    <textblock>i.</textblock>
    <textblock>FERC Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Steve Hocking, (202) 219-2656.</textblock>
    <textblock>j.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment Date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 28, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>k.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of proposed amendment:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nebraska Public Power District, licensee for the North Platte/Keystone Diversion Dam Project, filed an application to amend article 401 of their license. Article 401 requires the licensee to develop and maintain eight islands as nesting habitat for interior least terns and piping plovers. The proposed amendment would allow the licensee to substitute up to four sand pits for four of the eight islands they are required to develop. The proposed amendment requires a plan on how these sand pits would be developed. A draft plan was included in the licensee's filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>l. This notice also consists of the following standard paragraphs: B, C1, and D2.</textblock>
    <textblock>6 a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Application:</textblock>
    <textblock>As-Built Exhibits.</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Project No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>5867-038.</textblock>
    <textblock>c.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date Filed:</textblock>
    <textblock>July 30 and August 19, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>d.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>Alice Falls Corporation.</textblock>
    <textblock>e.</textblock>
    <textblock>Name of Project:</textblock>
    <textblock>Alice Falls Project.</textblock>
    <textblock>f.</textblock>
    <textblock>Location:</textblock>
    <textblock>On the Ausable River, in Clinton and Essex Counties, New York.</textblock>
    <textblock>g.</textblock>
    <textblock>Filed Pursuant to:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Power Act, 16 U.S.C. 791(a)-825(r).</textblock>
    <textblock>h. Applicant Contact: Mr. Charles McGrath, McGrath Hydro, Inc., 8 Petra Lane, Clifton Park, NY 12205, (518) 464-1081.</textblock>
    <textblock>i.</textblock>
    <textblock>FERC Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Paul Shannon, (202) 219-2866.</textblock>
    <textblock>j.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment Date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 23, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>k.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of Filings:</textblock>
    <textblock>Alice Falls Corporation filed as-built exhibits A, F, and G in accordance with article 33 of its license. The exhibits show the constructed configuration of the project's features. In particular, the exhibit G drawings show the realigned transmission line. The length of the transmission line is 1100 feet instead of the authorized 400 feet. The exhibit G drawings also show an additional two acres of land within the project boundary around the realigned portion of the transmission line.</textblock>
    <textblock>l. This paragraph also consists of the following standard paragraphs: B, C1, and D2.</textblock>
    <textblock>7 a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Application:</textblock>
    <textblock>Minor License.</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Project No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>10867-000.</textblock>
    <textblock>c.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date Filed:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 31, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>d.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>Holliday Historic Restoration Associates, Ltd.</textblock>
    <textblock>e.</textblock>
    <textblock>Name of Project:</textblock>
    <textblock>Holliday Hydroelectric Plant.</textblock>
    <textblock>f.</textblock>
    <textblock>Location:</textblock>
    <textblock>On the West Fork of the White River, in Noblesville, Hamilton County, Indiana.</textblock>
    <textblock>g.</textblock>
    <textblock>Filed Pursuant to:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Power Act 16 U.S.C. 791(a)-825(r).</textblock>
    <textblock>h.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>David H. Kinloch, 414 South Wenzel Street, Louisville, Kentucky 40204, (502) 589-0975.</textblock>
    <textblock>i.</textblock>
    <textblock>FERC Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mary C. Golato (202) 219-2804.</textblock>
    <textblock>j.</textblock>
    <textblock>Deadline for Interventions and Protests:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 10, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>k.</textblock>
    <textblock>Status of Environmental Analysis:</textblock>
    <textblock>This application has been accepted for filing and is ready for environmental analysis at this time_see attached paragraph D4.</textblock>
    <textblock>l.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of Project:</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed project consists of the following features: (1) An existing concrete dam 350 feet long and 10 feet high; (2) an existing reservoir, about 425 acres, with a normal water surface elevation of 764 feet mean sea level; (3) an existing powerhouse containing two new turbine-generator units having a total generating capacity of 450 kilowatts; and (4) appurtenant facilities. The applicant estimates that the total average annual generation would be 1,634,000 kilowatthours. The project site is owned by PSI Energy, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>m.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose of the Project:</textblock>
    <textblock>All project energy generated would be utilized by the applicant for sale.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
