<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00021</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration</textblock>
    <textblock>Talc; Consumer Uses and Health Perspectives; Public Meetings</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>21 CFR Part 347</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 78N-0021]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration, HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of public meetings.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) and the</textblock>
    <textblock>International Society of Regulatory Toxicology and Pharmacology (ISRTP) are announcing forthcoming public meetings to discuss the latest toxicologic and epidemiologic studies and how they reflect on issues related to the safe use of talc in consumer products.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meetings will be held on Monday, January 31, 1994, and Tuesday, February 1, 1994, 9 a.m. to 4:30 p.m. Registration by January 15, 1994, is required. Interested persons, whether or not they are able to attend, may submit written comments on the skin protectant drug product aspects of the issues described in this notice by March 2, 1994, referencing the docket number found in the heading of this document. Three copies of all comments are to be submitted, except that individuals may submit one copy.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meetings will be held at the Lister Hill Auditorium, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD. Submit written comments to the Dockets Management Branch (HFA-305), Food and Drug Administration, rm. 1-23, 12420 Parklawn Dr., Rockville, MD 20857.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Regarding registration and over-the-counter (OTC) skin protectant drug products contact: William E. Gilbertson, Center for Drug Evaluation and Research (HFD-810), Food and Drug Administration, 5600 Fishers Lane, Rockville, MD 20857, 301-594-5000.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regarding cosmetic products contact: John E. Bailey, Jr., Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition (HFS-100), Food and Drug Administration, 200 C St. SW., Washington, DC 20204, 202-205-4530.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>In the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of June 20, 1990 (55 FR 25204 at 25232), FDA proposed talc, 45 to 100 percent, as Category I (generally recognized as safe and effective and not misbranded) as an OTC skin protectant active ingredient for the treatment and prevention of diaper rash. Specific warnings and directions were proposed for powder products containing talc. The final monograph for OTC skin protectant drug products will be published in a future issue of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. The discussion of talc at these public meetings may be considered by the agency in the preparation of this final monograph for OTC skin protectant drug products.</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of these meetings is to provide a forum for an updated discussion of the origins, manufacture, characterization, toxicology, and epidemiology of talc and related products. The principal focus will be on the latest toxicologic and epidemiologic studies, particularly as they reflect on the safe uses of talc in consumer products.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following topic areas will be discussed: (1) Characteristics of cosmetic-grade talc; (2) a history of the uses of talc in a variety of consumer products; (3) current quality control measures to insure safety; (4) the regulatory history of talc; (5) recent National Toxicology Program studies of chronic pulmonary exposure of rodents to talc and the relevance of these studies to human risk assessment; and (6) the significance of contrasting epidemiologic studies of talc exposure.</textblock>
    <textblock>Speakers and panelists will include well-known regulatory specialists, toxicologists, epidemiologists, pathologists, talc product manufacturers, talc production experts, and consumer representatives. A critical panel discussion by speakers and invited experts will complete each session.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 11, 1994</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Michael R. Taylor,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Commissioner for Policy.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1083 Filed 1-12-94; 8:47 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
