<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00081</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>a. Criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>The statute requires that, to qualify for a cancellation,</textblock>
    <textblock>the borrower must be ``unable to complete his or her program''</textblock>
    <textblock>because the school closed. Participants at the San Francisco</textblock>
    <textblock>meeting recommended that the cancellation be available to student</textblock>
    <textblock>borrowers who are in attendance at the school at the time the</textblock>
    <textblock>school closes, or are on a leave of absence or left the school</textblock>
    <textblock>within 60 days prior to the school's closure because of</textblock>
    <textblock>deteriorating conditions at the school. The participants at the</textblock>
    <textblock>New York meeting agreed that students who are registered at the</textblock>
    <textblock>time the school closed should have their loans canceled but</textblock>
    <textblock>recommended that the benefit also be provided to borrowers who</textblock>
    <textblock>left within 90 days prior to the school's closure. Participants</textblock>
    <textblock>at the Kansas City meeting endorsed the 60-day time frame but</textblock>
    <textblock>also recommended that the regulations focus on the date of any</textblock>
    <textblock>announcement that the school is closing if that is earlier than</textblock>
    <textblock>the actual date that the school closed. Participants at the</textblock>
    <textblock>Atlanta meeting recommended that loan cancellation be provided to</textblock>
    <textblock>students who are in attendance or on a leave of absence at the</textblock>
    <textblock>time the school closed.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Prior Payments</textblock>
    <textblock>Participants at all of the meetings agreed that any payments</textblock>
    <textblock>made by the borrower prior to discharge of the loan should be</textblock>
    <textblock>refunded.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Teach-Outs</textblock>
    <textblock>Participants at the meetings discussed whether a loan made</textblock>
    <textblock>to a student who is offered a teach-out of the program in which</textblock>
    <textblock>the student was enrolled should be canceled. The participants at</textblock>
    <textblock>the Atlanta meeting concluded that a loan should not be</textblock>
    <textblock>discharged if the student completed a teach-out during the</textblock>
    <textblock>academic year for which the loan was made, but that the loan</textblock>
    <textblock>should be discharged if the borrower did not take or did not</textblock>
    <textblock>complete a teach-out during that time. Participants at the New</textblock>
    <textblock>York and Kansas City meetings concluded that a borrower should</textblock>
    <textblock>have the option of whether to accept a teach-out and should have</textblock>
    <textblock>the loan discharged if the student does not choose or does not</textblock>
    <textblock>complete a teach-out program. Attendees at the San Francisco</textblock>
    <textblock>meeting stated that they believed that teach-outs do not work</textblock>
    <textblock>well in practice and that loans should be canceled if a borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>does not choose to complete the program through a teach-out.</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Extent of Cancellation</textblock>
    <textblock>Attendees at each of the meetings also discussed whether</textblock>
    <textblock>loans should be canceled only for the academic term for which the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower received the loan or whether all loans received for the</textblock>
    <textblock>program should be canceled. Attendees at the Atlanta meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>agreed that only the loan made for the period in which the school</textblock>
    <textblock>closed should be canceled. Participants at the meetings in New</textblock>
    <textblock>York and San Francisco (and a substantial minority in Atlanta)</textblock>
    <textblock>recommended that the regulations distinguish between students</textblock>
    <textblock>enrolled in certificate programs and students enrolled in degree</textblock>
    <textblock>programs. The attendees at those meetings believed that</textblock>
    <textblock>certificate students were unlikely to be able to transfer the</textblock>
    <textblock>credits earned at the closed school and should have all loans</textblock>
    <textblock>canceled, but that students attending degree-granting schools are</textblock>
    <textblock>likely to be able to transfer their credits and should only</textblock>
    <textblock>receive cancellation of the loan for the period in which the</textblock>
    <textblock>school closed.</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Process and Documentation Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>Attendees at the San Francisco meeting recommended that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary be responsible for notifying the guaranty agencies when</textblock>
    <textblock>a school closes and that the agencies would be responsible for</textblock>
    <textblock>notifying the lenders of the loans eligible for cancellation.</textblock>
    <textblock>The attendees at that meeting also recommended that collection</textblock>
    <textblock>activity be suspended on the affected loans and that public</textblock>
    <textblock>service announcements be used to notify possibly affected</textblock>
    <textblock>students but that the students not be required to complete any</textblock>
    <textblock>applications or paperwork to prove their entitlement. The</textblock>
    <textblock>attendees at the Atlanta meeting also recommended that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary or a State agency be responsible for determining that a</textblock>
    <textblock>school has closed and that the agencies would notify the affected</textblock>
    <textblock>lenders. The attendees at that meeting also recommended that the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower not be required to provide documentation and recommended</textblock>
    <textblock>that credit bureau reporting be suspended during the</textblock>
    <textblock>investigation of possibly affected loans. Attendees at the New</textblock>
    <textblock>York meeting recommended that the date of a school's closure be</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by the applicable State licensing authority and also</textblock>
    <textblock>recommended that the student not be required to provide</textblock>
    <textblock>documentation of eligibility for cancellation of the loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Discharge of Loans for Borrowers Whose Eligibility was</textblock>
    <textblock>Falsely Certified by the School</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 437(c) to the HEA also provided that loans will be</textblock>
    <textblock>canceled for borrowers whose eligibility to borrow was falsely</textblock>
    <textblock>certified by the school. The specific issues described below</textblock>
    <textblock>were discussed in connection with this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Definition of ``False Certification''</textblock>
    <textblock>Participants at the San Francisco meeting recommended that</textblock>
    <textblock>the Department's regulations provide that the following</textblock>
    <textblock>situations should be considered ``false certification:'' a school</textblock>
    <textblock>certifies an application for a borrower who is not eligible</textblock>
    <textblock>because he or she does not have the ability to benefit from the</textblock>
    <textblock>training offered; there is fraud by the school in completing or</textblock>
    <textblock>certifying the loan application or the school cashes checks</textblock>
    <textblock>without the borrower's endorsement; or the school submits an</textblock>
    <textblock>incorrect budget, wrong expected family contribution, or other</textblock>
    <textblock>information vital to the determination of the borrower's</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility. The participants at the Atlanta meeting recommended</textblock>
    <textblock>that the definition of ``false certification'' include forged</textblock>
    <textblock>checks, falsification of the student's program eligibility or</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility for a particular loan amount, and falsification of</textblock>
    <textblock>the borrower's signature. Participants at the New York meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>recommended that the Department define ``false certification'' as</textblock>
    <textblock>including the situation in which the school falsely certifies</textblock>
    <textblock>that it is an eligible institution.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
