<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00175</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00102</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The effluent limitation for total recoverable arsenic is not quantifiable</textblock>
    <textblock>using the EPA approved analytical method, EPA method 206.2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thus, EPA has set forth reporting thresholds to measure the</textblock>
    <textblock>highest acceptable quantification level for this parameter. This</textblock>
    <textblock>reporting threshold does not authorize the discharge of this</textblock>
    <textblock>parameter in excess of the effluent limitation. For more information,</textblock>
    <textblock>see special conditions in Part IX. of this permit.</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Settleable Solids Monitoring. Settleable solids samples shall be representative of the discharge</textblock>
    <textblock>and shall be taken at a point prior to entering the receiving stream.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring shall be conducted in accordance with accepted</textblock>
    <textblock>analytical procedures (Standard Methods, 16th Edition, 1985). The</textblock>
    <textblock>Permittee shall report the sample results on the Annual DMR. See</textblock>
    <textblock>attachment 3 for sampling and analysis protocol.</textblock>
    <textblock>f. Flow Monitoring. Effluent flow shall be measured at the discharge prior to entering</textblock>
    <textblock>the receiving water. Effluent flow shall be measured at least once</textblock>
    <textblock>per day, for continuous discharges, or once during each discharge</textblock>
    <textblock>event if discharges are intermittent. The flow shall be measured in</textblock>
    <textblock>gallons per minute (gpm). The flow measurements, the number of</textblock>
    <textblock>discharge events, and the duration of each discharge event shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>reported in the Annual DMR for each day of the mining season.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Suction Dredges. a. Suction Dredge operations shall visually monitor for turbidity as</textblock>
    <textblock>described in Part II.C. once per day of operation. The Permittee</textblock>
    <textblock>shall maintain records of all information resulting from any visual</textblock>
    <textblock>inspections.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. The Permittee will report the period of suction dredging on the</textblock>
    <textblock>DMR. Visual violation occurrences will also be reported on the</textblock>
    <textblock>DMR along with the measures taken to comply with the provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>of Permit Part II.C.3.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Management Practices</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Mechanical Operations and Hydraulic Removal of Overburden</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The flow of surface waters (i.e., creek, river, or stream) into the plant</textblock>
    <textblock>site shall be interrupted and these waters diverted around and away to</textblock>
    <textblock>prevent incursion into the plant site.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Berms, including any pond walls, dikes, low dams, and similar water</textblock>
    <textblock>retention structures shall be constructed in a manner such that they are</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonably expected to reject the passage of water.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Measures shall be taken to assure that pollutant materials removed</textblock>
    <textblock>from the process water and wastewater streams will be retained in</textblock>
    <textblock>storage areas and not discharged or released to the waters of the</textblock>
    <textblock>United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. The amount of new water allowed to enter the plant site for use in</textblock>
    <textblock>material processing shall be limited to the minimum amount required as</textblock>
    <textblock>makeup water for processing operations.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. All water control devices such as diversion structures and berms and all</textblock>
    <textblock>solids retention structures such as berms, dikes, pond structures, and</textblock>
    <textblock>dams shall be maintained to continue their effectiveness and to protect</textblock>
    <textblock>from failure.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. The operator shall take whatever reasonable steps are appropriate to</textblock>
    <textblock>assure that, after the mining season, all mine areas, including ponds,</textblock>
    <textblock>are in a condition which will not cause additional degradation to the</textblock>
    <textblock>receiving waters over those resulting from natural causes.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Suction Dredges</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Dredging in waters of the United States is permitted only within the</textblock>
    <textblock>active stream channel.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Wherever practicable, the dredge shall be set to discharge into a quiet</textblock>
    <textblock>pool, where settling of dredge spoils can occur more rapidly.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Care shall be taken by the operator during refueling of the dredge to</textblock>
    <textblock>prevent spillage into public waters or to groundwater.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Dredging is not permitted during the periods that fish eggs could be in</textblock>
    <textblock>the gravel at the dredge site and harassment of fish in the stream is</textblock>
    <textblock>prohibited. ``The Atlas to the Catalog of Waters Important for Spawning,</textblock>
    <textblock>Rearing or Migration of Anadromous Fish'' lists the streams in the State</textblock>
    <textblock>which require a Habitat permit from the Alaska Department of Fish and</textblock>
    <textblock>Game.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Other Requirements_Mechanical Operations and Hydraulic Removal of Overburden</textblock>
    <textblock>The operator shall maintain fuel handling and storage facilities in a manner</textblock>
    <textblock>which will prevent the discharge of fuel oil into the receiving waters or on</textblock>
    <textblock>the adjoining shoreline. A Spill Prevention Control and Countermeasure</textblock>
    <textblock>Plan (SPCC Plan) shall be prepared and updated as necessary in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with provisions of 40 CFR part 112 for facilities storing 660</textblock>
    <textblock>gallons in a single container above ground, 1,320 gallons in the aggregate</textblock>
    <textblock>above ground, or 42,000 gallons below ground.</textblock>
    <textblock>The permittee shall indicate on the DMR if an SPCC Plan is necessary and</textblock>
    <textblock>in place at the site and if changes were made to the Plan over the previous</textblock>
    <textblock>year.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
