<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00179</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00102</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>G. Bypass of Treatment Facilities</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Bypass not exceeding limitations. The permittee may allow any bypass</textblock>
    <textblock>to occur which does not cause effluent limitations to be exceeded, but</textblock>
    <textblock>only if it also is for essential maintenance to assure efficient operation.</textblock>
    <textblock>These bypasses are not subject to the provisions of paragraphs 2 and</textblock>
    <textblock>3 of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Notice:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Anticipated bypass. If the permittee knows in advance of the need</textblock>
    <textblock>for a bypass, it shall submit prior notice, if possible at least 10 days</textblock>
    <textblock>before the date of the bypass.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Unanticipated bypass. The permittee shall submit notice of an</textblock>
    <textblock>unanticipated bypass as required under Part III.G., Notice of</textblock>
    <textblock>Noncompliance Reporting.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Prohibition of bypass.</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Bypass is prohibited and the Director or ADEC may take</textblock>
    <textblock>enforcement action against a permittee for a bypass, unless:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The bypass was unavoidable to prevent loss of life, personal</textblock>
    <textblock>injury, or severe property damage;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) There were no feasible alternatives to the bypass, such as the</textblock>
    <textblock>use of auxiliary treatment facilities, retention of untreated</textblock>
    <textblock>wastes, or maintenance during normal periods of equipment</textblock>
    <textblock>downtime. This condition is not satisfied if adequate back-up</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment should have been installed in the exercise of</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonable engineering judgment to prevent a bypass which</textblock>
    <textblock>occurred during normal periods of equipment downtime or</textblock>
    <textblock>preventive maintenance; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The permittee submitted notices as required under paragraph 2</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. The Director and ADEC may approve an anticipated bypass, after</textblock>
    <textblock>considering its adverse effects, if the Director and ADEC determine</textblock>
    <textblock>that it will meet the three conditions listed above in paragraph 3.a.</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>H. Upset Conditions</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Effect of an upset. An upset constitutes an affirmative defense to an</textblock>
    <textblock>action brought for noncompliance with such technology based permit</textblock>
    <textblock>effluent limitations if the requirements of paragraph 2 of this section are</textblock>
    <textblock>met. An administrative review of a claim that noncompliance was</textblock>
    <textblock>caused by an upset does not represent final administrative action for</textblock>
    <textblock>any specific event. A determination is not final until formal</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative action is taken for the specific violation(s).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Conditions necessary for a demonstration of upset. A permittee who</textblock>
    <textblock>wishes to establish the affirmative defense of upset shall demonstrate,</textblock>
    <textblock>through properly signed, contemporaneous operating logs, or other</textblock>
    <textblock>relevant evidence that:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. An upset occurred and that the permittee can identify the cause(s)</textblock>
    <textblock>of the upset;</textblock>
    <textblock>b. The permitted facility was at the time being properly operated;</textblock>
    <textblock>c. The permittee submitted notice of the upset as required under Part</textblock>
    <textblock>IV.G., Notice of Noncompliance Reporting; and</textblock>
    <textblock>d. The permittee complied with any remedial measures required under</textblock>
    <textblock>Part V.D., Duty to Mitigate.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Burden of proof. In any enforcement proceeding, the permittee seeking</textblock>
    <textblock>to establish the occurrence of an upset has the burden of proof.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Toxic Pollutants</textblock>
    <textblock>The permittee shall comply with effluent standards or</textblock>
    <textblock>prohibitions established under section 307(a) of the Act for toxic pollutants</textblock>
    <textblock>within the time provided in the regulations that establish those standards or</textblock>
    <textblock>prohibitions, even if the permit has not yet been modified to incorporate the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>VI. General Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Changes in Discharge of Toxic Substances</textblock>
    <textblock>Notification shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>provided to the Director and ADEC as soon as the permittee knows of, or</textblock>
    <textblock>has reason to believe:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. That any activity has occurred or will occur which would result in the</textblock>
    <textblock>discharge, on a routine or frequent basis, of any toxic pollutant which is</textblock>
    <textblock>not limited in the permit, if that discharge will exceed the highest of the</textblock>
    <textblock>following ``notification levels'':</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
