<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00091</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00060</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[AK-040-04-4210-03; AA-60570]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Realty Action: Section 1303(b) ANILCA Special Use Permit Proposal Near Unalakleet, AK</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management, Department of the Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of realty action.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice of realty action involves an application for a special use permit on public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management. The permit is intended to authorize continued use of approximately one (1) acre of land for an existing subsistence cabin and related structures near Unalakleet, Alaska. This land and the application has been examined and reviewed under the provisions of section 1303(b) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (ANILCA), as amended. The site for the application is located on the right bank of the Unalakleet National Wild River within the following described area:</textblock>
    <textblock>Kateel River Meridian, Alaska</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 18 S., R. 8 W.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 16 that portion within a one acre parcel around an existing cabin and other related structures.</textblock>
    <textblock>The area described contains 1.00 acre.</textblock>
    <textblock>The above land would be offered noncompetitively to the applicant and owner of the improvements, Mrs. Eunice E. Ryan of Unalakleet, Alaska, under a five (5) year permit which would only be renewable for the life of the applicant at no less than fair market rental. The permit would be issued under the provisions of section 1303(b) of ANILCA.</textblock>
    <textblock>The general terms and conditions for permits found in 43 CFR part 2920 will also apply.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested parties may submit comments on or before February 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be submitted to the Anchorage District Manager, 6881 Abbott Loop Road, Anchorage, Alaska 99507-2599.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Sandra Dunn (907) 267-1214.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 16, 1993.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard J. Vernimen,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Anchorage District Manager.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-979 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-JA-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
