<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00152</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00094</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Environmental Impact Statement: Pitt County, NC</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Highway Administration (FHWA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of intent.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FHWA is issuing this notice to advise the public that an environmental impact statement will be prepared for a proposed highway project within the City of Greenville and Pitt County, North Carolina.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Roy C. Shelton, Operations Engineer, Federal Highway Administration, suite 410, 310 New Bern Avenue, Raleigh, North Carolina 27601, Telephone (919) 856-4350.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FHWA, in cooperation with the North Carolina Department of Transportation (NCDOT), will prepare an environmental impact statement (EIS) on a proposed Greenville Southwest Bypass in the City of Greenville and Pitt County. The proposed action will be the construction of a multilane divided controlled access highway on new location from NC 11-903 south of Greenville around the southern and western portions of the city to US 264 west of Greenville. This proposed facility is a portion of a planned complete bypass facility which ultimately will provide for travel around Greenville and will relieve existing traffic congestion along NC 11-903 through Greenville. The proposed action is part of the 1990 Greenville Thoroughfare Plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>Alternatives under consideration include: (1) The ``no-build'' alternative, (2) improve existing facilities, and (3) a controlled access highway on new location.</textblock>
    <textblock>Letters describing the proposed action and soliciting comments are being sent to appropriate Federal, State and local agencies. Citizens Informational Workshops and meetings with local officials and neighborhood groups will be held in the study area. Public hearings will also be held. Information on the time and place of the workshops and hearings will be provided in the local news media. The draft EIS will be available for public and agency review and comment at the time of the hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>To ensure the full range of issues related to the proposed action are addressed and all significant issues identified, comments and suggestions are invited from all interested parties. Comments and questions concerning the proposed action should be directed to the FHWA at the address provided above.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Program Number 20.205, Highway Planning and Construction. The regulations implementing Executive Order 12372 regarding intergovernmental consultation on Federal programs and activities apply to this program.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued on: January 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Roy C. Shelton,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Operations Engineer, Raleigh, NC.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-941 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-22-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
