<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00038</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Use standardized curricula throughout the State;</textblock>
    <textblock>Ensure availability of continuing education programs;</textblock>
    <textblock>Require instructors to meet State requirements;</textblock>
    <textblock>Develop and enforce certification criteria for first responders and prehospital providers; and</textblock>
    <textblock>Require EMS operating organizations to collect data to evaluate emergency care in terms of frequency, category, and severity as well as the use of appropriate knowledge and skills.</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Transportation</textblock>
    <textblock>Each State should require safe, reliable ambulance transportation, which is critical to an effective EMS system. States should:</textblock>
    <textblock>Develop statewide transportation plans, including the identification of specific service areas;</textblock>
    <textblock>Implement regulations that provide for the systematic delivery of patients to appropriate facilities;</textblock>
    <textblock>Develop routine, standardized methods for inspection and licensing of all emergency medical transport vehicles;</textblock>
    <textblock>Establish a minimum number of providers at the desired level of certification on each response;</textblock>
    <textblock>Coordinate all emergency transports within the EMS system, including public, private, or specialty (air and ground) transport; and</textblock>
    <textblock>Develop regulations to ensure ambulance drivers are properly trained and licensed.</textblock>
    <textblock>V. Facilities</textblock>
    <textblock>It is imperative that the seriously injured patient be delivered in a timely manner to the closest appropriate facility. Each State should ensure that:</textblock>
    <textblock>Both stabilization and definitive care needs of the patient are considered;</textblock>
    <textblock>The determination is free of political considerations and the capabilities of the facilities are clearly understood by prehospital personnel;</textblock>
    <textblock>Hospital resources capabilities are known in advance, so that appropriate primary and secondary transport decisions can be made; and</textblock>
    <textblock>Agreements are made between facilities to ensure that patients receive treatment at the closest, most appropriate facility, including facilities in other states or counties.</textblock>
    <textblock>VI. Communications</textblock>
    <textblock>An effective communications system is essential to EMS operations and provides the means by which emergency resources can be accessed, mobilized, managed, and coordinated. Each State should require a communication system to:</textblock>
    <textblock>Begin with a universal system access number, such as 911;</textblock>
    <textblock>Provide for prioritized dispatch (dispatch-to-ambulance, ambulance-to-ambulance, ambulance-to-hospital, and hospital-to-hospital communication);</textblock>
    <textblock>Ensure the receiving facility is ready and able to accept the patient; and</textblock>
    <textblock>Provide for dispatcher training and certification standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each State should develop a statewide communications plan that defines State government roles in EMS system communications.</textblock>
    <textblock>VII. Trauma Systems</textblock>
    <textblock>Each State should maintain a fully functional trauma system to provide a high quality, effective patient care system. States should implement legislation requiring the development of a trauma system, including:</textblock>
    <textblock>Trauma center designation, using American College of Surgeons Committee on Trauma guidelines as a minimum;</textblock>
    <textblock>Triage and transfer standards for trauma patients;</textblock>
    <textblock>Data collection and trauma registry definitions for quality assurance;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
