<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00046</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The damage to manufactured homes by Hurricane Andrew was so extensive</textblock>
    <textblock>that many were rendered unrecognizable. Ninety-seven percent of all</textblock>
    <textblock>manufactured homes in Dade County were totally destroyed, while only eleven</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of single-family homes were destroyed. The American Red Cross</textblock>
    <textblock>reported that of the 1,176 licensed and registered manufactured homes in</textblock>
    <textblock>Homestead, Florida, 1,167 were completely destroyed. The American Red Cross</textblock>
    <textblock>and FEMA have also reported a total of 11,213 manufactured homes destroyed in</textblock>
    <textblock>Florida and Louisiana in Hurricane Andrew, and an additional 3,016</textblock>
    <textblock>manufactured homes experienced major damage. Almost 36% of all housing units</textblock>
    <textblock>destroyed during Hurricane Andrew were manufactured homes.</textblock>
    <textblock>The loss of these units had implications extending beyond the loss of</textblock>
    <textblock>the homes and possessions of their owners. These homes, shredded by the</textblock>
    <textblock>winds, also became dangerous flying missiles, inflicting more property damage</textblock>
    <textblock>on neighboring structures.</textblock>
    <textblock>In its October 1992 report on Hurricane Andrew, the Federal Emergency</textblock>
    <textblock>Management Agency (FEMA) stated that, ``in all areas, mobile homes</textblock>
    <textblock>(manufactured housing) were most susceptible to damage or destruction. Many</textblock>
    <textblock>mobile homes imploded from the wind loads of Hurricane Andrew. In coastal</textblock>
    <textblock>areas, where mobile homes were properly `cradled' and elevated, the cradled</textblock>
    <textblock>foundations remained intact, but the mobile homes mounted to these foundations</textblock>
    <textblock>were often heavily damaged or destroyed.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Concerns for potential losses during high winds in coastal and other</textblock>
    <textblock>areas were identified previously in a May 1991 report by the Federal Emergency</textblock>
    <textblock>Management Agency (FEMA), which predicted that the United States can expect</textblock>
    <textblock>more hurricanes of greater intensity during the 1990s and early 2000s than it</textblock>
    <textblock>has experienced in recent years. Furthermore, estimates suggest that by the</textblock>
    <textblock>year 2010 the population density on Florida's coasts will have increased about</textblock>
    <textblock>130 percent from the 1988 level. Moreover, as the national population ages,</textblock>
    <textblock>an increasing percentage of coastal inhabitants will probably be older</textblock>
    <textblock>individuals, a group more likely to occupy manufactured houses. The American</textblock>
    <textblock>Association of Retired Persons (AARP) reports that 40 percent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>purchasers of new manufactured homes are at least 50 years old. The elderly</textblock>
    <textblock>can be more difficult to evacuate and may be more prone to be injured during</textblock>
    <textblock>periods of extreme high winds.</textblock>
    <textblock>The technology for achieving economical wind resistant designs in</textblock>
    <textblock>housing is available. It involves calculations of risk for extreme wind-prone</textblock>
    <textblock>coastal areas and the establishment of construction standards based upon these</textblock>
    <textblock>risk calculations. Through use and implementation of this approach, risks of</textblock>
    <textblock>injury and death can be minimized and economic loss limited to acceptable</textblock>
    <textblock>levels in coastal areas subject to high winds.</textblock>
    <textblock>In determining a course of action to address these issues, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department had to balance two competing concerns: (1) The need to raise</textblock>
    <textblock>manufactured housing standards, to protect individuals, their homes, and their</textblock>
    <textblock>neighbors from future high winds; and (2) the need to preserve the</textblock>
    <textblock>affordability of a key source of low-cost housing. This rule is the result of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Department's decision to improve protection of homeowners in hurricane-</textblock>
    <textblock>prone areas as soon as possible, but to delay making changes to the standards</textblock>
    <textblock>in lower wind-risk areas, in order to give adequate consideration to cost</textblock>
    <textblock>factors. Although the changes are expected to increase costs to consumers in</textblock>
    <textblock>the high-wind areas, the Department has concluded that the increases are</textblock>
    <textblock>justified, because the improved standards will significantly reduce future</textblock>
    <textblock>losses to occupants and the public by strengthening the features that make</textblock>
    <textblock>manufactured homes vulnerable to damage and destruction in high winds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Perhaps more importantly, the improved standards may help avoid the</textblock>
    <textblock>inestimable costs of devastation to people's lives and emotional health and to</textblock>
    <textblock>the communities, in the likelihood that another powerful hurricane hits a</textblock>
    <textblock>community of manufactured homes in the hurricane-prone regions of the country.</textblock>
    <textblock>Field Investigations_Hurricane Andrew</textblock>
    <textblock>Among the major deficiencies contributing to manufactured housing damage</textblock>
    <textblock>in Hurricane Andrew were inadequate connections between exterior roof or wall</textblock>
    <textblock>coverings and supporting sheathing or framing and between walls, roofs and</textblock>
    <textblock>floors. In particular, losses of roof coverings were widespread, and were</textblock>
    <textblock>considered by some to be the first mode of failure for manufactured homes</textblock>
    <textblock>damaged in Hurricane Andrew. Other roof-related damage was due to loss of</textblock>
    <textblock>sheathing, failure of connections, or a combination of these problems.</textblock>
    <textblock>Numerous failures of uplift straps also occurred, when the staples pulled out</textblock>
    <textblock>through the metal straps, permitting the straps to tear away from the members</textblock>
    <textblock>to which they had been fastened. In some cases, entire sections of roofs were</textblock>
    <textblock>blown away.</textblock>
    <textblock>Another common area of failure was loss of exterior wall siding. Metal</textblock>
    <textblock>or plastic siding used in manufactured housing was readily damaged or</textblock>
    <textblock>penetrated by flying debris during the high winds in Hurricane Andrew. Loss</textblock>
    <textblock>of roof or wall cladding allows the building to be penetrated by the weather</textblock>
    <textblock>and has far-reaching consequences beyond the area of envelope integrity.</textblock>
    <textblock>As a result of these losses, and damage to windows and doors, there was</textblock>
    <textblock>significant water damage and deterioration to many manufactured homes. In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition, failure of coverings or attachments to the manufactured home</textblock>
    <textblock>structure also caused missile-type damage to other homes.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
