<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00116</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00066</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>5. Those rights for a buried water pipeline granted to Jensen Water District by R/W grant, UTU-53937.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Those rights for an access road granted to Leonard Heeney by R/W grant, UTU-47456.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Those rights for a road granted to Uintah County by R/W grant, UTU-71236.</textblock>
    <textblock>Oil &amp; Gas Leases</textblock>
    <textblock>Those rights granted to the holders of oil and gas (O&amp;G) leases, described below, pursuant to the Act of February 25, 1920 (41 Stat. 437; 30 U.S.C. 181, as amended):</textblock>
    <textblock>1. O&amp;G lease, U-65924, leased to Beard Oil Company, Myers W. Lockyard, and Petrowest Exploration, Incorporated.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. O&amp;G leases, U-67262 &amp; U-66075, leased to Atlantic Richfield and Beard Oil Company, respectively.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. O&amp;G lease, U-66823, leased to Atlantic Richfield.</textblock>
    <textblock>Grazing Permits</textblock>
    <textblock>The privilege of existing grazing permittees to graze their livestock on public lands encumbered by such permits would expire two years from the date of publication of the Notice of Realty Action in the Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, unless the permittees choose to waive their grazing privileges earlier.</textblock>
    <textblock>Floodplain</textblock>
    <textblock>Conveyance of these lands by the Secretary of the Interior shall not exempt the patent holder or subsequent owners of title from compliance with applicable Federal or State law and compliance with State or local land use plans, including floodplain management restrictions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The offered private land will be acquired subject to the following third party rights and reservations:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. A Class ``D'' Road Resolution executed by the Uintah County Commission recorded April 22, 1992 as Entry</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>92002016 in Book 527 at Page 211 of official records of Uintah County, Utah.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Any oil, gas, and mineral rights not reserved to the United States of America.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Rights-of-way and easements for roads, ditches, transmission and utility lines, now existing on, over, under or across said premises.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. An easement in favor of Northwest Pipeline Corporation, recorded September 19, 1979, as entry No. 171200, in the official records of Uintah County, Utah.</textblock>
    <textblock>Publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>will segregate the public lands from the operation of the public land laws and the mining laws, except for mineral leasing. The segregative effect will end upon issuance of patent or two (2) years from the date of publication, whichever occurs first.</textblock>
    <textblock>For a period of 45 days from the publication date of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, interested parties may submit comments to the District Manager, Vernal District Office, 170 South 500 East, Vernal, Utah 84078.</textblock>
  </text>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Peter Kempenich, Natural Resource Specialist, Phone (801) 781-4432.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 20, 1993.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David E. Little,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>District Manager.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-5 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-DQ-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
