<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00058</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00033</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT AGENCY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Public Information Collection Requirements Submitted to OMB for Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) has submitted to the Office of Management and Budget the following public information collection requirements for review and clearance in accordance with the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980, 44 U.S.C. chapter 35.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this information collection must be submitted on or before March 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Direct comments regarding the burden estimate or any aspect of this information collection, including suggestions for reducing this burden, to: The FEMA Information Collections Clearance Officer at the address below; and to Gary Waxman, Office of Management and Budget, 3235 New Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-7340, within 60 days of this notice.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the above information collection request and supporting documentation can be obtained by calling or writing Muriel Anderson, FEMA Information Collections Clearance Officer, Federal Emergency Management Agency, 500 C Street, SW., Washington, DC 20472, (202) 646-2624.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type:</textblock>
    <textblock>Reinstatement of 3067-0213.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>FEMA Contract Clause_Accessibility of Meetings to Persons with Disabilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abstract:</textblock>
    <textblock>Contractors who plan meetings, conferences, or seminars for FEMA must develop a plan to ensure that minimum accessibility standards for the disabled as set forth in the contract clause will be met. The plan must be approved by the FEMA Contracting Officer.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Businesses or other for-profit, non-profit institutions, small businesses or organizations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimate of Total Annual Reporting and Recordkeeping Burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>30 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>10.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Average Burden Time per Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>3 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>On occasion.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Wesley C. Moore,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Administrative Support.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-985 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6718-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
