<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00082</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>b. Need for Showing of Intent</textblock>
    <textblock>Participants at the San Francisco meeting recommended that</textblock>
    <textblock>the regulations provide that ``false certification'' must relate to</textblock>
    <textblock>the school's intent to deceive and not include a clerical error.</textblock>
    <textblock>The participants at the New York meeting, who also discussed this</textblock>
    <textblock>issue, did not reach a consensus regarding the requirement for a</textblock>
    <textblock>showing of intent by the school.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>Only the attendees at the Atlanta meeting discussed the</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures that should be utilized in implementing the provision</textblock>
    <textblock>for discharge of loans in cases of false certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>Participants at the Atlanta meeting recommended that the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations provide that the determination of a false</textblock>
    <textblock>certification can be made by the Department, the guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agency, or the courts. They also recommended that if the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency makes the decision, the regulations should allow</textblock>
    <textblock>the school to appeal that decision to the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>Participants at that meeting also recommended that a lender be</textblock>
    <textblock>required to notify the guaranty agency within 30 days of</textblock>
    <textblock>receiving a complaint that a loan was falsely certified and that</textblock>
    <textblock>collection activity be suspended while the agency investigates</textblock>
    <textblock>the claim. The agency would be required to complete its</textblock>
    <textblock>investigation within 6 months.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Repayment of Bankruptcy Claims</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Law 102-325 changed the procedure for payment of</textblock>
    <textblock>bankruptcy claims by the Department and requires the Secretary to</textblock>
    <textblock>repay the loan if collection of the loan is stayed under Title 11</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Bankruptcy Code. Participants at all of the regional</textblock>
    <textblock>meetings recommended that the Department define ``stay'' in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with the current definition in the Bankruptcy Code.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, in response to the Department's question regarding the</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate procedure for handling loans that are not ultimately</textblock>
    <textblock>discharged in bankruptcy, there were differences of opinion. The</textblock>
    <textblock>attendees at the San Francisco meeting recommended that if a loan</textblock>
    <textblock>was not likely to be discharged by the bankruptcy court, the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency should obtain the loan from the lender and hold</textblock>
    <textblock>it until the bankruptcy court action is completed and then return</textblock>
    <textblock>it to the lender. Attendees at the New York meeting recommended</textblock>
    <textblock>that lenders be permitted to file bankruptcy claims for payment</textblock>
    <textblock>directly to the Secretary and if the Secretary wanted the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency to service the account, the agency should be</textblock>
    <textblock>permitted to receive at least a portion of any repayment. They</textblock>
    <textblock>also recommended that the lender be given the option to</textblock>
    <textblock>repurchase any loan that is not discharged in bankruptcy.</textblock>
    <textblock>Participants at the Atlanta meeting recommended that lenders be</textblock>
    <textblock>required to repurchase any loans not discharged on which a claim</textblock>
    <textblock>was paid. Because this amendment has now been superseded by</textblock>
    <textblock>section 2(c)(63) of Public Law 103-208, which incorporated the</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions found in current FFEL Program regulations, these</textblock>
    <textblock>comments are now moot.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Garnishment</textblock>
    <textblock>The last statutory provision reflected in these proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations is section 488A of the HEA, which establishes a</textblock>
    <textblock>national wage garnishment law. That section was added by Public Law</textblock>
    <textblock>102-164, the Emergency Unemployment Compensation Act of 1991, and</textblock>
    <textblock>was not discussed during the regional meetings or the negotiated</textblock>
    <textblock>rulemaking sessions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Negotiated Rulemaking</textblock>
    <textblock>After completion of the regional meetings, the Department</textblock>
    <textblock>prepared draft proposed regulations to implement the provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>of Public Law 102-325 relating to the FFEL Program. In accordance</textblock>
    <textblock>with the requirements of section 492(b) of the HEA, those</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations were submitted to a negotiated rulemaking process.</textblock>
    <textblock>During the weeks of January 4-8 and February 1-5, 1993, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department met with negotiators selected from among individuals</textblock>
    <textblock>nominated by attendees at the regional meetings.</textblock>
    <textblock>The discussion below of the proposed regulations reflects</textblock>
    <textblock>those areas where the negotiators reached a consensus and the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations reflect that agreement. The discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>below also indicates where consensus was not reached during the</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiations. However, the negotiators did not choose to discuss</textblock>
    <textblock>every part of the proposed regulations. Accordingly, the</textblock>
    <textblock>discussion below of those issues not discussed during the</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiations reflects only the views of the Secretary.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
