<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00065</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00039</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Under the provisions of the Federal Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. chapter 35), we have submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) a request for an urgent review of a new information collection titled: ``Application for Fiscal Year 1994 Funds for Family Preservation and Family Support Services.'' This request for OMB clearance is made by the Children's Bureau of the Administration on Children, Youth and Families (ACYF) of the Administration for Children and Families.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Administration For Children and Families</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Agency Information Collection Under OMB Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the information collection request may be obtained from Stephen R. Smith, of the Office of Information Systems Management, ACF, by calling (202) 401-6964.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments and questions regarding the requested approval for information collection should be sent directly to: Laura Oliven, OMB Desk Officer for ACF, OMB Reports Management Branch, New Executive Office Building, room 3002, 725 17th Street NW., Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-7316.</textblock>
    <textblock>Information on Document</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Application for FY 1994 Funds for Family Preservation and Family Support Services.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>0980_New Request.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description:</textblock>
    <textblock>New legislation in the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act (OBRA) of 1994 authorizes entitlement funding to States and certain Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations for family preservation and family support services. The major purpose of family preservation services is to help alleviate family crises that otherwise might lead to the foster care placement of children, e.g., intensive in-home services, respite care, and services for adoptive parents. The major purpose of family support services is to provide preventive services to families to help alleviate stress (e.g., to prevent child abuse), increase parents' child-rearing abilities and parenting skills, and assist families to use other available community resources, e.g., center-based services, home visiting, and early developmental screening of children.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>92.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Frequency:</textblock>
    <textblock>1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Average Burden Hours Per Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>144.</textblock>
    <textblock>Total Burden Hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>13,248.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </address>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Larry Guerrero,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Director, Office of Information Systems Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1115 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4184-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
