<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00107</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00065</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Wilbur Cherry; A-154.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-154 described as follows: Beginning at the Northeast corner of said A-154; Thence, S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 15</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1050 feet, along the East line of said A-154; Thence, N. 82</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 21</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2000 feet; Thence, N. 01</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 30</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1500 feet, along the West line of said A-154; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 3500 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the West line of said A-154 at a point which lies N. 01</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 30</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 8050 feet from the Southwest corner of said A-154; Thence, N. 01</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 30</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 300 feet, along the West line of said A-154; Thence, Southerly, approximately 350 feet, along the westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Henry Emerson; A-203.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-203 described as follows: Beginning at the Southwest corner of said A-203; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 32</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2500 feet, along the West line of said A-203; Thence, N. 85</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 59</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2650 feet; Thence, S. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 33</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 4400 feet, along the East line of said A-203; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 4500 feet, along the northerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Peter Rich; A-433.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-433 described as follows: Beginning at the Northwest corner of said A-433; Thence, Easterly, approximately 1500 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 01</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 30</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 300 feet; Thence, Southerly, approximately 500 feet along the westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 01</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 30</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1500 feet, along the East line of said A-433; Thence, N. 59</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 31</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1600 feet; Thence, N. 01</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 30</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1250 feet, along the West line of said A-433, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Eliza A. Davis; A-565.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-565 described as follows: Beginning at the Northeast corner of said A-565; Thence, S. 01</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 30</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1250 feet; Thence, N. 59</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 31</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 450 feet; Thence, N. 44</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 57</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 3825 feet; Thence, N. 02</textblock>
    <textblock>○ 45</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 800 feet, along the West line of said A-565; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 5500 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Kriner; A-352.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>All.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>T. &amp; N. O. Railroad; A-680.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>All.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
