<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00166</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00102</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In establishing the arsenic limit, the ``Amendments to the Water Quality</textblock>
    <textblock>Standards Regulation; Compliance with CWA section 303(c)(2)(B);</textblock>
    <textblock>Final Rule'' (57 FR 6084, Tuesday, December 22, 1992) are used. This</textblock>
    <textblock>rulemaking promulgated the chemical-specific numeric criteria for</textblock>
    <textblock>priority toxic pollutants necessary to bring all States into compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>with the requirements of the CWA section 303(c)(2)(B). The primary</textblock>
    <textblock>focus of the rule is the inclusion of the federal water quality criteria for</textblock>
    <textblock>pollutant(s) in State standards as necessary to support water quality-based control programs (e.g. NPDES permits). The federal standard</textblock>
    <textblock>of 0.18 μg/l total recoverable arsenic is applicable to Alaska and this</textblock>
    <textblock>number has been used to derive the end-of-pipe limitation for the draft</textblock>
    <textblock>permits.</textblock>
    <textblock>Mixing zones are allowed under the Alaska standards for some</textblock>
    <textblock>pollutant discharges. However, 18 AAC 70.032(a) states *␣*␣* ``In</textblock>
    <textblock>applying the water quality criteria set out in this chapter, the</textblock>
    <textblock>department will, upon application and in its discretion, prescribe in its</textblock>
    <textblock>permits or certifications a volume of dilution for an effluent or</textblock>
    <textblock>substance within a receiving water unless pollutants discharged could</textblock>
    <textblock>bioaccumulate; concentrate or persist in the environment; cause</textblock>
    <textblock>carcinogenic, mutagenic, or teratogenic effects; or otherwise present a</textblock>
    <textblock>risk to human health *␣*␣*'' Arsenic is a carcinogen. In a letter, dated</textblock>
    <textblock>March 24, 1992, from the Alaska Department of Environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>Conservation Commissioner, John Sandor, to EPA Water Division</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, Charles Findley, the State has interpreted this to mean that</textblock>
    <textblock>``*␣*␣* a mixing zone may be prescribed where there is no reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>expectation of an adverse effect on human health or aquatic life, based</textblock>
    <textblock>on site-specific, chemical, physical and biological characteristics.'' EPA</textblock>
    <textblock>is not proposing a mixing zone for arsenic but would include a method</textblock>
    <textblock>for determining a mixing zone in the permit if the Department</textblock>
    <textblock>determines that such a mixing zone is appropriate and is in compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>with WQS.</textblock>
    <textblock>Two options are given to the permittee to determine the arsenic limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>If the ``natural'' background is not measured, the effluent limit is set</textblock>
    <textblock>according to federal standard at 0.18</textblock>
    <textblock>μg/l. The other option depends</textblock>
    <textblock>on the ``natural'' background levels of arsenic present in the receiving</textblock>
    <textblock>water. The ``natural'' background is defined as the total recoverable</textblock>
    <textblock>arsenic level upstream from all mining and other man-made</textblock>
    <textblock>disturbances. The WQS, 18 AC 70.010(a), states that ``[n]o person</textblock>
    <textblock>may conduct an operation that *␣*␣* contributes to a violation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>water quality standards *␣*␣*'' If the ``natural'' background levels are</textblock>
    <textblock>already above the federal standard, any discharge at or below the</textblock>
    <textblock>``natural'' background level will not elevate the existing concentrations in</textblock>
    <textblock>the stream thus not contributing further to a violation of WQS. The</textblock>
    <textblock>``natural'' background data must be provided with the annual Discharge</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring Report (DMR).</textblock>
    <textblock>Because the effluent limitation of 0.18 μg/L is not quantifiable using the</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA approved analytical method (206.2), EPA has set a reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>threshold to measure the highest acceptable quantification level for this</textblock>
    <textblock>parameter. When results cannot be quantified, values below the</textblock>
    <textblock>method detection level (1 μg/L) shall be report as zero and values</textblock>
    <textblock>above the method detection level but below the minimum level</textblock>
    <textblock>(4 μg/L) reported at 1/2 the minimum level or 2 μg/L. This reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>threshold does not authorize the discharge of this parameter in excess</textblock>
    <textblock>of the effluent limitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sediment.</textblock>
    <textblock>The sediment standard (18 ACC 70.020) is a narrative standard which</textblock>
    <textblock>reads, ``No increase in concentration of sediment, including settleable</textblock>
    <textblock>solids, above natural conditions.'' The method indicated for measuring</textblock>
    <textblock>sediments is the use of an Imhoff cone. The detection limit, the lowest</textblock>
    <textblock>measurable value, of an Imhoff cone is 0.2 ml/l. Therefore the</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum limit for sediment will be 0.2 ml/l measured as settleable</textblock>
    <textblock>solids for operations utilizing hydraulic removal of overburden.</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Basis for Monitoring and Reporting Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>A.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring:</textblock>
    <textblock>All self-monitoring requirements considered the remoteness of</textblock>
    <textblock>the mining operations, the magnitude of the pollutants discharged, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>practicability of maintaining a valid quality assurance program.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The measurement of settleable solids is an indication of overall</textblock>
    <textblock>treatment efficiency. The permit requires monitoring for settleable</textblock>
    <textblock>solids once per day during periods of discharge. If there is a</textblock>
    <textblock>discharge to waters of the United States, permittees are required to</textblock>
    <textblock>sample for settleable solids on a daily basis, even if sluicing does not</textblock>
    <textblock>occur. This is required because the operator is responsible at all times</textblock>
    <textblock>for the condition of the wastewater entering the receiving stream. Also,</textblock>
    <textblock>the results from settleable solids sampling can give the operator an</textblock>
    <textblock>immediate indication of the overall effectiveness of the treatment</textblock>
    <textblock>system and thus allow advanced planning for treatment system</textblock>
    <textblock>maintenance.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. EPA has concluded that the monitoring frequency for turbidity and</textblock>
    <textblock>arsenic will be once per season. Monitoring for these pollutants have</textblock>
    <textblock>been established at less frequent intervals because sampling and</textblock>
    <textblock>analysis for these parameters are more difficult and costly. Samples</textblock>
    <textblock>for monitoring purposes must be taken during sluicing or discharge at</textblock>
    <textblock>a time when the operation has reached equilibrium. For example,</textblock>
    <textblock>samples should be taken when sluice paydirt loading and effluent</textblock>
    <textblock>discharge are fairly constant.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
