<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00156</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00098</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Poverty Threshold</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Veterans Affairs.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) is hereby giving notice of the weighted average poverty threshold in 1992 for one person (unrelated individual) as established by the Bureau of the Census.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The 1992 poverty threshold is for consideration effective October 8, 1993, the date on which we notified our regional offices of such amount.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>John Bisset, Jr., Consultant, Regulations Staff, Compensation and Pension Service, Veterans Benefits Administration, Department of Veterans Affairs, 810 Vermont Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20420, (202) 233-3005.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>VA published a final regulation amending 38 CFR 4.16(a) in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of August 3, 1990, pages 31579-80. The amendment provided that marginal employment generally shall be deemed to exist when a veteran's earned annual income does not exceed the amount established by the Bureau of the Census as the poverty threshold for one person. VA noted that the weighted average poverty threshold in 1988 for one person (unrelated individual) as established by the Bureau of the Census was $6,024 and stated we would publish subsequent poverty threshold figures as notices in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bureau of the Census recently published the weighted average poverty thresholds for 1992. The threshold for one person (unrelated individual) is $7,143.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jesse Brown,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-898 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8320-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
