<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00112</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00065</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mary Thomas; A-75.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of said A-75 described as follows: Beginning on the Southerly line of said A-75 at a point which lies S. 65</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 3805.45 feet, from the most Easterly corner of said A-75; Thence, S. 65</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1969.57 feet, along the Southerly line of said A-75; Thence, N. 54</textblock>
    <textblock>○13</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2425 feet; Thence, N. 61</textblock>
    <textblock>○43</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1950 feet; Thence, N. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○26</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1400 feet; Thence, N. 65</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2200 feet; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 3500 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek; Thence, S. 63</textblock>
    <textblock>○16</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1200 feet; Thence, S. 53</textblock>
    <textblock>○26</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1750 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the Northeasterly line of said A-75 at a point which lies N. 54</textblock>
    <textblock>○46</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1901.61 feet, from the most Easterly corner of said A-75; Thence, S. 63</textblock>
    <textblock>○16</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2396.27 feet; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 3500 feet, along the northerly gradient line of Big Sandy Creek; Thence, N. 65</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1400 feet; Thence, S. 54</textblock>
    <textblock>○46</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2083.50 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning at the most Easterly corner of said A-75, Thence, S. 65</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 3000 feet, along the Southerly line of said A-75; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 3500 feet, along the northerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek; Thence, N. 63</textblock>
    <textblock>○16</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2800 feet; Thence, S. 54</textblock>
    <textblock>○46</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1650 feet, along the Northeasterly line of said A-75, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also, land in Polk County described as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>All land lying between the Northerly and Easterly gradient boundary and Southerly and Westerly gradient boundary of Big Sandy Creek extending upstream, from the East line of Polk County to the East line of the Big Sandy Creek Unit of the preserve.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
