<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00013</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>IV. Amendments to Commission Guideline No. 1</textblock>
    <textblock>Guideline No. 1 sets forth the Commission's economic and public interest requirements for initial and continuing designation of a contract market in a particular commodity. The Commission is proposing to revise this guideline to correct an improper rule reference. Specifically, item 5 in column 2 of the ``Option Designation Checklist For Options On Futures Contracts'' (option on futures checklist) and the ``Option Designation Checklist For Options on Physicals'' (option on physicals checklist) regarding the option expiration criteria cites Commission Regulation 33.4(d)(1) as the applicable Commission regulation for these criteria. However, as a result of substantive revisions to the Commission's option regulations adopted in September 1991 (56 FR 43694), many of the Commission's option regulations were renumbered, including Regulation 33.4(d)(1) which was renumbered as 33.4(b)(2). Therefore, the Commission hereby is amending the option checklists to replace 33.4(d)(1) with 33.4(b)(2) as the cited Commission regulation for the option expiration criteria in each of those checklists.</textblock>
    <textblock>Related Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The Regulatory Flexibility Act (RFA), 5 U.S.C. 601</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.,</textblock>
    <textblock>requires that agencies, in adopting rules, consider their impact on small businesses. The Commission has previously determined that contract markets are not small entities for purposes of the Regulatory Flexibility Act. 47 FR 18618 (April 30, 1982). Moreover, no additional regulatory burdens are imposed by these amendments. Therefore, the Acting Chairman on behalf of the Commission hereby certifies, pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 605(b), that the action taken herein will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (PRA), 44 U.S.C. 3501 et seq., imposes certain requirements on federal agencies (including the Commission) in connection with their conducting or sponsoring any collection of information as defined by the Paperwork Reduction Act. In compliance with the Act, the Commission has submitted these amended rules and their associated information collection requirements to the Office of Management and Budget.</textblock>
    <textblock>While these amended rules result in no increased burden, the group of rules (OMB control</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>3038-0007) of which they are a part has the following burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>Average Burden Hours per Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>50.34.</textblock>
    <textblock>Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>10,727,182.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Monthly.</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons wishing to comment on the estimated paperwork burden associated with these amended rules should contact Gary Waxman, Office of Management and Budget, room 3228, NEOB, Washington, DC 20503. Copies of the information collection submission to OMB are available from Joe F. Mink, CFTC Clearance Officer, 2033 K Street, NW., Washington, DC 20581, (202) 254-9735.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
