<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00021</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>COMMODITY FUTURES TRADING COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>New York Cotton Exchange Futures and Futures Option Contracts Based on Five Currency Cross-Rates: French Franc/Deutsche Mark, et al.</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Commodity Futures Trading Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability of the terms and conditions of proposed commodity futures and option contracts.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The New York Cotton Exchange (NYCE or Exchange) has applied for designation as a contract market in currency cross-rate futures and futures option contracts based on each of the following five currency crosses: French franc/Deutsche mark; Swedish krona/Deutsche mark; Italian lira/Deutsche mark; Japanese yen/Deutsche mark; and Deutsche mark/British pound. The Acting Director of the Division of Economic Analysis (Division) of the Commission, acting pursuant to the authority delegated by Commission Regulation 140.96, has determined that publication of the proposals for comment is in the public interest, will assist the Commission in considering the views of interested persons, and is consistent with the purposes of the Commodity Exchange Act.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before February 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons should submit their views and comments to Jean A. Webb, Secretary, Commodity Futures Trading Commission, 2033 K Street NW., Washington, DC 20581. Reference should be made to the NYCE currency cross-rate futures and futures option contracts.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Please contact Steve Sherrod of the Division of Economic Analysis, Commodity Futures Trading Commission, 2033 K Street NW., Washington, DC 20581, telephone 202-254-7303.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the terms and conditions will be available for inspection at the Office of the Secretariat, Commodity Futures Trading Commission, 2033 K Street, NW., Washington, DC 20581. Copies of the terms and conditions can be obtained through the Office of the Secretariat by mail at the above address or by phone at (202) 254-6314.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other materials submitted by the Exchange in support of the applications for contract market designation may be available upon request pursuant to the Freedom of Information Act (5 U.S.C. 552) and the Commission's Regulations thereunder (17 CFR part 145 (1987)), except to the extent they are entitled to confidential treatment as set forth in 17 CFR 145.5 and 145.9. Requests for copies of such materials should be made to the FOI, Privacy and Sunshine Act Compliance Staff of the Office of the Secretariat at the Commission's headquarters in accordance with 17 CFR 145.7 and 145.8.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person interested in submitting written data, views, or arguments on the proposed terms and conditions, or with respect to other materials submitted by the Exchange, should send such comments to Jean A. Webb, Secretary, Commodity Futures Trading Commission, 2033 K Street, NW., Washington, DC 20581 by the specified date.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Blake Imel,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-963 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6351-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
