<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00057</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Requirements for structural assemblies, components, connectors,</textblock>
    <textblock>fasteners, and a number of other areas will be strengthened so that parts and</textblock>
    <textblock>portions of the home will be able to resist the same wind forces as required</textblock>
    <textblock>for site-built and modular housing. In addition, the increased wind loads</textblock>
    <textblock>required by this rule are applicable whether structural systems, components,</textblock>
    <textblock>or other aspects of the design are substantiated by engineering analysis or by</textblock>
    <textblock>suitable load tests (see subpart E of part 3280). The revised standards also</textblock>
    <textblock>require that the ground anchoring and foundation support systems continue to</textblock>
    <textblock>be designed by a registered engineer or architect in a manner adequate to</textblock>
    <textblock>withstand the higher wind forces specified.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Section-by-Section Analysis</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary has determined that the following changes should be made</textblock>
    <textblock>to the standards:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 3280.4</textblock>
    <textblock>_The American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE) is</textblock>
    <textblock>added to the list of organizations issuing standards that are incorporated by</textblock>
    <textblock>reference. The street addresses are corrected for two other organizations</textblock>
    <textblock>listed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 3280.5</textblock>
    <textblock>_Technical and conforming corrections are made to</textblock>
    <textblock>standardize paragraph designations to</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>format and clarify the</textblock>
    <textblock>information to be included on data plates. The new requirements also</textblock>
    <textblock>incorporate changes to the data plate adopted in the Energy Rule (58 FR 54975,</textblock>
    <textblock>55003) for effect in October 1994, in order to avoid having inconsistent</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements become effective within a short time.</textblock>
    <textblock>The data plate is also being expanded to indicate that manufactured</textblock>
    <textblock>homes should not be located within 1500</textblock>
    <textblock>’ of the coastline in Wind Zones II and</textblock>
    <textblock>III unless the home and its anchoring or foundation system are designed for</textblock>
    <textblock>the increased requirements of Exposure D in ASCE 7-88. The data plate will</textblock>
    <textblock>now also indicate whether the home has been equipped with storm shutters and,</textblock>
    <textblock>if shutters are not provided, will strongly recommend that the home be made</textblock>
    <textblock>ready for these devices in accordance with the method described in the</textblock>
    <textblock>installation instructions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 3280.302(a)(8), 3280.303(d), 3280.305(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>_The definition</textblock>
    <textblock>and references to ``hurricane resistive design'' in these sections are deleted,</textblock>
    <textblock>in favor of the Wind Zone II and III designations in the revised Basic Wind</textblock>
    <textblock>Zone Map. These changes will result in the identification of design wind</textblock>
    <textblock>forces and wind speeds for which the home has been designed, rather than the</textblock>
    <textblock>designation of homes as ``hurricane resistive.''</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 3280.304</textblock>
    <textblock>_The incorporated standards are amended to</textblock>
    <textblock>require that the minimum design loads be based on ASCE 7-88, which replaces</textblock>
    <textblock>the obsolete ANSI A58.1-1982 standard currently referenced in this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, the National Design Specification for Wood Members (NDS),</textblock>
    <textblock>incorporated by reference, is updated to the most current specification issued</textblock>
    <textblock>by the American Forest and Paper Association (AFPA). Because manufacturers</textblock>
    <textblock>will need to redesign the structure's resistance to wind forces, the redesign</textblock>
    <textblock>should be accomplished with the most current design values for wood.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, the 1991 NDS is incorporated in its entirety into the standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 3280.305(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>_The standards are amended to require that for</textblock>
    <textblock>manufactured homes in high wind areas, the home and each wind resisting part,</textblock>
    <textblock>including components and cladding, be completely designed to resist the design</textblock>
    <textblock>wind pressures specified for a 50-year recurrence level by ASCE 7-88 or the</textblock>
    <textblock>pressures specified in a table of equivalent design wind load provisions. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Department has designated three wind zones: Zone I (current wind design</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for Zone I); Zone II (design wind speed of 100 mph); and Zone III</textblock>
    <textblock>(design wind speed of 110 mph).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Table of Design Pressures in the proposed rule is clarified and</textblock>
    <textblock>expanded. Editorial revisions to clarify the application of the uplift</textblock>
    <textblock>pressure requirements for exterior roof coverings, eaves and gables. In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition, footnotes are included to indicate:</textblock>
    <textblock>•Distributional pressure effects between windward and leeward walls;</textblock>
    <textblock>•The application of the Table is limited to roof slopes between 10 and</textblock>
    <textblock>30 degrees and that horizontal drag pressures need not be considered for roof</textblock>
    <textblock>slopes under 20 degrees;</textblock>
    <textblock>•The design uplift pressures are the same regardless of whether they</textblock>
    <textblock>are applied normal to the roof surface or to the horizontal projection of the</textblock>
    <textblock>roof; and</textblock>
    <textblock>•Exterior roof and wall coverings (excluding glazing), sheathing, and</textblock>
    <textblock>fastenings need not be evaluated for the design pressures specified by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Table, when fastened to a 3/8</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ structural rated sheathing and the sheathing is</textblock>
    <textblock>oriented and secured to framing members in accordance with the fastening</textblock>
    <textblock>schedule specified in the Table.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Basic Wind Zone Map is revised by delineating the boundary between</textblock>
    <textblock>Wind Zones I and II as the 90 mph isotach, and the boundary between Wind Zones</textblock>
    <textblock>II and III as the 100 mph isotach, on the ASCE 7-88 basic wind speed map.</textblock>
    <textblock>This change will result in certain areas of existing Wind Zone II being</textblock>
    <textblock>located in the modified Wind Zone I. The boundary between Wind Zones I and</textblock>
    <textblock>III in Alaska is now designated as the 90 mph isotach on the ASCE 7-88 map.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
