<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00101</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(j)</textblock>
    <textblock>Mandatory purchase by a lender of a loan subject to a</textblock>
    <textblock>bankruptcy claim.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The lender shall repurchase from the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency a loan held by the agency pursuant to a</textblock>
    <textblock>bankruptcy claim paid to that lender, unless the guaranty agency</textblock>
    <textblock>sells the loan to another lender, promptly after the earliest of</textblock>
    <textblock>the following events:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The lender may capitalize all outstanding interest</textblock>
    <textblock>accrued on a loan purchased under paragraph (j) of this section</textblock>
    <textblock>to cover any periods of delinquency prior to the bankruptcy</textblock>
    <textblock>action through the date the lender purchases the loan and</textblock>
    <textblock>receives the supporting loan documentation from the guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>(k)</textblock>
    <textblock>Claims for reimbursement from the Secretary on loans</textblock>
    <textblock>held by guaranty agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The Secretary pays a death, disability, bankruptcy,</textblock>
    <textblock>closed school, or false certification claim in an amount</textblock>
    <textblock>determined under ยง682.402(k)(5) on a loan held by a guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agency after the agency has paid a default claim to the lender</textblock>
    <textblock>thereon and received payment under its reinsurance agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary reimburses the guaranty agency only if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The guaranty agency determines that the borrower (or the</textblock>
    <textblock>student for whom a parent obtained a PLUS loan or each of the</textblock>
    <textblock>co-makers of a PLUS loan) has died, or the borrower (or each of</textblock>
    <textblock>the co-makers of a PLUS loan) has become totally and permanently</textblock>
    <textblock>disabled since applying for the loan, or has filed for relief in</textblock>
    <textblock>bankruptcy, in accordance with the procedures in paragraphs (b)</textblock>
    <textblock>through (f) of this section, or the student was unable to</textblock>
    <textblock>complete an educational program because the school closed, or the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower's eligibility to borrow (or the student's eligibility in</textblock>
    <textblock>the case of a PLUS loan) was falsely certified by an eligible</textblock>
    <textblock>school. For purposes of this paragraph, references to the</textblock>
    <textblock>``lender'' and ``guaranty agency'' in paragraphs (b) through (f) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section mean the guaranty agency and the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>respectively;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) In the case of a Stafford, SLS, or PLUS loan, the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency determines that the borrower (or the student for</textblock>
    <textblock>whom a parent obtained a PLUS loan, or each of the co-makers of a</textblock>
    <textblock>PLUS loan) has died, or the borrower (or each of the co-makers of</textblock>
    <textblock>a PLUS loan) has become totally and permanently disabled since</textblock>
    <textblock>applying for the loan, or has filed the petition for relief in</textblock>
    <textblock>bankruptcy within 10 years of the date the borrower entered</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment, exclusive of periods of deferment or periods of</textblock>
    <textblock>forbearance granted by the lender that extended the 10-year</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum repayment period, or the borrower was unable to complete</textblock>
    <textblock>an educational program because the school closed, or the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower's eligibility to borrow (or the student's eligibility in</textblock>
    <textblock>the case of a PLUS loan) was falsely certified by an eligible</textblock>
    <textblock>school.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
