<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00098</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(v) If the borrower fails to submit the written request and</textblock>
    <textblock>sworn statement described in paragraph (e)(3) of this section</textblock>
    <textblock>within 60 days of being notified of that option, the guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agency shall resume collection and shall be deemed to have</textblock>
    <textblock>exercised forbearance of payment of principal and interest from</textblock>
    <textblock>the date it suspended collection activity. The agency may</textblock>
    <textblock>capitalize, in accordance with §682.202(b), any interest accrued</textblock>
    <textblock>and not paid during that period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) A borrower's request for discharge and sworn statement</textblock>
    <textblock>may not be denied solely on the basis of failing to meet any time</textblock>
    <textblock>limits set by the lender or the guaranty agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7)</textblock>
    <textblock>Lender Responsibilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) If the lender receives</textblock>
    <textblock>information it believes to be reliable indicating that the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower may be eligible for a loan cancellation under paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) of this section, the lender shall immediately suspend any</textblock>
    <textblock>efforts to collect from the borrower on any loan received for the</textblock>
    <textblock>program of study for which the loan was made (but may continue to</textblock>
    <textblock>receive borrower payments), and inform the borrower of the</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures for requesting a discharge.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) If the borrower fails to submit the written request and</textblock>
    <textblock>sworn statement described in paragraph (e)(3) of this section</textblock>
    <textblock>within 60 days of being notified of that option, the lender shall</textblock>
    <textblock>resume collection and shall be deemed to have exercised</textblock>
    <textblock>forbearance of payment of principal and interest from the date</textblock>
    <textblock>the lender suspended collection activity. The lender may</textblock>
    <textblock>capitalize, in accordance with §682.202(b), any interest accrued</textblock>
    <textblock>and not paid during that period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The lender shall file a false certification claim with</textblock>
    <textblock>the guaranty agency in accordance with §682.402(g) no later than</textblock>
    <textblock>60 days after the lender receives the borrower's written request</textblock>
    <textblock>and sworn statement described in paragraph (e)(3) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section. If a lender receives a payment made by or on behalf of</textblock>
    <textblock>the borrower on the loan after the lender files a claim on the</textblock>
    <textblock>loan with the guaranty agency, the lender shall forward the</textblock>
    <textblock>payment to the guaranty agency within 30 days of its receipt. The</textblock>
    <textblock>lender shall assist the guaranty agency and the borrower in</textblock>
    <textblock>determining whether the borrower is eligible for discharge of the</textblock>
    <textblock>loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Within 30 days after receiving reimbursement from the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency for a false certification claim, the lender shall</textblock>
    <textblock>notify the borrower that the loan obligation has been discharged,</textblock>
    <textblock>and request that all credit bureaus to which it previously</textblock>
    <textblock>reported the status of the loan delete all adverse credit history</textblock>
    <textblock>assigned to the loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) Within 30 days after being notified by the guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agency that the borrower's request for a false certification</textblock>
    <textblock>discharge has been denied, the lender shall resume collection and</textblock>
    <textblock>notify the borrower of the reasons for the denial. The lender</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be deemed to have exercised forbearance of payment of</textblock>
    <textblock>principal and interest from the date the lender suspended</textblock>
    <textblock>collection activity, and may capitalize, in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>§682.202(b), any interest accrued and not paid during that</textblock>
    <textblock>period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(8)</textblock>
    <textblock>Requirements for admission on the basis of ability to</textblock>
    <textblock>benefit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) For periods of enrollment beginning between July 1,</textblock>
    <textblock>1987 and June 30, 1991, a student who had a general education</textblock>
    <textblock>diploma or received one before the scheduled completion of the</textblock>
    <textblock>program of instruction is deemed to have the ability to benefit</textblock>
    <textblock>from the training offered by the school.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A student not described in paragraph (e)(8)(i) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section is considered to have the ability to benefit from</textblock>
    <textblock>training offered by the school if the student_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Achieved a passing grade on a test_</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) Approved by the Secretary, for periods of enrollment</textblock>
    <textblock>beginning after July 1, 1991, or by the accrediting agency, for</textblock>
    <textblock>other periods; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) Administered in accordance with the requirements for use</textblock>
    <textblock>of the test; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Successfully completed a program of developmental or</textblock>
    <textblock>remedial education provided by the school.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Notwithstanding paragraphs (e)(8)(i) and (ii) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, a student did not have the ability to benefit from</textblock>
    <textblock>training offered by the school if the student had, at the time of</textblock>
    <textblock>enrollment, a condition or status, including one based on a</textblock>
    <textblock>physical or mental condition, age, or criminal record, that would</textblock>
    <textblock>have prevented the student from satisfying the physical</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements or the legal requirements of the State in which the</textblock>
    <textblock>student resided when the loan was made for either acceptance into</textblock>
    <textblock>the educational program offered by the school or performance of</textblock>
    <textblock>the occupation for which the program of instruction was designed</textblock>
    <textblock>to prepare the student.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) *␣*␣*</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
