<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00130</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00079</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that, on October 27, 1993, pursuant to section 6(a) of the National Cooperative Research and Production Act of 1993, 15 U.S.C. 4301,</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>(``the Act''), the Petroleum Environmental Research Forum (``PERF'') Project No. 91-05, titled ``Basic Principles and Control of Refinery Emulsion Formation_Part 2'', has filed written notification simultaneously with the Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission disclosing a membership change. The notifications were filed for the purpose of extending the Act's provisions limiting the recovery of antitrust plaintiffs to actual damages under specified circumstances. Specifically, Petro Canada, Calgary, Alberta T2P 3E3 Canada has become a participant in PERF Project No. 91-05.</textblock>
    <textblock>No other changes have been made in either membership or the planned activities of the group research project. Membership in this group research project remains open, and the participants intend to file additional written notification disclosing all changes in membership.</textblock>
    <textblock>On March 16, 1992, the participants filed the original notification pursuant to section 6(a) of the Act. The Department of Justice published a notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to section 6(b) of the Act on April 30, 1992 (57FR 18528).</textblock>
    <textblock>The last notification was filed with the Department on July 10, 1992. A notice was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to section 6(b) of the Act on August 21, 1992 (57 FR 38067).</textblock>
    <textblock>Information regarding participation in this project may be obtained from William J. Tracy, Mobil Research and Development Corporation, P.O. Box 480, 600 Billingsport Road, Paulsboro, NJ 08066-0480.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice Pursuant to the National Cooperative Research and Production Act of 1993_Petroleum Environmental Research Forum</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Joseph H. Widmar,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director of Operations Antitrust Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-930 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
