<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00178</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00102</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>H. Other Noncompliance Reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>Instances of noncompliance not</textblock>
    <textblock>required to be reported in IV.G. above shall be reported at the time that</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring reports for Part IV.B. are submitted. The reports shall contain</textblock>
    <textblock>the information listed in Part IV.G.3.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Inspection and Entry</textblock>
    <textblock>The permittee shall allow the Director, ADEC, or an</textblock>
    <textblock>authorized representative (including an authorized contractor acting as a</textblock>
    <textblock>representative of the Administrator), upon the presentation of credentials</textblock>
    <textblock>and other documents as may be required by law, to:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Enter upon the permittee's premises where a regulated facility or activity</textblock>
    <textblock>is located or conducted, or where records must be kept under the</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions of this permit;</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Have access to and copy, at reasonable times, any records that must</textblock>
    <textblock>be kept under the conditions of this permit;</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Inspect at reasonable times any facilities, equipment (including</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring and control equipment), practices, or operations regulated</textblock>
    <textblock>or required under this permit; and</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Sample or monitor at reasonable times, for the purpose of assuring</textblock>
    <textblock>permit compliance or as otherwise authorized by the Act, any</textblock>
    <textblock>substances or parameters at any location.</textblock>
    <textblock>V. Compliance Responsibilities</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Duty to Comply</textblock>
    <textblock>The permittee must comply with all conditions of this</textblock>
    <textblock>permit. Any permit noncompliance constitutes a violation of the Act and is</textblock>
    <textblock>grounds for enforcement action; for permit termination, revocation and</textblock>
    <textblock>reissuance, or modification; or for denial of a permit renewal application.</textblock>
    <textblock>The permittee shall give advance notice to the Director and ADEC of any</textblock>
    <textblock>planned changes in the permitted facility or activity which may result in</textblock>
    <textblock>noncompliance with permit requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Penalties for Violations of Permit Conditions</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Administrative Penalty. The Act provides that any person who violates a</textblock>
    <textblock>permit condition implementing sections 301, 302, 306, 307, 308, 318, or</textblock>
    <textblock>405 of the Act shall be subject to an administrative penalty, not to</textblock>
    <textblock>exceed $10,000 per day for each violation.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Civil Penalty. The Act provides that any person who violates a permit</textblock>
    <textblock>condition implementing sections 301, 302, 306, 307, 308, 318, or 405 of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Act shall be subject to a civil penalty, not to exceed $25,000 per day</textblock>
    <textblock>for each violation.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Criminal Penalties: a. Negligent Violations. The Act provides that any person who</textblock>
    <textblock>negligently violates a permit condition implementing sections 301,</textblock>
    <textblock>302, 306, 307, 308, 318, or 405 of the Act shall be punished by a</textblock>
    <textblock>fine of not less than $2,500 nor more than $25,000 per day of</textblock>
    <textblock>violation, or by imprisonment for not more than 1 year, or by both.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Knowing Violations. The Act provides that any person who</textblock>
    <textblock>knowingly violates a permit condition implementing sections 301,</textblock>
    <textblock>302, 306, 307, 308, 318, or 405 of the Act shall be punished by a</textblock>
    <textblock>fine of not less than $5,000 nor more than $50,000 per day of</textblock>
    <textblock>violation, or by imprisonment for not more than 3 years, or by both.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Knowing Endangerment. The Act provides that any person who</textblock>
    <textblock>knowingly violates a permit condition implementing sections 301,</textblock>
    <textblock>302, 306, 307, 308, 318, or 405 of the Act, and who knows at that</textblock>
    <textblock>time that he thereby places another person in imminent danger of</textblock>
    <textblock>death or serious bodily injury, shall, upon conviction, be subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>a fine of not more than $250,000 or imprisonment of not more than</textblock>
    <textblock>15 years, or both. A person which is an organization shall, upon</textblock>
    <textblock>conviction of violating this subparagraph, be subject to a fine of not</textblock>
    <textblock>more than $1,000,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>d. False Statements. The Act provides that any person who knowingly</textblock>
    <textblock>makes any false material statement, representation, or certification</textblock>
    <textblock>in any application, record, report, plan, or other document filed or</textblock>
    <textblock>required to be maintained under this Act or who knowingly falsifies,</textblock>
    <textblock>tampers with, or renders inaccurate any monitoring device or</textblock>
    <textblock>method required to be maintained under this Act, shall upon</textblock>
    <textblock>conviction, be punished by a fine of not more that $10,000, or by</textblock>
    <textblock>imprisonment for not more than 2 years, or by both.</textblock>
    <textblock>Except as provided in permit conditions in Part V.G., Bypass of Treatment</textblock>
    <textblock>Facilities and Part V.H., Upset Conditions, nothing in this permit shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>construed to relieve the permittee of the civil or criminal penalties for</textblock>
    <textblock>noncompliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Need to Halt or Reduce Activity not a Defense</textblock>
    <textblock>It shall not be a defense</textblock>
    <textblock>for a permittee in an enforcement action that it would have been necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>to halt or reduce the permitted activity in order to maintain compliance with</textblock>
    <textblock>the conditions of this permit.</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Duty to Mitigate</textblock>
    <textblock>The permittee shall take all reasonable steps to minimize</textblock>
    <textblock>or prevent any discharge in violation of this permit which has a reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>likelihood of adversely affecting human health or the environment.</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Proper Operation and Maintenance</textblock>
    <textblock>The permittee shall at all times</textblock>
    <textblock>properly operate and maintain all facilities and systems of treatment and</textblock>
    <textblock>control (and related appurtenances) which are installed or used by the</textblock>
    <textblock>permittee to achieve compliance with the conditions of this permit. Proper</textblock>
    <textblock>operation and maintenance also includes adequate laboratory controls and</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate quality assurance procedures. This provision requires the</textblock>
    <textblock>operation of back-up or auxiliary facilities or similar systems which are</textblock>
    <textblock>installed by a permittee only when the operation is necessary to achieve</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance with the conditions of the permit.</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Removed Substances</textblock>
    <textblock>Solids, sludges, or other pollutants removed in the</textblock>
    <textblock>course of treatment or control of wastewaters shall be disposed of in a</textblock>
    <textblock>manner so as to prevent any pollutant from such materials from entering</textblock>
    <textblock>waters of the United States.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
