<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00102</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(iii) In the case of a Consolidation loan, the guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agency determines that the borrower (or each of the co-makers)</textblock>
    <textblock>has died, become totally and permanently disabled since applying</textblock>
    <textblock>for the Consolidation loan, or has filed the petition for relief</textblock>
    <textblock>in bankruptcy within the maximum repayment period described in</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง682.209(h)(2), exclusive of periods of deferment or periods of</textblock>
    <textblock>forbearance granted by the lender that extended the maximum</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The guaranty agency has not written off the loan in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with the procedures established by the agency under</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง682.410(b)(6)(x), except for closed school and false</textblock>
    <textblock>certification discharges; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) The guaranty agency has exercised due diligence in the</textblock>
    <textblock>collection of the loan in accordance with the procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>established by the agency under ยง682.410(b)(6)(x), until the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower (or the student for whom a parent obtained a PLUS loan,</textblock>
    <textblock>or each of the co-makers of a PLUS loan) has died, or the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower (or each of the co-makers of a PLUS loan) has become</textblock>
    <textblock>totally and permanently disabled or filed a Chapter 12 or Chapter</textblock>
    <textblock>13 petition, or had the loan discharged in bankruptcy, or for</textblock>
    <textblock>closed school and false certification claims, the guaranty agency</textblock>
    <textblock>receives a request for discharge from the borrower or another</textblock>
    <textblock>party.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) [Reserved]</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Within 30 days of receiving reimbursement for a closed</textblock>
    <textblock>school or false certification claim, the guaranty agency shall</textblock>
    <textblock>pay the borrower an amount equal to the amount paid on the loan</textblock>
    <textblock>by or on behalf of the borrower, less any school tuition refunds</textblock>
    <textblock>or payments received by the holder, guaranty agency, or the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower from a tuition recovery fund, performance bond, or other</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party source.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) The Secretary pays the guaranty agency a percentage of</textblock>
    <textblock>the outstanding principal and interest that is equal to the</textblock>
    <textblock>complement of the reinsurance percentage paid on the loan. This</textblock>
    <textblock>interest includes interest that accrues during_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) For death, disability, or bankruptcy claims, the shorter</textblock>
    <textblock>of 60 days or the period from the date the guaranty agency</textblock>
    <textblock>determines that the borrower (or the student for whom a parent</textblock>
    <textblock>obtained a PLUS loan, or each of the co-makers of a PLUS loan)</textblock>
    <textblock>died, became totally and permanently disabled, or filed a</textblock>
    <textblock>petition for relief in bankruptcy until the Secretary authorizes</textblock>
    <textblock>payment; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) For closed school or false certification claims, the</textblock>
    <textblock>period from the date on which the guaranty agency received</textblock>
    <textblock>payment from the Secretary on a default claim to the date on</textblock>
    <textblock>which the Secretary authorizes payment of the closed school or</textblock>
    <textblock>false certification claim.</textblock>
    <textblock>(l) Payments received after the Secretary's payment of a</textblock>
    <textblock>death, disability, closed school, false certification, or</textblock>
    <textblock>bankruptcy claim.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) If the guaranty agency receives any</textblock>
    <textblock>payments from or on behalf of the borrower on or attributable to</textblock>
    <textblock>a loan on which the Secretary previously paid a bankruptcy claim,</textblock>
    <textblock>the guaranty agency shall remit 100 percent of these payments to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The guaranty agency shall remit to the Secretary all</textblock>
    <textblock>payments received from a tuition recovery fund, performance bond,</textblock>
    <textblock>or other third-party with respect to a loan on which the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary previously paid a closed school or false certification</textblock>
    <textblock>claim. The guaranty agency shall promptly return to the borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>or the borrower's representative, any payment on a discharged</textblock>
    <textblock>loan made by the borrower (or representative) and received after</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary pays a closed school or false certification claim.</textblock>
    <textblock>At the same time that the agency returns the payment, it shall</textblock>
    <textblock>notify the borrower (or representative) that there is no</textblock>
    <textblock>obligation to repay a loan discharged by virtue of death,</textblock>
    <textblock>disability, false certification, or closing of the school.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) If the guaranty agency has returned a payment to the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower, or the borrower's representative, with the notice</textblock>
    <textblock>described in paragraph (l)(2) of this section, and the borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>(or representative) continues to send payments to the guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agency, the agency shall remit all of those payments to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>(m)</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicable suspension of the repayment period.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of this section and 11 U.S.C. 523(a)(8)(A) with</textblock>
    <textblock>respect to loans guaranteed under the FFEL Program, an applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>suspension of the repayment period_</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
