<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00034</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Radio Broadcasting Services; Islesboro and Winter Harbor, ME</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL COMMUNICATIONS COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>47 CFR Part 73</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[MM Docket No. 93-203; RM-8245, RM-8340]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document allots Channel 288B1 to Islesboro, Maine, in response to a petition filed by Islesboro Broadcasting Company. See 58 FR 39722, July 26, 1993. There is a site restriction 16.7 kilometers (10.4 miles) south of the community. The coordinates for Channel 288B1 are 44-09-31 and 68-53-03. In response to a counterproposal filed by Winter Harbor Wireless Associates we will allot Channel 249A to Winter Harbor, Maine, at coordinates 44-23-42 and 68-05-06. Canadian concurrence has been obtained for both allotments. The applicants for Channel 288B1 at Islesboro must conform with the technical requirements of ยง73.1030(c)(1)-(5) of the Rules regarding protection to the Commission's monitoring station at Belfast, Maine. With this action, this proceeding is terminated.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective February 14, 1994. The window period for filing applications for Channel 288B1 at Isleboro, Maine, and Channel 249A at Winter Harbor, Maine, will open on February 15, 1994, and close on March 17, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Kathleen Scheuerle, Mass Media Bureau, (202) 634-6530.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a summary of the Commission's Report and Order, MM Docket No. 93-203, adopted December 9, 1993, and released December 30, 1993. The full text of this Commission decision is available for inspection and copying during normal business hours in the Commission's Reference Center (room 239), 1919 M Street NW., Washington, DC. The complete text of this decision may also be purchased from the Commission's copy contactors, International Transcription Services, Inc., 2100 M Street NW., suite 140, Washington, DC 20037, (202) 857-3800.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 47 CFR Part 73</textblock>
    <textblock>Radio broadcasting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 73 of title 47 of the Code of Federal Regulations is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 73 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>47 U.S.C. 154, 303.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง73.202</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 73.202(b), the Table of FM Allotments under Maine, is amended by adding Channel 288B1, Islesboro and Channel 249A, Winter Harbor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>47 CFR PART 73_[AMENDED]</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John A. Karouso,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Chief, Allocations Branch, Policy and Rules Division, Mass Media Bureau.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-953 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
