<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00068</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>519.770, 519.770-1, and 519.770-3</textblock>
    <textblock>[Removed]</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Sections 519.770, 519.770-1, and 519.770-3 are removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Section 552.219-72 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>552.219-72</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice to offerors of subcontracting plan requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>As prescribed in 519.708(a), insert the following provision:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice to Offerors of Subcontracting Plan Requirements (XXX 1993)</textblock>
    <textblock>The General Services Administration (GSA) is committed to assuring that maximum practicable opportunity is provided to small, small disadvantaged, and women-owned small business concerns to participate in the performance of this contract consistent with its efficient performance. GSA expects any subcontracting plan submitted pursuant to FAR 52.219-9 to reflect this commitment. Consequently, an offeror, other than a small business concern, before being awarded a contract exceeding $500,000 ($1,000,000 for construction) will be required to demonstrate that its subcontracting plan represents an aggressive program for involving small, small disadvantaged, and women-owned small business concerns as subcontractors in the performance of this contract.</textblock>
    <textblock>(End of Provision)</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Section 552.219-73 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>552.219-73</textblock>
    <textblock>Preparation, submission, and negotiation of subcontracting plans.</textblock>
    <textblock>As prescribed in 519.708(b), insert the following provision:</textblock>
    <textblock>Preparation, Submission, and Negotiation of Subcontracting Plans (XXX 1993)</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) An offeror, other than a small business concern, submitting an offer that exceeds $500,000 ($1,000,000 for construction) shall submit a subcontracting plan with its initial offer. The subcontracting plan will be negotiated concurrently with price and any required technical and management proposals, unless the offeror submits a previously-approved commercial products plan. Maximum practicable utilization of small, small disadvantaged, and women-owned small business concerns as subcontractors is a matter of national interest with both social and economic benefits. It is the General Services Administration's (GSA's) expectation that an offeror's subcontracting plan will reflect a commitment to assuring that small, small disadvantaged, and women-owned small business concerns are provided the maximum practicable opportunity, consistent with efficient contract performance, to participate as subcontractors in the performance of the resulting contract.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) GSA believes that this potential contract provides significant opportunities for the use of small, small disadvantaged, and women-owned small business concerns as subcontractors. Consequently, in addressing the eleven elements described at FAR 52.219-9(d), the offeror shall demonstrate that its subcontracting plan represents an aggressive program for involving small, small disadvantaged, and women-owned small business concerns in performing the contract. The subcontracting plan shall include a description of the offeror's subcontracting strategies used in any previous contracts, significant achievements, and how this plan will build upon those earlier achievements. Additionally, the offeror shall demonstrate through its plan that it understands the small business subcontracting program's objectives, GSA's expectations, and actions necessary to meet these goals and expectations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) In determining the acceptability of any subcontracting plan, the Contracting Officer will_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Review the plan to verify that the offeror has demonstrated an understanding of the small business subcontracting program's objectives and GSA's expectations with the respect to the program and has included all the information, goals, and assurances required by FAR 52.219-9;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Consider previous goals and achievements of contractors in the same industry;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Consider information and potential sources obtained from agencies administering national and local preference programs and other advocacy groups in evaluating whether the goals stated in the plan adequately reflect the anticipated potential for subcontracting to small, small disadvantaged, and women-owned small business concerns; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Review, when applicable, the offeror's description of its strategies, historical performance and significant achievements in placing subcontracts for the same or similar products or services with small, small disadvantaged, and women-owned small business concerns.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Failure to submit to subcontracting plan and/or correct deficiencies in the plan within the time specified by the Contracting Officer shall make the offeror ineligible for award.</textblock>
    <textblock>(End of Provision)</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Section 552.219-74 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>552.219-74</textblock>
    <textblock>Goals for subcontracting plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>As prescribed in 519.708(c), insert the following provision:</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
