<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00170</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00102</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>An environmental assessment (EA) of this proposed action has been completed</textblock>
    <textblock>(enclosed). Based on the EA, and in accordance with the guidelines for determining</textblock>
    <textblock>the significance of proposed federal actions (40 CFR 1508.27) and EPA criteria for</textblock>
    <textblock>initiating an environmental impact statement (EIS) (40 CFR 6.605), EPA has concluded</textblock>
    <textblock>that the proposed General NPDES permit will not result in a significant effect on the</textblock>
    <textblock>human environment. The proposed permit will not significantly affect land use patterns</textblock>
    <textblock>or population, wetlands or floodplains, threatened or endangered species, farmlands,</textblock>
    <textblock>ecologically critical areas, historic resources, air quality, water quality, noise levels, fish</textblock>
    <textblock>and wildlife resources, nor will it conflict with local, regional, or state land use plans or</textblock>
    <textblock>policies. The proposed permit conforms with all applicable federal statutes and</textblock>
    <textblock>executive orders.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed General Permit includes the same technology-based permit limits,</textblock>
    <textblock>established by regulation (40 CFR part 440, subpart M), as the individual permits</textblock>
    <textblock>currently do. The recirculation of process wastewater is required and the settleable</textblock>
    <textblock>solids concentration of the allowable discharge (i.e. excess water) is limited to 0.2</textblock>
    <textblock>milliliters per liter. Water quality-based limits are also included in the proposed permit.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed permit covers, in addition to conventional open-cut placer mining</textblock>
    <textblock>operations, placer mining operations utilizing hydraulic methods to remove</textblock>
    <textblock>overburden, and suction dredges. The proposed permit limits for the hydraulic</textblock>
    <textblock>overburden removal operations are based on the state sediment standard and best</textblock>
    <textblock>professional judgment and are the same as the limits for the conventional operations. The limits for the suction dredge operations would be based on best professional</textblock>
    <textblock>judgment.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed General Permit would reduce the yearly administrative burden of</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA associated with the processing of numerous individual permits. Because the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed General Permit and individual permits include essentially the same</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements, the primary impact related to permit type is expected to be</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative. No negative impacts to EPA, other agencies or operators are</textblock>
    <textblock>expected.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed General NPDES Permit may contribute to an improvement in</textblock>
    <textblock>environmental conditions because it would reduce the permitting administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>workload thus making available limited time that could be used for higher priority</textblock>
    <textblock>activities, such as permit compliance and inspections. The inclusion of suction dredge</textblock>
    <textblock>operations in the General Permit will improve the monitoring and compliance of these</textblock>
    <textblock>operations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the proposed action, the new source placer mining proposals requesting</textblock>
    <textblock>coverage under the General Permit would continue to be subject to individual NEPA</textblock>
    <textblock>reviews. This will enable EPA to evaluate the site-specific and cumulative impacts</textblock>
    <textblock>associated with the individual projects. Where an EA concludes that significant</textblock>
    <textblock>impacts are not anticipated, a Finding of No Significant Impact would be issued and</textblock>
    <textblock>the new source project would be granted coverage under the General Permit. If EPA</textblock>
    <textblock>determines that significant impacts from a proposed new source project may occur, an</textblock>
    <textblock>EIS would be prepared prior to EPA's final permit decision. Therefore the site-specific</textblock>
    <textblock>impacts of those projects would continue to be evaluated and considered prior to the</textblock>
    <textblock>permit actions. An individual permit may also be required by EPA in lieu of coverage</textblock>
    <textblock>under the General Permit.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the above reasons EPA has determined that an EIS will not be prepared for</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed action.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments pertaining to this Finding of No Significant Impact may be submitted to: Rick Seaborne, Environmental Protection Agency, Environmental Review Section, 1200 Sixth Avenue, WD-126, Seattle, WA 98101.</textblock>
    <textblock>No administrative action will be taken for at least 30 days after the release of this</textblock>
    <textblock>Finding of No Significant Impact. EPA will fully consider all comments before taking</textblock>
    <textblock>final action.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣␣Sincerely,</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Charles E. Findley,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Water Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
