<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00151</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00094</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Environmental Impact Statement: Multiple Counties, Alabama</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Highway Administration (FHWA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of intent.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FHWA is issuing this notice to advise the public that two Environmental Impact Statements will be prepared for a proposed highway that will traverse the northern section of the State of Alabama.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Joe D. Wilkerson, Division Administrator, Federal Highway Administration, 500 Eastern Boulevard, suite 200, Montgomery, Alabama 36117-2018, Telephone (205)223-7370.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FHWA, in cooperation with the State of Alabama Department of Transportation, will prepare two Environmental Impact Statements (EIS's) for Project DPS-A002(001). The proposal is to construct a multi-lane, limited access roadway that will function as a major segment of a Memphis to Atlanta transportation corridor. The facility will provide a direct link between the two metropolitan areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>The facility, approximately 273.58 kilometers (170 miles) in length, will be divided into two segments for location studies and assessment of environmental impacts. Two Environmental Impact Statements will be prepared, one for the western part of the route, approximately 120.7 kilometer (75 miles) in length, from the Alabama/Mississippi State line and extending to an undermined point near Interstate Highway 65 near the center of Alabama and the second Impact Statement written for the eastern part of the project, approximately 152.9 kilometers (95 miles) in length, beginning at an undetermined point near Interstate Highway 65 near Huntsville, Alabama, and extending to the Alabama/Georgia border. There will be coordination in the location and environmental studies to establish a common location at I-65.</textblock>
    <textblock>Alternatives under consideration include: (1) Alternate route locations, (2) a no action alternative, and (3) postponing the action Alternative.</textblock>
    <textblock>Letters describing the proposed action and soliciting comments will be sent to appropriate Federal, State, and local agencies, and to private organizations and citizens who have previously expressed or are known to have an interest in this proposal. A series of public meetings will be held beginning in early 1994. In addition, public hearings will also be held. Public notice will be given of the time and place of the meetings and hearings. The Draft Environmental Impact Statements will be available for public and agency review and comment prior to the public hearings.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
