<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00087</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>By allowing a filing of a claim on the date ``collection of</textblock>
    <textblock>the loan is stayed''_the date of the filing of the petition by</textblock>
    <textblock>the borrower, or, in a Chapter 13 case, by the endorser or the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower_rather than the date a borrower receives a discharge,</textblock>
    <textblock>the statute might be read to permit claims to be submitted if an</textblock>
    <textblock>endorser files, rather than, as under prior law, only in borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>bankruptcies. Nothing in the amendments suggested that such a</textblock>
    <textblock>result was intended, and the proposed regulations would permit</textblock>
    <textblock>the submission of a bankruptcy claim only in the case of a</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower bankruptcy.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations would continue to require lenders</textblock>
    <textblock>to file proofs of claim in the bankruptcy proceeding, unless the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency directs otherwise or the holder is officially</textblock>
    <textblock>notified by the court that no assets are available for</textblock>
    <textblock>distribution. If the guaranty agency later receives notice that</textblock>
    <textblock>assets have become available, the guarantor must file a proof of</textblock>
    <textblock>claim at that point.</textblock>
    <textblock>Participants in the negotiated rulemaking proceedings noted</textblock>
    <textblock>that a growing number of discharges were being received by</textblock>
    <textblock>borrowers who file sequential bankruptcy petitions, particularly</textblock>
    <textblock>those who first file for relief in Chapter 13. During the</textblock>
    <textblock>pendency of the prior bankruptcy case, loans in repayment less</textblock>
    <textblock>than seven years are non-dischargeable without proof of undue</textblock>
    <textblock>hardship, yet cannot be enforced by the holder according to their</textblock>
    <textblock>original terms; little or nothing may be paid on those loans</textblock>
    <textblock>during the proceeding. Rather than attempting to show that</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment would constitute an undue hardship, or negotiating an</textblock>
    <textblock>income-sensitive repayment arrangement with the holder, borrowers</textblock>
    <textblock>who complete their Chapter 13 proceeding may then file a second</textblock>
    <textblock>bankruptcy petition, making sure that the second is filed more</textblock>
    <textblock>than seven years after the loan entered repayment.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bankruptcy Code excludes the period of ``any applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>suspension of the repayment period'' from the seven-year period</textblock>
    <textblock>during which loans are dischargeable only for undue hardship. 11</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S.C. 523(a)(8)(A). If the term ``suspension of the repayment</textblock>
    <textblock>period'' is read, as these borrowers contend, to include only</textblock>
    <textblock>forbearance or deferments granted by the holder of the loan, the</textblock>
    <textblock>reality of the forbearance imposed by virtue of the automatic</textblock>
    <textblock>stay in the prior bankruptcy_which barred enforcement of the</textblock>
    <textblock>loan according to its terms during the pendency of the bankruptcy_would be ignored, and borrowers who have neither made the</textblock>
    <textblock>required seven-year attempt to repay nor demonstrated undue</textblock>
    <textblock>hardship would obtain a discharge in the second bankruptcy. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary does not consider this interpretation of the statute to</textblock>
    <textblock>be consistent with its purpose, and the only court that has</textblock>
    <textblock>addressed this precise issue has concluded that the period during</textblock>
    <textblock>which enforcement of a loan is stayed in a prior bankruptcy is an</textblock>
    <textblock>``applicable suspension of the repayment period'' for purposes of</textblock>
    <textblock>computing the seven-year period for a subsequent bankruptcy.</textblock>
    <textblock>In</textblock>
    <textblock>re Saburah,</textblock>
    <textblock>136 B.R. 246, 254 (Bankr. C.D. Cal. 1992).</textblock>
    <textblock>In light of the above discussion, the Secretary proposes to</textblock>
    <textblock>interpret the term ``applicable suspension of the repayment</textblock>
    <textblock>period'' to include periods during which the automatic stay in a</textblock>
    <textblock>bankruptcy proceeding is in effect. The Secretary further</textblock>
    <textblock>recognizes that a borrower who in fact meets his or her</textblock>
    <textblock>obligation under the original repayment agreement during the</textblock>
    <textblock>bankruptcy has acted in a manner consistent with the intent of</textblock>
    <textblock>the statute, and this proposed interpretation would not regard</textblock>
    <textblock>the period of the first bankruptcy as a period of suspension of</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment for the borrower.</textblock>
    <textblock>The death and bankruptcy requirements in proposed ยง682.402</textblock>
    <textblock>are taken directly from the HEA. There is no change to the</textblock>
    <textblock>current disability cancellation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Closed School Cancellations</textblock>
    <textblock>The closed school cancellation provision is taken, in large</textblock>
    <textblock>part, directly from the mandates of the HEA, although the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations reflect some areas of necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>interpretation. The discussion that follows is grouped into</textblock>
    <textblock>three major areas where the Secretary and the negotiators had</textblock>
    <textblock>discretion to interpret the statutory closed school cancellation</textblock>
    <textblock>provision:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Student Withdrawal Prior to the Closing of the School</textblock>
    <textblock>There was unanimous agreement among the negotiators and the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary that it would be inequitable to strictly limit a closed</textblock>
    <textblock>school cancellation to only those students who were in attendance</textblock>
    <textblock>at the school on the date that the school officially closed. As</textblock>
    <textblock>discussed earlier, conditions at the school immediately preceding</textblock>
    <textblock>its closing may have caused a deterioration in the educational</textblock>
    <textblock>program that would have prompted a student to withdraw. Such a</textblock>
    <textblock>student should not lose entitlement to a loan cancellation</textblock>
    <textblock>because of his or her prescience or inability to tolerate the</textblock>
    <textblock>school's deterioration. To balance the interests of students and</textblock>
    <textblock>the federal taxpayers (who ultimately must pay the cost of each</textblock>
    <textblock>cancelled loan), the Secretary proposes to limit this withdrawal</textblock>
    <textblock>period to not more than 90 days prior to the date the school</textblock>
    <textblock>closed.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Student Use of Teach-out or Transfer of Academic</textblock>
    <textblock>Credits</textblock>
    <textblock>As discussed earlier, the Secretary does not believe that a</textblock>
    <textblock>student who completed the educational program for which the loan</textblock>
    <textblock>was intended, even though the completion occurred through a</textblock>
    <textblock>teach-out at another school or by the student's transfer of</textblock>
    <textblock>academic credits earned at the closed school, should be able to</textblock>
    <textblock>avoid repaying that loan. The student is not required to</textblock>
    <textblock>transfer those credits or make use of a teach-out opportunity,</textblock>
    <textblock>but if the student chooses to do so, then the Secretary believes</textblock>
    <textblock>that, because the student was able to complete the educational</textblock>
    <textblock>program, it would be unfair to require the Federal taxpayer to</textblock>
    <textblock>pay the student's loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Student Statement Requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary believes that a statement made by the student</textblock>
    <textblock>under penalty of perjury demonstrating eligibility for a closed</textblock>
    <textblock>school discharge should be obtained from the student to assist</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary or the Secretary's designees in pursuing claims</textblock>
    <textblock>against the closed school. Without this statement, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's ability to protect the interests of the Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>taxpayer would be frustrated.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
