<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00182</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00102</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>J. ``Make-up Water'' means that volume of water needed to replace</textblock>
    <textblock>process water lost due to evaporation and seepage in order to maintain</textblock>
    <textblock>the quantity necessary for the operation of the beneficiation process.</textblock>
    <textblock>K. ``New Water'' means water from any discrete source such as a river,</textblock>
    <textblock>creek, lake or well which is deliberately allowed or brought into the plant</textblock>
    <textblock>site.</textblock>
    <textblock>L. ``Plant Site'' means the area occupied by the mine, necessary haulage</textblock>
    <textblock>ways from the mine to the beneficiation process, the beneficiation area,</textblock>
    <textblock>the area occupied by the wastewater treatment storage facilities and the</textblock>
    <textblock>storage areas for waste materials and solids removed from the</textblock>
    <textblock>wastewaters during treatment.</textblock>
    <textblock>M. ``Receiving Water'' means waters such as lakes, rivers, streams, creeks, or any other surface waters which receive wastewater discharges.</textblock>
    <textblock>N. ``Severe property damage'' means substantial physical damage to</textblock>
    <textblock>property, damage to the treatment facilities which causes them to</textblock>
    <textblock>become inoperable, or substantial and permanent loss of natural</textblock>
    <textblock>resources which can reasonably be expected to occur in the absence</textblock>
    <textblock>of a bypass. Severe property damage does not mean economic loss</textblock>
    <textblock>caused by delays in production.</textblock>
    <textblock>O. ``Short circuiting'' means ineffective settling ponds due to inadequate or insufficient retention characteristics, excessive sediment deposition, embankment infiltration/percolation, lack of maintenance, etc.</textblock>
    <textblock>P. ``Upset'' means an exceptional incident in which there is unintentional and temporary noncompliance with technology-based permit effluent limitations because of factors beyond the reasonable control of the</textblock>
    <textblock>permittee. An upset does not include noncompliance to the extent</textblock>
    <textblock>caused by operational error, improperly designed treatment facilities,</textblock>
    <textblock>inadequate treatment facilities, lack of preventive maintenance, or</textblock>
    <textblock>careless or improper operation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Q. ``Wastewater'' means all water used in and resulting from the</textblock>
    <textblock>beneficiation process (including but not limited to the water used to</textblock>
    <textblock>move the ore to and through the beneficiation process, the water used</textblock>
    <textblock>to aid in classification, and the water used in gravity separation), mine</textblock>
    <textblock>drainage, and infiltration and drainage waters which commingle with</textblock>
    <textblock>mine drainage or waters resulting from the beneficiation process.</textblock>
    <textblock>IX. Special Conditions_Effluent Limits Below Detection Levels</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Reporting Levels</textblock>
    <textblock>1. For purpose of reporting, the permittee shall use the reporting threshold equivalent to the minimum level (ML). The ML is defined as the</textblock>
    <textblock>concentration in a sample equivalent to the concentration of the lowest</textblock>
    <textblock>calibration standard analyzed in a specific analytical procedure,</textblock>
    <textblock>assuming that all the method-specified sample weights, volumes and</textblock>
    <textblock>processing steps have been followed. As such, the permittee must</textblock>
    <textblock>utilize a standards equivalent to the concentration of the ML for arsenic</textblock>
    <textblock>which is 4 μg/L.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. For the purpose of reporting on the DMR, actual analytical results</textblock>
    <textblock>should be reported whenever possible. All analytical values at or above</textblock>
    <textblock>the ML shall be reported as the measured value. When the results</textblock>
    <textblock>cannot be quantified, values below the method detection limit (1 μg/L)</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be reported as zero (0 μg/L) and values above the method</textblock>
    <textblock>detection level and below the ML shall be reported as 1/2 the ML or</textblock>
    <textblock>2 μg/L.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Reporting Details</textblock>
    <textblock>In the ``Comment'' section of the DMR, the permittee</textblock>
    <textblock>shall report the lowest calibration standard used and the ML achieved.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
