<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00053</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00028</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Responsible Agency: Office of Federal Activities, General Information (202) 260-5076 Or (202) 260-5075. Weekly receipt of Environmental Impact Statements Filed January 03, 1994 Through January 07, 1994 Pursuant to 40 CFR 1506.9.</textblock>
    <textblock>EIS No. 940000, Draft EIS, IBR, AZ, Glen Canyon Dam Operation, Implementation, Colorado River Storage Project, Funding and COE Section 10 and 404 Permits, Coconino County, AZ, Due: April 11, 1994, Contact: Lee J. McQuivey (801) 524-5479.</textblock>
    <textblock>EIS No. 940001, Final EIS, BLM, AK, Fort Wainwright Maneuver Area, Resource Management Plan for Nonmilitary Uses, AK, Due: February 15, 1994, Contact: Jim Ducker (907) 271-3369.</textblock>
    <textblock>EIS No. 940002, Final EIS, BLM, AK, Fort Greely Maneuver Area and Air Drop Zone, Resource Management Plan for Nonmilitary Uses, AK, Due: February 15, 1994, Contact: Jim Ducker (907) 271-3369.</textblock>
    <textblock>EIS No. 940003, Draft EIS, AFS, ID, Lower Elkhorn Timber Sale, Harvesting Timber and Road Construction, Payette National Forest, New Meadows Ranger District, Idaho County, ID, Due: March 15, 1994, Contact: Mike Balboni (208) 634-0629.</textblock>
    <textblock>EIS No. 940004, Final EIS, BLM, AZ, Kingman Resource Area, Resource Management Plan, Implementation, Mohave, Yavapi and Coconino, AZ, Due: February 14, 1994, Contact: Ken R. Drew (602) 757-3161.</textblock>
    <textblock>EIS No. 940005, Revised Draft EIS, COE, FL, Fort Pierce Harbor Navigation Improvement Project, Additional Information concerning Plan Modifications, Indian River, St. Lucie County, FL, Due: February 28, 1994, Contact: Jonathan D. Moulding (904) 232-2286.</textblock>
    <textblock>EIS No. 940006, Draft EIS, UAF, CA, Castle Air Force Base (AFB) Disposal and Reuse, Implementation, Merced County, CA, Due: March 02, 1994, Contact: Ltc. Gary Baumgartel (210) 536-3907.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[ER-FRL-4707-4]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Environmental Impact Statements; Notice of Availability</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard E. Sanderson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Federal Activities.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1006 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE: 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
