<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00049</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Official policy requiring that organizations receiving Federal highway safety program grant funds have and enforce an employee safety belt use policy; and</textblock>
    <textblock>Encouragement for automobile insurers to offer economic incentives for policy holders to wear safety belts, to secure small children in child safety seats, and to purchase cars equipped with air bags.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Enforcement Program</textblock>
    <textblock>Each State should have a strong law enforcement program, coupled with public information and education, to increase safety belt and child safety seat use. Essential components of a law enforcement program include:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written, enforced belt use policies for law enforcement agencies with sanctions for noncompliance to protect law enforcement officers from harm and for officers to serve as role models for the motoring public;</textblock>
    <textblock>Vigorous enforcement of public safety belt use and child safety seat laws, including citations and warnings;</textblock>
    <textblock>Accurate reporting of occupant protection system information on accident report forms, including use or non-use of belts, type of belt, and presence of and deployment of air bag;</textblock>
    <textblock>Public information and education (PI&amp;E) campaigns to inform the public about occupant protection laws and related enforcement activities;</textblock>
    <textblock>Routine monitoring of citation rates for non-use of safety belts and child safety seats; and</textblock>
    <textblock>Certification of an occupant protection training course for both basic and in-service training by the Police Officer Standards and Training (POST) board.</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Public Information and Education Program</textblock>
    <textblock>As part of each State's public information and education program, the State should enlist the support of a variety of media, including mass media, to improve public awareness and knowledge about safety belts, air bags, and child safety seats. To sustain or increase rates of safety belt and child safety seat use, a well-organized, effectively managed public information program should:</textblock>
    <textblock>Identify and target specific audiences, (e.g., low-use, high risk motorists) and develop messages appropriate for these audiences;</textblock>
    <textblock>Address the enforcement of the State's belt use and child passenger safety laws; the safety benefits of regular, correct safety belt (both manual and automatic) and child safety seat use; and the additional protection provided by air bags;</textblock>
    <textblock>Capitalize on special events, such as nationally recognized safety weeks and local enforcement campaigns;</textblock>
    <textblock>Coordinate different materials and media campaigns where practicable, (e.g., by using a common theme and logo);</textblock>
    <textblock>Use national themes and materials to the fullest extent possible;</textblock>
    <textblock>Publicize belt-use surveys and other relevant statistics;</textblock>
    <textblock>Encourage news media to report belt use and non-use in motor vehicle crashes;</textblock>
    <textblock>Involve media representatives in planning and disseminating public information campaigns;</textblock>
    <textblock>Encourage private sector groups to incorporate belt-use messages into their media campaigns;</textblock>
    <textblock>Take advantage of all media outlets: television, radio, print, signs, billboards, theaters, sports events, health fairs; and</textblock>
    <textblock>Evaluate all media campaign efforts.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
