<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00105</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00065</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Samuel Lint; A-368.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-368 described as follows: Beginning at the Northeast corner of said A-368; Thence, S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>’ E., 1200 feet, along the East line of said A-368; Thence, S. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○09</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 850 feet; Thence, N. 11</textblock>
    <textblock>○38</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1300 feet, along the East right-of-way line of U.S. Highway 69 and 287; Thence, Easterly, approximately 1200 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning at the point of intersection of the West right-of-way line of U.S. Highway 69 and 287 with the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 10</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>42</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1750 feet, along the West right-of-way line of U.S. Highway 69 and 287 to the point of intersection of said West right-of-way of U.S. Highway 69 and 287 with the East right-of-way line of the Southern Pacific Railroad; Thence, N. 20</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1800 feet, along the East right-of-way line of the Southern Pacific Railroad; Thence, Easterly, approximately 250 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning at the Northwest corner of said A-368; Thence, Easterly, approximately 1250 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 20</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1200 feet, along the Westerly right-of-way line of Southern Pacific Railroad; Thence, S. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○09</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1325 feet; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○32</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1050 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>James U. Richardson; A-436.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-436 described as follows: Beginning at the Northeast corner of said A-436; Thence, S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○14</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 700 feet, along the East line of said A-436; Thence, N. 49</textblock>
    <textblock>○04</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 400 feet; Thence, N. 71</textblock>
    <textblock>○14</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2000 feet; Thence, West, 2250 feet; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○47</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2700 feet, along the East line of the tract of land now or formerly owned by G.D. Flowers, A-436-6; Thence, S. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1300 feet, along the North line of said A-436-6; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○47</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1600 feet, along the West line of said A-436; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 9000 feet along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Sam Overstreet; A-851.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-851 described as follows: Beginning on the West line of said A-851 at a point which lies N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○47</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1150 feet, from the Southwest corner of said A-851; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○37</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 250 feet, along the West line of said A-851; Thence, Northeasterly, approximately 4000 feet along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○47</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1600 feet, along the East line of said A-851; Thence, S. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1250 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Rodriguez; A-434.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-434 described as follows: Beginning at the Southwest corner of A-434; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○19</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 500 feet, along the West line of said A-434; Thence, N. 45</textblock>
    <textblock>○56</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1800 feet; Thence, S. 80</textblock>
    <textblock>○41</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1450 feet; Thence, S. 01</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 900 feet; Thence, Northwesterly and Southwesterly, along the northerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Edward Lubititet; A-366.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-366 described as follows: Beginning at the Southwest corner of said A-366; Thence, N. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1000 feet, along the West line of said A-366; Thence, S. 82</textblock>
    <textblock>○53</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 3475 feet; Thence, S. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1300 feet, along the East line of said A-366; Thence, Westerly, approximately 4500 feet along the northerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Jacob Buckman; A-85.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-85 described as follows: Beginning at the Northwest corner of said A-85; Thence, Easterly, approximately 3500 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○11</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 350 feet, along the East line of said A-85; Thence, N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○10</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 3275 feet; Thence, N. 02</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 850 feet, along the West line of said A-85, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Thomas J. Hatton; A-279.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-279 described as follows: Beginning at the Southwest corner of said A-279; Thence, N. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2000 feet, along the West line of said A-279; Thence, S. 59</textblock>
    <textblock>○47</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 3200 feet; Thence, S. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1000 feet, along the East line of said A-279; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 3000 feet along the northerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Luke Bryan; A-76.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-76 described as follows: Beginning at the Northeast corner of said A-76; Thence, S. 02</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 850 feet along the East line of said A-76; Thence, N. 38</textblock>
    <textblock>○02</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1025 feet; Thence, S. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○36</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1300 feet; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○15</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 600 feet, along the West line of said A-76; Thence, Southeasterly, 2500 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>William Hamilton; A-266.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of said A-266 described as follows: Beginning at the Southwest corner of said A-266; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1300 feet, along the West line of said A-266; Thence, S. 75</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2050 feet; Thence, S. 04</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2000 feet, along the East line of said A-266; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 3250 feet, along the northerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Lewis Andrews; A-65.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-65 described as follows: Beginning at the Northeast corner of said A-65; Thence, S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○15</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 600 feet, along the East line of said A-65, Thence, S. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○36</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 900 feet; Thence, N. 14</textblock>
    <textblock>○35</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1275 feet; Thence, N. 39</textblock>
    <textblock>○12</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1125 feet; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○15</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 350 feet, along the West line of said A-65; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 3000 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Thomas Penny; A-424.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
