<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00047</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Other losses were precipitated by prior deterioration around windows and</textblock>
    <textblock>doors that had allowed moisture to enter, thereby weakening the resistance of</textblock>
    <textblock>surrounding wood framing and floor decking. Apparently this deterioration was</textblock>
    <textblock>a result of inadequate design or enforcement practices, or a combination of</textblock>
    <textblock>both. In some manufactured homes the loss of opening protection resulted in</textblock>
    <textblock>increased internal pressures within the buildings, which contributed to the</textblock>
    <textblock>failure of interior components including ceilings. In other cases, entire</textblock>
    <textblock>sections of sliding glass doors on leeward walls were literally sucked out of</textblock>
    <textblock>their frames because of inadequate resistance of the combined assembly to the</textblock>
    <textblock>wind forces imposed during Hurricane Andrew.</textblock>
    <textblock>Edges and corners of roofs and endwalls of manufactured homes appeared</textblock>
    <textblock>to have been particularly vulnerable to the high wind forces, according to the</textblock>
    <textblock>damage typically reported in these areas. Structural failures of endwalls</textblock>
    <textblock>also occurred, but the presence of nearby interior shearwalls prevented</textblock>
    <textblock>further losses (though not all designs are provided with interior shearwalls</textblock>
    <textblock>in the vicinity of the endwall). However, in many other cases, the entire</textblock>
    <textblock>superstructure was completely removed from the floor system.</textblock>
    <textblock>Numerous anchor system failures were reported in the areas subjected to</textblock>
    <textblock>the highest wind speeds. Many of the systems failed due to improper</textblock>
    <textblock>installation or the type of anchor used. In addition, anchor capacity</textblock>
    <textblock>appeared to have been reduced further because of the saturated condition of</textblock>
    <textblock>the soil.</textblock>
    <textblock>Summary of NIST Report</textblock>
    <textblock>As part of its review of the adequacy of the Federal Manufactured</textblock>
    <textblock>Housing Construction and Safety Standards (FMHCSS), the Department contracted</textblock>
    <textblock>for a study by Dr. Richard D. Marshall of the National Institute of Standards</textblock>
    <textblock>and Technology (NIST) [Report NISTIR 5189, May 1993]. According to Dr.</textblock>
    <textblock>Marshall and several other investigative reports, damage to manufactured homes</textblock>
    <textblock>in Hurricane Andrew ranged from loss of roofing to total destruction. In</textblock>
    <textblock>general, HUD-labeled units suffered less damage than did pre-HUD units.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, conventional residential construction adjacent to manufactured home</textblock>
    <textblock>parks performed better, in some instances significantly better, than did</textblock>
    <textblock>manufactured homes. Based on wind speed assessments and damage surveys, it</textblock>
    <textblock>appears that HUD-labeled manufactured homes began to experience damage to roof</textblock>
    <textblock>and wall coverings at fastest-mile wind speeds of up to 95 mph (43 m/s), and</textblock>
    <textblock>significant structural damage at wind speeds of from 100 to 120 mph (45 to 54</textblock>
    <textblock>m/s).</textblock>
    <textblock>Commonly observed failures included loss of roof membranes and blow-off</textblock>
    <textblock>of roof sheathing, failure of uplift straps at truss-to-wall connections where</textblock>
    <textblock>staple crowns pulled through the strap, loss of cladding on endwalls and near</textblock>
    <textblock>corners where large negative (suction) pressures developed, loss of</textblock>
    <textblock>appurtenances with resultant missile damage and damage to the primary house</textblock>
    <textblock>unit at connection points, complete separation of the superstructure from the</textblock>
    <textblock>floor and chassis frame, and loss of the complete unit because of the failure</textblock>
    <textblock>of tiedown straps or the withdrawal of soil anchors. The NIST report also</textblock>
    <textblock>pointed out that the capacity of the anchors appeared to have exceeded the</textblock>
    <textblock>marginal resistance of the superstructure, and that if the superstructure</textblock>
    <textblock>separation failures had not occurred, the number of anchor systems failures</textblock>
    <textblock>could have been much more widespread.</textblock>
    <textblock>In almost every case in Florida, some form of anchoring had been</textblock>
    <textblock>installed. Outside the area of strongest winds, there were relatively few</textblock>
    <textblock>anchor failures. Within the radius of strongest winds, anchor failures that</textblock>
    <textblock>were observed involved 2 ft. (610 mm) helical ground anchors (some embedded in</textblock>
    <textblock>about 3 cu.ft. (0.8 cu.m) of concrete) or rock anchors into coral. No</textblock>
    <textblock>failures of 4 ft. (1.2 m) helical anchors were noted. However, it is not</textblock>
    <textblock>clear that any anchors of that length were actually installed in the area</textblock>
    <textblock>subjected to the highest winds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Marshall of NIST compared wind load provisions of the current FMHCSS</textblock>
    <textblock>with the American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE) Standard ANSI/ASCE 7-88,</textblock>
    <textblock>the South Florida Building Code, the Standard Building Code, and wind design</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions proposed by the Manufactured Housing Institute. Based on these</textblock>
    <textblock>comparisons of design loads for manufactured housing units of typical</textblock>
    <textblock>dimension and geometry, considering the rationale for using importance factors</textblock>
    <textblock>and unreduced pressure coefficients, and in view of the fact that it is a true</textblock>
    <textblock>consensus standard, Dr. Marshall concluded that ANSI/ASCE</textblock>
    <textblock>7-88 should be the</textblock>
    <textblock>basis for updating the wind load requirements for manufactured housing. In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition, since the NIST study only addressed design loads, in the interest of</textblock>
    <textblock>safety and economy, it was also recommended that prescriptive requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed standard be consistent with the specified design loads and that</textblock>
    <textblock>testing and analysis to assure this consistency be conducted.</textblock>
    <textblock>ASCE 7-88: Consensus Procedures for Development and Adoption</textblock>
    <textblock>The ASCE, founded in 1852, is the oldest civil engineering organization</textblock>
    <textblock>in the United States and has a membership of more than 110,000. The ANSI/ASCE</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard 7-88, Minimum Design Loads for Buildings and Other Structures</textblock>
    <textblock>(November 1990) (ASCE 7-88, in this preamble), was developed by ASCE based on</textblock>
    <textblock>studies conducted at academic and research institutions in the United States</textblock>
    <textblock>and other parts of the world.</textblock>
    <textblock>ASCE 7-88 is the only truly consensus minimum design load standard</textblock>
    <textblock>currently available in the United States. The ASCE rules, approved by the</textblock>
    <textblock>American National Standards Institute (ANSI), require all standards committees</textblock>
    <textblock>to have a membership balanced between producers, consumers, building</textblock>
    <textblock>officials, and general interest groups. Each of these groups represents</textblock>
    <textblock>between 20% to 40% of the committee membership. At the time ASCE 7-88 was</textblock>
    <textblock>adopted, 89 members were on the standards committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>The approval or revision of an ASCE standard is an elaborate process,</textblock>
    <textblock>which involves extensive balloting and resolution of all negative votes. When</textblock>
    <textblock>a standard is to be adopted, the standards committee is broken down by</textblock>
    <textblock>expertise into task committees. Those task committees draft the standard and</textblock>
    <textblock>present it to the full standards committee for balloting. All objections</textblock>
    <textblock>within the standards committee are satisfied by one of three ways: (1) the</textblock>
    <textblock>objector agrees to withdraw the objection; (2) by a vote of 75%, the full</textblock>
    <textblock>committee accepts the objection and changes the standard; or (3) by a vote of</textblock>
    <textblock>75%, the full committee rejects the objection. The full committee then votes</textblock>
    <textblock>on the standard.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order for the standard to pass the full standards committee, at least</textblock>
    <textblock>65% of the committee membership must vote and 75% of those votes must be in</textblock>
    <textblock>the affirmative. Moreover, the affirmative votes cannot be less than 55% of</textblock>
    <textblock>the approved voting membership. After the standard passes the standards</textblock>
    <textblock>committee, it is issued to the public for further comment. As in the</textblock>
    <textblock>standards committee, all objections are individually considered and processed</textblock>
    <textblock>in the same manner (i.e., withdrawn or accepted or rejected by a vote of 75%</textblock>
    <textblock>of the standards committee). After a certain cutoff date and after all</textblock>
    <textblock>objections are addressed, the standard is published as an ASCE consensus</textblock>
    <textblock>standard.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
