<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00101</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00065</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the North line of A-30 at a point which lies N. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>29</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 7300 feet from the Northwest corner of said A-30; Thence, N. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>29</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 300 feet; Thence, Westerly, approximately 600 feet, along the northerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the North line of A-30 at a point which lies N. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>29</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 7700 feet from the Northwest corner of said A-30; Thence, N. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>29</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 811.83 feet; Thence, S. 18</textblock>
    <textblock>○41</textblock>
    <textblock>55</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1012.93 feet; Thence, N. 77</textblock>
    <textblock>○58</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 650 feet; Thence, West, 300 feet; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 1250 feet, along the easterly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, N. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>’29</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 300 feet, along the North line of A-30; Thence, Easterly, approximately 1000 feet along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the South line of A-30 at a point which lies N. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○42</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 6550 feet from the Northwest corner of the Henry Binns survey, A-6; Thence, Northwesterly and Northeasterly, approximately 11,000 feet, along the easterly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, N. 85</textblock>
    <textblock>○01</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 700 feet; Thence, S. 42</textblock>
    <textblock>○41</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 4900 feet; Thence, S. 37</textblock>
    <textblock>○15</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1425 feet; Thence, S. 32</textblock>
    <textblock>○14</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 657 feet; Thence, S. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○42</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 766 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>F. P. Elliott; A-18.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of said A-18 described as follows: Beginning on the North line of said A-18 at a point which lies N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○44</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 4488.81 feet, from the Northwest corner of said A-18, Thence, N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○44</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 3500 feet, along the North line of said A-18; Thence, S. 21</textblock>
    <textblock>○24</textblock>
    <textblock>28</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2352.86 feet; Thence, S. 14</textblock>
    <textblock>○00</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 400 feet; S. 14</textblock>
    <textblock>○02</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1250 feet; Thence, S. 33</textblock>
    <textblock>○45</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2500 feet; Thence, S. 14</textblock>
    <textblock>○40</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1150 feet; Thence, S. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>29</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 811.83 feet, along the South line of said A-18; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 11,750 feet, along the easterly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the North line of said A-18 at a point which lies N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○44</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2500 feet from the Northwest corner of said A-18; Thence, N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○44</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 988.81 feet, along the North line of said A-18; Thence, Southeasterly and Northeasterly approximately 500 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○44</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 600 feet, along the North line of A-18; Thence, Southeasterly 11,800 feet, along the westerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>29</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 300 feet, along the South line of said A-18; Thence, Northwesterly and Southwesterly, 800 feet, along the northerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>29</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1300 feet, along the South line of A-18; Thence, N. 16</textblock>
    <textblock>○41</textblock>
    <textblock>06</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 3455.80 feet; Thence, N. 00</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1900 feet; Thence, N. 60</textblock>
    <textblock>○58</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1850 feet; Thence, N. 48</textblock>
    <textblock>○46</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1006.93 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the North line of said A-18 at a point which lies N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○44</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 3588.81 feet from the Northwest corner of said A-18; Thence, N. 86</textblock>
    <textblock>○44</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 100 feet, along the North line of said A-18; Thence, Westerly, 150 feet, along the northerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning on the South line of said A-18 at a point which lies N. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>29</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 6850 feet from the Southwest corner of said A-18; Thence, Northeasterly and Southeasterly, approximately 500 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○07</textblock>
    <textblock>29</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 300 feet, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>A.A. Burell; A-5.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
