<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00125</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00074</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with Departmental policy, notice is hereby given that a proposed consent decree in</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Wauconda Sand &amp; Gravel Co.,</textblock>
    <textblock>was lodged on December 23, 1993 with the United States District Court for the Northern District of Illinois. The proposed consent decree would resolve civil claims that the United States has asserted against 17 defendants under Section 107 of CERCLA, 42 U.S.C. 9607, for reimbursement of response costs incurred in connection with the Wauconda Sand &amp; Gravel Site in Lake County, Illinois.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed consent decree requires defendants to pay $566,448.15 to the Hazardous Substances Superfund as reimbursement for response costs incurred at the Site through March 31, 1989. Under the proposed decree, this sum will be paid in two installments, the last of which is due within 180 days after entry of the consent decree. The proposed consent decree also requires defendants to reimburse oversight costs incurred by the United States Environmental Protection Agency (``U.S. EPA'') after March 31, 1992 in monitoring compliance with a December 19, 1989 administrative order issued pursuant to section 106 of CERCLA, 42 U.S.C. 9606. In addition, the proposed consent decree provides that defendants will reimburse any costs incurred by the United States in enforcing terms of the decree.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Justice will receive, for a period of thirty (30) days from the date of this publication, comments relating to the proposed consent decree. Comments should be addressed to the Assistant Attorney General, Environment and Natural Resources Division, Department of Justice, Washington, DC 20530, and should refer to</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Wauconda Sand &amp; Gravel Co.,</textblock>
    <textblock>No. 93-C-7637 (N.D. Ill.) and DOJ Ref. No. 90-11-2-153A.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed Consent Decree may be examined at any of the following offices: (1) The Office of the United States Attorney, Northern District of Illinois, 219 South Dearborn Street, Chicago Illinois 60604; (2) the Region V office of U.S. EPA, 77 West Jackson Blvd., Chicago, Illinois 60604-3590; and (3) the Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., 4th floor, Washington, DC 20005, (202) 624-0892. A copy of the proposed consent decree may be obtained in person or by mail from the Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., 4th floor, Washington, DC 20005. In requesting a copy please enclose a check in the amount of $75.75 (25 cents per page reproduction costs) payable to ``Consent Decree Library.''</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Lodging of Consent Decree Pursuant to the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (``CERCLA'')</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John C. Cruden,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Environmental Enforcement Section, Environment and Natural Resources Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-929 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
