<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00084</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary agrees with the sentiment expressed at the</textblock>
    <textblock>regional meetings and by the negotiators that conditions at the</textblock>
    <textblock>school immediately preceding its closing may cause a</textblock>
    <textblock>deterioration in the educational program that would cause a</textblock>
    <textblock>student to withdraw. A student who withdraws under these</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances should be deemed to have been unable to complete</textblock>
    <textblock>his or her educational program because of the school's closure.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of considering the borrower eligible for loan</textblock>
    <textblock>discharge, and to balance the interests of the borrower and the</textblock>
    <textblock>federal taxpayers (who ultimately must pay the cost of each</textblock>
    <textblock>cancelled loan), the Secretary proposes to limit this withdrawal</textblock>
    <textblock>period to not more than 90 days prior to the date the school</textblock>
    <textblock>closed.</textblock>
    <textblock>False Certification by a School of a Student's Eligibility To</textblock>
    <textblock>Borrow</textblock>
    <textblock>Participants in the regional meetings and the negotiators</textblock>
    <textblock>offered a wide variety of different actions by the school or the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower that they believed should be considered a false</textblock>
    <textblock>certification of eligibility to borrow; these included virtually</textblock>
    <textblock>every express or implied representation in any way related to the</textblock>
    <textblock>FFEL Program made by the student to the school, or by the school</textblock>
    <textblock>to the lender, guarantor, accrediting agency, state authority, or</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary. The Secretary has not adopted these views in the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations, because the language of the statute itself</textblock>
    <textblock>and its legislative history shows that the intended scope of the</textblock>
    <textblock>authority to discharge loan obligations is considerably narrower</textblock>
    <textblock>than these commenters suggest. The statute authorizes discharge</textblock>
    <textblock>only if the school made a false ``certification of the student's</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility,'' a term used only in the FFEL Program regulations,</textblock>
    <textblock>where it refers, only to those representations made by the school</textblock>
    <textblock>on the loan application itself regarding the status of the loan</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant (or the student for whom a parent wishes to obtain a</textblock>
    <textblock>PLUS loan) as an eligible student, 34 CFR 682.603; 682.201; and</textblock>
    <textblock>668.7, and not to other written representations that relate to</textblock>
    <textblock>the borrower's request for a loan, the school's participation in</textblock>
    <textblock>the FFEL Program, or the quality of the school</textblock>
    <textblock>s program,</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities, or placement services. The legislative history</textblock>
    <textblock>further explains that this provision was intended to provide</textblock>
    <textblock>relief where the student was ``left without the skills needed to</textblock>
    <textblock>obtain employment'' because of the false certification of</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility. H. R. Rep. No. 447, 102d Cong. 2d Sess. 52 (1991).</textblock>
    <textblock>The scope of the relief proposed by the Secretary here is guided</textblock>
    <textblock>by these two principles: that the false certification be that</textblock>
    <textblock>made by the school on the loan application regarding the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower's eligibility, and that the falsity of the certification</textblock>
    <textblock>be directly related to the failure to provide necessary skills</textblock>
    <textblock>for employment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Some negotiators urged that grounds for cancellation should</textblock>
    <textblock>include such falsifications as forgery of the borrower's</textblock>
    <textblock>signature on the loan application or on the loan disbursement</textblock>
    <textblock>check. However, these representations are not part of the</textblock>
    <textblock>process of the ``certification of the student's eligibility to</textblock>
    <textblock>borrow.'' Moreover, as a practical matter, a borrower victimized</textblock>
    <textblock>by a forged loan application can be injured only if the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower's endorsement is then forged on the loan disbursement</textblock>
    <textblock>check, or the check is negotiated without the borrower's</textblock>
    <textblock>endorsement at all. In either case, the borrower is generally</textblock>
    <textblock>not liable because such a loan is generally not legally</textblock>
    <textblock>enforceable. Therefore, not only does forgery not constitute a</textblock>
    <textblock>falsification in the loan ``certification'' process, but the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower who is the victim of a forgery and did not receive the</textblock>
    <textblock>proceeds of the loan already has a complete defense to repayment</textblock>
    <textblock>of the loan, and needs no cancellation relief under this new</textblock>
    <textblock>section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other negotiation participants suggested that erroneous</textblock>
    <textblock>school representations on a loan application regarding such</textblock>
    <textblock>matters as the borrower's (or student's) income, resources,</textblock>
    <textblock>family contribution, or recommended loan amount should be</textblock>
    <textblock>sufficient to constitute grounds for cancellation under this</textblock>
    <textblock>section. This kind of error could result in the borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>receiving a loan in a larger amount than he or she qualifies to</textblock>
    <textblock>receive. However, that student may nevertheless receive quality</textblock>
    <textblock>training at the school, and this kind of error or</textblock>
    <textblock>misrepresentation does not directly or invariably cause the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower to be ``left without the skills needed to obtain</textblock>
    <textblock>employment.'' In addition, errors or misstatements of the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower's financial need frequently result in the borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>receiving a loan either that only marginally exceeds the amount</textblock>
    <textblock>for which he or she actually qualified, or that qualified only</textblock>
    <textblock>for reinsurance but not for interest subsidies. Section 437(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>directs the discharge of the ``borrower's liability on the loan''_language that does not suggest that a partial discharge was</textblock>
    <textblock>contemplated or intended; discharging the borrower from financial</textblock>
    <textblock>obligation for the entire loan in such circumstances where the</textblock>
    <textblock>misstatement of financial need affects only part of the loan, or</textblock>
    <textblock>only the borrower's right to interest subsidies on all or part of</textblock>
    <textblock>that loan, is a remedy completely out of proportion to any injury</textblock>
    <textblock>suffered by the borrower as a result of the erroneous</textblock>
    <textblock>certification of his or her financial need. For these reasons,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary concludes that erroneous representations of the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower's financial need are not the kind of false</textblock>
    <textblock>certifications for which section 437 was intended to provide</textblock>
    <textblock>relief.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
