<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00058</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In South Carolina, it is believed that the state's rural initiative involving sheriffs contributed to a significant reduction in crashes, injuries, and fatalities in 1991 as compared to 1989. During that period, the state experienced 12,472 fewer crashes, 2,331 fewer injuries and 106 fewer fatalities. South Carolina's PSA campaign also received widespread recognition from across the State and is believed to have contributed to the reduction of crashes during the time the campaign was operational.</textblock>
    <textblock>During the first year of the St. Louis enforcement operation, ending September 1991, the average speed dropped from 62 mph to 61 mph on the 55 mph roadways in the metro area, as a result of the police agencies issuing 3,698 citations and 5,600 warnings for speeding during the Operation Gateway period. This cooperative program is continuing and is expected to result in further speed decreases on the involved roadways in the metro St. Louis area.</textblock>
    <textblock>Similarly, the speed control efforts targeting commercial vehicles appear to be effective, with early results from the 1987 Commercial Motor Vehicle Enforcement project in California indicating that all crashes where commercial vehicles were at fault decreased by 3.5% (from 810 in 1986 to 782 in 1987) in the five test sites throughout the State. Further, the number of accidents caused by commercial vehicles which resulted in injuries in these test sites also declined by 11.2% (from 259 in 1986 to 230 in 1987). Accompanying that reduction was a corresponding decrease in the societal cost of injuries and fatalities resulting from such crashes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Determination Regarding Speed Control</textblock>
    <textblock>The agencies believe it is clear that excessive speed does represent a significant traffic safety problem. Speeding is a problem throughout the country in all regions and on all types of roads. Numerous countermeasures have been developed that have proven to be most effective in addressing this problem.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agencies, therefore, tentatively conclude that Speed Control meets all requisite criteria and propose to include it as a National Priority Program Area.</textblock>
    <textblock>School Bus Safety as a National Priority Area</textblock>
    <textblock>Is School Bus Safety a Problem of National Concern?</textblock>
    <textblock>The safety of children in school buses has been a primary concern of parents and school systems ever since buses began to be used to transport children. That concern has helped develop school buses into the safest form of transportation in the country. According to the National Safety Council's ``Accident Facts'' (1991), during the 1989-90 school year, it is estimated that 380,000 buses were used to transport 22 million pupils approximately 3.8 billion miles (21 million miles per school day). The National Safety Council statistics also indicate fatality rates per hundred million passenger miles in 1989 were 1.12 for passenger cars and 0.04 for school buses.</textblock>
    <textblock>The relative safety of school buses is evident from the following table, which shows all vehicle occupant fatalities. Included are the number of preschool (0-4) and school-age children (5-18) who were fatally injured in motor vehicle crashes in 1990, and the type of vehicle in which they were riding at the time.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table 1._Occupant Fatalities by Vehicle Type and Age Group Fatal Accident Reporting System</textblock>
    <textblock>1990</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Total</textblock>
    <textblock>1Age of occupant</textblock>
    <textblock>20-4</textblock>
    <textblock>25-12</textblock>
    <textblock>213-18</textblock>
    <textblock>219+</textblock>
    <textblock>2Unknown</textblock>
    <textblock>Total</textblock>
    <textblock>37,134</textblock>
    <textblock>623</textblock>
    <textblock>716</textblock>
    <textblock>4,292</textblock>
    <textblock>31,466</textblock>
    <textblock>37</textblock>
    <textblock>Vehicle type:</textblock>
    <textblock>Passenger Car</textblock>
    <textblock>24,092</textblock>
    <textblock>476</textblock>
    <textblock>457</textblock>
    <textblock>3,042</textblock>
    <textblock>20,086</textblock>
    <textblock>31</textblock>
    <textblock>Light Truck/Van</textblock>
    <textblock>7,387</textblock>
    <textblock>101</textblock>
    <textblock>164</textblock>
    <textblock>701</textblock>
    <textblock>6,419</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>Medium Truck</textblock>
    <textblock>134</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
    <textblock>125</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>Heavy Truck</textblock>
    <textblock>571</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
    <textblock>556</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>Motorcycle</textblock>
    <textblock>3,244</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>27</textblock>
    <textblock>310</textblock>
    <textblock>2,904</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>School Bus</textblock>
    <textblock>13</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>Other Bus</textblock>
    <textblock>19</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>14</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>On/Off Road Vehicle</textblock>
    <textblock>1,214</textblock>
    <textblock>33</textblock>
    <textblock>35</textblock>
    <textblock>149</textblock>
    <textblock>997</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>Other Vehicle</textblock>
    <textblock>296</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>19</textblock>
    <textblock>55</textblock>
    <textblock>218</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>Unknown</textblock>
    <textblock>164</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>15</textblock>
    <textblock>141</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
