<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00070</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Rulemaking_Payment of Discounts by Motor Carriers of Property to the Nonpayer of Freight Charges</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>INTERSTATE COMMERCE COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>49 CFR Part 1312</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Ex Parte No. MC-180 (Sub-No. 2)]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interstate Commerce Commission (ICC).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Rule; Discontinue proceeding.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>By a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPR) served June 4, 1993, and published at 58 FR 32340, June 9, 1993, the Commission instituted this proceeding to determine whether off-bill discounting where it does or may result in a misrepresentation of shipping charges should be found to be an unreasonable practice or otherwise unlawful. However, the ``Negotiated Rates Act of 1993'' (Pub. L. 103-180), since has been enacted and amends subchapter IV of chapter 107 of title 49, United States Code, by adding section 10767. Section 10767 requires that the Commission establish regulations to prohibit, except for certain services, motor common and contract carriers of property from providing a reduction in a tariff rate or contract rate to a person who is a nonpayer of freight charges. The Commission must issue these regulations by April 2, 1994. Because section 10767 supersedes the NPR, the Commission is discontinuing this proceeding.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Charles E. Langyher, (202) 927-5160 or Ronald A. Hall, (202) 927-5595; TDD for hearing-impaired: (202) 927-5721.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission's rules implementing section 10767 are published in Ex Parte No. MC-180 (Sub-No. 3),</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations Implementing Section 7 of the ``Negotiated Rates Act of 1993''</textblock>
    <textblock>. To purchase a copy of the full decision, write to, call, or pick up in person from: Dynamic Concepts, Inc., room 2229, Interstate Commerce Commission Building, Washington, DC 20423. Telephone: (202) 289-4357/4359. [Assistance for the hearing-impaired is available through TDD service, (202) 927-5721.]</textblock>
    <textblock>This decision will not affect significantly the quality of the human environment or the conservation of energy resources.</textblock>
    <textblock>Decided: December 30, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Commission, Chairman McDonald, Vice Chairman Simmons, Commissioners Phillips and Philbin.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Sidney L. Strickland, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1011 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7035-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
