<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00018</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Decision Following Petition by Domestic Interested Party_Location of Country of Origin Marking for Frozen Produce Packages</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Customs Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>19 CFR Part 175</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[T.D. 94-5 Correction]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Customs Service, Treasury.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final interpretive rule; correction.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document corrects a previously published decision of Customs by adding Headquarters Ruling HQ 735085 (June 4, 1993), to the list of previous determinations affected by the decision.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>effective date:</textblock>
    <textblock>The decision regarding the marking of frozen produce articles published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 29, 1993, and this correction of that decision become effective as to merchandise entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption, on or after February 11, 1994. Parties adversely affected by any compliance obligations of the December 29 decision or this correction shall have until May 8, 1994, to bring their frozen produce packaging into conformity with these requirements. After that date, all packaged frozen produce articles entered for consumption or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption and not marked to indicate the country of origin in accordance with this decision and other marking requirements of the Tariff Act and Customs Regulations shall be assessed marking duties.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Robert Cascardo, Value and Marking Branch, (202) 482-7010.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 29, 1993, Customs published a decision in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 68743) concerning the country of origin marking requirements for imported frozen produce. The decision implemented a new Customs interpretation of section 304 of the Tariff Act of 1930, as amended (19 U.S.C. 1304). Under the decision, packages of imported frozen produce will be required to be marked with their country of origin on the front side of the packaging in specified types and styles. However, the decision's section entitled: ``Previous Decisions Affected'' should have made clear that HQ 735085 (June 4, 1993) was being modified accordingly. This section on page 68747, second column, is corrected to read, in its entirety, as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Previous Decisions Affected</textblock>
    <textblock>HRL 731830 (November 21, 1988), is revoked. HQ 735085 (June 4, 1993), and a related determination, HRL 735222 (June 28, 1993), are modified such that the rendering of the required marking shall be in accordance with this decision. T.D. 91-48 (May 28, 1991), is modified. Conspicuous marking within the meaning of T.D. 91-48 shall be limited to marking which complies with the specifications set forth in this decision.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Harvey B. Fox,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Regulations and Rulings.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-880 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4820-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
