<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00083</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Proposed Regulatory Changes</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 682.202␣Permissible Charges by Lenders to Borrowers</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations would implement the requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>section 427A of the HEA. The changes in this section include the</textblock>
    <textblock>creation of variable interest rates for new Stafford loan</textblock>
    <textblock>borrowers and the return of excess interest to certain Stafford</textblock>
    <textblock>loan borrowers.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary estimates that lenders collectively will need</textblock>
    <textblock>an additional 250,000 hours to comply with the requirement that</textblock>
    <textblock>excess interest be returned to certain Stafford loan borrowers.</textblock>
    <textblock>This requirement is taken directly from the HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 682.208␣Due Diligence in Servicing a Loan</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations would implement the requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>section 428(b)(2)(F) of the HEA. Under the regulations, in cases</textblock>
    <textblock>where the holder of the loan remains the same, but there is a</textblock>
    <textblock>servicing change that results in a change in the identity of the</textblock>
    <textblock>party to whom the borrower must send payments or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>communications, the Secretary would apply the same borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>notification requirements that are required by current</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations at 34 CFR 682.208(e) when a loan is sold or</textblock>
    <textblock>transferred.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary does not view this requirement as one that</textblock>
    <textblock>imposes any additional burden because lenders and servicers</textblock>
    <textblock>already notify borrowers, as a normal business practice, whenever</textblock>
    <textblock>there is a servicing change that results in a change in the</textblock>
    <textblock>identity of the party to whom the borrower must send payments or</textblock>
    <textblock>direct communications. This requirement is taken directly from</textblock>
    <textblock>the HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 682.402␣Death, Disability, Closed School, False</textblock>
    <textblock>Certification, and Bankruptcy Payments</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations would implement the requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>section 437 of the HEA. The regulations reflect the new</textblock>
    <textblock>statutory provision for cancellation of a parent's PLUS loan if</textblock>
    <textblock>the student for whom the parent borrowed died. This was not a</textblock>
    <textblock>subject of controversy at the regional meetings or during the</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations implement the requirements of the</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA with regard to the discharge of a borrower's liability on an</textblock>
    <textblock>FFEL Program loan if the student was unable to complete an</textblock>
    <textblock>educational program because of the closure of the school. In</textblock>
    <textblock>developing criteria to be used to determine a borrower's</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility for a closed school loan discharge, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>believes that a student who completed his or her educational</textblock>
    <textblock>program by transferring academic credits or hours earned at the</textblock>
    <textblock>closed school to another school, or who completed the program</textblock>
    <textblock>through a teach-out of the educational program at a different</textblock>
    <textblock>school, should not qualify for a loan cancellation. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes that the closed school discharge was intended</textblock>
    <textblock>to benefit students who could not complete their education</textblock>
    <textblock>because their school closed, and does not believe that a student</textblock>
    <textblock>who was able to complete the educational program for which the</textblock>
    <textblock>loan paid should be able to avoid repaying that loan. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary is particularly interested in receiving public comment</textblock>
    <textblock>as to the appropriate treatment of a borrower's loan obligations</textblock>
    <textblock>if the educational program for which the loan was obtained was a</textblock>
    <textblock>multi-year program and the student was able to complete one or</textblock>
    <textblock>more years of that program.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary also believes, contrary to the majority</textblock>
    <textblock>sentiment expressed at the regional meetings and by the</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiators, that a borrower should submit to the holder a sworn</textblock>
    <textblock>statement that demonstrates that the borrower is eligible for a</textblock>
    <textblock>closed school discharge to assist the Secretary or the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's designees in pursuing claims against the closed</textblock>
    <textblock>school, and to secure the borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>s written commitment to the</textblock>
    <textblock>representations on which he or she seeks relief. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>believes that an affidavit or sworn statement is essential in</textblock>
    <textblock>protecting the interests of the federal taxpayer, and therefore</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes that one be obtained from the student as a condition of</textblock>
    <textblock>loan discharge. By virtue of Federal law (28 U.S.C. 1746), this</textblock>
    <textblock>affidavit or statement need not be notarized, but the borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>must state in the document that the borrower makes the statement</textblock>
    <textblock>under penalty of perjury.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
