<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00089</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>There are minimal burdens, if any, that will be associated</textblock>
    <textblock>with including a warning about possible wage garnishment in the</textblock>
    <textblock>delinquency letters that are already required to be sent to</textblock>
    <textblock>borrowers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12866</textblock>
    <textblock>These proposed regulations have been reviewed in accordance</textblock>
    <textblock>with Executive Order 12866. Under the terms of the order the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary has assessed the potential costs and benefits of this</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory action.</textblock>
    <textblock>The potential costs associated with the proposed regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>are those resulting from statutory requirements and those</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by the Secretary to be necessary for administering</textblock>
    <textblock>this program effectively and efficiently, as discussed in those</textblock>
    <textblock>sections of the preamble that relate to specific sections of the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations. Burdens specifically associated with information</textblock>
    <textblock>collection requirements, if any, are identified and explained</textblock>
    <textblock>elsewhere in this preamble under the heading</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980</textblock>
    <textblock>In assessing the potential costs and benefits_both</textblock>
    <textblock>quantitative and qualitative_of these proposed regulations, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary has determined that the benefits of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations justify the costs, and do not interfere with State,</textblock>
    <textblock>local, and tribal governments in the exercise of their</textblock>
    <textblock>governmental functions.</textblock>
    <textblock>To assist the Department in complying with the specific</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of Executive Order 12866, the Secretary invites</textblock>
    <textblock>comment on whether there may be further opportunities to reduce</textblock>
    <textblock>any potential costs or increase potential benefits resulting from</textblock>
    <textblock>these proposed regulations without impeding the effective and</textblock>
    <textblock>efficient administration of the program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act Certification</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary certifies that these proposed regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>would not have a significant economic impact on a substantial</textblock>
    <textblock>number of small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Certain reporting, recordkeeping, and compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements are imposed on guaranty agencies, lenders, and</textblock>
    <textblock>schools by the regulations. These requirements, however, would</textblock>
    <textblock>not have a significant impact because they would not impose</textblock>
    <textblock>excessive regulatory burdens or require unnecessary Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>supervision.</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 682.208, 682.402, and 682.410 contain information</textblock>
    <textblock>collection requirements. As required by the Paperwork Reduction</textblock>
    <textblock>Act of 1980, the Department of Education will submit a copy of</textblock>
    <textblock>these sections to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for</textblock>
    <textblock>its review. (44 U.S.C. 3504(h))</textblock>
    <textblock>These regulations affect the following types of entities</textblock>
    <textblock>that participate in the FFEL Program: Guaranty agencies, lenders,</textblock>
    <textblock>and schools. The Department needs and uses this information to</textblock>
    <textblock>properly carry out its responsibility to administer certain</textblock>
    <textblock>aspects of the HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual public reporting burden for this collection of</textblock>
    <textblock>information is not expected to significantly increase. The</textblock>
    <textblock>collection and reporting of the information in §§682.208 and</textblock>
    <textblock>682.410 reflect normal business practice, whereas the closed</textblock>
    <textblock>school cancellation provision of §682.402 essentially substitutes</textblock>
    <textblock>a closed school claim for a default claim that normally would</textblock>
    <textblock>have occurred if the student did not repay a loan made for</textblock>
    <textblock>attendance at a school that closed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Organizations and individuals desiring to submit comments on</textblock>
    <textblock>the information collection requirements should direct them to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, OMB, room 3002, New</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503; Attention:</textblock>
    <textblock>Daniel J. Chenok.</textblock>
    <textblock>Invitation To Comment</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to submit comments and</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendations regarding these proposed regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>All comments submitted in response to these proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations will be available for public inspection, during and</textblock>
    <textblock>after the comment period, in ROB-3, room 4310, 7th and D Streets,</textblock>
    <textblock>SW., Washington, DC, between the hours of 8:30 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through Friday of each week except Federal holidays.</textblock>
    <textblock>Assessment of Educational Impact</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary particularly requests comments on whether the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations in this document would require transmission</textblock>
    <textblock>of information that is being gathered by or is available from any</textblock>
    <textblock>other agency or authority of the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 34 CFR Part 682</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedure, Colleges and</textblock>
    <textblock>universities, Education, Loan programs-education, Reporting and</textblock>
    <textblock>recordkeeping requirements, Student aid, Vocational education.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Numbers: 84.032 Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Family Education Loan Program)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 11, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard W. Riley,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of Education.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
