<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00041</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>k. With this notice, we are initiating consultation with the STATE HISTORIC PRESERVATION OFFICER (SHPO), as required by section 106, National Historic Preservation Act, and the regulations of the Advisory council on Historic Preservation, 36 CFR, at section 800.4.</textblock>
    <textblock>l. Under ยง4.32 (b)(7) of the Commission's regulations (18 CFR), if any resource agency, Indian Tribe, or person believes that the applicant should conduct an additional scientific study to form an adequate factual basis for a complete analysis of the application on its merits, they must file a request for the study with the Commission, not later than 60 days after the application is filed, and must serve a copy of the request on the applicant.</textblock>
    <textblock>m. The Commission's deadline for the applicant's filing of a final amendment to the application is March 27, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>10 a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Application:</textblock>
    <textblock>License (Tendered Notice).</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Project No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>11452-000.</textblock>
    <textblock>c.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date Filed:</textblock>
    <textblock>December 28, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>d.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>Northern California Power Agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>e.</textblock>
    <textblock>Name of Project:</textblock>
    <textblock>Angels.</textblock>
    <textblock>f.</textblock>
    <textblock>Location:</textblock>
    <textblock>On Angels Creek in Calaveras County, CA.</textblock>
    <textblock>g. Filed pursuant to Federal Power Act, 16 U.S.C. sections 791(a)_825(r).</textblock>
    <textblock>h.</textblock>
    <textblock>Competing Application:</textblock>
    <textblock>Project No. 2699-001, filed December 21, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>i.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>James Lynch, Environmental Liaison Northern California Power Agency, 180 Cirby Way, Roseville, CA 95678; (916) 781-4275.</textblock>
    <textblock>j.</textblock>
    <textblock>FERC Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Hector Perez, (202) 219-2843.</textblock>
    <textblock>k.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of Project:</textblock>
    <textblock>The existing project consists of: (1) The 5.6-foot high, 64-foot long gunite faced rock-wall and concrete buttress Angels Diversion Dam; (2) the Upper Angels Canal, approximately 2.5 miles long, to Ross Reservoir; (3) the 100-acre-feet gross storage capacity Ross Reservoir and a 44-foot high and 710-foot long earthfill, masonry, and rock structure dam; (5) the Lower Angels Canal, approximately 3.3 miles long; (6) the Angels Forebay with a gross storage capacity of 2 acre-feet; (7) the 8,624-foot long Angels Penstock; (8) a powerhouse with an installed capacity of 1,400 kW; and (9) other appurtenances.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Applicant proposes to remove the Angels Penstock and decommission power generation facilities in the existing powerhouse.</textblock>
    <textblock>l. Under ยง4.32(b)(7) of the Commission's regulations (18 CFR), if any resource agency, Indian Tribe, or person believes that the applicant should conduct an additional scientific study to form an adequate factual basis for a complete analysis of the application on its merits, they must file a request for the study with the Commission, not later than 60 days after the application is filed, and must serve a copy of the request on the applicant.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard Paragraphs</textblock>
    <textblock>A2. Development Application_Any qualified applicant desiring to file a competing application must submit to the Commission, on or before the specified deadline date for the particular application, a competing development application, or a notice of intent to file such an application. Submission of a timely notice of intent allows an interested person to file the competing development application no later than 120 days after the specified deadline date for the particular application. Applications for preliminary permits will not be accepted in response to this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>A3. Development Application_Any qualified development applicant desiring to file a competing application must submit to the Commission, on or before the specified comment date for the particular application, a competing development application, or a notice of intent to file such an application. Submission of a timely notice of intent allows an interested person to file the competing development application no later than 120 days after the specified comment date for the particular application. Applications for preliminary permits will not be accepted in response to this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>A9. Notice of intent_A notice of intent must specify the exact name, business address, and telephone number of the prospective applicant, and must include an unequivocal statement of intent to submit, if such an application may be filed, either a preliminary permit application or a development application (specify which type of application). A notice of intent must be served on the applicant(s) named in this public notice.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
