<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00035</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Black Hills has requested that further notice requirements be waived and the acceptance of the Agreement for filing be entered forthwith.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Philadelphia Electric Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-318-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 21, 1993, Philadelphia Electric Company, Public Service Electric and Gas Company, Atlantic City Electric Company and Delmarva Power &amp; Light Company (the Peach Bottom Owners) submitted the Owners Agreement for Peach Bottom No. 2 and 3 Nuclear Units, dated November 24, 1971, as supplemented, and asked the Commission to disclaim jurisdiction over it. This Agreement, according to the Peach Bottom Owners, is not required to be filed under Section 205 of the Federal Power Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. PacifiCorp</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-319-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 21, 1993, PacifiCorp, tendered for filing in accordance with Commission's Order pertaining to agreements involving final amnesty for jurisdictional service and waiver of notice, issued July 30, 1993 under Docket No. PL93-2-002, the Service Agreement between Tri-State Generation and Transmission Association Inc. (Tri-State) and PacifiCorp, effective September 28, 1989.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of this filing were supplied to Tri-State, the Public Utility Commission of Oregon and the Utah Public Service Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>PacifiCorp requests in accordance with 18 CFR 35.11 of the Commission's Rules and Regulations and that a waiver of prior notice requirements be granted.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Wisconsin Power and Light Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-320-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 21, 1993, Wisconsin Power and Light Company tendered for filing with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission one Letter Agreement between Wisconsin Power and Light Company (WP&amp;L) and Water Works and Lighting Commission (WWLC). Under the General Purpose Energy Agreement, WP&amp;L will make non-firm energy available to WWLC, with terms and quantities to be arranged by mutual agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Wisconsin Power and Light respectfully requests an effective date sixty (60) days from the date of filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the filing has been served on the Public Service Commission of Wisconsin.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Massachusetts Electric Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-321-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that Massachusetts Electric Company (MECo), on December 21, 1993, tendered for filing two power purchases contract assignments that it has entered into with New England Power Company.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>10. PacifiCorp</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-323-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that PacifiCorp, on December 21, 1993, tendered for filing, in accordance with 18 CFR 35.13(a)(2)(i)(C) of the Commission's Rules and Regulations, a Wheeling Agreement between PacifiCorp and City of Bountiful Light &amp; Power (Bountiful City) dated October 4, 1978.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the Wheeling Agreement, PacifiCorp provides non-firm wheeling of energy for Bountiful City.</textblock>
    <textblock>PacifiCorp's filing herein, is in response to the Commission's July 30, 1993, Final Order in Docket No. PL93-2-000 regarding prior notice and filing requirements (Final Order). PacifiCorp requests, pursuant to the Final Order and 18 CFR 35.11 of the Commission's Rules and Regulations that a waiver of prior notice be granted and that an effective date of October 4, 1978 be assigned. This date being the effective date of the Wheeling Agreement. Such waiver will have no effect on wholesale or wheeling customers under other rate schedules.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of this filing were supplied to the Public Service Commission of Utah.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 20, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard Paragraphs</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rules 211 and 214 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (18 CFR 385.211 and 18 CFR 385.214). All such motions or protests should be filed on or before the comment date. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-966 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
