<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00045</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The recommendations of the Advisory Council as a whole were included in</textblock>
    <textblock>a resolution. The resolution questioned the sufficiency of the evidence to</textblock>
    <textblock>support adoption of the proposed rule and recommended that: (1) The Department</textblock>
    <textblock>undertake negotiated rulemaking or other comparable process for this standard;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) the costs of any rule be considered, both cumulatively and by zones; (3)</textblock>
    <textblock>the Department examine its legal and regulatory authority with respect to</textblock>
    <textblock>installation, if it finds that an installation standard would be an</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate means of increasing wind safety; (4) the Department consider all</textblock>
    <textblock>nationally recognized model codes; (5) the Department make available documents</textblock>
    <textblock>relating to the development of new wind standards; (6) the Advisory Council be</textblock>
    <textblock>reconvened to review public comments and the Department's analysis; (7) the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department should promptly complete the process of updating the wind</textblock>
    <textblock>standards, considering the issues and questions raised by the Advisory Council</textblock>
    <textblock>and in public comments; and (8) the Department should prepare an adequate</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory impact analysis upon which it can support the decisions to be made</textblock>
    <textblock>on implementation of new standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department has considered the conclusions and recommendations of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council in developing this final rule and the final regulatory impact</textblock>
    <textblock>analysis. The regulatory impact analysis is responsive to several of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council's concerns, while this preamble addresses other points raised</textblock>
    <textblock>by the Advisory Council.</textblock>
    <textblock>With respect to the other points raised by the Advisory Council, many</textblock>
    <textblock>commenters also suggested that installation is a crucial factor in the safety</textblock>
    <textblock>of manufactured homes. The Department agrees that the installation of</textblock>
    <textblock>manufactured housing units may be an important factor in the safety of such</textblock>
    <textblock>housing and is initiating a review of the Department's authority and ability</textblock>
    <textblock>to influence tiedown requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, the Department does not believe there is any significant</textblock>
    <textblock>advantage in, or that the public interest would be served by, reconvening the</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council for the purpose of reviewing the public comments or the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department's compliance with its statutory responsibilities in the development</textblock>
    <textblock>of these standards. Nor does the Department believe there is any advantage to</textblock>
    <textblock>the public interest in undertaking negotiated rulemaking for these standards</textblock>
    <textblock>because they have been subject to an extensive notice and comment period and</textblock>
    <textblock>have been discussed with the Advisory Council, a body representative of the</textblock>
    <textblock>manufactured housing industry, government, and consumers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Major Differences From Proposed Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>As a result of the Department's review of public comments and</textblock>
    <textblock>consultation with the Advisory Council, at this time the Department has</textblock>
    <textblock>decided not to pursue substantial changes to the standards in areas of the</textblock>
    <textblock>country not generally subject to hurricanes (Wind Zone I). However, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department recognizes that in many areas of the country the Federal standards</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable to the design and construction of manufactured housing are far</textblock>
    <textblock>below standards specified for site-built and modular housing by State and</textblock>
    <textblock>local codes. Thus, the Department shall initiate a new review of the</textblock>
    <textblock>standards for the rest of the country, and it expects to publish proposals for</textblock>
    <textblock>these areas next year.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department has also decided not to include in the final rule the</textblock>
    <textblock>following items that were in the proposed rule:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Maximum dimension of 12</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ for roof overhangs;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Lower load duration factor than provided in the 1991 National</textblock>
    <textblock>Design Specification for Wood Construction (NDS);</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Requirement for a 1.5 safety factor to calculate resistance of</textblock>
    <textblock>anchoring and foundation systems to higher design forces in Wind Zones II</textblock>
    <textblock>and III;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Manufacturer's design and details for a permanent foundation system</textblock>
    <textblock>(certified by a registered professional engineer or architect) applicable to</textblock>
    <textblock>each manufactured home design; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Shortened period for implementation of the standards after</textblock>
    <textblock>publication.</textblock>
    <textblock>Relationship to Energy Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 25, 1993, the Department published a final rule amending the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Manufactured Home Construction and Safety Standards (FMHCSS) to</textblock>
    <textblock>include preemptive standards significantly upgrading the existing energy</textblock>
    <textblock>conservation requirements (58 FR 54975) (Energy Rule). The effective date of</textblock>
    <textblock>that rule is October 25, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Several of the provisions to be affected by the Energy Rule are also</textblock>
    <textblock>affected by the rule published today. Because of the earlier effective date</textblock>
    <textblock>for those provisions in today's rule, the Department will publish technical</textblock>
    <textblock>amendments to the Energy Rule, before the effective date of that rule, that</textblock>
    <textblock>also will reflect the new requirements imposed under today's rule. In some</textblock>
    <textblock>minor instances, the changes adopted in today's rule already include</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements that otherwise would have been imposed upon the effective date of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Energy Rule. Those changes are identified further in the section-by-</textblock>
    <textblock>section analysis later in this preamble.</textblock>
    <textblock>Problem To Be Addressed</textblock>
    <textblock>Each year significant damage to manufactured housing is produced by</textblock>
    <textblock>straight winds, hurricanes, and tornadoes. Damage is primarily in the form of</textblock>
    <textblock>roof failure, loss of roof diaphragm material, connection failures, and</textblock>
    <textblock>tiedown/foundation failures. The most predictable areas for wind damage to</textblock>
    <textblock>manufactured housing are those subject most directly to hurricanes. Last year</textblock>
    <textblock>Hurricanes Andrew and Iniki provided dramatic examples of the destruction</textblock>
    <textblock>faced by housing in hurricane-prone areas.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
