<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00038</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>k. With this notice, we are initiating consultation with the State Historic Preservation Officer (SHPO), as required by 106, of the National Historic Preservation Act, and the regulations of the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation, 36 CFR 800.4.</textblock>
    <textblock>l. In accordance with ยง4.32(b)(7) of the Commission's regulations, if any resource agency, SHPO, Indian Tribe, or person believes that an additional scientific study should be conducted in order to form an adequate, factual basis for a complete analysis of this application on its merits, they must file a request for the study with the Commission, together with justification for such request, not later than 60 days from the filing date and serve a copy of the request on the Applicant.</textblock>
    <textblock>3 a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Application:</textblock>
    <textblock>New License for Major Project (Tendered Notice).</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Project No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>2687-014.</textblock>
    <textblock>c.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date Filed:</textblock>
    <textblock>December 20, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>d.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pacific Gas &amp; Electric Company.</textblock>
    <textblock>e.</textblock>
    <textblock>Name of Project:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pit 1 Project.</textblock>
    <textblock>f.</textblock>
    <textblock>Location:</textblock>
    <textblock>On the Fall River and the Pit River, near the towns of Fall River Mills, McArthur, and Burney, in Shasta County, California.</textblock>
    <textblock>g.</textblock>
    <textblock>Filed Pursuant to:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Power Act, 16 U.S.C. 791(a)-825(r).</textblock>
    <textblock>h.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Steve Christ, Project Manager, Pacific Gas &amp; Electric Company, P.O. Box 770000, P10A, San Francisco, California 94177, (415) 973-2629.</textblock>
    <textblock>i.</textblock>
    <textblock>FERC Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Michael Strzelecki, (202) 219-2827.</textblock>
    <textblock>j.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of Project:</textblock>
    <textblock>The project as licensed consists of: (1) A 15-foot-high concrete diversion structure on the Fall River forming a small impoundment; (2) a 40-foot-high earthen dam on the Fall River forming a 222-acre forebay impoundment; (3) an intake structure on each impoundment; (4) a 1,200-foot-long canal carrying water from each intake structure to a tunnel; (5) the 10,076-foot-long, 14-foot-high tunnel; (6) two 1,372-foot-long penstocks; (7) a powerhouse containing two generating units with a total installed capacity of 61 MW; (8) a 1,150-foot-long tailrace returning water to the Pit River; and (9) appurtenant facilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>k. With this notice, we are initiating consultation with the STATE HISTORIC PRESERVATION OFFICER (SHPO), as required by 106, National Historic Preservation Act, and the regulations of the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation, 36 CFR 800.4.</textblock>
    <textblock>l. Under ยง4.32(b)(7) of the Commission's regulations (18 CFR 4.32(b)(7)), if any resource agency, SHPO, Indian Tribe, or person believes that the applicant should conduct an additional scientific study to form an adequate factual basis for a complete analysis of the application on its merits, they must file a request for the study with the Commission not later than 60 days after the application is filed, and must serve a copy of the request on the applicant.</textblock>
    <textblock>m. The Commission's deadline for the applicant's filing of a final amendment to the application is March 20, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>4 a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Application:</textblock>
    <textblock>Subsequent License (Tendered Notice).</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Project No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>2699-001</textblock>
    <textblock>c.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date Filed:</textblock>
    <textblock>December 21, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>d.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pacific Gas and Electric Company.</textblock>
    <textblock>e.</textblock>
    <textblock>Name of Project:</textblock>
    <textblock>Angels Hydroelectric Project.</textblock>
    <textblock>f.</textblock>
    <textblock>Location:</textblock>
    <textblock>On Angels Creek in Calaveras County California.</textblock>
    <textblock>g.</textblock>
    <textblock>Filed Pursuant to:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Power Act 16 USC 791(a)-825(r).</textblock>
    <textblock>h.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Shan Bhattacharya, Manager, Hydro Generation Department, Pacific Gas and Electric Company, 201 Mission Street, room 1012, P.O. Box 770000, Mail P10A, San Francisco, CA 94177, (415) 973-4603.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annette Faraglia, Attorney, Law Department, Pacific Gas and Electric Company, 77 Beale Street, room 3051, P.O. Box 7442, San Francisco, CA 94120-7442, (415) 973-7145.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
