<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00056</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Other Specific Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department is encouraged to coordinate this rule with a</textblock>
    <textblock>review of seismic and flood loads, especially with respect to foundation and</textblock>
    <textblock>attachment designs (25).</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The requirements in the proposed rule for a permanent</textblock>
    <textblock>foundation design have been eliminated in this final rule. However, as the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department continues to review the issue of adequate anchoring/foundation</textblock>
    <textblock>systems for manufactured homes, it will also review these other</textblock>
    <textblock>considerations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>There are not enough DAPIA personnel in the HUD system to</textblock>
    <textblock>review and approve design changes within the time provided for the</textblock>
    <textblock>effectiveness of this rule (83, 124, 136, 179).</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department has agreed to delay the effectiveness of the</textblock>
    <textblock>new requirements for 180 days, which should allow sufficient time for the</textblock>
    <textblock>DAPIA process, as well.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department should consider requiring the DAPIA approval</textblock>
    <textblock>stamp on all pages of a manufacturer's installation instructions (48).</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The final rule continues to require that the manufacturer</textblock>
    <textblock>provide installation instructions certified by a registered professional</textblock>
    <textblock>engineer indicating at least one acceptable system of anchoring (24 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>3280.306(b)). However, the Department will consider the suggestion to require</textblock>
    <textblock>a DAPIA approval stamp on each page of the manufacturers' installation</textblock>
    <textblock>instructions when developing future revisions to the Manufactured Home</textblock>
    <textblock>Procedural and Enforcement Regulations (24 CFR part 3282).</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>Some explanation is needed about the effect of the new</textblock>
    <textblock>standards on ``B'' letters, interpretative bulletins, and compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>determinations (122).</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>This new standard supersedes any portions of ``B'' letters,</textblock>
    <textblock>interpretative bulletins, and compliance determinations that are in conflict</textblock>
    <textblock>with this standard.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>If the higher standards are adopted, manufacturers will prefer</textblock>
    <textblock>to build modular homes that meet the necessary State standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Manufacturers are free to channel their activities in any way</textblock>
    <textblock>that best responds to market forces. In the development of the regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>impact analysis, the Department has accounted for the cost of potential lost</textblock>
    <textblock>business. To the extent that manufacturers could redirect their production to</textblock>
    <textblock>alternative housing, the costs of the higher standards would be lessened.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, as noted above, the Department believes that the trend in State</textblock>
    <textblock>standards also will be to stricter wind standards. Therefore, while</textblock>
    <textblock>manufactured homes may experience a price increase because of these standards,</textblock>
    <textblock>they will be affordable relative to site-built homes meeting the higher State-imposed standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department should prepare a brochure on hurricane</textblock>
    <textblock>awareness and windstorm protection.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>As noted in the discussion on Improved Anchoring and</textblock>
    <textblock>Foundation Systems earlier in the preamble, the Department is reviewing what</textblock>
    <textblock>would be an appropriate consumer information disclosure requirement on</textblock>
    <textblock>installation. As part of that review, the Department may consider</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements on the disclosure of general information relating to high winds</textblock>
    <textblock>and hurricanes, and may coordinate with FEMA on the development of a brochure</textblock>
    <textblock>on hurricane awareness and protection for occupants of manufactured homes.</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>Other specific comments that have become moot as a result of the</textblock>
    <textblock>decision not to proceed with changes in Wind Zone I and requirements relating</textblock>
    <textblock>to a permanent foundation system are not addressed in this preamble.)</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Description of Changes to the Standards</textblock>
    <textblock>Because of the risk of loss of life to building occupants and the</textblock>
    <textblock>extraordinary loss of property due to Hurricane Andrew, the Department has</textblock>
    <textblock>determined that it is necessary to amend the Federal Manufactured Home</textblock>
    <textblock>Construction and Safety Standards (FMHCSS) to raise the level of wind</textblock>
    <textblock>resistance standards, especially in areas subject to high winds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Specifically, the Department is amending the FMHCSS to include a Basic Wind</textblock>
    <textblock>Zone Map that is based on the map contained in the incorporated standard</textblock>
    <textblock>ASCE 7-88, ``Minimum Design Loads for Buildings and Other Structures.''</textblock>
    <textblock>The revised map contains a more concentrated area for the 100 mph wind</textblock>
    <textblock>zone than was specified in the current standard or the proposed rule. The</textblock>
    <textblock>boundary between Wind Zones I and II follows the 90 mph isotach on the</textblock>
    <textblock>ASCE 7-88 basic wind speed map, while the boundary between Wind Zones II and</textblock>
    <textblock>III remains the 100 mph isotach indicated in the proposed rule. The design</textblock>
    <textblock>wind speeds for high wind areas are designated as 100 mph for Wind Zone II and</textblock>
    <textblock>110 mph for Wind Zone III. This rule does not change the current design wind</textblock>
    <textblock>speed for Wind Zone I.</textblock>
    <textblock>Based on the revised map, this final rule enumerates the States,</textblock>
    <textblock>Territories, and local governments in which the more stringent standards will</textblock>
    <textblock>be applicable. The enumerated areas are those that the Department has</textblock>
    <textblock>determined to be at least partially within the higher wind zones demarcated on</textblock>
    <textblock>the revised map. The Department also will monitor local building code</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements and will consider adoption through rulemaking of requirements for</textblock>
    <textblock>manufactured homes that are comparable to any more stringent requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>established for site-built homes by a State or local building authority.</textblock>
    <textblock>The current wind standard for manufactured housing is considered</textblock>
    <textblock>inadequate because it addresses only positive (external) design wind pressures</textblock>
    <textblock>for walls, components, windows, and cladding, without specifying that designs</textblock>
    <textblock>must take into account the effect of negative pressure (suction) on these</textblock>
    <textblock>building elements, as well as internal pressures on walls and roof/ceiling</textblock>
    <textblock>systems. The formulae used in ASCE 7-88 also include other factors, which</textblock>
    <textblock>account for higher uplift forces on roof eaves, ridges, overhangs, and</textblock>
    <textblock>corners. These and other issues are now addressed in high wind areas by</textblock>
    <textblock>requiring the manufactured home structure, components, and cladding to be</textblock>
    <textblock>designed to resist design wind forces for Exposure C, as specified in</textblock>
    <textblock>ASCE 7-88.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
