<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00099</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Suspension of collection activity.</textblock>
    <textblock>If the lender is</textblock>
    <textblock>notified that a borrower has filed a petition for relief in</textblock>
    <textblock>bankruptcy, the lender shall immediately suspend any collection</textblock>
    <textblock>efforts outside the bankruptcy proceeding against the borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>and_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Against any co-maker or endorser if the borrower has</textblock>
    <textblock>filed for relief under Chapters 12 or 13; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Against any co-maker or endorser who has filed for</textblock>
    <textblock>relief in bankruptcy.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Determination of filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>The lender shall determine that</textblock>
    <textblock>a borrower has filed a petition for relief in bankruptcy on the</textblock>
    <textblock>basis of receiving a notice of the first meeting of creditors or</textblock>
    <textblock>other confirmation issued by the bankruptcy court.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>Proof of claim.</textblock>
    <textblock>Unless instructed otherwise by the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency, the lender shall file a proof of claim with the</textblock>
    <textblock>bankruptcy court within_</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Claim procedures for a loan held by a lender.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Documentation.</textblock>
    <textblock>A lender shall provide the guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agency with the following documentation when filing a death,</textblock>
    <textblock>disability, closed school, false certification, or bankruptcy</textblock>
    <textblock>claim:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The original promissory note, or, if the lender no</textblock>
    <textblock>longer has the original promissory note, a copy of the note</textblock>
    <textblock>certified by the lender as a true and accurate copy;</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) In the case of a closed school claim, the documentation</textblock>
    <textblock>described in paragraph (d)(3) of this section, or any other</textblock>
    <textblock>documentation as the Secretary may require;</textblock>
    <textblock>(vii) In the case of a false certification claim, the</textblock>
    <textblock>documentation described in paragraph (e)(3) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Filing deadlines.</textblock>
    <textblock>A lender shall file a death,</textblock>
    <textblock>disability, closed school, false certification, or bankruptcy</textblock>
    <textblock>claim within the following periods:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Within 60 days of the date on which the lender</textblock>
    <textblock>determines that a borrower (or the student on whose behalf a</textblock>
    <textblock>parent obtained a PLUS loan) has died, or the lender determines</textblock>
    <textblock>that the borrower is totally and permanently disabled.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) In the case of a closed school claim, the lender shall</textblock>
    <textblock>file a claim with the guaranty agency no later than 60 days after</textblock>
    <textblock>the borrower submits to the lender the written request and sworn</textblock>
    <textblock>statement described in paragraph (d)(3) of this section or after</textblock>
    <textblock>the lender is notified by the Secretary or the Secretary's</textblock>
    <textblock>designee or by the guaranty agency to do so.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) In the case of a false certification claim, the lender</textblock>
    <textblock>shall file a claim with the guaranty agency no later than 60 days</textblock>
    <textblock>after the borrower submits to the lender the written request and</textblock>
    <textblock>sworn statement described in paragraph (e)(3) of this section or</textblock>
    <textblock>after the lender is notified by the Secretary or the Secretary's</textblock>
    <textblock>designee or by the guaranty agency to do so.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
