<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00094</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00063</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[NV-930-04-4210-05; N58101; 4-00154]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Realty Action: Lease or Sale of Public Lands for Recreation and Public Purpose, Pershing County, NV</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In response to an application from the Pershing County Fair and Recreation Board, the following described land is being considered for an eighteen hole championship golf course pursuant to the Recreation and Public Purpose Act as amended (43 U.S.C. 869,</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>):</textblock>
    <textblock>Mount Diablo Meridian, Nevada</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 27 N., R. 31 E.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 7, E1/2SE1/4NE1/4, NE1/4SW1/4SE1/4, S1/2SW1/4SE1/4, E1/2SE1/4;</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 8, SW1/4NW1/4, W1/2SW1/4;</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 18, N1/2NE1/4, E1/2NE1/4NW1/4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Totalling approximately 350 acres.</textblock>
    <textblock>Upon publication of this Notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>the above described lands will be segregated from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the general mining laws, but not the Recreation and Public Purpose Act and the Mineral Leasing Laws.</textblock>
    <textblock>When the required environmental, archaeological and mineral reports are completed and a determination is made that the lands are suitable for the use proposed, a subsequent Notice of Realty Action will be published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>and appropriate newspapers classifying the lands for lease/conveyance. At that time, a 45 day public comment period will be provided.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Chuck Valentine, Bureau of Land Management, 705 E. Fourth Street, Winnemucca, Nevada 89445, (702) 623-1500.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Ronald Wenker,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>District Manager, Winnemucca.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-928 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-HC-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
