<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00180</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00102</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>a. One hundred micrograms per liter (100 μg/l);</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Two hundred micrograms per liter (200 μg/l) for acrolein and</textblock>
    <textblock>acrylonitrile; five hundred micrograms per liter (500 μg/l) for</textblock>
    <textblock>2,4-dinitrophenol and for 2-methyl-4, 6-dinitrophenol; and one</textblock>
    <textblock>milligram per liter (1 mg/l) for antimony;</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Five (5) times the maximum concentration value reported for that</textblock>
    <textblock>pollutant in the permit application in accordance with 40 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>122.21(g)(7); or</textblock>
    <textblock>d. The level established by the Director in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>40 CFR 122.44(f).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. That any activity has occurred or will occur which would result in any</textblock>
    <textblock>discharge, on a non-routine or infrequent basis, of a toxic pollutant</textblock>
    <textblock>which is not limited in the permit, if that discharge will exceed the</textblock>
    <textblock>highest of the following ``notification levels'':</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Five hundred micrograms per liter (500 μg/l);</textblock>
    <textblock>b. One milligram per liter (1 mg/l) for antimony;</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Ten (10) times the maximum concentration value reported for that</textblock>
    <textblock>pollutant in the permit application in accordance with 40 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>122.21(g)(7); or</textblock>
    <textblock>d. The level established by the Director in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>40 CFR 122.44(f).</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Planned Changes</textblock>
    <textblock>The permittee shall give notice to the Director and</textblock>
    <textblock>ADEC as soon as possible of any planned physical alterations or additions</textblock>
    <textblock>to the permitted facility. Notice is required only when:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The alteration or addition to a permitted facility may meet one of the</textblock>
    <textblock>criteria for determining whether a facility is a new source as determined</textblock>
    <textblock>in 40 CFR 122.29(b); or</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The alteration or addition could significantly change the nature or</textblock>
    <textblock>increase the quantity of pollutants discharged. This notification applies</textblock>
    <textblock>to pollutants which are subject neither to effluent limitations in the</textblock>
    <textblock>permit, nor to notification requirements under part VI.A.1.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Anticipated Noncompliance</textblock>
    <textblock>The permittee shall also give advance notice</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Director and ADEC of any planned changes in the permitted facility</textblock>
    <textblock>or activity which may result in noncompliance with permit requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Permit Actions</textblock>
    <textblock>This permit may be modified, revoked and reissued, or</textblock>
    <textblock>terminated for cause. The filing of a request by the permittee for a permit</textblock>
    <textblock>modification, revocation and reissuance, or termination, or a notification of</textblock>
    <textblock>planned changes or anticipated noncompliance, does not stay any permit</textblock>
    <textblock>condition.</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Duty to Reapply</textblock>
    <textblock>If the permittee wishes to continue an activity regulated</textblock>
    <textblock>by this permit after the expiration date of this permit, the permittee must</textblock>
    <textblock>apply for and obtain a new permit. The application should be submitted at</textblock>
    <textblock>least 180 days before the expiration date of this permit.</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Duty to Provide Information</textblock>
    <textblock>The permittee shall furnish to the Director</textblock>
    <textblock>and ADEC, within a reasonable time, any information which the Director or</textblock>
    <textblock>ADEC may request to determine whether cause exists for modifying,</textblock>
    <textblock>revoking and reissuing, or terminating this permit, or to determine</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance with this permit. The permittee shall also furnish to the Director</textblock>
    <textblock>or ADEC, upon request, copies of records required to be kept by this</textblock>
    <textblock>permit.</textblock>
    <textblock>G. Other Information</textblock>
    <textblock>When the permittee becomes aware that it failed to</textblock>
    <textblock>submit any relevant facts in a permit application, or submitted incorrect</textblock>
    <textblock>information in a permit application or any report to the Director or ADEC, it</textblock>
    <textblock>shall promptly submit such facts or information.</textblock>
    <textblock>H. Signatory Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>All applications, reports or information submitted</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Director and ADEC shall be signed and certified.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. All permit applications shall be signed as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. For a corporation: by a responsible corporate officer.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. For a partnership or sole proprietorship: by a general partner or</textblock>
    <textblock>the proprietor, respectively.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. For a municipality, state, federal, or other public agency: by either</textblock>
    <textblock>a principal executive officer or ranking elected official.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. All reports required by the permit and other information requested by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Director or ADEC shall be signed by a person described above or</textblock>
    <textblock>by a duly authorized representative of that person. A person is a duly</textblock>
    <textblock>authorized representative only if:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. The authorization is made in writing by a person described above</textblock>
    <textblock>and submitted to the Director and ADEC, and</textblock>
    <textblock>b. The authorization specified either an individual or a position having</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility for the overall operation of the regulated facility or</textblock>
    <textblock>activity, such as the position of plant manager, operator of a well or</textblock>
    <textblock>a well field, superintendent, position of equivalent responsibility, or</textblock>
    <textblock>an individual or position having overall responsibility for</textblock>
    <textblock>environmental matters for the company. (A duly authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>representative may thus be either a named individual or any</textblock>
    <textblock>individual occupying a named position.)</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Changes to authorization. If an authorization under paragraph IV.H.2. is</textblock>
    <textblock>no longer accurate because a different individual or position has</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility for the overall operation of the facility, a new authorization</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfying the requirements of paragraph VI.H.2. must be submitted to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Director and ADEC prior to or together with any reports,</textblock>
    <textblock>information, or applications to be signed by an authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>representative.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Certification. Any person signing a document under this section shall</textblock>
    <textblock>make the following certification:</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
