<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00041</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463), announcement is made of the following National Advisory body scheduled to meet during the month of February 1994:</textblock>
    <textblock>Name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Committee on Infant Mortality.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date and Time:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 16-17, 1994, 8:30 a.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Grand Ballroom, The Grand Hotel, 2250 M Street, NW., Washington, DC 20037.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting is open to the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Committee provides advice and recommendations to the Secretary on the following: Department programs which are directed at reducing infant mortality and improving the health status of pregnant women and infants; how best to coordinate the variety of Federal, State, local and private programs and efforts that are designed to deal with the health and social problems impacting on infant mortality; and the implementation of the Healthy Start initiative and infant mortality objectives from Healthy People: 2000: National Health Promotion and Disease Prevention Objectives.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agenda:</textblock>
    <textblock>Topics that will be discussed include: Presentation on the History of Maternal-Child Health; analysis of Health Care Reform and Infant Mortality; and updates on current programs at the National level.</textblock>
    <textblock>Anyone requiring information regarding the Committee should contact Dr. Peter van Dyck, Executive Secretary, Advisory Committee on Infant Mortality, Health Resources and Services Administration, room 18-44, Parklawn Building, 5600 Fishers Lane, Rockville, Maryland 20857, Telephone (301) 443-2204.</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons interested in attending any portion of the meeting should contact Ms. Kerry P. Nesseler, Maternal and Child Health Bureau, Health Resources and Services Administration, Telephone (301) 443-2204.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agenda Items are subject to change as priorities dictate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Health Resources and Services Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Advisory Council Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jackie E. Baum,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Advisory Committee Management Officer, HRSA.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-950 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-15-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
