<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00106</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00065</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-424 described as follows: Beginning at the Northeast corner of said A-424; Thence, S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○15</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 350 feet, along the East line of said A-424; Thence, S. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○28</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2700 feet; Thence, N. 02</textblock>
    <textblock>○45</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1050 feet, along the West line of said A-424; Thence, Southeasterly, approximately 4000 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>W.O. Flowers; A-205.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-205 described as follows: Beginning at the Southwest corner of said A-205; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 800 feet, along the West line of said A-205; Thence, S. 75</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1900 feet; Thence,</textblock>
    <textblock>S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1300 feet, along the East line of said A-205; Thence, Northwesterly, approximately 2500 feet, along the northerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>D.F. Singleton; A-881.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-881 described as follows: Beginning at the Southwest corner of said A-881; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1000 feet, along the West line of said A-881; Thence, S. 75</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 350 feet; Thence, S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 800 feet, along the East line of said A-881; Thence, Southwesterly and Northwesterly, approximately 500 feet, along the northerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>T.&amp;N.O. Railroad; A-482.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-482 described as follows: Beginning at the Northeast corner of said A-482; Thence, S. 02</textblock>
    <textblock>○45</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1050 feet, along the East line of said A-482; Thence, S. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○28</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2650 feet; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○15</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1100 feet, along the West line of said A-482; Thence, Easterly, approximately 2700 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Louis E. Nordman; A-412.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-412 described as follows: Beginning at the Southwest corner of said A-412; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○54</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1500 feet, along the West line of said A-412; Thence, S. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○17</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 2600 feet; Thence, S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1000 feet, along the East line of said A-412; Thence, Westerly, approximately 2500 feet, along the northerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>James E. Price; A-556.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-556 described as follows: Beginning at the Northeast corner of said A-556; Thence, S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○15</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1100 feet, along the East line of said A-556; Thence, S. 87</textblock>
    <textblock>○28</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 2700 feet; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○15</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 850 feet, along the West line of said A-556; Thence, Easterly, approximately 3200 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Andrew Hay; A-264.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-264 described as follows: Beginning at the Northeast corner of said A-264; Thence, S. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○15</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 850 feet, along the East line of said A-264; Thence, N .85</textblock>
    <textblock>○49</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 300 feet; Thence, N. 02</textblock>
    <textblock>○58</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 600 feet; Thence, Northeasterly and Southeasterly approximately 450 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also Beginning at the Northwest corner of said A-264; Thence, Southeasterly and Northeasterly, approximately 2250 feet, along the southerly gradient boundary of Village Creek; Thence, S. 02</textblock>
    <textblock>○58</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 850 feet; Thence, S. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○04</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1600 feet; Thence, N. 03</textblock>
    <textblock>○15</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1550 feet along the West line of said A-264, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>Wilson Brooks; A-79.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>ALL, of said A-79 that lies North of Farm Road 943.</textblock>
    <textblock>Survey and Abstract No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Helfenstein; A-263.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portion:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part of A-263 described as follows: Beginning at the Southwest corner of said A-263; Thence, N.04</textblock>
    <textblock>○33</textblock>
    <textblock>W., 1950 feet, along the West line of said A-263; Thence, N. 88</textblock>
    <textblock>○31</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 4600 feet; Thence, S. 05</textblock>
    <textblock>○04</textblock>
    <textblock>E., 1950 feet, along the East line of said A-263; Thence, Northwesterly and Southwesterly, approximately 7500 feet along the northerly gradient boundary of Village Creek, to the Point of Beginning.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
