<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00038</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Regulations Implementing Section 7 of the ``Negotiated Rates Act of 1993''</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>INTERSTATE COMMERCE COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>49 CFR Parts 1051, 1053 and 1312</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Ex Parte No. MC-180 (Sub-No. 3)]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interstate Commerce Commission (ICC).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The ``Negotiated Rates Act of 1993'' amends the Interstate Commerce Act by adding section 10767. Section 10767 requires that the Commission establish regulations to prohibit, except for certain services, motor common and contract carriers of property from providing a reduction in a tariff rate or contract rate to a person who is a nonpayer of freight charges. This proceeding establishes, as set forth below, the regulations required by the statute.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 13, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Charles E. Langyher (202) 927-5160 or Ronald A. Hall (202) 927-5595; TDD for hearing impaired: (202) 927-5721.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>By a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPR) in Ex Parte No. MC-180 (Sub-No. 2), Rulemaking_Payment of Discounts by Motor Carriers of Property to the Nonpayer of Freight Charges (not printed) served June 4, 1993 (58 FR 32340, June 9, 1993), the Commission instituted a proceeding to determine whether off-bill discounting where it does or may result in a misrepresentation of shipping charges should be found to be an unreasonable practice or otherwise unlawful. However, the ``Negotiated Rates Act of 1993'' (Pub. L. 103-180) since has been enacted and amends subchapter IV of chapter 107 of title 49, United States Code, by adding section 10767, which requires that the Commission issue regulations by April 2, 1994, that will:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Prohibit,</textblock>
    <textblock>except as described in (4) below, motor common and contract carriers of property from providing a reduction in a tariff or contract rate to any party other than the person directly responsible to the carrier for payment of the transportation service according to the bill of lading, receipt, or contract, or an agent of the person paying for the transportation. 49 U.S.C. 10767(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Require</textblock>
    <textblock>a motor common carrier of property to disclose, either by a shipping document or an electronic transmission, the actual tariff rate, charge, or allowance to the person directly responsible for payment for the transportation service. 49 U.S.C. 10767(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Prohibit</textblock>
    <textblock>any person from causing a motor common carrier of property to present a document to any party of the transaction, which contains false or misleading information about the actual tariff rate, charge, or allowance. 49 U.S.C. 10767(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>Permit</textblock>
    <textblock>motor common and contract carriers of property to make actual tariff or contract payments or allowances to a party to the transaction, when such party performs a transportation service that would otherwise be performed by the carrier, such as a loading and unloading service, provided that the payment or allowance is reasonably related to the cost that such party knows or has reason to know would otherwise be incurred by the motor carrier if it had performed the service. 49 U.S.C. 10767(c).</textblock>
    <textblock>Because section 10767 supersedes the NPR, the Ex Parte No. MC-180 (Sub-No. 2) proceeding is discontinued.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission does not believe this revision requires notice and comment rulemaking under section 553 of the Administrative Procedure Act (5 U.S.C. 553) because it establishes regulations mandated by Congress.</textblock>
    <textblock>This decision will not affect significantly either the quality of the human environment or the conservation of energy resources.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects</textblock>
    <textblock>49 CFR Part 1051</textblock>
    <textblock>Buses, Freight, Motor carriers, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>49 CFR Part 1053</textblock>
    <textblock>Motor contract carriers.</textblock>
    <textblock>49 CFR Part 1312</textblock>
    <textblock>Motor carriers, Moving of household goods, Pipelines, Tariffs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Decided: December 30, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Commission, Chairman McDonald, Vice Chairman Simmons, Commissioners Phillips, and Philbin.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Sidney L. Strickland, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
