<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00086</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00055</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Notice of Availability of the Proposed Twin Falls County Solid Waste Facility (TFSWF) Draft Environmental Impact Statement and Draft Land Use Plan Amendment</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[ID-020-4060-02]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Twin Falls County, Idaho has made application to purchase 1083.77 acres of public land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), on which they propose to construct, operate and maintain a state of the art ``Subtitle D'' solid waste facility. The proposed project is located near Hub Butte, 10 miles south of the City of Twin Falls, Idaho. The purpose of the proposed facility would be to bring Twin Falls County into compliance with the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act (RCRA) and its associated regulations, 40 CFR 257 and 258 ``Subtitle D''. These regulations set forth many new requirements for solid waste facilities that are in operation after April 9, 1993 that the existing facilities in Twin Falls County do not meet. The proposed facility would be constructed and administered by Twin Falls County and would be operated by a private contractor.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>All comments must be received by BLM or postmarked by April 15, 1994. A formal public meeting to receive comments on the Draft Environmental Impact Statement and Draft Plan Amendment (DEIS/DPA) will be held on February 15, 1994 in the College of Southern Idaho cafeteria in Twin Falls, ID from 7 p.m. to 9 p.m.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments regarding the DEIS/DPA may be made orally at the meeting or they can be submitted in writing to the Burley District Manager, Bureau of Land Management, Route 3, Box 1, Burley, Idaho 83318.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Scott Barker, Project Manager, Bureau of Land Management, Burley District Office, Route 3, Box 1, Burley, Idaho 83318. Phone (208) 678-5514.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>A Draft Environmental Impact Statement/Draft Plan Amendment (DEIS/DPA) has been prepared which identifies resource values and analyzes the environmental impacts to these resource that would be expected from the proposed action. The DEIS/DPA identifies the preferred alternative, which is the proposed action, and a no action alternative. The Bureau of Land Management is the lead Federal Agency in the preparation of the TFSWF DEIS/DPA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the DEIS/DPA are being sent to all individuals and agencies that have participated in the public scoping process or have otherwise asked to be included on the mailing list.</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional copies are available from the Burley District of the Bureau of Land Management, Route 3, Box 1, Burley, Idaho, 83318. The Burley District telephone number is (208) 678-5514.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Marvin R. Bagley,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate District Manager.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-920 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-CG-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
