<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00153</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00095</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Modification of a Railroad Signal System or Relief From the</textblock>
    <textblock>Requirements of 49 CFR Part 236</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to 49 CFR part 235 and 49 U.S.C. App. 26, the following railroads have petitioned the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) seeking approval for the discontinuance or modification of the signal system or relief from the requirements of 49 CFR part 236 as detailed below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Block Signal Application (BS-AP)-No. 3273</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>Buffalo &amp; Pittsburgh Railroad, Inc., Mr. R. T. Haley,</textblock>
    <textblock>Signal Supervisor C&amp;S,</textblock>
    <textblock>201 North Penn Street,</textblock>
    <textblock>Punxsutawney, Pennsylvania 15767.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Buffalo &amp; Pittsburgh Railroad, Inc., seeks approval of the proposed discontinuance and removal of the signal system, on the single main track, between Macklin, milepost 282.4 and Eidenau, milepost 303.5, near Butler, Pennsylvania, on the Butler Branch.</textblock>
    <textblock>The reason given for the proposed changes is to retire facilities no longer required for present operation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rules Standards &amp; Instructions Application (RS&amp;I-AP)-No. 1089</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant:</textblock>
    <textblock>Consolidated Rail Corporation,</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. J. F. Noffsinger,</textblock>
    <textblock>Chief Engineer_C&amp;S,</textblock>
    <textblock>2001 Market Street,</textblock>
    <textblock>P.O. Box 41410,</textblock>
    <textblock>Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 19101-1410.</textblock>
    <textblock>Consolidated Rail Corporation (Conrail) seeks relief from the requirements of ยง236.566 (49 CFR 236.566) of the Rules, Standard and Instructions to the extent that they be allowed to operate nonequipped locomotives in automatic cab signal territory, on the two main tracks between ``CP Jacks,''</textblock>
    <textblock>milepost 191.3 and ``CP Gray,'' milepost 223.3, on the Pittsburgh Line, Harrisburg Division, for the following operations:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Wire trains, work trains, wreck trains, and ballast cleaners to and from work;</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Engines and diesel cars moving to and from shops; and</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Engines used in switching and transfer service, with or without cars, not exceeding 20 miles per hour.</textblock>
    <textblock>The reason given for the proposed changes is that exemptions are already authorized for operation of nonequipped locomotives under the same circumstances in cab signal territory at other locations on Conrail, and that this relief request would be an extention of those already existing exemptions.</textblock>
    <textblock>RS&amp;I-AP-No. 1090</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicants:</textblock>
    <textblock>Union Pacific Railroad Company,</textblock>
    <textblock>and Missouri Pacific Railroad Company,</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. E. J. McCaddon,</textblock>
    <textblock>Director of Locomotive Maintenance Operations,</textblock>
    <textblock>Harriman Dispatching Center,</textblock>
    <textblock>850 Jones Street,</textblock>
    <textblock>Omaha, Nebraska 68102-2920.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Union Pacific Railroad Company and Missouri Pacific Railroad Company (UP&amp;MP) jointly seek relief from the requirements of Section 236.590 (49 CFR 236.590) of the Rules, Standard and Instructions for all locomotives owned, leased, or operated under contract by the UP&amp;MP, equipped with Automatic Train Control Systems (including automatic train control, automatic train stop, and coded cab signals), to the extent that the carrier be permitted to extend the current 2 year time limit (736 days) to 3 years, for change out or removal and cleaning of the following pneumatic valves associated with Automatic Train Control Systems:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. ``EBPS''_Engine Brake Pressure Switch 35/20 PSI.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. ``SBPS''_Service Brake Pressure Switch 35/20 PSI.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. ATC_Magnet Valve.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. CCS_Magnet Valve.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant's justification for relief: To allow easier scheduling of air brake work since time limits would coincide with other locomotive valves, providing improved inventory control, reducing required inventory, and reducing locomotive down-time. The carrier also states the failure frequency is less than air brake valves currently changed and cleaned on a</textblock>
    <textblock>3 year basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any interested party desiring to protest the granting of an application shall set forth specifically the grounds upon which the protest is made, and contain a concise statement of the interest of the protestant in the proceeding. The original and two copies of the protest shall be filed with the Associate Administrator for Safety, FRA, 400 Seventh Street, SW., Washington, DC 20590 within 45 calendar days of the date of</textblock>
    <textblock>issuance of this notice. Additionally, one copy of the protest shall be furnished to the applicant at the address listed above.</textblock>
    <textblock>FRA expects to be able to determine these matters without oral hearing. However, if a specific request for an oral hearing is accompanied by a showing that the party is unable to adequately present his or her position by written statements, an application may be set for public hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC on January 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Railroad Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Application for Approval of Discontinuance or</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Phil Olekszyk,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Associate Administrator for Safety.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-901 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-06-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
