<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00044</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Friday</textblock>
    <textblock>January 14, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part II</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Housing and Urban Development</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the Assistant Secretary for Housing-Federal Housing Commissioner</textblock>
    <textblock>24 CFR Parts 3280 and 3282</textblock>
    <textblock>Manufactured Home Construction and Safety Standards on Wind Standards; Final Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 10␣/␣Friday, January 14, 1994␣/␣Rules and Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>24 CFR Parts 3280 and 3282</textblock>
    <textblock>Manufactured Home Construction and Safety Standards</textblock>
    <textblock>on Wind Standards</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of the Assistant Secretary for Housing-Federal Housing Commissioner</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. R-93-1632; FR-3380-F-02]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 2502-AF91</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the Assistant Secretary for Housing-Federal Housing</textblock>
    <textblock>Commissioner, HUD.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>HUD is amending the Federal Manufactured Home Construction and</textblock>
    <textblock>Safety Standards (FMHCSS) to improve the resistance of manufactured homes to</textblock>
    <textblock>wind forces in areas prone to hurricanes. Under this rule, manufactured homes</textblock>
    <textblock>will have to be designed to withstand wind speeds of up to 110 miles an hour</textblock>
    <textblock>in hurricane-prone areas, in accordance with design provisions of the American</textblock>
    <textblock>Society of Civil Engineers Standard ANSI/ASCE 7-88. Also, the Department is</textblock>
    <textblock>making certain other changes to the standards to ensure that structural</textblock>
    <textblock>assemblies, components, windows, connectors, and fasteners will be adequate</textblock>
    <textblock>for the area in which the home is to be placed. The revised standard also</textblock>
    <textblock>requires exterior roof and wall coverings to be fastened adequately to</textblock>
    <textblock>sheathing and framing members, to resist higher design wind pressures.</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of this rule is to increase the safety of manufactured</textblock>
    <textblock>homes, thereby reducing deaths and injuries and extensive property damage</textblock>
    <textblock>losses in areas where wind-induced damage is a particular hazard and risk.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>July 13, 1994, except that §§3280.403(b) and (e) and 3280.404(b) and (e) will become</textblock>
    <textblock>effective January 17, 1995. The incorporation by reference of certain publications listed in</textblock>
    <textblock>the regulations is approved by the Director of the Federal Register as of July 13, 1994, except that the incorporation by reference of publications listed in</textblock>
    <textblock>§§3280.403(b) and (e) and 3280.404(b) and (e) will become effective January 17, 1995.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>G. Robert Fuller, Director, Manufactured</textblock>
    <textblock>Housing and Construction Standards Division, Department of Housing and Urban</textblock>
    <textblock>Development, 451 Seventh Street, SW., ATTN: Mailroom B-133, Washington, DC</textblock>
    <textblock>20410-8000. Telephones: (voice) (202) 755-7430; (TDD) (202) 708-4594. (These</textblock>
    <textblock>are not toll-free numbers.)</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Background</textblock>
    <textblock>Developmental History</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety</textblock>
    <textblock>Standards Act of 1974 (42 U.S.C. 5401-5426, at 5401) (the Act) is to reduce</textblock>
    <textblock>the number of personal injuries and deaths and the amount of insurance costs</textblock>
    <textblock>and property damage resulting from manufactured home accidents, and to improve</textblock>
    <textblock>the quality and durability of manufactured homes. Section 604 of the Act</textblock>
    <textblock>confers authority on the Secretary of HUD to issue, amend, or revoke any</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal manufactured home construction or safety standard.</textblock>
    <textblock>Following Hurricane Andrew, the Department conducted field</textblock>
    <textblock>investigations of the damage experienced in the hurricane by manufactured</textblock>
    <textblock>housing units, as part of a full-scale review of the Federal manufactured home</textblock>
    <textblock>standards. The goal of these investigations and the review of materials and</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendations was to ensure that the Federal standards provide adequate</textblock>
    <textblock>protection to manufactured home occupants during high wind conditions. On</textblock>
    <textblock>April 14, 1993, the Department published a proposed rule (58 FR 19536) that</textblock>
    <textblock>reported the preliminary conclusions of the Department's efforts, and sought</textblock>
    <textblock>public comment on changes that the Department was considering for the Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>standards. The Department also contacted each of the members of the National</textblock>
    <textblock>Manufactured Home Advisory Council (Advisory Council), individually, in order</textblock>
    <textblock>to solicit their individual comments on the proposed wind standards rule,</textblock>
    <textblock>because the proposed timetable for final publication did not permit convening</textblock>
    <textblock>the Advisory Council. The individual responses of the Advisory Council</textblock>
    <textblock>members have been considered as public comments and included in the docket</textblock>
    <textblock>file for this rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>On June 9, 1993, the Department announced (58 FR 32316) that the comment</textblock>
    <textblock>period would be extended to July 9, 1993. The Department has continued to</textblock>
    <textblock>receive and consider comments well after that date, while this final rule was</textblock>
    <textblock>being developed. Because the timeframe originally proposed for the</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation of standard changes was postponed as a result of public</textblock>
    <textblock>comments and the extension of the comment deadline, the Department consulted</textblock>
    <textblock>with the National Manufactured Home Commission and convened the Advisory</textblock>
    <textblock>Council for consultation and to seek recommendations from the Advisory Council</textblock>
    <textblock>as a whole (see the notice published at 58 FR 34586 (June 28, 1993)). The</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council met in Washington, DC, on July 13 and 14, 1993, to discuss</textblock>
    <textblock>wind standards and other proposals for changes to the standards for</textblock>
    <textblock>manufactured housing.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
