<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00075</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940114-2-00046</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Public Law 92-463, notice is hereby given of the meeting of the Biomedical Library Review Committee on March 2-3, 1994, convening at 8:30 a.m. in the Board Room of the National Library of Medicine, Building 38, 8600 Rockville Pike, Bethesda, Maryland.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting on March 2 will be open to the public from 8:30 a.m. to approximately 11 a.m. for the discussion of administrative reports and program developments. Attendance by the public will be limited to space available. Individuals who plan to attend and need special assistance, such as sign-language interpretation or other reasonable accommodations, should contact Dr. Roger W. Dahlen at 301-496-4221 two weeks before the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with provisions set forth in sections 552b(c)(4) and 552b(c)(6), title 5, U.S.C., and section 10(d) of Public Law 92-463, the meeting on March 2 will be closed to the public for the review, discussion, and evaluation of individual grant applications from 11 a.m. to approximately 5 p.m., and on March 3 from 8:30 a.m. to adjournment. These applications and the discussion could reveal confidential trade secrets or commercial property, such as patentable material, and personal information concerning individuals associated with the applications, disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Robert W. Dahlen, Scientific Review Administrator, and Chief, Biomedical Information Support Branch, Extramural Programs, National Library of Medicine, 8600 Rockville Pike, Bethesda, Maryland 20894, telephone number: 301-496-4221, will provide summaries of the meeting, rosters of the committee members, and other information pertaining to the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Program No. 93.879_Medical Library Assistance, National Institutes of Health)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Library of Medicine; Meeting of the Biomedical Library Review Committee</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Susan K. Feldman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Committee Management Officer, NIH.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1021 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4140-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
