<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-0-00028</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-0-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>e. Review Under Executive Order 12612</textblock>
    <textblock>f. Review Under Executive Order 12778</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Regulatory Review</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulatory action has been determined not to be a ``significant</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory action'' under Executive Order 12866, ``Regulatory Planning and</textblock>
    <textblock>Review,'' (58 FR 51735, October 4, 1993). Accordingly, this action was not</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to review under the Executive Order by the Office of Information and</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Affairs.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Review Under the National Environmental Policy Act</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the Council on Environmental Quality Regulations (40 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>1500-1508), the Department has established guidelines for its compliance with</textblock>
    <textblock>the provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) of 1969 (42</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S.C. 4321</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>). Pursuant to Appendix A of Subpart D of 10 CFR Part</textblock>
    <textblock>1021, National Environmental Policy Act Implementing Procedures, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Energy has determined that this rule is categorically excluded</textblock>
    <textblock>from the need to prepare an environmental impact statement or environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Review Under the Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>To the extent that new information collection or recordkeeping</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements are imposed by this rulemaking they are provided for under</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Management and Budget paperwork clearance package No. 1910-0300.</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Review Under the Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule was reviewed under the Regulatory Flexibility Act of 1980, Public</textblock>
    <textblock>Law 96-354, which requires preparation of a regulatory flexibility analysis</textblock>
    <textblock>for any rule which is likely to have significant economic impact on a</textblock>
    <textblock>substantial number of small entities. This rule will have no impact on</textblock>
    <textblock>interest rates, tax policies or liabilities, the cost of goods or services, or</textblock>
    <textblock>other direct economic factors. It will also not have any indirect economic</textblock>
    <textblock>consequences, such as changed construction rates. DOE certifies that this</textblock>
    <textblock>rule will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of</textblock>
    <textblock>small entities and, therefore, no regulatory flexibility analysis has been</textblock>
    <textblock>prepared.</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Review Under Executive Order 12612</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12612, entitled ``Federalism,'' 52 FR 41685 (October 30,</textblock>
    <textblock>1987), requires that regulations, rules, legislation, and any other policy</textblock>
    <textblock>actions be reviewed for any substantial direct effects on States, on the</textblock>
    <textblock>relationship between the Federal Government and the States, or in the</textblock>
    <textblock>distribution of power and responsibilities among various levels of government.</textblock>
    <textblock>If there are sufficient substantial direct effects, then the Executive Order</textblock>
    <textblock>requires preparation of a federalism assessment to be used in all decisions</textblock>
    <textblock>involved in promulgating and implementing a policy action. This rule will not</textblock>
    <textblock>affect States substantially.</textblock>
    <textblock>f. Review Under Executive Order 12778</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 2 of Executive Order 12778 instructs each agency subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12291 to adhere to certain requirements in promulgating new</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations and reviewing existing regulations. These requirements, set forth</textblock>
    <textblock>in sections 2(a) and (b)(2), include eliminating drafting errors and needless</textblock>
    <textblock>ambiguity, drafting the regulations to minimize litigation, providing clear</textblock>
    <textblock>and certain legal standards for affected legal conduct, and promoting</textblock>
    <textblock>simplification and burden reduction. Agencies are also instructed to make</textblock>
    <textblock>every reasonable effort to ensure that the regulation: Specifies clearly any</textblock>
    <textblock>preemptive effect, effect on existing Federal law or regulation, and</textblock>
    <textblock>retroactive effect; describes any administrative proceedings to be available</textblock>
    <textblock>prior to judicial review and any provisions for the exhaustion of such</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative proceedings; and defines key terms. DOE certifies that this</textblock>
    <textblock>rule meets the requirements of sections 2(a) and 2(b) of Executive Order</textblock>
    <textblock>12778.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 48 CFR Part 970</textblock>
    <textblock>Government procurement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, D.C. on February 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>G. L. Allen,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>for Procurement and Assistance Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
