<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00011</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Endangered Species; Permits</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>agency:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS) NOAA, Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Receipt of a Request to Modify Permit 823 (P503C).</textblock>
    <textblock>On April 1, 1993 (58 FR 18205), the Idaho Department of Fish and Game (IDFG) was issued Permit No. 823 to take listed Snake River fall and spring/summer chinook salmon (</textblock>
    <textblock>Oncorhynchus tshawytscha</textblock>
    <textblock>) and listed Snake River sockeye salmon (</textblock>
    <textblock>O. nerka</textblock>
    <textblock>) for the purposes of scientific research, as authorized by the Endangered Species Act (ESA) (16 U.S.C. 1531-1543) and the NMFS regulations governing listed fish and wildlife permits (50 CFR parts 217-227). On June 16, 1993 (58 FR 34244) IDFG was issued an amendment to Permit 823.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that IDFG has applied for a modification to Permit 823. IDFG has reevaluated their estimates of effects to listed salmon based on the results of 1993 activities, and they included the handling of listed broodyear 1992 hatchery fish in their estimates. In addition, IDFG requests authorization to assume the responsibilities for research in the Lemhi River, formerly conducted by the Idaho Cooperative Fish and Wildlife Research Unit (ICFWRU) under Permit 820. The activities include smolt trapping, snorkeling, collecting listed chinook salmon for genetic analysis, and PIT tagging. ICFWRU has also requested this transfer of authorization. The modification would be valid for the duration of the permit, through November 30, 1997.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written data or views, or requests for a public hearing on this application for a modification should be submitted to the Director, Office of Protected Resources, National Marine Fisheries Service, 1335 East-West Hwy., Silver Spring, MD 20910, within 30 days of the publication of this notice. Those individuals requesting a hearing should set forth the specific reasons why a hearing on this particular application would be appropriate. The holding of such hearing is at the discretion of the Assistant Administrator for Fisheries. All statements and opinions contained in this application summary are those of the applicant and do not necessarily reflect the views of the National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>Documents submitted in connection with the above application are available for review by interested persons in the following offices by appointment:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Protected Resources, National Marine Fisheries Service, 1335 East-West Hwy., Silver Spring, MD 20910 (301-713-2322); and</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental and Technical Services Division, National Marine Fisheries Service, 911 North East 11th Ave., room 620, Portland, OR 97232 (503-230-5400).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </action>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Herbert W. Kaufman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Director, Office of Protected Resources.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2633 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
