<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00010</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[I.D. 013194E]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Pacific Fishery Management Council; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of public meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Pacific Fishery Management Council's Salmon Technical Team will meet on February 15-18, 1994, at the Council office, 2000 SW. First Avenue, suite 420, Portland, OR; telephone: (503) 326-6352. The meeting will begin on February 15 at 10 a.m. and at 8 a.m. on the other days. The meeting will run until 5 p.m. each day.</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the meeting is to draft the 1994 stock status report, ``Preseason I Stock Abundance Analysis for 1994 Ocean Salmon Fisheries''. The final report will be distributed to the public and reviewed by the Council at its March meeting in Portland.</textblock>
    <textblock>This meeting is physically accessible to people with disabilities. Requests for sign language interpretation or other auxiliary aids should be directed to Michelle Perry Sailer on (503) 326-6352 at least 5 days prior to the meeting date.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>John Coon, Fishery Management Coordinator (Salmon), Pacific Fishery Management Council,</textblock>
    <textblock>2000 SW. First Avenue, suite 420, Portland, OR 97201; telephone: (503) 326-6352.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David S. Crestin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Office of Fisheries Conservation and Management, National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2637 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
