<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00104</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00054</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Agency Information Collection Under OMB Review</textblock>
  </text>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Endowment for the Humanities.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) has sent to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) the following proposals for the collection of information under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. chapter 35).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this information collection must be submitted on or before March 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send comments to Ms. Susan Daisey, Assistant Director, Grants Office, National Endowment for the Humanities, 1100 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., room 310, Washington, DC 20506 (202-606-8494) and Mr. Steve Semenuk, Office of Management and Budget, New Executive Office Building, 726 Jackson Place, NW., room 3002, Washington, DC 20503 (202-395-6880).</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Susan Daisey, Assistant Director, Grants Office, National Endowment for the Humanities, 1100 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., room 310, Washington, DC 20506 (202) 606-8494 from whom copies of forms and supporting documents are available.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>All of the entries are grouped into new forms, revisions, extensions, or reinstatements. Each entry is issued by NEH and contains the following information: (1) the title of the form; (2) the agency form number, if applicable; (3) how often the form must be filled out; (4) who will be required or asked to report; (5) what the form will be used for; (6) an estimate of the number of responses; (7) the frequency of response; (8) an estimate of the total number of hours needed to fill out the form; (9) an estimate of the total annual reporting and recordkeeping burden. None of these entries are subject to 44 U.S.C. 3504(h).</textblock>
    <textblock>Category: Revisions</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Division of State Programs: Guidelines for State Council Proposals.</textblock>
    <textblock>Form Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>Not Applicable.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Collection:</textblock>
    <textblock>Biennially or Triennially (At council's own option).</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>State humanities councils apply for funding.</textblock>
    <textblock>Use:</textblock>
    <textblock>Application for benefits by state humanities councils to be granted to nonprofit groups and organizations in their states to make focused coherent humanities education possible in places and by methods that are appropriate to adults. Information will be used by panelists, and the Endowment's Chairman to determine eligibility for funding.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>26-28.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Biennially or Triennially.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Hours for Respondents to Provide Information:</textblock>
    <textblock>87 per respondent or 2262-2436 total hours for all respondents.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Total Annual Reporting and Recordkeeping Burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>46-220 hours.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donald Gibson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Deputy Chairman.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2572 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7536-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
