<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00042</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00026</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>During the week of December 27 through December 31, 1993, the decisions and orders summarized below were issued with respect to applications for other relief filed with the Office of Hearings and Appeals of the Department of Energy. The following summary also contains a list of submissions that were dismissed by the Office of Hearings and Appeals.</textblock>
    <textblock>Appeals</textblock>
    <textblock>Armor Elevator Company, Inc., 12/28/93, LFA-0340</textblock>
    <textblock>Armor Elevator Company, Inc., filed an Appeal from a denial by the Batavia Area Office of a Request for Information which the firm had submitted under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA). In considering the Appeal, the DOE found that the requested documents were not agency records because Batavia neither created nor obtained the material. Important issues that were considered in the Decision and Order were (i) whether the contractor responsible for maintaining and operating a government location is considered an agency for purposes of the FOIA and (ii) the test for classification as an agency record.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cynthia Ann Virostek, 12/29/93, LFA-0342</textblock>
    <textblock>Cynthia Ann Virostek filed an Appeal from a determination issued by the Office of the Executive Secretariat (OES) of the DOE, in response to a request for information submitted under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA). In its determination, the OES released a letter requested by Virostek but stated that the enclosures to the letter could not be located. In her Appeal, Virostek challenged the adequacy of this determination. The letter requested by Virostek was authored by Robert Seamans, the Administrator of the Energy Research and Development Administration (ERDA) and was addressed to the Chairman of Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), who had submitted a draft report to ERDA and requested its views. The enclosures to the letter were not stand-alone documents but were created as part of ERDA's response to the NRC, solely for the purpose of supplementing with greater detail the view set forth in the body of the letter. In considering the Appeal, the DOE found that because of the nature of the enclosures, the search performed by the OES through the archives of files of the ERDA Administrator was reasonably calculated to uncover the material sought by the appellant. Accordingly, Virostek's Appeal was denied.</textblock>
    <textblock>Government Accountability Project, 12/27/93, LFA-0341</textblock>
    <textblock>The Government Accountability Project (GAP) filed an Appeal from a denial of a waiver of fees by the Director of the Office of Communications of the Richland Field Office (Richland) of the DOE. In considering the Appeal, the DOE found that while whistleblower litigation did not constitute a ``commercial interest'' under the fee waiver statute, neither did it automatically satisfy the public interest requirement of the statute. The Appeal was remanded to Richland to determine whether any of the information to be disclosed met the public interest requirement of the fee waiver statute.</textblock>
    <textblock>Refund Applications</textblock>
    <textblock>The Office of Hearings and Appeals issued the following Decisions and Orders concerning refund applications, which are not summarized. Copies of the full texts of the Decisions and Orders are available in the Public Reference Room of the Office of Hearings and Appeals.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Issuance of Decisions and Orders During the Week of December 27 Through December 31, 1993</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Beacon Oil Company/Atkerson Beacon Service et al</textblock>
    <textblock>RF238-89</textblock>
    <textblock>12/29/93</textblock>
    <textblock>Childress County</textblock>
    <textblock>RF272-87754</textblock>
    <textblock>12/29/93</textblock>
    <textblock>Farmers Union Oil Company</textblock>
    <textblock>RF272-88267</textblock>
    <textblock>12/29/93</textblock>
    <textblock>Co-op Supply, Inc</textblock>
    <textblock>RF272-88797</textblock>
    <textblock>12/29/93</textblock>
    <textblock>Gulf Oil Corporation/Colonial Stores, Inc</textblock>
    <textblock>RF300-18168</textblock>
    <textblock>12/29/93</textblock>
    <textblock>Gulf Oil Corporation/VT Petroleum, Inc</textblock>
    <textblock>RF300-19595</textblock>
    <textblock>12/29/93</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
