<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00102</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00052</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NATIONAL FOUNDATION ON THE ARTS AND HUMANITIES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Agency Information Collection Under OMB Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Endowment for the Humanities.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) has sent to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) the following proposals for the collection of information under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. Chapter 35).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this information collection must be submitted on or before March 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send comments to Ms. Susan Daisey, Assistant Director, Grants Office, National Endowment for the Humanities, 1100 Pennsylvania Avenue NW., room 310, Washington, DC 20506 (202-606-8494) and Mr. Steve Semenuk, Office of Management and Budget, New Executive Office Building, 726 Jackson Place NW., room 3002, Washington, DC 20503 (202-395-6880).</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Susan Daisey, Assistant Director, Grants Office, National Endowment for the Humanities, 1100 Pennsylvania Avenue NW., room 310, Washington, DC 20506 (202) 606-8494 from whom copies of forms and supporting documents are available.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>All of the entries are grouped into new forms, revisions, extensions, or reinstatements. Each entry is issued by NEH and contains the following information: (1) The title of the form; (2) the agency form number, if applicable; (3) how often the form must be filled out; (4) who will be required or asked to report; (5) what the form will be used for; (6) an estimate of the number of responses; (7) the frequency of response; (8) an estimate of the total number of hours needed to fill out the form; (9) an estimate of the total annual reporting and recordkeeping burden. None of these entries are subject to 44 U.S.C. 3504(h).</textblock>
    <textblock>Category:</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information Survey Form and Instructions for Panelists and Reviewers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Form Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>3136-0123.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Collection:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ad hoc.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals: academic scholars, writers, teachers, and other experts in the humanities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Use:</textblock>
    <textblock>Peer review process and application evaluation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>500.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Once.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Hours for Respondents to Provide Information:</textblock>
    <textblock>0.33 per respondent.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Total Annual Reporting and Recordkeeping Burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>165 hours.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donald Gibson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Deputy Chairman.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2628 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7536-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
