<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-0-00008</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-0-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Standard Instrument Approach Procedures; Miscellaneous Amendments</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 97</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 27592; Amdt. No. 1584]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This amendment establishes, amends, suspends, or revokes Standard Instrument Approach Procedures (SIAPs) for operations at certain airports. These regulatory actions are needed because of the adoption of new or revised criteria, or because of changes occurring in the National Airspace System, such as the commissioning of new navigational facilities, addition of new obstacles, or changes in air traffic requirements. These changes are designed to provide safe and efficient use of the navigable airspace and to promote safe flight operations under instrument flight rules at the affected airports.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective:</textblock>
    <textblock>An effective date for each SIAP is specified in the amendatory provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>Incorporation by reference_approved by the Director of the Federal Register on December 31, 1980, and reapproved as of January 1, 1982.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Availability of matters incorporated by reference in the amendment as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>For Examination</textblock>
    <textblock>1. FAA Rules Docket, FAA Headquarters Building, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591;</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The FAA Regional Office of the region in which the affected airport is located; or</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The Flight Inspection Field Office which originated the SIAP.</textblock>
    <textblock>For Purchase</textblock>
    <textblock>Individual SIAP copies may be obtained from:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. FAA Public Inquiry Center (APA-200), FAA Headquarters Building, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591; or</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The FAA Regional Office of the region in which the affected airport is located.</textblock>
    <textblock>By Subscription</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of all SIAPs, mailed once every 2 weeks, are for sale by the Superintendent of Documents, U.S. Government Printing Office, Washington, DC 20402.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Paul J. Best, Flight Procedures Standards Branch (AFS-420), Technical Programs Division, Flight Standards Service, Federal Aviation Administration, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591; telephone (202) 267-8277.</textblock>
  </further>
</doc>
