<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00094</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00044</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. CO-050-4210-04; COC54886]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Realty Action; Colorado</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of realty action COC-54886, recreation and public purpose classification and application for lease and patent, for a Gliderport, Park County, Colorado.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The following public lands are classified as suitable for lease under the Recreation and Public Purposes Act (R&amp;PP) of July 14, 1926, as amended, 43 U.S.C. 869 et. seq., and the regulations thereunder 43 CFR 2740 and 2912. The public lands involved are segregated from the public land laws including the general mining laws, except for the R&amp;PP Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sixth Principal Meridian, Colorado</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 9 S., R. 76 W., sec. 3, S1/2,</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 4, S1/2NE1/4, NE1/4SE1/4;</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 10, N1/2N1/2.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested parties may submit comments on this action on or before March 15, 1994. Objections will be reviewed and this realty action may be sustained, vacated, or modified. Unless vacated or modified, this realty action will become final.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>District Manager, Bureau of Land Management, PO Box 2200, Canon City, CO 81215-2200.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>David Hallock, Realty Specialist BLM, Royal Gorge Resource Area, PO Box 2200, Canon City, CO 81215-2200; Phone: (719) 275-0631.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the classification and application for an R&amp;PP lease is to allow recreational development investment on public land by the Denver &amp; South Park Soaring, Inc. for use as a gliderport. If issued, the lease will be issued subject to valid existing rights. A grazing lease may need to be cancelled in part.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 20, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donnie R. Sparks,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>District Manager, Canon City.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2635 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-JB-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
