<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-0-00030</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-0-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(21) DOE Directives (i.e., Orders and Notices) numbered in the series</textblock>
    <textblock>between 1540 and 1541 (Materiels), between 5000.2 and 5000.4 (Unusual</textblock>
    <textblock>Occurrence Reporting), in the series between 5400 and 5500 (Environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>Quality and Impact), and between 5820.1 and 5820.3 (Radioactive Waste</textblock>
    <textblock>Management), and involving requirements for contractors; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(22) Other, Federal and non-Federal, environmental protection laws,</textblock>
    <textblock>codes, ordinances, Executive Orders, regulations, and requirements in DOE</textblock>
    <textblock>Directives, as identified in writing by the contracting officer. Errors in or</textblock>
    <textblock>omissions from the list of laws above, or failure to identify a requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>having the force and effect of law, shall not be construed as waiving a</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement for the contractor to comply with such law or requirement nor</textblock>
    <textblock>shall they form the basis for a defense by the contractor in an</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative, civil, or criminal proceeding, including providing a basis for</textblock>
    <textblock>a claim for the allowability of a fine, penalty, or other cost associated with</textblock>
    <textblock>failure to comply with such law or requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The contractor shall assist the Department of Energy in complying, as</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable, with the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, as amended (42 U.S.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>4321</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.);</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The Endangered Species Act of 1973, as amended (16 U.S.C. 1531</textblock>
    <textblock>et</textblock>
    <textblock>seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.);</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act, as amended (16 U.S.C. 661</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.);</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The Noise Control Act of 1972, as amended (42 U.S.C. 4901</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.);</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) The National Historic Preservation Act of 1966, as amended (16 U.S.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>470</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.);</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) The Wild and Scenic Rivers Act, as amended (16 U.S.C. 1273</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.);</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Farmland Protection Policy Act of 1981 (7 U.S.C. 4201</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.);</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) Executive Order 11988 of May 24, 1977, Floodplain Management;</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) Executive Order 11990, of May 24, 1977, Protection of Wetlands;</textblock>
    <textblock>(10) Executive Order 12088 of October 13, 1978, Federal Compliance with</textblock>
    <textblock>Pollution Control Standards;</textblock>
    <textblock>(11) Executive Order 12580 of January 23, 1987, Superfund Implementation;</textblock>
    <textblock>(12) Executive Order 12843 of April 23, 1993, Procurement Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>and Policies for Ozone-Depleting Substances;</textblock>
    <textblock>(13) Executive Order 12845 of April 23, 1993, Requiring Agencies to Purchase Energy Efficient Computer Equipment;</textblock>
    <textblock>(14) Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Circular No. A-106 of December</textblock>
    <textblock>31, 1974, Reporting Requirements in Connection with the Prevention, Control,</textblock>
    <textblock>and Abatement of Environmental Pollution of Existing Federal Facilities; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(15) Other, Federal and non-Federal, environmental protection laws,</textblock>
    <textblock>codes, ordinances, regulations, and DOE Directives, as identified in writing</textblock>
    <textblock>by the contracting officer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The contractor shall, with regard to the environmental protection</textblock>
    <textblock>laws, codes, ordinances, Executive Orders, regulations and directives included</textblock>
    <textblock>in or covered by paragraphs (a) and (b) of this clause, set forth appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>environmental protection requirements in subcontracts with respect to work to</textblock>
    <textblock>be performed on-site at a DOE-owned or -leased facility.</textblock>
    <textblock>(End of Clause)</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2738 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
