<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00096</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00046</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The proposal for changes to Form MMS-4030, Payor Information Form_Solid Minerals, has been submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for approval under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. chapter 35). Copies of the revised form and explanatory material may be obtained by contacting Jeane Kalas at (303) 231-3046. Comments and suggestions on the revisions should be made directly to the Bureau Clearance Officer at the telephone number listed below, and to the OMB Paperwork Reduction Project, Washington, DC 20503, telephone (202) 395-7340.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Supporting Statement for Revised Solid Minerals Payor Information Form.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abstract:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Minerals Management Service (MMS) Royalty Management Program has revised Form MMS-4030, the Solid Minerals Payor Information Form by removing obsolete fields and adding pertinent fields to make it easier for customers and MMS to establish and update the payor data base. ``Dear Payor'' letters were sent to all solid mineral payors in October 1993 describing the revised form and asking for comments. This supporting statement requests OMB approval for the use of the revised form.</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau Form Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>MMS-4030.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency:</textblock>
    <textblock>To establish a data base and subsequently to change the data base.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Solid mineral companies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Completion Time:</textblock>
    <textblock>20 minutes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Responses:</textblock>
    <textblock>150.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Burden Hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>145.</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau Clearance Officer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Arthur Quintana (703) 787-1101.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 10, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Minerals Management Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Information Collection Submitted to the Office of Management and Budget for Review Under the Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donald L. Sant,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Associate Director for Royalty Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2634 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-MR-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
