<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-0-00031</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-0-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Monday</textblock>
    <textblock>February 7, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part IV</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Treasury</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Foreign Assets Control</textblock>
    <textblock>31 CFR Part 500</textblock>
    <textblock>Foreign Assets Control Regulations; Prospective Lifting of Vietnam Embargo; Final Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 25␣/␣Monday, February 7, 1994␣/␣Rules and Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Foreign Assets Control</textblock>
    <textblock>31 CFR Part 500</textblock>
    <textblock>Foreign Assets Control Regulations; Prospective Lifting of Vietnam Embargo</textblock>
  </text>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Foreign Assets Control, Treasury.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule; amendment.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the President's announcement at 5:05 p.m. Eastern Standard Time, February 3, 1994, the Treasury Department is lifting prospectively the embargo against Vietnam and authorizing new financial, trade, and other transactions with Vietnam and Vietnamese nationals. This final rule does not unblock assets within U.S. jurisdiction blocked prior to this time, nor does it affect enforcement actions with respect to prior violations of the embargo.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>5:05 p.m. Eastern Standard Time, February 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Steven I. Pinter, Chief of Licensing (tel.: 202/622-2480), or William B. Hoffman, Chief Counsel (tel.: 202/622-2410), Office of Foreign Assets Control, Department of the Treasury, Washington, D.C. 20220.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Electronic Availability</textblock>
    <textblock>This document is available as an electronic file on</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Bulletin Board</textblock>
    <textblock>the day of publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. By modem dial 202/512-1387 or call 202/512-1530 for disks or paper copies. This file is available in Postscript, WordPerfect 5.1 and ASCII.</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On February 3, 1994, President Clinton stated that he was lifting the trade embargo against Vietnam because he had determined that this step offered the best way to resolve the fate of American prisoners of war and missing in action. Accordingly, the Office of Foreign Assets Control (``FAC'') is amending the Foreign Assets Control Regulations, 31 CFR part 500 (the ``FACR''), to add §500.578, authorizing new transactions involving property in which Vietnam or its nationals have an interest. The effect of this amendment is that transactions involving such property coming within the jurisdiction of the United States or into the possession or control of persons subject to the jurisdiction of the United States after 5:05 p.m. E.S.T., February 3, 1994, or in which an interest of Vietnam or a national thereof arises after that time, are authorized by general license. Newly authorized transactions include, but are not limited to, importations from and exportations to Vietnam (not otherwise restricted), new investment, travel-related transactions and brokering transactions. Property blocked as of 5:04 p.m. E.S.T., February 3, 1994, remains blocked. Reports due under general or specific license must still be filed covering activities prior to the effective date of this rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because the FACR involve a foreign affairs function, Executive Order 12866 and the provisions of the Administrative Procedure Act, 5 U.S.C. 553, requiring notice of proposed rulemaking, opportunity for public participation, and delay in effective date, are inapplicable. Because no notice of proposed rulemaking is required for this rule, the Regulatory Flexibility Act, 5 U.S.C. 601-612, does not apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 31 CFR Part 500</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedure, Banks, Banking, Foreign investments in U.S., Foreign trade, Securities, Vietnam.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set forth in the preamble, 31 CFR part 500 is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 500_FOREIGN ASSETS CONTROL REGULATIONS</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 500 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>50 U.S.C. App. 1-44; E.O. 9193, 3 CFR, 1938-1943 Comp., p. 1174; E.O. 9989, 3 CFR, 1943-1948 Comp., p. 748.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart E_Licenses, Authorizations and Statements of Licensing Policy</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 500.578 is added to subpart E to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>␣500.578 Authorization of new transactions concerning certain Vietnamese property.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Transactions involving property in which Vietnam or a national thereof has an interest are authorized where:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The property comes within the jurisdiction of the United States or into the control or possession of a person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States at or after 5:05 p.m. E.S.T., February 3, 1994; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The interest in the property of Vietnam or a Vietnamese national arises at or after 5:05 p.m. E.S.T., February 3, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Unless otherwise authorized by the Office of Foreign Assets Control, all property and interests in property that were blocked pursuant to subpart B of this part as of 5:04 p.m. E.S.T., February 3, 1994, and any income accruing thereon or proceeds arising therefrom, remain blocked and subject to the prohibitions and requirements of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>R. Richard Newcomb,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Foreign Assets Control.</textblock>
    <textblock>Approved: February 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John P. Simpson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Assistant Secretary (Regulatory, Tariff &amp; Trade Enforcement).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2963 Filed 2-4-94; 1:14 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4810-25-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
