<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00207</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00095</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>CAG-44.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-45.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP94-111-000, Mangum Brick Company, Inc. v. Arkansas Energy Resources, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-46.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP89-224-010, RP89-203-007, RP90-139-012 and RP91-69-003, Southern Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-47.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-67-002, Southern Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-48.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RS92-26-011, Koch Gateway Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-49.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP93-69-003, Petal Gas Storage Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-50.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. CP93-141-000, CP93-141-001 and CP93-141-002, Iroquois Gas Transmission System and Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. CP93-141-000 and 001, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-51.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP92-134-009, Southern Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>Hydro Agenda</textblock>
    <textblock>H-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Reserved</textblock>
    <textblock>Electric Agenda</textblock>
    <textblock>E-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. TX93-2-000, City of Bedford, Virginia, City of Danville Virginia, City of Martinsville, Virginia, Town of Richlands, Virginia and Blue Ridge Power Agency. Opinion on initial decision.</textblock>
    <textblock>E-2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. TX93-2-001, City of Bedford, Virginia, City of Danville Virginia, City of Martinsville, Virginia, Town of Richlands, Virginia and Blue Ridge Power Agency. Proposed order and order on further proceedings.</textblock>
    <textblock>Oil and Gas Agenda</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Pipeline Rate Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>PR-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Reserved</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Restructuring Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>RS-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-24-014, 012 and 013, Texas Gas Transmission Corporation. Order on compliance and rehearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>RS-2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RS92-46-008, Pacific Gas Transmission Company. Order on clarification.</textblock>
    <textblock>RS-3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-69-013, RS92-69-014, CP88-651-012,</textblock>
    <textblock>RP93-20-006, RP91-166-025, CP92-79-006 and RP93-5-019, Northwest Pipeline Corporation. Order on compliance and rehearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>RS-4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-60-019, RP88-44-047, RP92-185-009, RP91-188-013, RP92-214-009, RP93-153-002, CP89-896-007, CP89-1540-006, CP90-2214-007, CP92-466-003, CP92-511-003 and CP93-180-004</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP93-19-003, Arizona Public Service Company,</textblock>
    <textblock>et al</textblock>
    <textblock>., v. El Paso Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CI93-8-003. El Paso Gas Marketing Company. Order on compliance and rehearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>RS-5.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-3-005, CP88-820-000, RP94-53-000, RS92-3-006, Arkla Energy Resources Company. Order on compliance and rehearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Pipeline Certificate Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>PC-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. CP93-258-000 and CP93-258-001, Mojave Pipeline Company. Order on jurisdiction over Northward Expansion proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 2, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2799 Filed 2-3-94; 10:51 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
