<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00132</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00067</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Commission further notes that approving the current proposal, including Amendment No. 1, on an accelerated basis will permit the NYSE to compete on an equal basis with the other options exchanges for orders in ADR options. Accordingly, since the Commission finds that the current proposal involves the exact same issues as the above-noted proposals, the Commission believes it is consistent with sections 19(b)(2) and 6(b)(5) of the Act</textblock>
    <textblock>to approve the NYSE's proposal on an accelerated basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Solicitation of Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to submit written data, views and arguments concerning the proposed rule change, including Amendment No. 1 to the proposed rule change. Persons making written submissions should file six copies thereof with the Secretary, Securities and Exchange Commission, 450 Fifth Street, NW., Washington, DC 20549. Copies of the submission, all subsequent amendments, all written statements with respect to the proposed rule change that are filed with the Commission, and all written communications relating to the proposed rule change between the Commission and any person, other than those that may be withheld from the public in accordance with the provisions of 5 U.S.C. 552, will be available for inspection and copying in the Commission's Public Reference Section, 450 Fifth Street, NW., Washington, DC. Copies of such filing will also be available for inspection and copying at the principal office of the above-mentioned self-regulatory organization. All submissions should refer to the file number in the caption above and should be submitted by February 28, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is therefore ordered</textblock>
    <textblock>, Pursuant to section 19(b)(2) of the Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>that the proposed rule change (SR-NYSE-93-43) is approved, effective February 7, 1994. Accordingly, the Exchange may submit listing certificates for ADR options as specified herein on February 7, 1994 pursuant to Rule 12d1-3 under the Act and commence trading in the options according to the time parameters established in the Joint Options Listing Procedures Plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Commission, by the Division of Market Regulation, pursuant to delegated authority.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>23</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(2) and 78f(b)(5) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>23</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>24</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(2) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>24</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>25</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 200.30-3(a)(12) (1993).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>25</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2710 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
