<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-1-00004</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-1-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>8 CFR 214.2(s)(7) requires that NATO dependents must pay taxes and Social Security on their earnings, and clarifies that they have no criminal, civil, or administrative immunities regarding matters arising from their employment.</textblock>
    <textblock>8 CFR 214.2(s)(8) clarifies that there is no appeal from a denial of employment authorization.</textblock>
    <textblock>8 CFR 214.2(s)(9) discusses unauthorized employment and resultant penalties.</textblock>
    <textblock>8 CFR 214.2(s)(10) discusses NATO-7 dependents. Since this rule parallels the regulations governing ``A'' nonimmigrants which preclude employment by A-3 dependents, and since A-3 and NATO-7 classifications are comparable, this rule eliminates future grants of employment authorization for NATA-7 dependents, but allows those NATA-7 dependents currently with employment authorization to continue until the expiration of such authorization.</textblock>
    <textblock>Finally, this rule amends 8 CFR 274a.12(c)(7) by eliminating future grants of employment authorization for NATA-7 dependents.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with 5 U.S.C. 605(b), the Commissioner of the Immigration and Naturalization Service certifies that this rule will not have a significant adverse economic impact on a substantial number of small entities. This rule is not a major rule within the meaning of section 1(b) of E.O. 12291, nor does this rule have Federalism implications warranting the preparation of a Federalism Assessment in accordance with E.O. 12612.</textblock>
    <textblock>The information collection requirement contained in this regulation has been submitted to the Office of Budget and Management (OMB) under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act, for review and clearance.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects</textblock>
    <textblock>8 CFR Part 214</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedures, Aliens, Authority delegation (government agencies), Employment.</textblock>
    <textblock>8 CFR Part 274a</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedures, Aliens, Employment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, chapter I of title 8 of the Code of Federal Regulations is proposed to be amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 214_NONIMMIGRANT CLASSES</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 214 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>8 U.S.C. 1101, 1103, 1182, 1184, 1186a, 1221, 1281, 1282; 8 CFR part 2.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. In ยง214.2, paragraph (s) is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง214.2</textblock>
    <textblock>Special requirements for admission, extension, and maintenance of status.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(s)</textblock>
    <textblock>NATO nonimmigrant aliens</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>General.</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Background.</textblock>
    <textblock>Nonimmigrant aliens classified as NATO-1 through NATO-5 are officials of NATO, the members of the armed forces of a country signatory to the Agreement Between the Parties to the North Atlantic Treaty Regarding the Status of Their Forces signed in London, June 1951 (NATO Status of Forces Agreement), who are entering in accordance with that agreement or the Protocol on the Status of International Military Headquarters set up pursuant to the North Atlantic Treaty (Paris Protocol), and members of their immediate families. Aliens classified as NATO-6 are civilian employees either of a force entering in accordance with the NATO Status of Forces Agreement or of an allied headquarters (Supreme Allied Commander, Atlantic, SACLANT) set up pursuant to the Paris Protocol and members of their immediate families. Servants or attendants of aliens classified as NATO-1 through NATO-6 are classified as NATO-7, as are members of the immediate families of such servants or attendants.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
