<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00095</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00045</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[NM-920-4210-06; NMNM 021067]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Proposed Continuation of Withdrawal; New Mexico</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The United States Forest Service proposes that a 155.70-acre withdrawal for the Fort Bayard Administrative Site continue for an additional 20 years. The lands will remain closed to mining, but will be opened to surface entry, mineral leasing, and to such forms of disposition as may by law be made of the National Forest System lands.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be received by March 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be sent to: BLM, New Mexico State Director, P.O. Box 27115, Santa Fe, NM 87502.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Georgiana E. Armijo, BLM, New Mexico State Office, 505-438-7594.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The United States Forest Service proposes that the withdrawal of lands made by Public Land Order No. 1290, be continued for a period of 20 years pursuant to Section 204 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, 43 U.S.C. 1714(f) (1988). The lands are described as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>New Mexico Principal Meridian</textblock>
    <textblock>Gila National Forest</textblock>
    <textblock>Fort Bayard Administrative Site</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 17 S., R. 13 W.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Tract A</textblock>
    <textblock>From the quarter corner common to sections 35 and 36, T. 17 S., R. 13 W., the line runs N. 89</textblock>
    <textblock>○53</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W. 1,530 feet to point of beginning, thence N. 89</textblock>
    <textblock>○53</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W. 1,150 feet; N. 00</textblock>
    <textblock>○28</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W. 1,855 feet; S. 52</textblock>
    <textblock>○38</textblock>
    <textblock>’ E. 215 feet; S. 30</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>’ 1. 2,000 feet, to point of beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>Tract B</textblock>
    <textblock>From the quarter corner common to sections 25 and 36, T. 17 S., R. 13 W., the line runs S. 02</textblock>
    <textblock>○04</textblock>
    <textblock>’ E. 2,675 feet, thence N. 89</textblock>
    <textblock>○53</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W. 1,590 feet; N. 00</textblock>
    <textblock>○43</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W. 615 feet; West 400 feet; N. 22</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>’ E. 1,450 feet; N. 47</textblock>
    <textblock>○03</textblock>
    <textblock>’ E. 1,590 feet; N. 18</textblock>
    <textblock>○18</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W. 2,380 feet; East 990 feet; S. 01</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>’ E. 2,660 feet, to point of beginning.</textblock>
    <textblock>The areas described aggregate 155.70 acres in Grant County.</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the withdrawal is to protect the Fort Bayard Administrative Site. The withdrawal currently segregates the lands from surface entry, mining, and mineral leasing. The lands will be opened to surface entry, mineral leasing, and to such forms of disposition as may by law be made of the National Forest System lands.</textblock>
    <textblock>For a period of 90 days from the date of publication of this notice, all persons who wish to submit comments in connection with the proposed withdrawal continuation may present their views in writing to the New Mexico State Director at the address indicated above.</textblock>
    <textblock>The authorized officer of the Bureau of Land Management will undertake such investigations as are necessary to determine the existing and potential demand for the lands and their resources. A report will be prepared for consideration by the Secretary of the Interior, the President, and the Congress, who will determine whether or not the withdrawal will be continued and if so, for how long. The final determination on the continuation of the withdrawal will be published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. The existing withdrawal will continue until such final determination is made.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 27, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Carol L. Sampson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting State Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2632 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-FB-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
