<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00060</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00028</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Basis for Rate Development_P-DP</textblock>
    <textblock>Firm Power Rate</textblock>
    <textblock>The provisional firm power P-DP rate was designed to reflect the power/transmission split as derived in the Apportionment of Cost Study and continues to maintain a 50/50 split between revenue from energy and capacity rates based on a 60-percent load factor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Step one of the provisional P-DP rates consists of a 5.79 mills/kWh energy rate and $2.54/kW/month capacity rate effective February 1, 1994. The necessary composite rate is 11.58 mills/kWh, which is an increase of 28 percent over the existing composite rate of 9.03 mills/kWh.</textblock>
    <textblock>Step two of the provisional P-DP rates consists of a 6.01 mills/kWh energy rate and $2.63/kW/month capacity rate effective October 1, 1995. The necessary composite rate is 12.01 mills/kWh, which is an increase of 33 percent over the existing composite rate of 9.03 mills/kWh.</textblock>
    <textblock>Transmission Service Rates</textblock>
    <textblock>The provisional firm transmission service P-DP rate was designed to reflect the power/transmission split as derived in the Apportionment of Cost Study. Step one of the provisional P-DP rates for firm transmission service is $10.40/kW/year ($.87/kW/month) and nonfirm transmission service is 1.98 mills/kWh. The step-one rate for firm transmission service for SLCA/IP is $5.20/kW/season ($.87/kW/month). A season for the firm transmission service rate for SLCA/IP is 6 months.</textblock>
    <textblock>Step two of the provisional P-DP rates for firm transmission service is $12.55/kW/year ($1.05/kW/month) and nonfirm transmission service is 2.39 mills/kWh. The step two rate for firm transmission service for SLCA/IP is $6.27/kW/season ($1.05/kW/month).</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>During the 143-day comment period, Western received 31 written comments. In addition, nine speakers commented during the September 11, 1992, public comment forum. During the reopening of the comment forum of an additional 70 days, Western received 19 written comments. In addition, seven speakers commented during the July 14, 1993, public comment forum. All comments were reviewed and considered in the preparation of this rate order.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments were received from the following sources:</textblock>
    <textblock>Aguila Irrigation District (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Ak-Chin Indian Community (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Arizona Municipal Power Users' Association (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Arizona Power Pooling Association (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Arizona Public Service Company (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Buckeye Water Conservation &amp; Drainage District (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Basic Management, Inc. (Nevada)</textblock>
    <textblock>Central Arizona Water Conservation District (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Chemstar Lime Company (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Colorado River Commission of Nevada (Nevada)</textblock>
    <textblock>Electrical District Number Two, Pinal County (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Electrical District Number Five, Pinal County (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Electrical District Number Seven (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Harquahala Irrigation District (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Irrigation and Electrical Districts Association of Arizona (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Maricopa Water District (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>McMullen Valley Water Conservation and Drainage District (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Metropolitan Water District of Southern California (California)</textblock>
    <textblock>Meyer, Hendricks, Victor, Osborn &amp; Maledon (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Nevada Power Company (Nevada) 25 Overton Power District No. 5 (Nevada)</textblock>
    <textblock>Pioneer Chlor-Alkali (Nevada)</textblock>
    <textblock>Roosevelt Irrigation District (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Roosevelt Water Conservation District (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Safford, City of, Arizona, (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Salt River Project (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>San Carlos Irrigation and Drainage District (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Southern California Edison (California)</textblock>
    <textblock>Titanium Metal Corporations (Nevada)</textblock>
    <textblock>Tonopah Irrigation District (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Valley Electric Association, Inc. (Nevada)</textblock>
    <textblock>Representatives of the following organizations made oral comments:</textblock>
    <textblock>Arizona Power Authority_Leroy Michael, Jr. &amp; David Helsby (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Basic Management, Inc._Richard F. Brown. (Nevada)</textblock>
    <textblock>Colorado River Commission of Nevada_Thomas Cahill, Don Allen, and</textblock>
    <textblock>David Luttrell (Nevada)</textblock>
    <textblock>Five Hoover Customer Entities_Jay I. Moyes (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Irrigation &amp; Electrical Districts Association of Arizona_Robert S. Lynch (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Overton Power District No. 5 and Valley Electric</textblock>
    <textblock>Association_Jim McManus (Nevada)</textblock>
    <textblock>Pioneer Chlor-Alkali Company_Terry Graves (Nevada)</textblock>
    <textblock>Salt River Project_Leslie James &amp; Jim Transgrud (Arizona)</textblock>
    <textblock>Most of the comments received at the public meetings and in correspondence dealt with costs of annual expenses, replacements and additions, the proposed alternative transmission service rates, consideration of stepped rates, and the Apportionment of Cost Study. All comments were considered in developing the provisional P-DP rates.</textblock>
    <textblock>The comments and responses, paraphrased for brevity, are discussed below. Direct quotes from comment letters are used for clarification where necessary.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
