<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00206</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00095</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>CAG-28.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. GP93-8-000, North Dakota Industrial Commission, Tight Formation Determination, North Dakota-3, Red River Formation, FERC No. JD93-05716T</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-29.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-10-007, CP71-273-006, RP92-134-008 and RP93-15-005, Southern Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-30.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-5-014, RP90-108-024, RP91-82-015, RP91-161-020, RP92-3-011, RP93-66-004 and RP93-115-004, Columbia Gas Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-6-013, RP90-107-021, RP91-160-017, RP92-2-011 and CP93-736-003, Columbia Gulf Transmission Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-31.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-16-006, CP91-2448-006, MG88-3-007, RP91-138-003 and RP91-187-012, Florida Gas Transmission Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-32.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-43-011 and RP93-4-014, Mississippi River Transmission Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-33.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RS92-64-010, High Island Offshore System</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RS92-88-012, U-T Offshore System</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-34.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RS92-23-021, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RS92-33-008, East Tennessee Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-35.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-25-008 and CP93-504-004, Trunkline Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-36.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RS92-45-013, Natural Gas Pipeline Company of America</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-37.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RS92-63-010, Great Lakes Gas Transmission Limited Partnership</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-38.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-86-016, RP92-108-012 and RP92-137-022, Transcontinental Gas Pipe Line Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-39.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RS92-8-007, Northern Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-40.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP87-75-009, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-41. Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-42.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. TC92-6-001 and TC92-6-002, South Georgia Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-43.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP93-425-000, CNG Transmission Corporation</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
