<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00110</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00059</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(Order Suspending Byproduct Material License No. 37-28540-01); Hearing (Staff Order Suspending License Effective Immediately)</textblock>
    <textblock>February 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Before Administrative Judges: G. Paul Bollwerk, III, Chairman, Dr. Charles N. Kelber, Dr. Peter S. Lam.</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 20, 1993, the NRC staff issued an immediately effective order suspending Byproduct Materials License No. 37-28540-01. (58 FR 6825). That license authorizes Oncology Services Corporation (OSC) to use sealed-source iridium-192 for high dose rate (HDR) human brachytherapy treatments in six OSC facilities in Pennsylvania. As justification for the order, the staff cited a number of circumstances that it asserted demonstrated ``a significant corporate management breakdown in the control of licensed activities'' (58 FR at 6826), including a November 1992 incident at OSC's Indiana (Pennsylvania) Regional Cancer Center in which a patient given an HDR brachytherapy treatment was returned to her nursing home with a iridium-192 source mistakenly still inside her body.</textblock>
    <textblock>The January 1993 order provided that on or before February 20, 1993, licensee OSC or any other person adversely affected by the order could submit an answer to the order, which could include a request for a hearing. On February 2, 1993, OSC filed a request for a hearing regarding the order. The Commission referred this submission to the Atomic Safety and Licensing Board Panel on February 5, 1993, for the appointment of a presiding officer to conduct any necessary proceedings. On February 10, 1993, the Chief Administrative Judge of the Panel appointed this Atomic Safety and Licensing Board pursuant to the Commission's referral. (58 FR 9224). The Board consists of Dr. Charles N. Kelber, Dr. Peter S. Lam, and G. Paul Bollwerk, III, who will serve as Chairman of the Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>On February 23, 1993, the staff filed the first of a series of motions asking for a delay of the proceeding so as not to interfere with various ongoing investigations relating to some of the circumstances forming the basis for the suspension order. Acting on these requests, the Board delayed the beginning of discovery by the parties through early December 1993. See LBP-93-6, 37 NRC 207,</textblock>
    <textblock>vacated in part as moot,</textblock>
    <textblock>CLI-93-17, 38 NRC 44 (1993); LBP-93-10, 37 NRC 455,</textblock>
    <textblock>aff'd,</textblock>
    <textblock>CLI-93-17, 38 NRC 44, (1993); LBP-93-20, 38 NRC 130 (1993). By letter dated November 16, 1993, the staff informed the Board that it would not request any further delays in the proceeding as a result of the investigations. As a consequence, on January 26, 1994, the Board conducted a prehearing conference. Thereafter, on February 1, 1994, the Board issued an unpublished prehearing conference order in which it ruled on various discovery and scheduling matters.</textblock>
    <textblock>Please take notice that a hearing will be conducted in this proceeding. The parties to the hearing are the NRC staff and OSC. The hearing will be governed by the hearing procedures set forth in 10 CFR part 2, subpart G (10 CFR 2.700-.790).</textblock>
    <textblock>During the course of the proceeding, the Board may conduct an oral argument, as provided in 10 CFR 2.755, and may hold additional prehearing conferences pursuant to 10 CFR 2.752. The public is invited to attend any oral argument or prehearing conference, as well as any evidentiary hearing, which may be held pursuant to 10 CFR 2.750-.751. The Board will establish the schedules for any such sessions at a later date, through notices to be published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>and/or made available to the public at NRC Public Document Rooms.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with 10 CFR 2.715(a), any person, not a party to the proceeding, may submit a written limited appearance statement setting forth his or her position on the issues in this proceeding. These statements do not constitute evidence but may assist the Board and/or parties in the definition of the issues being considered. Written limited appearance statements should be sent to the Office of the Secretary, U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555, Attention: Docketing and Service Branch. A copy of the statement also should be served on the Chairman of the Atomic Safety and Licensing Board. The Board will make a determination at a later date whether oral limited appearance statements will be entertained.</textblock>
    <textblock>Documents relating to this proceeding are available for public inspection at the Commission's Public Document Room, the Gelman Building, 2120 L Street, NW., Washington, DC 20555.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: Bethesda, Maryland, February 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Atomic Safety and Licensing Board.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 030-31765-EA, EA 93-006, ASLBP No. 93-674-03-EA]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Atomic Safety and Licensing Board; Oncology Services Corporation</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>G. Paul Bollwerk, III,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, Administrative Judge.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2664 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7590-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
