<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00115</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00063</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Level III:</textblock>
    <textblock>On a per contracting action basis, Level III Legal Officers have authority to:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Execute contracts with total estimated fees up to $250,000;</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Execute task orders with total fees up to $500,000 under pre-established task order agreements;</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Execute administrative changes to contracts, task order agreements, task orders, and contract modifications including changes in delivery, cost, and schedule, where the fees for the change or modification result in the modified contract not exceeding $250,000;</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Execute contract terminations with total fees up to $250,000; and</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Execute contract claim settlements with total fees up to $100,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>Level IV Legal Officers in the Washington, DC office have authority, on a per contracting action basis, to:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Execute contracts with total estimated fees (including options) up to $2,000,000;</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Execute individual task orders with total estimated fees up to $2,000,000;</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Execute administrative changes to contracts, task order agreements, and task orders and contract modifications including changes in delivery, cost or schedule, where the fees for the change or modifications result in the modified contract not exceeding $2,000,000;</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Execute contract terminations with total fees up to $1,000,000; and</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Execute contract claim settlements with fees up to $200,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>Level IV Legal Officers in field offices have authority, on a per contracting action basis, to:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Execute contracts with total estimated fees (including options) up to $1,000,000;</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Execute individual task orders with total estimated fees up to $1,000,000;</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Execute administrative changes to contracts, task order agreements, task orders, and contract modifications including changes in delivery, cost, and schedule, where the fees for the change or modification result in the modified contract not exceeding $1,000,000;</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Execute contract terminations with total fees up to $500,000; and</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Execute contract claim settlements with total fees up to $100,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Level V Legal Officer (the General Counsel of the RTC), on a per contracting action basis, has unlimited authority to:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Execute contracts, including task order agreements;</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Execute task orders;</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Execute administrative changes to contracts, task order agreements, task orders, and contract modifications thereof;</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Execute contract terminations; and</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Execute contract claim settlements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Legal Officers are given a certificate of appointment, showing the level of the warrant. The certificate shall be signed by RTC's General Counsel. This certificate, or a copy, must be presented prior to executing a contract or taking one of the other actions listed above.</textblock>
    <textblock>The public should be aware that this notice, and the referenced Statement, apply only to RTC contracts for the provision of legal services. The RTC on January 21, 1994 (59 FR 3382) issued a notice, summarizing the parameters of the correlative Warranted Contracting Officer program for contracts for non-legal services, and is making publicly available a corresponding statement of the parameters of that program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Resolution Trust Corporation.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John M. Buckley, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2647 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6714-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
