<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00098</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00048</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App. 2) and implementing regulation 41 CFR 101-6, announcement is made of the following committee meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>Name of Committee:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Industrial Security Program Policy Advisory Committee (NISPPAC).</textblock>
    <textblock>Date of Meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 24, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Time of Meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>10 a.m. to 12 p.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Archives at College Park, 8601 Adelphi Road, College Park, Maryland 20740-6001.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose:</textblock>
    <textblock>To discuss National Industrial Security Program (NISP) policy matters. The agenda will include a discussion on the status of the NISP Operating Manual, discussion and voting on the NISPPAC Bylaws, and a discussion on the status of the draft replacement of Executive Order 12356 and the report of the Joint DoD/DCI Security Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>This meeting will be open to the public. However, due to space limitations and access procedures, the names and telephone numbers of individuals planning to attend must be submitted to the Information Security Oversight Office (ISOO) no later than February 21, 1994. Written statements from the public will be accepted in lieu of an opportunity for comment.</textblock>
    <textblock>For Further Information Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Steven Garfinkel, Director, ISOO, 750 17th Street NW., suite 530, Washington, DC 20006, telephone (202) 634-6150.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>INFORMATION SECURITY OVERSIGHT OFFICE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Industrial Security Program Policy Advisory Committee; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Steven Garfinkel,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Information Security Oversight Office.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2629 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6820-AF-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
