<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00045</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00028</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Western Area Power Administration</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Parker-Davis Project Notice of Rate Order No. WAPA-55</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Western Area Power Administration, DOE.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Rate Order_Parker-Davis Project (P-DP) Firm Power Rate and Firm and Nonfirm Transmission Service Rate Adjustments.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is given of the confirmation and approval by the Deputy Secretary of the Department of Energy (DOE) of Rate Order No. WAPA-55 placing the proposed rate schedules_firm power PD-F4, firm transmission service PD-FT4, nonfirm transmission service PD-NFT4, and firm transmission service for Salt Lake City Area/Integrated Projects (SLCA/IP) PD-FCT4_for the P-DP of the Western Area Power Administration (Western) into effect on an interim basis. These proposed P-DP rates, hereafter called the provisional P-DP rates, will remain in effect on an interim basis until the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) confirms, approves, and places them into effect on a final basis for a 5-year period or until superseded.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Deputy Secretary, DOE, approved the existing P-DP rate schedules PD-F3, PD-FCT3, and PF-NFT3 by Rate Order No. WAPA-48 on an interim basis, effective on October 1, 1990 (55 FR 36887, September 7, 1990). FERC approved the P-DP rate schedules on a final basis through September 30, 1992, by Order dated November 15, 1990 (53 FERC Par. 62,157).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Assistant Secretary for Conservation and Renewable Energy on August 19, 1992 by Rate Order No. WAPA-57, extended these rate schedules for not more than one year (57 FR 39400, August 31, 1992). The Acting Assistant Secretary for Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy on September 29, 1993, by Rate Order No. WAPA-64, further extended these rate schedules through March 31, 1994 (58 FR 50917; September 29, 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>Neither of said WAPA Rate Orders, 57 or 64 were submitted to FERC for its concurrence, inasmuch as these orders were in the nature of temporary extensions of existing rates, pending the development of long term rates, so that FERC approval would have been premature. In any event, rates of such nature need not be approved by FERC, as specified in existing regulations, 10 CFR 902.23(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>Western is proposing to implement a two-step process for the provisional P-DP rates for firm power and firm and nonfirm transmission service. Step one of the provisional P-DP rates will become effective February 1, 1994, and step two of the provisional P-DP rates will become effective October 1, 1995.</textblock>
    <textblock>Step one of the provisional P-DP rates consists of an energy rate of 5.79 mills per kilowatthour (mills/kWh) and a capacity rate of $2.54 per kilowatt/month (kW/month) for a composite rate of 11.58 mills/kWh. Step one of the provisional P-DP rates for transmission service consists of a firm transmission service rate of $10.40 per kilowatt/year (kW/year), a nonfirm transmission service rate of 1.98 mills/kWh, and a firm transmission service rate for SLCA/IP of $5.20/kW/season. A season for the firm transmission service rate for SLCA/IP is 6 months.</textblock>
    <textblock>Step two of the provisional P-DP rates consists of an energy rate of 6.01 mills/kWh and a capacity rate of $2.63/kW/month for a composite rate of 12.01 mills/kWh. Step two of the provisional P-DP rates for transmission service consists of a firm transmission service rate of $12.55/kW/year, a nonfirm transmission service rate of 2.39 mills/kWh, and a firm transmission service rate for SLCA/IP of $6.27/kW/season.</textblock>
    <textblock>A comparison of existing P-DP rates and the two-step provisional P-DP rates follows:</textblock>
  </summary>
  <table>
    <textblock>Comparison of Existing P-DP Rates and Step One Provisional P-DP Rates</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Existing rates FY 1990</textblock>
    <textblock>1Provisional rates effective 2/1/1994*</textblock>
    <textblock>1Percent change (%)</textblock>
    <textblock>Power Rate Schedule</textblock>
    <textblock>PD-F3</textblock>
    <textblock>PD-F4</textblock>
    <textblock>Composite (mills/kWh)</textblock>
    <textblock>9.03</textblock>
    <textblock>11.58</textblock>
    <textblock>28</textblock>
    <textblock>Energy (mills/kWh)</textblock>
    <textblock>4.52</textblock>
    <textblock>5.79</textblock>
    <textblock>28</textblock>
    <textblock>Capacity ($/kW/month)</textblock>
    <textblock>1.98</textblock>
    <textblock>2.54</textblock>
    <textblock>28</textblock>
    <textblock>Firm Transmission Service Rate Schedule</textblock>
    <textblock>PD-FT3</textblock>
    <textblock>PD-FT4</textblock>
    <textblock>Firm Transmission Service ($/kW/year)</textblock>
    <textblock>8.20</textblock>
    <textblock>10.40</textblock>
    <textblock>27</textblock>
    <textblock>Nonfirm Transmission Service Rate Schedule</textblock>
    <textblock>PD-NFT3</textblock>
    <textblock>PD-NFT4</textblock>
    <textblock>Nonfirm Transmission Service (mills/kWh)</textblock>
    <textblock>1.50</textblock>
    <textblock>1.98</textblock>
    <textblock>32</textblock>
    <textblock>Firm Transmission Service for SLCA/IP Rate Schedule</textblock>
    <textblock>PD-FCT3</textblock>
    <textblock>PD-FCT4</textblock>
    <textblock>Firm Transmission Service for SLCA/IP ($/kW/season)</textblock>
    <textblock>4.10</textblock>
    <textblock>5.20</textblock>
    <textblock>27</textblock>
    <textblock>*The first steps of the provisional P-DP rates are in effect from February 1, 1994, through September 30, 1995.</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
