<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00044</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00027</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Southeastern Power Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Cumberland System of Projects</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Southeastern Power Administration (Southeastern), DOE.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Southeastern proposes to replace Rate Schedules CC-1-C, CK-1-B, CM-1-B, CBR-1-B, CEK-1-B, CSI-1-B, and CTV-1-B currently applicable to Cumberland Basin Projects power and seeks approval of new Rate Schedules CC-1-D, CK-1-C, CM-1-C, CBR-1-C, CEK-1-C, CSI-1-C, and CTV-1-C, for a 5-year period July 1, 1994, through June 30, 1999.</textblock>
    <textblock>Opportunities will be available for interested persons to review the present rates, to review the proposed rates and supporting studies, to participate in a public forum and to submit written comments. Southeastern will evaluate all comments received in this process.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments are due on or before May 10, 1994. A public information and comment forum will be held in Nashville, Tennessee, on March 10, 1994. Persons desiring to speak at the forum should notify Southeastern at least 4 days before the forum is scheduled, so that a list of forum participants can be prepared. Others may speak if time permits.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Five copies of written comments should be submitted to: Administrator, Department of Energy, Southeastern Power Administration, Samuel Elbert Building, Elberton, Georgia 30635. The public information and comment forum for the Cumberland Basin Projects will begin at 10 a.m. on March 10, 1994, in room A135 U.S. Courthouse Annex, 801 Broadway, Nashville, Tennessee 37203.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Leon Jourolmon, Director, Power Marketing Division, Department of Energy, Southeastern Power Administration, Samuel Elbert Building, Elberton, Georgia 30635.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) by order issued September 26, 1989, in Docket No. EF89-3021-000 confirmed and approved Wholesale Power Rate Schedules CBR-1-B, CSI-1-B, CM-1-B, CC-1-B, CK-1-B, CTV-1-B, and CC-1-C, applicable to Cumberland Basin Projects' power for the period July 1, 1989, through June 30, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>DISCUSSION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Existing rate schedules for the present Cumberland System are predicated upon a May 1989 repayment study and other supporting data all of which is contained in FERC Docket No. EF89-3021-000. The current repayment study prepared in January of 1994 for the combined Cumberland System shows that existing rates are not adequate to recover all costs required by present repayment criteria.</textblock>
    <textblock>A revised repayment study with a net $2,235,000 revenue increase in each future year over the current repayment study demonstrates that all costs are paid within their repayment life. The net additional requirement amounts to a net 6 percent increase in revenues and is primarily due to increased O&amp;M costs at the generating projects. It is proposed that revised rate schedules applicable to TVA (for the benefit of preference customers served from the TVA System) and Other Preference Customers of Southeastern contain the following unit rates:</textblock>
    <textblock>The referenced January 1994 current repayment study along with a</textblock>
    <textblock>revised repayment study dated January 1994 and previous system</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment studies are available for examination at the Samuel Elbert Building, Elberton, Georgia 30635. Proposed Rate Schedules</textblock>
    <textblock>CC-1-D, CK-1-C, CM-1-C, CBR-1-C, CSI-1-C, CEK-1-C, and CTV-1-C are</textblock>
    <textblock>also available.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Elberton, Georgia, January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <table>
    <textblock>TVA Rate Schedule</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Capacity at the generator/kw/month</textblock>
    <textblock>$1.181</textblock>
    <textblock>Energy at the generator/kwh (mills)</textblock>
    <textblock>6.532</textblock>
    <textblock>Other Customers Rate Schedules (Excluding Carolina Power &amp; Light Area):</textblock>
    <textblock>Capacity delivered at interconnections with adjacent utilities/kw/month</textblock>
    <textblock>$1.791</textblock>
    <textblock>Energy delivered at interconnections with adjacent utilities/kwh (mills)</textblock>
    <textblock>6.665</textblock>
    <textblock>Customers served through the facilities of Carolina Power &amp; Light, Western Division (Rate Schedule CC-1-D)</textblock>
    <textblock>Capacity delivered kw/month</textblock>
    <textblock>$2.039</textblock>
    <textblock>Energy delivered kwh (mills)</textblock>
    <textblock>7.091</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John A. McAllister, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2737 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
