<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-1-00034</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-1-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Summary of Petitions Received; Dispositions of Petitions Issued</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Chapter I</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Summary Notice No. PR-94-3]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of petitions for rulemaking received and of dispositions of prior petitions.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to FAA's rulemaking provisions governing the application, processing, and disposition of petitions for rulemaking (14 CFR part 11), this notice contains a summary of certain petitions requesting the initiation of rulemaking procedures for the amendment of specified provisions of the Federal Aviation Regulations and of denials or withdrawals of certain petition previously received. The purpose of this notice is to improve the public's awareness of, and participation in, this aspect of FAA's regulatory activities. Neither publication of this notice nor the inclusion or omission of information in the summary is intended to affect the legal status of any petition or its final disposition.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on petitions received must identify the petition docket number involved and must be received April 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send comments on any petition in triplicate to:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, Office of the Chief Counsel, Attn: Rules Docket No.</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXXXXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591.</textblock>
    <textblock>The petition, any comments received, and a copy of any final disposition are filed in the assigned regulatory docket and are available for examination in the Rules Docket (AGC-200), room 915G, FAA Headquarters Building (FOB 10A), 800 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20591; telephone (202) 267-3132.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Frederick M. Haynes, Office of Rulemaking (ARM-1), Federal Aviation Administration, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591; telephone (202) 267-3939.</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice is published pursuant to paragraphs (b) and (f) of ยง11.27 of part 11 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (14 CFR part 11).</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC on January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donald P. Byrne,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Chief Counsel for Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Petitions for Rulemaking</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No.:</textblock>
    <textblock>26864.</textblock>
    <textblock>Petitioner:</textblock>
    <textblock>Grant W. Young.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations Affected:</textblock>
    <textblock>14 CFR 121, 125, 127, and 135.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of Rulechange Sought:</textblock>
    <textblock>To require operators and third party maintenance facilities to use standardized forms when performing routine and non-routine maintenance at the C-check level and above.</textblock>
    <textblock>Petitioner's Reason for the Request:</textblock>
    <textblock>The petitioner feels the enormous variation in methods and forms leads to extreme difficulty in comparative analysis; and that by standardizing the forms, the ability to draw meaningful conclusions will be significantly improved, thereby enhancing safety and FAR compliance.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2683 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
