<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00015</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Avoca Natural Gas Storage; Notice of Intent To Prepare an Environmental Assessment for the Proposed Avoca Gas Storage Field Project and Request for Comments on Environmental Issues</textblock>
    <textblock>February 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The staff of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC or the Commission) will prepare an environmental assessment (EA) that will discuss environmental impacts of the construction and operation of facilities proposed in the Avoca Gas Storage Field Project.</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>This EA will be used by the Commission in its decision-making process to determine whether an environmental impact statement is necessary and whether or not to approve the project.</textblock>
    <textblock>Summary of the Proposed Project</textblock>
    <textblock>Avoca Natural Gas Storage (Avoca) wants Commission authorization to construct and operate a new underground natural gas storage field near the town of Avoca in Steuben County, New York. Avoca proposes to solution mine 10 caverns out of a bedded salt formation. The caverns would have 6.72 billion cubic feet (BCF) of storage capacity (5 BCF working gas capacity). Avoca would construct the following facilities to use these caverns for natural gas storage:</textblock>
    <textblock>•10 solution-mined cavern wells;</textblock>
    <textblock>•3 water source wells;</textblock>
    <textblock>•6 brine disposal wells;</textblock>
    <textblock>•5,100 feet of 20-inch-diameter natural gas pipeline;</textblock>
    <textblock>•900 feet of 24-inch-diameter natural gas pipeline;</textblock>
    <textblock>•7,000 feet of 12-inch-diameter water withdrawal pipeline;</textblock>
    <textblock>•15,400 feet of 12-inch-diameter water injection pipeline;</textblock>
    <textblock>•15,400 feet of 12-inch-diameter brine return pipeline;</textblock>
    <textblock>•25,600 feet of 12-inch-diameter brine disposal pipeline;</textblock>
    <textblock>•15,400 feet of 2-inch-diameter diesel injection pipeline;</textblock>
    <textblock>•A new 25,000-horsepower compressor station;</textblock>
    <textblock>•An electric-motor driven pumping station (leach plant);</textblock>
    <textblock>•A 0.23-acre, double-lined, brine settling pond;</textblock>
    <textblock>•Gas dehydration facilities; and</textblock>
    <textblock>•Storage tanks for coolant water, glycol, lube oil, hydrocarbons, methanol, and diesel fuel.</textblock>
    <textblock>Schedule</textblock>
    <textblock>Avoca would develop the proposed project in three stages (referred to below as Phase 1, 2, and 3) over a period of 3 to 4 years.</textblock>
    <textblock>Phase 1 would include the construction of all solution mining, gas handling, water production, and brine disposal facilities. Phase 1 would also include the development and operation of four storage caverns_with approximately 2 BCF of storage capacity. Completion of Phase 1 would take about 18 to 20 months.</textblock>
    <textblock>Phase 2 would include the development of four additional storage caverns (another 2 BCF of storage capacity).</textblock>
    <textblock>Phase 3 would include the development of the final 2 caverns (with 1 BCF of storage capacity). Phases 2 and 3 would each take about 1 year to complete.</textblock>
    <textblock>The general location of these facilities is shown in appendix 1.</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>Land Requirements for Construction</textblock>
    <textblock>Avoca would use 200 acres of land for the Avoca Gas Storage Field Project. Of this total, 60 acres are associated with surface facilities such as the well pads, leach plant, compressor station, and brine ponds. The remaining 140 acres would be disturbed by activities related to gas, water supply, and brine disposal pipelines. Any temporary work areas, storage yards, etc., would be contained within the area designated for gas handling facilities.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. CP94-161-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Avoca Natural Gas Storage's (Avoca) application was filed with the Commission under section 7 of the Natural Gas Act and part 157 of the Commission's regulations.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The appendices referenced in this notice are not being printed in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. Copies are available from the Commission's Public Reference Branch, room 3104, 941 North Capitol Street NE., Washington, DC 20426, or call (202) 208-1371. Copies of the appendices were sent to all those receiving this notice in the mail.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
