<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00014</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940207-2-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Basic Energy Sciences Advisory Committee; Notice of Open Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463, 86 Stat. 770), notice is hereby given of the following meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>Name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Basic Energy Sciences Advisory Committee (BESAC)</textblock>
    <textblock>Date and Time:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 24, 1994_8:30 a.m.-5 p.m., February 25, 1994_8:30 a.m. 5 p.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>Albuquerque Hilton Hotel, 1901 University Boulevard, NE., Albuquerque, New Mexico 87102.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Iran L. Thomas, Department of Energy, Office of Basic Energy Sciences (ER-10), Office of Energy Research, Washington, DC 20585, Telephone: 301-903-3081.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose of the Committee:</textblock>
    <textblock>To provide advice on a continuing basis to the Department of Energy (DOE) on the many complex scientific and technical issues that arise in the planning, management, and implementation of the research program for the Office of Basic Energy Sciences (BES).</textblock>
    <textblock>Tentative Agenda:</textblock>
    <textblock>Briefings and discussions of:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 24, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>•Presentations of Basic Energy Sciences program activities at Ames Laboratory and Pacific Northwest Laboratory.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Review and Discussion of Questions/Answers submitted by</textblock>
    <textblock>Ames Laboratory and Pacific Northwest Laboratory.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Public Comment (10 Minute Rule).</textblock>
    <textblock>February 25, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>•Presentations of Basic Energy Sciences program activities at Los Alamos National Laboratory and Sandia National Laboratories/Albuquerque and Livermore.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Review and Discussion of Questions/Answers submitted by Los Alamos National Laboratory and Sandia National Laboratories/Albuquerque and Livermore.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Public Comment (10 Minute Rule).</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Participation:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting is open to the public. Written statements may be filed with the Committee either before or after the meeting. Members of the public who wish to make oral statements pertaining to agenda items should contact: Iran L. Thomas at the address or telephone number listed above. Requests must be received 5 days prior to the meeting and reasonable provisions will be made to include the presentation on the agenda. The Chairperson of the Committee is empowered to conduct the meeting in a fashion that will facilitate the orderly conduct of business.</textblock>
    <textblock>Transcripts:</textblock>
    <textblock>The transcript of the meeting will be available for public review and copying at the Freedom of Information Public Reading Room, 1E-190, Forrestal Building, 1000 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC, between 9 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through Friday, except Federal holidays.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued at Washington, DC on February 2, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of Energy Research</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Marcia L. Morris,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Advisory Committee, Management Officer.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2739 Filed 2-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
