<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00070</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 960.13 of the proposed rule provides that at the time</textblock>
    <textblock>of initial disbursement of a subsidized advance or a direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy by a Bank for an approved AHP application, the Bank shall</textblock>
    <textblock>verify in writing that the project complies with all applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements contained in proposed §960.9 and all obligations</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the approved AHP application. The Bank shall</textblock>
    <textblock>verify the amount of subsidy being provided in connection with the</textblock>
    <textblock>application and being charged against the AHP fund. The Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall include in its AHP implementation plan its verification</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures for such purposes.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Monitoring Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14 of the proposed rule sets forth the requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>for monitoring AHP-assisted housing projects. Section 960.14 is</textblock>
    <textblock>intended to implement the statutory requirement of section</textblock>
    <textblock>10(j)(9)(C) of the Act, which provides that the Board's</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations shall ensure that advances made under the AHP be used</textblock>
    <textblock>only to assist projects for which adequate long-term monitoring is</textblock>
    <textblock>available. See 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(9)(C).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board's existing AHP regulation provides that each Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>must monitor housing projects funded through its AHP. See 12 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>960.7(b). Section 960.14(a) of the proposed rule carries forward</textblock>
    <textblock>this requirement, and §960.14(e) through (h) of the proposed rule</textblock>
    <textblock>sets forth the specific monitoring requirements for the Banks,</textblock>
    <textblock>which are discussed further below. Section 960.14(b) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule provides that each Bank shall include in its AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation plan an explanation of how it intends to meet the</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring requirements of §960.14 of the proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under §960.14(c) of the proposed rule, a Bank may contract</textblock>
    <textblock>with an applicant, a state housing finance agency, or another</textblock>
    <textblock>entity to perform the tasks required to carry out the Bank's</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring responsibilities; however, the Bank remains ultimately</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible for meeting the monitoring requirements set forth in</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.14 (e) through (h) of the proposed rule. Thus, a Bank may</textblock>
    <textblock>decide in its monitoring plan that applicants will have no</textblock>
    <textblock>long-term monitoring responsibilities. Alternatively, the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>may decide to require applicants to perform long-term monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>as a condition of approval of an AHP award, or the Bank may</textblock>
    <textblock>determine what entity has the responsibility for monitoring on a</textblock>
    <textblock>project-by-project basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Applicant Monitoring of Construction or Rehabilitation</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(d) of the proposed rule adds a new requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>that if a subsidized advance or direct subsidy is used to finance</textblock>
    <textblock>construction or rehabilitation of a project, the Bank shall</textblock>
    <textblock>require the applicant to monitor the construction or</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitation until completion, and to make progress reports to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank. Where an applicant finances construction or</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitation, the applicant usually monitors the progress of the</textblock>
    <textblock>project in connection with approving disbursements of funds to the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower. Therefore, the Board believes that where an applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>uses a subsidized advance or direct subsidy to make loans for</textblock>
    <textblock>construction or rehabilitation of an AHP-assisted project, the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant is in the best position to monitor the progress of such</textblock>
    <textblock>construction or rehabilitation and to make progress reports to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Bank Monitoring Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14 (e) through (h) of the proposed rule sets forth</textblock>
    <textblock>the specific aspects of an AHP project that a Bank is required to</textblock>
    <textblock>monitor. Section 960.14(e) of the proposed rule sets for the</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring responsibilities that are long-term in nature, as</textblock>
    <textblock>required by section 10(j)(9)(C) of the Act. See 12 U.S.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>1430(j)(9)(C). Section 960.14(f) and (h) of the proposed rule</textblock>
    <textblock>sets forth the short-term monitoring responsibilities for</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance with the special needs and economic mobility</textblock>
    <textblock>priorities. Section 960.14(g) sets forth the monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibilities for the District Bank priority or priorities,</textblock>
    <textblock>which may or may not be long-term, depending on the nature of the</textblock>
    <textblock>priority selected by the Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring of long-term requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(e) of the proposed rule sets forth the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for monitoring the long-term requirements for</textblock>
    <textblock>owner-occupied and rental housing projects assisted under the AHP.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Owner-occupied housing units.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(e)(1)(i) of the proposed rule provides that at</textblock>
    <textblock>the time a household enters into a purchase contract for an</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP-assisted housing unit or by the closing on the financing for</textblock>
    <textblock>such unit, or at the time a household that already owns the</textblock>
    <textblock>housing unit receives a commitment of a loan or a grant pursuant</textblock>
    <textblock>to the AHP, the Bank or its designee shall obtain a certification</textblock>
    <textblock>from the sponsor that the household has an income at or below the</textblock>
    <textblock>level committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
