<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00075</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(1) A legally binding agreement or other legally enforceable</textblock>
    <textblock>mechanism that permits it to recover these funds from the sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>or owner; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If the Bank agrees and such an agreement is legally</textblock>
    <textblock>enforceable, a three-party agreement that includes the Bank, the</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor or owner and the applicant that permits the Bank to</textblock>
    <textblock>recover these funds from the sponsor or owner.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.16(a)(4) of the proposed rule provides that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board in its discretion may grant a waiver of any required</textblock>
    <textblock>remedial actions under this paragraph (a) upon written request by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank, applicant, sponsor or owner.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Other Types of Non-Compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>Non-compliance by a party with the AHP requirements, such as</textblock>
    <textblock>due to inadvertent errors by such party or changes in</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances that are outside such party's control, does not</textblock>
    <textblock>warrant imposition of the most severe remedial actions since the</textblock>
    <textblock>party lacked the intent to violate such requirements. In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition, in many such cases, the non-compliance can be rectified</textblock>
    <textblock>within a reasonable period of time.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, ยง960.16(b) of the proposed rule provides that in</textblock>
    <textblock>the event of inadvertent non-compliance by an applicant, sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>or owner, the Bank shall provide such party with a reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>period of time in which to take reasonable efforts, pursuant to a</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance plan approved by the Bank, to remedy the</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance. The Bank in its discretion may exclude such party</textblock>
    <textblock>from participation in the AHP while it is under a compliance plan,</textblock>
    <textblock>or in its discretion may require the applicant to increase the</textblock>
    <textblock>long-term period committed to in its AHP application for the</textblock>
    <textblock>project by the amount of time the project has been in</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.16(b) of the proposed rule further provides that if</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicant, sponsor or owner takes no reasonable efforts to</textblock>
    <textblock>comply with the compliance plan, then such party is in willful</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance with the requirements of this part and is subject</textblock>
    <textblock>to the remedial actions contained in paragraph (a) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section. If the applicant, sponsor or owner takes reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>efforts pursuant to the compliance plan to remedy the</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance under paragraph (b) and such efforts are</textblock>
    <textblock>unsuccessful, the applicant, sponsor or owner would be subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>the remedial actions for fraud or willful non-compliance, but may</textblock>
    <textblock>apply to the Bank for a waiver of any such required remedial</textblock>
    <textblock>actions. The Bank shall report to the Board in writing on any</textblock>
    <textblock>waivers approved pursuant to paragraph (b) within 30 calendar days</textblock>
    <textblock>of such approval.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Sale of AHP-assisted Owner-Occupied Housing Unit to</textblock>
    <textblock>Income-Ineligible Household</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Recapture requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.16(c) of the proposed rule provides generally that</textblock>
    <textblock>in the event that a household sells its AHP-assisted</textblock>
    <textblock>owner-occupied housing unit to a household whose income exceeds</textblock>
    <textblock>the level committed to in the AHP application prior to the end of</textblock>
    <textblock>the required long-term period, then:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) If the Bank provided a direct subsidy to the applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>which was passed on as a grant to the seller, the Bank shall</textblock>
    <textblock>require the seller to repay a</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>share, except for</textblock>
    <textblock>de</textblock>
    <textblock>minimis</textblock>
    <textblock>amounts, of the grant received by such seller. The amount</textblock>
    <textblock>to be repaid shall be reduced for every year the seller owned the</textblock>
    <textblock>unit, to be repaid from any net gain from the sale of the unit</textblock>
    <textblock>after deduction for sales expenses, and to be returned to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank. The proposed rule provides, however, that the Bank in its</textblock>
    <textblock>discretion may waive such requirement if the imposition of such</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement will cause undue hardship on the seller, as defined by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank in its AHP implementation plan; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) If the Bank provided a subsidized advance to the applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>and the applicant provided a below market rate loan to the seller,</textblock>
    <textblock>then the applicant shall either repay to the Bank that portion of</textblock>
    <textblock>the advance used to make the loan to the seller or the Bank shall</textblock>
    <textblock>convert that portion of the advance used to make the loan to the</textblock>
    <textblock>seller to a market rate advance with an interest rate equal to the</textblock>
    <textblock>market rate of interest at the time the advance was made, and any</textblock>
    <textblock>unused AHP subsidy which had been set aside by the Bank to</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidize that portion of the advance used to make the loan to the</textblock>
    <textblock>seller shall be made available by the Bank for additional AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Exception to recapture requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.16(c)(3) of the proposed rule provides that the</textblock>
    <textblock>recapture requirements described above shall not apply provided</textblock>
    <textblock>the sponsor, pursuant to a legally binding agreement with the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank, assists another household with an income at or below the</textblock>
    <textblock>level committed to in the AHP application in the manner originally</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
