<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00100</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(2) The Bank shall set forth in its AHP implementation plan the</textblock>
    <textblock>nature, frequency and duration for monitoring compliance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>District Bank priority or priorities.</textblock>
    <textblock>(h)</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring compliance with the economic mobility priority.</textblock>
    <textblock>If an applicant in its AHP application commits to fund a project</textblock>
    <textblock>that meets the requirements of §960.10(d)(5), the Bank or its</textblock>
    <textblock>designee shall obtain a certification from the sponsor or the</textblock>
    <textblock>owner upon completion and full occupancy of the project, as</textblock>
    <textblock>required under §960.15(c)(4), that the sponsor or the owner has</textblock>
    <textblock>met such requirements as committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.15</textblock>
    <textblock>Reporting requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Reporting by the Banks.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each Bank shall provide accurate</textblock>
    <textblock>and timely reports and documentation to, and in the format</textblock>
    <textblock>requested by, the Board concerning the Bank's AHP, as the Board</textblock>
    <textblock>may from time to time require.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Reporting by applicants.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Each Bank shall require an</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant receiving a subsidized advance or direct subsidy</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to this part to report at least annually to the Bank on</textblock>
    <textblock>the manner in which it has used the funds, with such reports</textblock>
    <textblock>continuing until the funds have been fully disbursed by the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If subsidized advances or direct subsidies are used to</textblock>
    <textblock>finance construction or rehabilitation of a project, the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall require the applicant to report to the Bank at reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>intervals determined by the Bank, and described in the Bank's AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation plan, on the progress of the construction or</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitation until completion.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Reporting by the sponsor or owner.</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Owner-occupied housing units_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Initial certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>Where a subsidized advance or direct subsidy is used to finance</textblock>
    <textblock>the purchase of an owner-occupied housing unit, the Bank shall</textblock>
    <textblock>require the sponsor to certify, at the time a household enters</textblock>
    <textblock>into a purchase contract for such unit or at the closing on the</textblock>
    <textblock>financing for such unit, that the unit has been sold to a</textblock>
    <textblock>household with an income at or below the level committed to in the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP application. Where a subsidized advance or direct subsidy is</textblock>
    <textblock>used to finance the rehabilitation of an owner-occupied housing</textblock>
    <textblock>unit, the Bank shall require the sponsor to certify at the time a</textblock>
    <textblock>loan or grant is committed to fund such rehabilitation that the</textblock>
    <textblock>household that owns and occupies the unit has an income at or</textblock>
    <textblock>below the level committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Reports of subsequent sale.</textblock>
    <textblock>If an owner-occupied housing</textblock>
    <textblock>unit assisted by a grant provided under the AHP is not subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>a deed restriction or other legally enforceable mechanism</textblock>
    <textblock>restricting transfer of ownership to a household with an income at</textblock>
    <textblock>or below the level committed to in the AHP application, the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall require the sponsor to report to the Bank or its designee,</textblock>
    <textblock>at least annually for the required long-term period, the number of</textblock>
    <textblock>any such units that are sold to households whose incomes exceed</textblock>
    <textblock>the level committed to in the AHP application, and to certify to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank that it is continuing to satisfy its commitment, pursuant</textblock>
    <textblock>to its legally binding agreement with the Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rental housing units_certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bank shall</textblock>
    <textblock>require the sponsor or owner to certify, upon initial full</textblock>
    <textblock>occupancy of the units in an AHP-assisted rental housing project</textblock>
    <textblock>but no later than one year after initial disbursement of the</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advance or direct subsidy, and annually thereafter,</textblock>
    <textblock>that the project's units, or portion thereof, are affordable for</textblock>
    <textblock>and occupied by households with incomes at or below the levels</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Special needs_initial certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>If an applicant in</textblock>
    <textblock>its AHP application commits to fund a housing project that will</textblock>
    <textblock>provide housing units for persons with a special need, or will</textblock>
    <textblock>provide a continuing special service to occupants pursuant to</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.10(d)(3), the Bank shall require the sponsor or the owner to</textblock>
    <textblock>certify upon completion and full occupancy of the project that the</textblock>
    <textblock>project's units, or portion thereof, are occupied by persons with</textblock>
    <textblock>such special needs or that a special service is being provided to</textblock>
    <textblock>occupants, as committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>Economic mobility_certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>If an applicant in its</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP application commits to fund a housing project that meets the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for economic mobility under §960.10(d)(5), the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall require the sponsor or the owner to certify upon completion</textblock>
    <textblock>and full occupancy of the project that the sponsor or owner has</textblock>
    <textblock>met such requirements, as committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Other reports.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bank shall require applicants or</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsors to provide such other reports as the Bank deems necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>in order to fulfill its monitoring obligations under §960.14.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart H_Corrective and Remedial Actions for Fraud or Non-Compliance With AHP Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.16</textblock>
    <textblock>Corrective and remedial actions for fraud or</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Fraud or willful non-compliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) In the event of an</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant's, sponsor's or owner's fraud with respect to the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of this part, the Bank shall exclude the applicant,</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor or owner, respectively, on a permanent basis, from future</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the AHP. In the event of an applicant's,</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor's or owner's willful non-compliance with the requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>of this part, the Bank shall suspend the applicant, sponsor or</textblock>
    <textblock>owner, respectively, at least on a temporary basis, from future</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the AHP during the period such willful</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance continues, and may exclude such party permanently</textblock>
    <textblock>from future participation in the AHP.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) In the event of an applicant's fraud or willful</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance with respect to the requirements of this part, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank shall recover from the applicant the full amount of the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy provided to the project.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)(i) In the event of a sponsor's or owner's fraud or willful</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance with respect to the requirements of this part, the</textblock>
    <textblock>full amount of the AHP subsidy shall be recovered from the sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>or owner by the applicant and returned to the Bank or, if</textblock>
    <textblock>previously agreed to by the Bank, shall be recovered by the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>from the sponsor or owner. If efforts to recover the AHP subsidy</textblock>
    <textblock>from the sponsor or owner are unsuccessful, the applicant shall</textblock>
    <textblock>not be liable for such funds.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
