<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00094</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(ii) If the purchaser does not satisfy the requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (a)(3)(i) of this section, and if the Bank provided a</textblock>
    <textblock>direct subsidy to the applicant which was passed on as a grant to</textblock>
    <textblock>the seller, the seller must repay a pro rata portion of the grant</textblock>
    <textblock>as provided in §960.16(d)(1); or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) If the purchaser does not satisfy the requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (a)(3)(i) of this section, and if the Bank provided a</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advance to the applicant which in turn provided a below</textblock>
    <textblock>market rate loan to the seller, then the provisions of</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.16(d)(2) shall apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The Bank's AHP implementation plan shall permit the owner</textblock>
    <textblock>of an AHP-assisted rental housing project to sell such project as</textblock>
    <textblock>provided for in paragraph (a)(3) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart D_Applications for AHP Subsidized Advances or Direct</textblock>
    <textblock>Subsidies</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.6</textblock>
    <textblock>Establishment of AHP funding cycles and available AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidies.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Establishment of AHP funding cycles.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Each Bank shall</textblock>
    <textblock>establish at least two but no more than four AHP funding cycles</textblock>
    <textblock>per year during which applications for subsidized advances or</textblock>
    <textblock>direct subsidies will be accepted. The schedule for such funding</textblock>
    <textblock>cycles, including application due dates, is to be determined by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank in its discretion, but shall allow for sufficient time</textblock>
    <textblock>intervals to ensure an adequate pool of applicants to compete in</textblock>
    <textblock>each funding cycle. The funding cycle schedule, including</textblock>
    <textblock>application due dates, shall be described in detail in the Bank's</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP implementation plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Each Bank shall inform the general public and its members</textblock>
    <textblock>of the number and dates of its AHP funding cycles for the year and</textblock>
    <textblock>the approximate amount of available AHP subsidies for each funding</textblock>
    <textblock>cycle at least 45 calendar days before the due date for AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>applications for the first funding cycle for the year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Available AHP subsidies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each Bank shall allocate</textblock>
    <textblock>comparable amounts of AHP subsidies for each AHP funding cycle</textblock>
    <textblock>during the year.</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.7</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP application approval process.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each Bank shall require applicants for</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advances or direct subsidies to submit to the Bank an</textblock>
    <textblock>application which, at a minimum, contains all of the information</textblock>
    <textblock>described in this paragraph and any other information which the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank determines is necessary in order to take action on such</textblock>
    <textblock>application pursuant to this part, including the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A concise description of the purpose of the request and</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed uses of the funds, and its relationship to the priorities</textblock>
    <textblock>identified in §960.10(d), the targeting criterion identified in</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.10(e), and the other objectives identified in §960.10(f);</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A statement of how the project will satisfy the authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>uses and long-term requirements, including a description of legal</textblock>
    <textblock>mechanisms to be used to ensure compliance by the project with</textblock>
    <textblock>such requirements, contained in §§960.3 and 960.5;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) A statement of how the project will comply with the fair</textblock>
    <textblock>housing law requirement contained in §960.9(b);</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) A statement of how the project will satisfy the feasibility</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement contained in §960.9(d);</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) A statement of how the project's sponsor satisfies the</textblock>
    <textblock>qualification requirement contained in §960.9(e);</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) A statement of whether a subsidized advance or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy has been requested and the amount of such funds requested;</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) A disclosure of whether or not the applicant has a direct</textblock>
    <textblock>or indirect interest in the property or project. If the applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>has an interest in the property and the application is approved,</textblock>
    <textblock>then prior to the transfer of AHP funds to the project, an</textblock>
    <textblock>independent current appraisal of the fair market value of such</textblock>
    <textblock>property must be provided, unless the applicant demonstrates that</textblock>
    <textblock>the property is being sold or otherwise transferred to the sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>at a price substantially below the fair market value;</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) A statement of the project's costs; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) A certification from the applicant's, the sponsor's and the</textblock>
    <textblock>loan fund's or loan consortium's board of directors, or president</textblock>
    <textblock>or senior officer if so delegated by the board of directors, that</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicant, the sponsor and the loan fund or loan consortium</textblock>
    <textblock>will comply with all requirements of this part and all obligations</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Action on applications.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The Bank shall review, score</textblock>
    <textblock>and take action on an AHP application pursuant to the requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>contained in §§960.8, 960.9 and 960.10, and shall notify the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant of such action no later than 60 calendar days after the</textblock>
    <textblock>application due date for the AHP funding cycle.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
