<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00060</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Consistent with §960.4(b) of the Board's existing AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation, §960.6(b) of the proposed rule provides that each</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank shall allocate comparable amounts of AHP subsidies for each</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP funding cycle during the year. See 12 CFR 960.4(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Specific Application and Scoring Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Application Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule does not mandate use of a uniform AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application form by all of the Banks. Rather, the Board believes</textblock>
    <textblock>that, consistent with current practice under the AHP, each Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>should continue to devise its own AHP application form, because</textblock>
    <textblock>each Bank will have its own special information requirements as a</textblock>
    <textblock>result of the specific priorities and scoring criteria adopted by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, as discussed further below, all AHP applications must</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfy certain threshold requirements in order to be considered</textblock>
    <textblock>for scoring under the proposed rule. Thus, certain information</textblock>
    <textblock>from applicants must be received by all Banks in order for the</textblock>
    <textblock>Banks to be able to determine whether the applications satisfy the</textblock>
    <textblock>threshold requirements in the proposed rule and to score the</textblock>
    <textblock>applications under the scoring criteria. Accordingly, §960.7(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>of the proposed rule provides that each Bank shall require</textblock>
    <textblock>applicants for subsidized advances or direct subsidies under the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP to submit to the Bank an application which, at a minimum,</textblock>
    <textblock>contains all of the information described below and any other</textblock>
    <textblock>information which the Bank determines is necessary in order to</textblock>
    <textblock>take action on such application, including the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A concise description of the purpose of the request and</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed uses of the funds, and its relationship to the priorities</textblock>
    <textblock>identified in proposed §960.10(d), the targeting criterion</textblock>
    <textblock>identified in proposed §960.10(e), and the other objectives</textblock>
    <textblock>identified in proposed §960.10(f);</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A statement of how the project will satisfy the authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>uses and long-term requirements, including a description of legal</textblock>
    <textblock>mechanisms to be used to ensure compliance by the project with</textblock>
    <textblock>such requirements, contained in proposed §§960.3 and 960.5;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) A statement of how the project will comply with the fair</textblock>
    <textblock>housing law requirement contained in proposed §960.9(b);</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) A statement of how the project will satisfy the feasibility</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement contained in proposed §960.9(d);</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) A statement of how the project's sponsor satisfies the</textblock>
    <textblock>qualification requirement contained in proposed §960.9(e);</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) A statement of whether a subsidized advance or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy has been requested and the amount of such funds requested;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
