<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00045</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Eligible products (end products but not components) on defense contracts subject to the Trade Agreements Act or NAFTA; and</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>11. Section 225.603 is amended to add new paragraph (1)(ii)(C), and to revise paragraph (1)(iii)(C)(</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>225.603</textblock>
    <textblock>Procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) 252.225-7037, Duty-Free Entry_NAFTA Country End Products and Supplies; or</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>) Such acquisition abroad is authorized by the terms of the contract, the subcontract, or by the contracting officer. In any case, follow the procedures required by the clauses in FAR 52.225-10, Duty-Free Entry, and 252.225-7009, Duty-Free Entry_Qualifying Country End Products and Supples, and 252.225-7037, Duty-Free Entry_NAFTA Country End Products and Supplies, to the extent practicable.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>12. Section 225.605-70 is amended by redesignating paragraph (c) as paragraph (d), and adding new paragraph (c) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>225.605-70</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional solicitation provisions and contract clauses.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Use the clause at 252.225-7037, Duty-Free Entry_NAFTA Country End Products and Supplies, in all solicitations and contracts for supplies and services when the clause at FAR 52.225-10, Duty-Free Entry, is not used and NAFTA applies (see 225.403-70).</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 252_SOLICITATION PROVISIONS AND CONTRACT CLAUSES</textblock>
    <textblock>13. Section 252.225-7001 is amended by revising the clause heading and paragraph (c) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>252.225-7001</textblock>
    <textblock>Buy American Act and Balance of Payments Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>As prescribed in 225.109(d), use the following clause:</textblock>
    <textblock>Buy American Act and Balance of Payments Program (January 1994)</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The Contractor agrees that it will deliver only domestic end products unless, in its offer, it specified delivery of other end products in the Buy American Act and Balance of Payments Certificate or the Buy American Act_Trade Agreements_Balance of Payments Program Certificate. An offer certifying that a qualifying country end product will be supplied requires the Contractor to deliver a qualifying country end product or a domestic end product.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(End of clause)</textblock>
    <textblock>14. Section 252.225-7006 is amended by revising the section heading, the clause title, and paragraph (a); paragraph (b) is revised; paragraph (c)(2)(v) is redesignated as paragraph (vi) and reprinted for the convenience of the reader; and a new paragraph (c)(2)(v) is added, to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>252.225-7006</textblock>
    <textblock>Buy American Act_Trade Agreements_Balance of Payments Program Certificate.</textblock>
    <textblock>As prescribed in 225.408(a)(1), use the following provision:</textblock>
    <textblock>Buy American Act_Trade Agreements_Balance of Payments Program Certificate (Jan. 1994)</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Caribbean Basin country end product, designated country end product, domestic end product, NAFTA country end product, nondesignated country end product, qualifying country end product,</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. made end product</textblock>
    <textblock>have the meanings given in the Trade Agreements or Buy American Act and Balance of Payments Program clauses of this solicitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Evaluation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Offers will be evaluated by giving preference to U.S. made end products, qualifying country end products, designated country end products, NAFTA country end products, and Caribbean Basin country end products over other end products.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Certifications. *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) The Offeror certifies that the following supplies qualify as NAFTA country end products: (insert line item number) (insert country of origin).</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) The Offeror certifies that the following supplies are other nondesignated country end products. (insert line item number) (insert country of origin).</textblock>
    <textblock>(End of provision)</textblock>
    <textblock>15. Section 252.225-7007 is amended by revising the section heading and clause title; to revise the introductory language; to redesignate current paragraphs (a)(5), (6), and (7) as (a)(7), (8), and (9) respectively and add new paragraphs (a)(5) and (6); to revise newly designated paragraph (a)(9)(ii); and to revise paragraphs (b), (c), and (d), to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>252.225-7007</textblock>
    <textblock>Trade Agreements.</textblock>
    <textblock>As prescribed in 225.408(a)(2), use the following clause:</textblock>
    <textblock>Trade Agreements (Jan. 1994)</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)</textblock>
    <textblock>NAFTA country end product</textblock>
    <textblock>means an article that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Is wholly the growth, product, or manufacture of the NAFTA country; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Has, in the case of an article which consists in whole or in part of materials from another country or instrumentality, been substantially transformed in a NAFTA country into a new and different article of commerce with a name, character, or use distinct from that of the article or articles from which it was so transformed. The term includes services (except transportation services) incidental to its supply, provided that the value of those incidental services does not exceed the value of the product itself. It does not include service contracts as such.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6)</textblock>
    <textblock>North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) country</textblock>
    <textblock>means Canada or Mexico.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) In the case of an article which consists in whole or in part of materials from another country or instrumentality, has been substantially transformed in the United States into a new and distinct article of commerce with a name, character, or use distinct from that of the article or articles from which it was so transformed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) This clause implements the Trade Agreements Act of 1979 (19 U.S.C. 2501</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>), the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act of 1993, and the Caribbean Basin Initiative by providing a preference for U.S. made end products and designated country end products over nondesignated country end products, except nondesignated country end products which are qualifying country end products, NAFTA country end products, or Caribbean Basin end products.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The Contractor agrees to deliver under this contract only U.S. made end products unless, in its offer, it specified delivery of qualifying country, NAFTA country, or nondesignated country end products in the Buy American Act_Trade Agreements_Balance of Payments Program Certificate provision.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
