<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00083</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 960.19(d)(2) of the proposed rule provides that during</textblock>
    <textblock>the term of a temporary suspension approved by the Board, the</textblock>
    <textblock>affected Bank shall provide to the Board such financial reports as</textblock>
    <textblock>the Board shall require to monitor the financial condition of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank, and the Board shall continue to monitor the Bank's financial</textblock>
    <textblock>condition. The requirement that the Board shall monitor the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank's financial condition is added because it is required by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Act. See 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(6)(D).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.19(d)(3) of the proposed rule provides that if,</textblock>
    <textblock>prior to the conclusion of the temporary suspension period, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board determines that the Bank has returned to a position of</textblock>
    <textblock>financial stability, the Board may, upon written notice to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank, terminate the temporary suspension.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Application for Extension of Temporary Suspension Period</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.19(e)(1) of the proposed rule provides that if a</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank's board of directors determines that the Bank has not</textblock>
    <textblock>returned to, or is not likely to return to, a position of</textblock>
    <textblock>financial stability at the conclusion of the temporary suspension</textblock>
    <textblock>period, the Bank may apply in writing for an extension of the</textblock>
    <textblock>temporary suspension period, stating the grounds for such</textblock>
    <textblock>extension.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §960.19(e)(2) provides that the Board shall approve</textblock>
    <textblock>or disapprove a Bank's application for an extension of a temporary</textblock>
    <textblock>suspension period within 30 calendar days of receipt of such</textblock>
    <textblock>application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §960.19(e)(3) provides that the Board's decision on</textblock>
    <textblock>an application for an extension of a temporary suspension period</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be in writing, shall be accompanied by specific findings and</textblock>
    <textblock>reasons for such action, and shall state the effective date and</textblock>
    <textblock>time period if an extension is approved.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Notice to Congress</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.19(f)(1) of the proposed rule provides that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board shall notify the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban</textblock>
    <textblock>Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on</textblock>
    <textblock>Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs of the Senate not less than 60</textblock>
    <textblock>calendar days before any temporary suspension (or extension of</textblock>
    <textblock>such suspension) approved pursuant to this section takes effect.</textblock>
    <textblock>Deleted from this provision is the requirement in the Board's</textblock>
    <textblock>existing regulation that a copy of the Board's suspension decision</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be forwarded to the Congress since, as discussed above, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Act only requires that the Board provide notice to Congress of the</textblock>
    <textblock>suspension decision. See 12 CFR 960.11(f); 12 U.S.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>1430(j)(6)(F).</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §960.19(f)(2) provides that a temporary suspension</textblock>
    <textblock>(or extension of such suspension) shall become effective as</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by the Board, unless a joint resolution of Congress is</textblock>
    <textblock>enacted disapproving such suspension (or extension thereof). The</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule deletes the provision in the Board's existing</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation that a temporary suspension extension may not take</textblock>
    <textblock>effect until at least 30 days after the Board gives the required</textblock>
    <textblock>notice to Congress, because this is inconsistent with the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement in the existing regulation that the Board must notify</textblock>
    <textblock>the Congress at least 60 days before such extension takes effect.</textblock>
    <textblock>See 12 CFR 960.11(g).</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §960.19(f)(2) also deletes from the Board's existing</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation the requirement that a joint resolution of Congress</textblock>
    <textblock>disapproving a suspension or extension of a suspension must be</textblock>
    <textblock>enacted prior to the Board's determined effective date, in order</textblock>
    <textblock>to track more closely the actual language in the Act. See 12</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S.C. 1430(j)(6)(F).</textblock>
    <textblock>O. Affordable Housing Reserve Fund</textblock>
    <textblock>Consistent with the Board's existing AHP regulation,</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.20(a) of the proposed rule provides that if a Bank fails to</textblock>
    <textblock>use or commit the full amount of its required annual contribution</textblock>
    <textblock>to the AHP, 90 percent of the amount that has not been used or</textblock>
    <textblock>committed in that year shall be deposited by the Bank in an</textblock>
    <textblock>Affordable Housing Reserve Fund established and administered by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Board. See 12 CFR 960.12. The 10 percent of the unused and</textblock>
    <textblock>uncommitted amount retained by the Bank should be fully used or</textblock>
    <textblock>committed by the Bank during the following year, and any remaining</textblock>
    <textblock>portion must be deposited in the Affordable Housing Reserve Fund.</textblock>
    <textblock>A Bank is deemed to have used or committed its required</textblock>
    <textblock>contribution where amounts are remaining at the end of the year</textblock>
    <textblock>because funding the next highest ranking project would exceed the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank's required AHP contribution for the year. Such amounts</textblock>
    <textblock>remaining shall be combined with returned AHP funds to fund the</textblock>
    <textblock>next highest scoring AHP project or projects, or carried over by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank to the next year's AHP funding cycles.</textblock>
    <textblock>The language allowing these amounts to remain at the end of the</textblock>
    <textblock>year is added in the proposed rule to take into account situations</textblock>
    <textblock>where amounts remain uncommitted at the end of the year because</textblock>
    <textblock>the balance of required AHP contributions remaining is too small</textblock>
    <textblock>to fund the Bank's next highest scoring AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>The last sentence in proposed paragraph (a) also is new, making</textblock>
    <textblock>explicit that such amounts remaining and funds returned to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank shall fund other AHP projects and need not be transferred to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Affordable Housing Reserve Fund.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.20(b) of the proposed rule provides that by January</textblock>
    <textblock>15 of each year, each Bank shall provide to the Board a statement</textblock>
    <textblock>indicating the amount of unused and uncommitted funds from the</textblock>
    <textblock>prior year, if any, which will be deposited in the Affordable</textblock>
    <textblock>Housing Reserve Fund.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
