<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00086</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00070</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Intent To Rule on Application To Impose and Use and Impose Only the Revenue From a Passenger Facility Charge (PFC) at Pullman-Moscow Regional Airport, Pullman, WA</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of intent to rule on application.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA proposes to rule and invites public comment on the application to impose and use the revenue from a PFC at Pullman-Moscow Regional Airport under the provisions of the Aviation Safety and Capacity Expansion Act of 1990 (title IX of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990) (Public Law 101-508) and part 158 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (14 CFR part 158).</textblock>
    <textblock>This document supersedes the notice, ``Intent to rule on application to impose and use and impose only the revenue from a Passenger Facility Charge (PFC) at Pullman-Moscow Regional Airport, Pullman, Washington'', published on December 29, 1993 (58 FR 68985).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before February 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this application may be mailed or delivered in triplicate to the FAA at the following address: J. Wade Bryant, Seattle Airports District Office, SEA-ADO, Federal Aviation Administration, 1601 Lind Avenue SW., suite 250, Renton, WA 98055-4056.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, one copy of any comments submitted to the FAA must be mailed or delivered to Mr. David Crowner, airport Manager at the following address: Pullman-Moscow Regional Airport, 3200 Airport Complex N., Pullman, WA 99163.</textblock>
    <textblock>Air carriers and foreign air carriers may submit copies of written comments previously provided to Pullman-Moscow Regional Airport under ยง158.23 of part 158.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Mary Vargas, (206) 227-2660; Seattle Airports District Office, SEA-ADO; Federal Aviation Administration; 1601 Lind Avenue SW., suite 250, Renton, WA 98055-4056. The application may be reviewed in person at this same location.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA proposes to rule and invites public comment on the application to impose and use the revenue from a PFC at Pullman-Moscow Regional Airport under the provisions of the Aviation Safety and Capacity Expansion Act of 1990 (title IX of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990) (Public Law 101-508) and part 158 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (14 CFR part 158).</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 20, 1993, the FAA determined that the application to impose and use the revenue from a PFC submitted by the City of Pullman, WA and the City of Pullman, WA and the City of Moscow, ID was substantially complete with the requirements of ยง158.25 of part 158. The FAA will approve or disapprove the application, in whole or in part, no later than March 22, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following is a brief overview of the application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Level of the proposed PFC:</textblock>
    <textblock>3.00</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed charge effective date:</textblock>
    <textblock>April 1, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed charge expiration date:</textblock>
    <textblock>October 31, 1997</textblock>
    <textblock>Total estimated PFC revenue:</textblock>
    <textblock>$169,287.65</textblock>
    <textblock>Brief description of proposed project(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>Impose and Use projects: Runway 5/23 rehabilitation, runway and taxiway signage, lighting upgrade and runway 5 safety area stabilization, master plan update, aircraft rescue and fire fighting (ARFF) vehicle acquisition and storm water pollution prevention plan development, modify ARFF building and expand general aviation (GA) apron.</textblock>
    <textblock>Class or classes of air carriers which the public agency has requested not be required to collect PFCs:</textblock>
    <textblock>Only those Air taxi's defined as follows: the carriage in air commerce of persons for compensation or hire as a commercial operator, but not an air carrier, on an ``on-demand'' basis with aircraft having a maximum seating capacity of less than twenty passengers or a maximum payload capacity of less than 6,000 pounds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person may inspect the application in person at the FAA office listed above under</textblock>
    <textblock>``FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT''</textblock>
    <textblock>and at the FAA regional Airports office located at: Federal Aviation Administration, Northwest Mountain Region, Airports Division, ANM-600, 1601 Lind Avenue SW., suite 540 Renton, WA 98055-4056.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, any person may, upon request, inspect the application, notice and other documents germane to the application in person at the City of Pullman.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Renton, Washington on December 22, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Edward G. Tatum,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Airports Division, Northwest Mountain Region.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-248 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
