<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00099</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring during construction or rehabilitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>If</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advances or direct subsidies are used to finance</textblock>
    <textblock>construction or rehabilitation of a project, the Bank shall</textblock>
    <textblock>require the applicant to monitor the construction or</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitation until completion, and to make progress reports to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank, as required under §960.15(b)(2).</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring long-term requirements._</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Owner-occupied housing._</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Initial certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>At the time a household enters into</textblock>
    <textblock>a purchase contract for an AHP-assisted housing unit or at the</textblock>
    <textblock>closing on the financing for such unit, or at the time a household</textblock>
    <textblock>that already owns a housing unit receives a commitment of a loan</textblock>
    <textblock>or a grant pursuant to the AHP, the Bank or its designee shall</textblock>
    <textblock>obtain a certification from the sponsor, as required under</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.15(c)(1)(i), that the household has an income at or below</textblock>
    <textblock>the level committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring after initial sale.</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) During the required</textblock>
    <textblock>long-term period applicable to an owner-occupied housing unit</textblock>
    <textblock>assisted by a grant provided under the AHP, the Bank or its</textblock>
    <textblock>designee shall monitor the unit to determine whether it has been</textblock>
    <textblock>sold to a household with an income that exceeds the level</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Monitoring shall include, but is not limited to, periodic</textblock>
    <textblock>review of relevant reports or certifications obtained from the</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor, including reports and certifications received pursuant to</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.15(c)(1)(ii) and, at least on a sample basis, periodic</textblock>
    <textblock>review of land title records at intervals to be determined by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank, based on the amount of funds received by the project</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to the AHP, the type and complexity of the project, or</textblock>
    <textblock>other factors deemed relevant by the Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rental housing._</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Restriction on transfer.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bank shall require an AHP-assisted rental housing project to be subject to a deed</textblock>
    <textblock>restriction or other legally enforceable mechanism which requires</textblock>
    <textblock>that upon sale of the project prior to the end of the long-term</textblock>
    <textblock>period during which the project's rental units, or portion</textblock>
    <textblock>thereof, must remain affordable for and occupied by households</textblock>
    <textblock>with incomes at or below the levels committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application, the Bank or its designee receives notice of the sale,</textblock>
    <textblock>and:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The project's rental units, or portion thereof, must</textblock>
    <textblock>continue to be affordable for and occupied by households with</textblock>
    <textblock>incomes at or below the levels committed to in the AHP application</textblock>
    <textblock>for the remainder of the long-term period committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application, and the purchaser agrees to be subject to the same</textblock>
    <textblock>restrictions on resale that applied to the seller; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) If the purchaser does not satisfy the requirements in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (e)(2)(i)(A) of this section, and if the Bank provided a</textblock>
    <textblock>direct subsidy to the applicant which was passed on as a grant to</textblock>
    <textblock>the seller, the seller must repay the grant as provided in</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.16(d)(1); or</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) If the purchaser does not satisfy the requirements in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (e)(2)(i)(A) of this section, and if the Bank provided a</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advance to the applicant which in turn provided a below</textblock>
    <textblock>market rate loan to the seller, then the provisions of</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.16(d)(2) shall apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Initial certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>Upon initial full occupancy of the</textblock>
    <textblock>units in an AHP-assisted rental housing project, or one year after</textblock>
    <textblock>initial disbursement of the subsidized advance or direct subsidy,</textblock>
    <textblock>whichever occurs first, the Bank or its designee shall obtain a</textblock>
    <textblock>certification from the sponsor or the owner, as required under</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.15(c)(2), that the project's units, or portion thereof, are</textblock>
    <textblock>affordable for and occupied by households with incomes at initial</textblock>
    <textblock>occupancy at or below the levels committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring after initial occupancy.</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) During the</textblock>
    <textblock>long-term period for which the units, or portion thereof, of an</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP-assisted rental housing project must remain affordable for and</textblock>
    <textblock>occupied by households with incomes at or below the levels</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application, the Bank or its designee</textblock>
    <textblock>shall monitor the project to determine whether the project's</textblock>
    <textblock>units, or portion thereof, remain affordable for and occupied by</textblock>
    <textblock>households with incomes at or below the levels committed to in the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Monitoring shall include, but is not limited to, periodic</textblock>
    <textblock>review of relevant household income and rent reports or</textblock>
    <textblock>certifications obtained from the sponsor or the owner, including</textblock>
    <textblock>certifications received pursuant to §960.15(c)(2) and, at least</textblock>
    <textblock>on a sample basis, periodic inspections of the project at</textblock>
    <textblock>intervals to be determined by the Bank, based on the amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>funds received by the project pursuant to the AHP, the type and</textblock>
    <textblock>complexity of the project, or other factors deemed relevant by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring compliance with the special needs priority.</textblock>
    <textblock>If</textblock>
    <textblock>an applicant in its AHP application commits to fund a housing</textblock>
    <textblock>project that will address a special need pursuant to</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.10(d)(3), either through providing units for persons with a</textblock>
    <textblock>special need, or through providing a special service for</textblock>
    <textblock>occupants, as defined in the Banks AHP implementation plan:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The Bank or its designee shall obtain a certification from</textblock>
    <textblock>the sponsor or owner upon completion and occupancy of the project,</textblock>
    <textblock>as required under §960.15(c)(3), that the project's units, or</textblock>
    <textblock>portion thereof, are occupied by persons with such special need,</textblock>
    <textblock>as committed to in the AHP application, or that a special service</textblock>
    <textblock>is being provided, as committed to in the AHP application; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) In the case of a special service being provided pursuant to</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.10(d)(3), the Bank or its designee shall monitor the</textblock>
    <textblock>project, as determined by the Bank in its AHP implementation plan,</textblock>
    <textblock>for at least one year from the date of initial full occupancy of</textblock>
    <textblock>the project, to verify that such special service continues to be</textblock>
    <textblock>provided to the households, as committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring compliance with the District Bank priority or</textblock>
    <textblock>priorities.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) If an applicant in its AHP application commits to</textblock>
    <textblock>fund a project that meets a District Bank priority or priorities</textblock>
    <textblock>established by the Bank pursuant to §960.10(d)(4), the Bank or</textblock>
    <textblock>its designee shall monitor the project to verify that it continues</textblock>
    <textblock>to meet the Bank priority or priorities.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
