<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00089</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(1) Adjusting the household income limit according to the</textblock>
    <textblock>following adjustment factors for households of more than or fewer</textblock>
    <textblock>than four persons:</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For each person in excess of eight, eight percent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>four-person household base income limit shall be added to the</textblock>
    <textblock>income limit for an eight-person household for the area.</textblock>
    <textblock>Advance</textblock>
    <textblock>means a loan from a Bank that is:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Provided pursuant to a written agreement;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Supported by a note or other written evidence of the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower's obligation; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Fully secured by collateral in accordance with the Act and</textblock>
    <textblock>part 935 of this chapter.</textblock>
    <textblock>Affordable for low- or moderate-income households</textblock>
    <textblock>means:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) For purposes of rental housing units, that rents, including</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonable utility costs, charged to households for such units do</textblock>
    <textblock>not exceed 30 percent of the income of a household (assuming a</textblock>
    <textblock>household size of 1.5 persons per bedroom or 1.0 person per unit</textblock>
    <textblock>without a separate bedroom) which has an income of 80 percent of</textblock>
    <textblock>the median income for the area, as adjusted and published by the</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development, except that in</textblock>
    <textblock>areas where the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development adjusts</textblock>
    <textblock>this income figure downward because of prevailing construction</textblock>
    <textblock>costs, low housing costs, or unusually high household incomes,</textblock>
    <textblock>then ``affordable for low- or moderate-income households'' means</textblock>
    <textblock>that rents, including reasonable utility costs, charged to</textblock>
    <textblock>households for such units do not exceed 30 percent of the income</textblock>
    <textblock>of a household which has an income of 80 percent of the median</textblock>
    <textblock>income for the area, as published by the U.S. Department of</textblock>
    <textblock>Housing and Urban Development, with adjustment for household size,</textblock>
    <textblock>but without the adjustments made by the Secretary of Housing and</textblock>
    <textblock>Urban Development for prevailing construction costs, low housing</textblock>
    <textblock>costs, or unusually high household incomes; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If a rental housing unit is targeted to households whose</textblock>
    <textblock>income is less than 80 percent of the median income for the area,</textblock>
    <textblock>then ``affordable for low- or moderate-income households'' means</textblock>
    <textblock>that the rent, including reasonable utility costs, charged to a</textblock>
    <textblock>household for such unit does not exceed 30 percent of the maximum</textblock>
    <textblock>qualifying income of the targeted households of the size expected</textblock>
    <textblock>to occupy the unit.</textblock>
    <textblock>Affordable for very low-income households</textblock>
    <textblock>means:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) For purposes of rental housing units, that rents, including</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonable utility costs, charged to households for such units do</textblock>
    <textblock>not exceed 30 percent of the income of a household (assuming a</textblock>
    <textblock>household size of 1.5 persons per bedroom or 1.0 person per unit</textblock>
    <textblock>without a separate bedroom) which has an income of 50 percent of</textblock>
    <textblock>the median income for the area, as adjusted and published by the</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development, except that in</textblock>
    <textblock>areas where the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development adjusts</textblock>
    <textblock>this income figure downward because of prevailing construction</textblock>
    <textblock>costs, low housing costs, or unusually high household incomes,</textblock>
    <textblock>then ``affordable for very low-income households'' means that rents,</textblock>
    <textblock>including reasonable utility costs, charged to households for such</textblock>
    <textblock>units do not exceed 30 percent of the income of a household which</textblock>
    <textblock>has an income of 50 percent of the median income for the area, as</textblock>
    <textblock>published by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development,</textblock>
    <textblock>with adjustment for household size, but without the adjustments</textblock>
    <textblock>made by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for</textblock>
    <textblock>prevailing construction costs, low housing costs, or unusually</textblock>
    <textblock>high household incomes.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If a rental housing unit is targeted to a household whose</textblock>
    <textblock>income is less than 50 percent of the median income for the area,</textblock>
    <textblock>then ``affordable for very low-income households'' means that the</textblock>
    <textblock>rent, including reasonable utility costs, charged to a household</textblock>
    <textblock>for such unit does not exceed 30 percent of the maximum qualifying</textblock>
    <textblock>income of the targeted households of the size expected to occupy</textblock>
    <textblock>the unit.</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>means the Affordable Housing Program established pursuant</textblock>
    <textblock>to this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>means a member that applies to the Bank of which it</textblock>
    <textblock>is a member for AHP funds to be used pursuant to the requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>Area</textblock>
    <textblock>means, for purposes of defining ``median income for the</textblock>
    <textblock>area,'' a metropolitan statistical area, a county, or a</textblock>
    <textblock>nonmetropolitan area, as established by the U.S. Office of</textblock>
    <textblock>Management and Budget.</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>means a Federal Home Loan Bank established under the</textblock>
    <textblock>authority of the Act.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1No persons</textblock>
    <textblock>1Percent adjustment</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>70.</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>80.</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>90.</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>Base.</textblock>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
    <textblock>108.</textblock>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
    <textblock>116.</textblock>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
    <textblock>124.</textblock>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
    <textblock>132.</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
