<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00080</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 960.17(e)(3)(ii)(A) of the proposed rule provides that</textblock>
    <textblock>the loan fund or loan consortium shall have in place a legally</textblock>
    <textblock>binding agreement or other legally enforceable mechanism that</textblock>
    <textblock>permits it to recover from the sponsor or owner the full amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>the AHP subsidy provided to the project in the event of the</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor's or owner's fraud or willful non-compliance with respect</textblock>
    <textblock>to the AHP requirements, and the applicant shall have in place a</textblock>
    <textblock>legally binding agreement or other legally enforceable mechanism</textblock>
    <textblock>that permits it to recover from the loan fund or loan consortium</textblock>
    <textblock>such amount recovered by the loan fund or loan consortium from the</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor or owner.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.17(e)(3)(ii)(B) of the proposed rule also provides</textblock>
    <textblock>that the applicant shall have in place, if the Bank agrees and</textblock>
    <textblock>such agreement is legally enforceable, a four-party agreement that</textblock>
    <textblock>includes the Bank, the applicant, the loan fund or loan</textblock>
    <textblock>consortium, and the sponsor or owner, that permits the Bank to</textblock>
    <textblock>recover from the sponsor or owner the full amount of the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy provided to the project in the event of the sponsor's or</textblock>
    <textblock>owner's fraud or willful non-compliance with respect to the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.17(e)(4) of the proposed rule provides that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board in its discretion may grant a waiver of any required</textblock>
    <textblock>remedial actions for fraud or willful non-compliance with respect</textblock>
    <textblock>to the AHP requirements, upon written request by the Bank,</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant, loan fund or loan consortium, sponsor or owner.</textblock>
    <textblock>M. Required Annual AHP Contributions</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.18 of the proposed rule requires each Bank to fund</textblock>
    <textblock>its AHP annually in accordance with the formula set forth in</textblock>
    <textblock>section 10(j)(5) of the Act. See 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(5). Proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.18 is consistent with ยง960.10 of the Board's existing AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation, except for minor wording changes and deletion of</textblock>
    <textblock>language regarding required funding in 1990 through 1993 which is</textblock>
    <textblock>no longer necessary. See 12 CFR 960.10.</textblock>
    <textblock>Specifically, proposed ยง960.18 provides that each Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall fund its AHP in accordance with the following formula:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) In 1994, the greater of:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) 6 percent of the Bank's net earnings for the previous year;</textblock>
    <textblock>or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) That Bank's</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>share of an aggregate of $75 million</textblock>
    <textblock>to be contributed in total by the Banks, such proration being made</textblock>
    <textblock>on the basis of the net earnings of the Banks for the previous</textblock>
    <textblock>year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) In 1995 and each year thereafter, the greater of:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) 10 percent of the Bank's net earnings for the previous</textblock>
    <textblock>year; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) That Bank's</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>share of an aggregate of $100 million</textblock>
    <textblock>to be contributed in total by the Banks, such proration being made</textblock>
    <textblock>on the basis of the net earnings of the Banks for the previous</textblock>
    <textblock>year.</textblock>
    <textblock>The term ``net earnings of a Bank'' is defined in proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.1. The definition has been revised from the definition in</textblock>
    <textblock>the Board's existing AHP regulation in order to more accurately</textblock>
    <textblock>track its definition in section 10(j)(8) of the Act. See 12 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>960.1(j); 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(8).</textblock>
    <textblock>N. Temporary Suspension of AHP Contributions</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.19 of the proposed rule sets forth the provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>governing temporary suspensions by Banks of their required annual</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP contributions. A number of revisions have been made to this</textblock>
    <textblock>section in the Board's existing AHP regulation in order to more</textblock>
    <textblock>accurately track the language in section 10(j)(6) of the Act</textblock>
    <textblock>concerning this section and to provide greater clarity. See</textblock>
    <textblock>12 CFR 960.11; 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(6).</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Application for Temporary Suspension</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
