<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00063</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>This proposed provision is consistent with the requirement of</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance with fair housing laws contained in ยง960.5(a)(2)(i) of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Board's existing AHP regulation, and the requirement under</textblock>
    <textblock>existing practice that applications indicate how the sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes to affirmatively further such compliance. See 12 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>960.5(a)(2)(i).</textblock>
    <textblock>c.</textblock>
    <textblock>The twenty percent requirement and alternatives.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.9(c) of the proposed rule incorporates the existing</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum subsidy limitation requirement and alternatives contained</textblock>
    <textblock>in ยง960.9 of the Board's interim rule, with minor changes in</textblock>
    <textblock>language and one substantive modification discussed below. See</textblock>
    <textblock>12 CFR 960.9 (58 FR 17968 (April 7, 1993)). The 20 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement and the alternatives discussed below implement the</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum subsidy limitation requirement contained in section</textblock>
    <textblock>10(j)(9)(F) of the Act. See 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(9)(F). Since the</textblock>
    <textblock>20 percent requirement or an alternative must be satisfied by all</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP applications to avoid over-subsidization of a project, it is</textblock>
    <textblock>set forth as a threshold requirement in the proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The twenty percent requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.9(c)(1)(i) of the proposed rule provides generally</textblock>
    <textblock>that a Bank shall not offer subsidized advances or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidies to applicants in excess of that amount needed to reduce</textblock>
    <textblock>the monthly housing costs for income-eligible households, as</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application, to 20 percent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>household's gross monthly income (the 20 percent requirement). In</textblock>
    <textblock>projects where other forms of federal, state, local or private</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized assistance are being used in conjunction with AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advances or direct subsidies, the total amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized assistance, including funds provided under the AHP,</textblock>
    <textblock>shall not be in excess of the amount needed to reduce the monthly</textblock>
    <textblock>housing costs for the income-eligible households, as committed to</textblock>
    <textblock>in the AHP application, to 20 percent of the household's gross</textblock>
    <textblock>monthly income.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monthly housing costs are defined in proposed ยง960.9(c)(1)(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>as:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) For households in AHP-assisted owner-occupied housing</textblock>
    <textblock>units, mortgage principal and interest payments, real property</textblock>
    <textblock>taxes, homeowners' insurance, a reasonable estimate of utility</textblock>
    <textblock>costs excluding telephone service, and for households in</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP-assisted condominium, cooperative, mutual housing or other</textblock>
    <textblock>housing projects involving common ownership, those portions of any</textblock>
    <textblock>regular operating assessment or fee allocated for principal and</textblock>
    <textblock>interest payments, taxes, insurance and a reasonable estimate of</textblock>
    <textblock>utilities attributable to the household's share of the common area</textblock>
    <textblock>and/or the individual unit; and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
