<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00021</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Federal Old-Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance and Supplemental Security Income; Listing of Impairments_Respiratory System</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Social Security Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>20 CFR Parts 404 and 416</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Regulations No. 4 and 16]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 0960-AB00</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Social Security Administration, HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Correction to final rules.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document contains corrections to the final rules published Thursday, October 7, 1993 (58 FR 52346). The rules revised the criteria in the Listing of Impairments (the listings) that we use to evaluate respiratory impairments for adults and children who claim Social Security benefits or supplemental security income payments based on disability under titles II and XVI of the Social Security Act.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>October 7, 1993.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Sandy Bond, Office of Regulations, Social Security Administration, 6401 Security Boulevard, Baltimore, MD 21235, (410) 965-1794.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>The final rules that are the subject of these corrections revised the respiratory listings to reflect advances in medical knowledge, treatment, and methods of evaluating respiratory impairments.</textblock>
    <textblock>The final rules, as published, contain a number of errors and omissions in several tables and cross-references which require correction.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, the publication on October 7, 1993, of the final rules, which were the subject of FR Doc. 93-24238, is corrected as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix 1</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. On page 52361, in the first column, in listing 3.00E, the first sentence after the introductory text is corrected by adding the words ``and paragraph A of 3.04'' after the words ``paragraph A and B of 3.02''.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. On page 52361, in the third column, in listing 3.00E, the first sentence of the last paragraph is corrected by adding the words ``and 3.04'' after the words ``in 3.02''.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. On page 52364, in the second column, in listing 3.04C., in table IV, the last entry in the second column, ``71 or less'', is corrected to read ``71 or more''.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 21, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Neil J. Stillman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Assistant Secretary for Information Resources Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-221 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4190-29-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
