<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00085</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 960.21(a)(5) of the proposed rule provides that an</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council member who, subsequent to appointment, is no</textblock>
    <textblock>longer employed by or associated with a community or nonprofit</textblock>
    <textblock>organization actively involved in providing or promoting low- or</textblock>
    <textblock>moderate-income housing in the Bank's District may continue to</textblock>
    <textblock>serve on the Advisory Council until the end of his or her term.</textblock>
    <textblock>Allowing the Advisory Council member to serve out the remainder of</textblock>
    <textblock>his or her term promotes continuity in the collective experience</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Advisory Council. Further, the member may still have</textblock>
    <textblock>relevant experience related to low-income housing needs in the</textblock>
    <textblock>District, which may continue to benefit the Advisory Council.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, the Board recognizes that the Advisory Council member may</textblock>
    <textblock>no longer represent the interests of the community and nonprofit</textblock>
    <textblock>sector. Therefore, the Board specifically requests comments on</textblock>
    <textblock>this provision of the proposed rule. The Board also specifically</textblock>
    <textblock>requests comments on whether a member who is no longer employed by</textblock>
    <textblock>or associated with a community or nonprofit organization should be</textblock>
    <textblock>entitled to vote on the Advisory Council if he or she becomes a</textblock>
    <textblock>state or local housing finance agency official.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.21(b) of the proposed rule provides that each</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council shall elect from among its voting members a</textblock>
    <textblock>chairperson and a vice chairperson.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.21(c) of the proposed rule carries forward the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement of the Board's existing AHP regulation that each</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council shall designate a member, or request that a</textblock>
    <textblock>member of the Bank's staff be designated, to act as secretary to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Advisory Council. See 12 CFR 960.14(g). The secretary shall</textblock>
    <textblock>record and maintain the minutes of the meetings of the Advisory</textblock>
    <textblock>Council, which shall contain, among other things, a record of the</textblock>
    <textblock>persons present, a description of the matters discussed, and</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendations made. The person acting as secretary at a meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>shall certify to the accuracy of the minutes of that meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.21(d)(1) of the proposed rule adds a new</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement that, prior to the approval of the Bank's proposed AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation plan by the Bank's board of directors, the Bank's</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council shall review the proposed AHP implementation plan</textblock>
    <textblock>and provide its recommendations to the Bank's board of directors</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to the requirements of ยง960.2(c) discussed above under</textblock>
    <textblock>the section on the adoption of the AHP implementation plan. This</textblock>
    <textblock>provision is intended to give the Advisory Councils a greater role</textblock>
    <textblock>in advising the Banks on how AHP funds should be allocated to meet</textblock>
    <textblock>the low-income housing needs in their Districts.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.21(d)(2) of the proposed rule adds a new</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement that upon request of the Advisory Council, the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall provide the Advisory Council with copies of any AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>applications from prior AHP funding cycles. The Board is aware</textblock>
    <textblock>that some Banks have already adopted this practice. This</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement is intended to aid the Advisory Council members in</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluating how the AHP application priorities and scoring criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>adopted by the Bank in its AHP implementation plan affect the</textblock>
    <textblock>allocation of AHP funds among different types of housing projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further, this requirement is subject to any limitations of other</textblock>
    <textblock>laws that may require the Bank to keep information in an AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application confidential. The Bank may require Advisory Council</textblock>
    <textblock>members to agree to keep all or parts of AHP applications</textblock>
    <textblock>confidential. The Board specifically requests comments on the</textblock>
    <textblock>advantages and disadvantages of allowing Advisory Council members</textblock>
    <textblock>to examine AHP applications received by the Bank in prior AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>funding cycles.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.21(e) of the proposed rule carries forward the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement in the Board's existing AHP regulation that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council shall meet with representatives of the board of</textblock>
    <textblock>directors of the Bank at least quarterly to advise the Bank on</textblock>
    <textblock>low- and moderate-income housing programs and needs in the Bank's</textblock>
    <textblock>District and on the utilization of AHP subsidized advances and</textblock>
    <textblock>direct subsidies for these purposes. See 12 CFR 960.14(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.21(f) of the proposed rule requires each Advisory</textblock>
    <textblock>Council to submit to the Board annually by March 1 its analysis of</textblock>
    <textblock>the low-income housing activity of its Bank. This is a change</textblock>
    <textblock>from the January 31 date in the Board's existing AHP regulation,</textblock>
    <textblock>and is intended to give the Advisory Councils sufficient time</textblock>
    <textblock>after the end of the year to compile and evaluate year-end data in</textblock>
    <textblock>order to prepare their reports to the Board. See 12 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>960.14(j).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
