<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00066</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Nonprofit or state or local government sponsored projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications for projects that finance the purchase,</textblock>
    <textblock>construction or rehabilitation of housing sponsored by a nonprofit</textblock>
    <textblock>organization, a state or political subdivision of a state, a local</textblock>
    <textblock>housing authority or a state housing finance agency. (See</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed ยง960.10(d)(2).)</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Special needs projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications for projects that address special needs, which shall be defined by the Bank in its AHP implementation plan, which special needs may include but are not limited to:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Empowering the households or residents through programs</textblock>
    <textblock>such as resident management of the property, self-help housing,</textblock>
    <textblock>homesteading, and sweat equity;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Providing housing for special needs populations such as</textblock>
    <textblock>homeless persons, abused or battered persons, persons with AIDS,</textblock>
    <textblock>mentally or physically disabled persons, or persons with substance</textblock>
    <textblock>abuse problems;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Providing housing in rural areas or areas targeted by</textblock>
    <textblock>local, state or federal governments for community development or</textblock>
    <textblock>revitalization through the development of affordable housing or</textblock>
    <textblock>economic investment; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Providing housing with special services to meet the needs</textblock>
    <textblock>of low- or moderate-income households including, but not limited</textblock>
    <textblock>to, child care, job training, medical care, substance abuse</textblock>
    <textblock>programs, independent living skill training, and rental household</textblock>
    <textblock>and homeowner household counseling. (See proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.10(d)(3).)</textblock>
    <textblock>In defining the special needs priority in its AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation plan, a Bank is not required to include all of the</textblock>
    <textblock>special needs listed as examples above. Rather, a Bank may be</textblock>
    <textblock>selective in giving priority to some special needs and not others</textblock>
    <textblock>in devising its scoring system. In addition, the Bank may select</textblock>
    <textblock>other special needs not listed as examples above if the special</textblock>
    <textblock>needs chosen are similar in nature to such examples.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) District Bank priority. Applications for projects that meet one or more priorities recommended by the Bank's Advisory Council and adopted by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank's board of directors that each address a housing need in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank's district and are consistent with the purposes of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bank shall describe in its AHP implementation plan how the</textblock>
    <textblock>points for the priority or priorities will be distributed. (See</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed ยง960.10(d)(4).)</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Economic mobility priority. Applications for projects that provide housing for low- or moderate-income households that move from low- or moderate-income neighborhoods or housing projects to neighborhoods, mixed-income buildings or owner-occupied housing developments in which at least</textblock>
    <textblock>50 percent of the households have incomes above the median income</textblock>
    <textblock>for the area, as published by the U.S. Department of Housing and</textblock>
    <textblock>Urban Development. (See proposed ยง960.10(d)(5).)</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Scoring for objectives.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board's existing AHP regulation contains the following ``objectives'' scoring criteria: Targeting; long-term retention; effectiveness; community involvement; community stability; and</textblock>
    <textblock>innovation. The proposed rule makes long-term retention a</textblock>
    <textblock>threshold criteria and adds a new objective called ``applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>participation.'' A description of this new objective and the other</textblock>
    <textblock>criteria are set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>c.</textblock>
    <textblock>Scoring for targeting objective.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.10(e) of the proposed rule provides that an application can receive a maximum of 20 points for the targeting objective category. This is an increase from 15 points under the existing regulation. The proposed rule provides that the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall award points to applications based on the extent to which</textblock>
    <textblock>the project(s) serve(s) the greatest percentage of very low-, low-</textblock>
    <textblock>and moderate-income households, in that priority order. In the</textblock>
    <textblock>alternative, if a weighted-average scoring methodology is provided</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Bank's AHP implementation plan, the Bank shall award points</textblock>
    <textblock>to an application based on the extent to which the project has the</textblock>
    <textblock>lowest weighted-average income determined by multiplying the</textblock>
    <textblock>percentage of units reserved for households at certain income</textblock>
    <textblock>levels by those incomes expressed as a percentage of median</textblock>
    <textblock>income, and adding the totals. Applications shall be scored</textblock>
    <textblock>relative to each other with the maximum number of points allowable</textblock>
    <textblock>awarded to the application(s) that best achieve(s) the targeting</textblock>
    <textblock>objective, and the remaining application scores shall be adjusted</textblock>
    <textblock>and awarded points on a declining scale basis. However,</textblock>
    <textblock>owner-occupied housing projects shall be scored as one group and</textblock>
    <textblock>rental housing projects shall be scored as a separate group.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
