<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00074</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 960.15(d) of the proposed rule provides that each Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall require applicants or sponsors to provide such other reports</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Bank, in addition to the reports and documentation required</textblock>
    <textblock>by §960.15 of the proposed rule, as the Bank deems necessary in</textblock>
    <textblock>order to fulfill its monitoring obligations under §960.14 of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>K. Corrective and Remedial Actions for Fraud or Non-Compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>With AHP Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 10(j) of the Act is silent on what specific corrective</textblock>
    <textblock>and remedial actions should be imposed when there is fraud or</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance with the requirements of the AHP. See 12 U.S.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>1430(j). Accordingly, the Board has the discretion to determine,</textblock>
    <textblock>as a matter of policy, what those requirements should be.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board's existing AHP regulation provides that, where funds</textblock>
    <textblock>provided under the AHP will not be or are no longer being used for</textblock>
    <textblock>their approved purposes, the amount of committed but unused</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy or improperly used subsidy shall be recovered and made</textblock>
    <textblock>available by the Bank for future AHP projects. See 12 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>960.8(a). The existing regulation requires the Bank, in</textblock>
    <textblock>recapturing such funds, to take any or all of the following</textblock>
    <textblock>actions, without limitation on other remedies, in its discretion:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Reprice the advance at the interest rate charged to members</textblock>
    <textblock>on non-subsidized advances of comparable type and maturity at the</textblock>
    <textblock>time of the original advance;</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Call the advance;</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Assess a prepayment fee; or</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Require the member to reimburse the Bank for the amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>the unused or improperly used subsidy on the advance or other</textblock>
    <textblock>assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Id.</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.8(b). In addition, some Banks have adopted procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>that require a direct subsidy to be converted to an advance if the</textblock>
    <textblock>project is found to be in non-compliance with the requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>the AHP regulation.</textblock>
    <textblock>A number of concerns have been raised about this recapture</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement. First, it may not be equitable to require the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant to reimburse the Bank when it is the sponsor that is in</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance with the AHP requirements. Second, requiring</textblock>
    <textblock>recapture of the AHP subsidy could in some situations result in</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicant having to foreclose against a property in order to</textblock>
    <textblock>recover the funds to repay an advance to the Bank, thereby</textblock>
    <textblock>eliminating affordable housing units even when only a few of the</textblock>
    <textblock>units in the project may be out of compliance with AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>In short, it has become clear through the operation of the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>that the recapture remedy may not be the appropriate remedial</textblock>
    <textblock>action in all circumstances. Other less severe remedial actions</textblock>
    <textblock>may be more appropriate depending on the nature of the</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance that has occurred. In addition, the remedial</textblock>
    <textblock>actions should be directed only at the parties that are in</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance. Accordingly, the proposed rule contains</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions that tailor the remedial actions required to the nature</textblock>
    <textblock>of the non-compliance and the party committing the non-compliance,</textblock>
    <textblock>which are discussed further below.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Fraud or Willful Non-Compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>Fraud and willful non-compliance are the most extreme examples</textblock>
    <textblock>of non-compliance with the AHP requirements. Accordingly, the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule applies the most severe remedial actions_</textblock>
    <textblock>exclusion or suspension from future participation in the AHP and</textblock>
    <textblock>recovery of the full amount of the AHP subsidy_to parties that</textblock>
    <textblock>have committed fraud or are in willful non-compliance with respect</textblock>
    <textblock>to the AHP requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Specifically, §960.16(a)(1) of the proposed rule provides that</textblock>
    <textblock>in the event of an applicant's, sponsor's or owner's fraud with</textblock>
    <textblock>respect to the AHP requirements, the Bank shall exclude the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant, sponsor or owner, respectively, on a permanent basis,</textblock>
    <textblock>from future participation in the AHP. In the event of an</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant's, sponsor's or owner's willful non-compliance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP requirements, the Bank shall suspend the applicant, sponsor or</textblock>
    <textblock>owner, respectively, at least on a temporary basis, from future</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the AHP during the period such willful</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance continues, and may exclude such party permanently</textblock>
    <textblock>from future participation in the AHP. The Board specifically</textblock>
    <textblock>requests comments as to whether the Banks should be able to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine whether fraud or willful non-compliance has occurred, or</textblock>
    <textblock>whether such determination should be made by the Board, or by</textblock>
    <textblock>either the Bank or the Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, §960.16(a)(2) of the proposed rule provides that</textblock>
    <textblock>in the event of an applicant's fraud or willful non-compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>with respect to the AHP requirements, the Bank shall recover from</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicant the full amount of the AHP subsidy provided to the</textblock>
    <textblock>project.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.16(a)(3)(i) of the proposed rule provides that in</textblock>
    <textblock>the event of a sponsor's or owner's fraud or willful</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance with respect to the AHP requirements, the full</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of the AHP subsidy shall be recovered from the sponsor or</textblock>
    <textblock>owner by the applicant and returned to the Bank or, if previously</textblock>
    <textblock>agreed to by the Bank, shall be recovered by the Bank from the</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor or owner. If efforts to recover the AHP subsidy from the</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor or owner are unsuccessful, the applicant shall not be</textblock>
    <textblock>liable for such funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order to be able to implement this recapture requirement,</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicant is required, under proposed §960.16(a)(3)(ii), to</textblock>
    <textblock>have in place either:</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
