<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00058</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(3) Increase in household income or sale of project before end</textblock>
    <textblock>of required long-term period. (i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Increase in household income.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.5(a)(2) of the proposed rule provides that all</textblock>
    <textblock>households occupying a rental housing unit subject to the</textblock>
    <textblock>income-targeting requirement of paragraph (a)(1) of this section</textblock>
    <textblock>must satisfy the income-eligibility requirement applicable to such</textblock>
    <textblock>income-targeted unit, as committed to in the AHP application, upon</textblock>
    <textblock>initial occupancy. The household may continue to occupy the</textblock>
    <textblock>income-targeted unit even if its income increases above the</textblock>
    <textblock>income-eligibility requirement for such unit. The unit may</textblock>
    <textblock>continue to count toward meeting the income-targeting requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application, provided the rent charged</textblock>
    <textblock>remains affordable to the household as defined in proposed ยง960.1</textblock>
    <textblock>(as further discussed below). However, if the household's income</textblock>
    <textblock>rises above 140 percent of the income-targeting level committed to</textblock>
    <textblock>in the AHP application, the sponsor must make the next available</textblock>
    <textblock>rental housing unit in the project affordable to and available for</textblock>
    <textblock>occupancy by a household whose income is at or below the</textblock>
    <textblock>income-targeting level committed to in the AHP application for the</textblock>
    <textblock>original unit. Once the next available rental housing unit is so</textblock>
    <textblock>occupied, the rent charged on the unit occupied by the household</textblock>
    <textblock>whose income has risen shall no longer be subject to the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement that it be affordable for households at the</textblock>
    <textblock>income-targeting level committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>This approach is consistent with the approach followed in the</textblock>
    <textblock>LIHTC program. Under the LIHTC program, a unit is in compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>with the occupancy requirements until the tenant's income has</textblock>
    <textblock>risen to 140 percent of the qualifying income. See 26 U.S.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง42(g)(2)(D)(i). The next available unit must then be rented to an</textblock>
    <textblock>income-eligible tenant at an affordable rent. See</textblock>
    <textblock>id.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 42(g)(2)(D)(ii). This approach allows the household to achieve</textblock>
    <textblock>stability by allowing increases in income without fear of</textblock>
    <textblock>displacement or increased rents. In addition, it does not cause</textblock>
    <textblock>destabilization of the project's cash flow by having the project</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor provide additional income-eligible units with reduced</textblock>
    <textblock>rents that may reduce the income of the project. It also would be</textblock>
    <textblock>consistent with the treatment of rents under the AHP's 20 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement (also known as the maximum subsidy rule), which is</textblock>
    <textblock>currently an interim rule of the Board, and which is incorporated</textblock>
    <textblock>in ยง960.9(c) of this proposed rule. (See discussion of 20</textblock>
    <textblock>percent requirement below.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.1 of the proposed rule defines ``affordable for very</textblock>
    <textblock>low-income households'' to mean:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) For purposes of rental housing units, that rents, including</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonable utility costs, charged to households for such units do</textblock>
    <textblock>not exceed 30 percent of the income of a household (assuming a</textblock>
    <textblock>household size of 1.5 persons per bedroom or 1.0 person per unit</textblock>
    <textblock>without a separate bedroom) which has an income of 50 percent of</textblock>
    <textblock>the median income for the area, as adjusted and published by HUD,</textblock>
    <textblock>except that in areas where the Secretary adjusts this income</textblock>
    <textblock>figure downward because of prevailing construction costs, low</textblock>
    <textblock>housing costs, or unusually high household incomes, then</textblock>
    <textblock>``affordable for very low-income households'' means that rents,</textblock>
    <textblock>including reasonable utility costs, charged to households for such</textblock>
    <textblock>units do not exceed 30 percent of the income of a household which</textblock>
    <textblock>has an income of 50 percent of the median income for the area, as</textblock>
    <textblock>published by HUD, with adjustment for household size, but without</textblock>
    <textblock>the adjustments made by the Secretary for prevailing construction</textblock>
    <textblock>costs, low housing costs, or unusually high household incomes;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If a rental unit is targeted to a household whose income is</textblock>
    <textblock>less than 50 percent of the median income for the area, then</textblock>
    <textblock>``affordable for very low-income households'' means that the rent,</textblock>
    <textblock>including reasonable utility costs, charged to a household for</textblock>
    <textblock>such unit does not exceed 30 percent of the maximum qualifying</textblock>
    <textblock>income of the targeted households of the size expected to occupy</textblock>
    <textblock>the unit.</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposed definition implements section 10(j)(13)(D) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Act, which defines ``affordable for very low-income households'' to</textblock>
    <textblock>mean that rents charged to tenants for units made available for</textblock>
    <textblock>occupancy by low-income families shall not exceed 30 percent of</textblock>
    <textblock>the adjusted income of a family whose income equals 50 percent of</textblock>
    <textblock>the income for the area (as determined by the Secretary of HUD)</textblock>
    <textblock>with adjustment for family size. 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(13)(D).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.1(b) of the Board's existing AHP regulation contains a</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of the term that is similar to the statutory</textblock>
    <textblock>definition. See 12 CFR 960.1(b).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
