<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00028</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Adjustment of Import Limits for Certain Cotton and Man-Made Fiber Textile Products Produced or Manufactured in Guatemala</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements (CITA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Issuing a directive to the Commissioner of Customs reducing limits.</textblock>
  </action>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 12, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nicole Bivens Collinson, International Trade Specialist, Office of Textiles and Apparel, U.S. Department of Commerce, (202) 482-4212. For information on the quota status of these limits, refer to the Quota Status Reports posted on the bulletin boards of each Customs port or call (202) 927-5850. For information on embargoes and quota re-openings, call (202) 482-3715.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 11651 of March 3, 1972, as amended; section 204 of the Agricultural Act of 1956, as amended (7 U.S.C. 1854).</textblock>
    <textblock>The 1994 limits for Categories 340/640 and 351/651 are being reduced for carryforward used.</textblock>
    <textblock>A description of the textile and apparel categories in terms of HTS numbers is available in the CORRELATION: Textile and Apparel Categories with the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (see</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice 58 FR 62645, published on November 29, 1993). Also see 58 FR 61679, published on November 22, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>The letter to the Commissioner of Customs and the actions taken pursuant to it are not designed to implement all of the provisions of the bilateral agreement, but are designed to assist only in the implementation of certain of its provisions.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rita D. Hayes,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements</textblock>
    <textblock>January 5, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Commissioner of Customs,</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Treasury, Washington, DC 20229.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dear Commissioner: This directive amends, but does not cancel, the directive issued to you on November 12, 1993, by the Chairman, Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements. That directive concerns imports of certain cotton, wool and man-made fiber textile products, produced or manufactured in Guatemala and exported during the twelve-month period beginning on January 1, 1994 and extending through December 31, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective on January 12, 1994, you are directed to reduce the limits for the following categories, as provided under the terms of the current bilateral agreement between the Governments of the United States and Guatemala:</textblock>
    <textblock>The guaranteed access level for Categories 340/640 and 351/651 remain unchanged.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements has determined that these actions fall within the foreign affairs exception to the rulemaking provisions of 5 U.S.C. 553(a)(1).</textblock>
    <textblock>Sincerely,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <table>
    <textblock>1Category</textblock>
    <textblock>1Adjusted twelve-month limit</textblock>
    <textblock>340/640</textblock>
    <textblock>943,400 dozen.</textblock>
    <textblock>351/651</textblock>
    <textblock>200,000 dozen.</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rita D. Hayes,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-514 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DR-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
