<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00115</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Radio Broadcasting Services; Jensen Beach and Melbourne, FL</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL COMMUNICATIONS COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>47 CFR Part 73</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[MM Docket No. 93-307, RM-8386]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document requests comments on a joint petition by HLG, Inc., licensee of Station WHLG(FM), Jensen Beach, Florida, and City Broadcasting Co., Inc., license of Station WGGD(FM), Melbourne, Florida, proposing the substitution of Channel 272C3 for Channel 272A at Jensen Beach, Florida, and modification of the license for Station WHLG(FM) to specify the higher powered channel, and the substitution of Channel 236A for Channel 272A at Melbourne, Florida, and the modification of Station WGGD(FM)'s license to specify the alternate Class A channel. Channel 272C3 can be allotted to Jensen Beach in compliance with the minimum distance separation requirements of the Commission's Rules at the licensed transmitter site. The coordinates for Channel 272C3 at Jensen Beach are 27-12-53 North Latitude and 80-15-24 West Longitude. Channel 236A can be allotted to Melbourne in compliance with the minimum distance separation requirements of the Commission's Rules with a site restriction of 6.4 kilometers (4.0 miles) north of the community, in order to avoid a short-spacing to Station WWRM(FM), Channel 235C, Tampa, Florida. The coordinates for Channel 236A at Melbourne are 28-08-08 North Latitude and 80-35-35 West Longitude.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be filed on or before February 25, 1994, and reply comments on or before March 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission, Washington, DC 20554. In addition to filing comments with the FCC, interested parties should serve the petitioner, or its counsel or consultant, as follows: Bruce A. Eisen, Kaye, Scholer, Fierman, Hays &amp; Handler, 901 15th Street, NW., suite 1100, Washington, DC 20005-2327 (Counsel for HLG, Inc. and City Broadcasting Company, Inc.).</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nancy J. Walls, Mass Media Bureau, (202) 634-6530.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a synopsis of the Commission's Notice of Proposed Rule Making, MM Docket No. 93-307, adopted December 8, 1993, and released January 4, 1994. The full text of this Commission decision is available for inspection and copying during normal business hours in the FCC Reference Center (Room 239), 1919 M Street, NW., Washington, DC. The complete text of this decision may also be purchased from the Commission's copy contractors, International Transcription Service, Inc., (202) 857-3800, 1919 M Street, NW., room 246, or 2100 M Street, NW., suite 140, Washington, DC 20037.</textblock>
    <textblock>Provisions of the Regulatory Flexibility Act of 1980 do not apply to this proceeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>Members of the public should note that from the time a Notice of Proposed Rule Making is issued until the matter is no longer subject to Commission consideration or court review, all</textblock>
    <textblock>ex parte</textblock>
    <textblock>contacts are prohibited in Commission proceedings, such as this one, which involve channel allotments. See 47 CFR 1.1204(b) for rules governing permissible</textblock>
    <textblock>ex parte</textblock>
    <textblock>contacts.</textblock>
    <textblock>For information regarding proper filing procedures for comments, see 47 CFR 1.415 and 1.420.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 47 CFR Part 73</textblock>
    <textblock>Radio broadcasting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John A. Karousos,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Chief, Allocations Branch, Policy and Rules Division, Mass Media Bureau.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-471 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
