<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00008</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to its authority under the Foreign-Trade Zones Act of June 18, 1934, as amended (19 U.S.C. 81a-81u), the Foreign-Trade Zones Board (the Board) adopts the following Order: Expansion of foreign-trade zone 35 and approval of export processing activity (beef products), Philadelphia, Pennsylvania area.</textblock>
    <textblock>Whereas, an application from the Philadelphia Regional Port Authority, grantee of Foreign-Trade Zone No. 35 (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania area), for authority to expand its general-purpose zone to include a site in King of Prussia, Pennsylvania, adjacent to the Philadelphia Customs port of entry, and for authority on behalf of American Foodservice Corporation (AFSC) to conduct activity within FTZ 35 involving the processing of beef products for export, was filed by the Foreign-Trade Zones (FTZ) Board on June 21, 1993, (Docket 26-93, 58 FR 35428, 7/1/93);</textblock>
    <textblock>Whereas, notice inviting public comment was given in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>and the application has been processed pursuant to the FTZ Act and the Board's regulations; and,</textblock>
    <textblock>Whereas, the Board, in consultation with the U.S. Department of Agriculture, has found that the requirements of the Act and the regulations are satisfied, and that approval of the expansion and the beef processing activity for export is in the public interest;</textblock>
    <textblock>Now, therefore, the Board hereby orders:</textblock>
    <textblock>The application for said expansion and for said processing activity is approved, subject to the Act and the Board's regulations, including ยง400.28, and further subject to the following restrictions:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. AFSC shall reexport all beef admitted to the zone in foreign status (19 CFR 146.41 and 146.42); and,</textblock>
    <textblock>2. AFSC shall comply with all meat inspection requirements of the U.S. Department of Agriculture's Food Safety and Inspection Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>Signed at Washington, DC, this 29th day of December 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Order No. 678]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>American Food Service Corp., Pennsylvania; Application</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Barbara R. Stafford,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Import Administration, Chairman, Committee of Alternates Foreign-Trade Zones Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>Attest:</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John J. Da Ponte, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Executive Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-507 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DS-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
