<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00069</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>2. Calculation of AHP Subsidy</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board is considering adopting rules on the calculation of</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP subsidies for subsidized advances and specifically requests</textblock>
    <textblock>comments on the following proposals. Under consideration is</textblock>
    <textblock>whether AHP application approvals should commit to provide a</textblock>
    <textblock>dollar amount of subsidy, or should commit to make a subsidized</textblock>
    <textblock>advance at a specific interest rate. Another possibility is that</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank can select on a case-by-case basis to do one or the other</textblock>
    <textblock>or both but the choice must be specified in its approval. The</textblock>
    <textblock>rule could require the Bank's AHP implementation plan to describe</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank's procedures in this area.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board specifically requests comments as to whether an AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>approval should commit to provide a specific dollar amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy for a subsidized advance. If interest rates rise after</textblock>
    <textblock>the approval, should the interest rate on the subsidized advance</textblock>
    <textblock>be increased so that the present value of the amount needed to</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidize the reduction in interest rate is equal to the subsidy</textblock>
    <textblock>amount originally approved? Should the applicant be given the</textblock>
    <textblock>option of either reducing the principal amount of the loan and</textblock>
    <textblock>keeping the originally requested interest rate unchanged, or</textblock>
    <textblock>increasing the interest rate on the loan and keeping the principal</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of the loan unchanged? If interest rates fall after the</textblock>
    <textblock>approval, should the specific dollar amount of approved subsidy</textblock>
    <textblock>stay the same, or be adjusted?</textblock>
    <textblock>Alternatively, if the AHP approval commits to make a subsidized</textblock>
    <textblock>loan at a specified interest rate, then a number of issues are</textblock>
    <textblock>raised. First, should the amount of the subsidy to be charged</textblock>
    <textblock>against the AHP fund be calculated at the time the application is</textblock>
    <textblock>approved, or at the time of disbursement. If the calculation is</textblock>
    <textblock>not done at the time the application is approved but is done at</textblock>
    <textblock>the time of funding and interest rates have fallen since the</textblock>
    <textblock>approval, the amount of the subsidy provided to subsidize the</textblock>
    <textblock>advance would decrease and the amount of subsidy charged against</textblock>
    <textblock>the AHP fund would decrease. If the calculation is done at the</textblock>
    <textblock>time of funding and interest rates have risen since the approval,</textblock>
    <textblock>the amount of the subsidy provided to subsidize the advance would</textblock>
    <textblock>increase and the amount of subsidy charged against the AHP fund</textblock>
    <textblock>would increase. If the increase in subsidy is permitted to be</textblock>
    <textblock>charged against the AHP fund, should there be any limits on the</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of increase in subsidy? If the amount that could be</textblock>
    <textblock>charged against the AHP fund could be increased without limit,</textblock>
    <textblock>these charges could reduce the amount of funds available for</textblock>
    <textblock>future cycles of AHP funding. One option would be to put an upper</textblock>
    <textblock>limit, for example a specified number of basis points, as the</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum amount by which additional AHP funds would be provided to</textblock>
    <textblock>cover the interest rate increase. Another option would be to</textblock>
    <textblock>approve the amount of the subsidy as well as the interest rate on</textblock>
    <textblock>the advance at the time the advance is approved and permit the</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy to be increased up to a specified amount. Another issue</textblock>
    <textblock>is whether funds from future AHP funding cycles should be used to</textblock>
    <textblock>pay for increased subsidies due to interest rate increases. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Board specifically requests comments on these options.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board is concerned about the calculation of subsidies where</textblock>
    <textblock>non-amortizing subsidized advances are used by members to fund</textblock>
    <textblock>amortizing AHP loans from members to sponsors. Since principal is</textblock>
    <textblock>repaid on a different schedule for amortizing loans than</textblock>
    <textblock>non-amortizing loans, the Banks must adjust their subsidy</textblock>
    <textblock>calculation methodologies to ensure that they have properly</textblock>
    <textblock>adjusted for these differences. As AHP principal is repaid to a</textblock>
    <textblock>member but not repaid to the Bank, the benefit of these subsidized</textblock>
    <textblock>funds may not be passed on to the ultimate borrower, as required</textblock>
    <textblock>in section 10(j)(9)(E) of the Act. See 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(9)(E).</textblock>
    <textblock>Without proper adjustment for differences in the cash flows for an</textblock>
    <textblock>amortizing loan and an interest-only advance, the amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy actually received by a project will be less than the</textblock>
    <textblock>amount incurred by the Bank as an AHP expense. The Board</textblock>
    <textblock>specifically requests comments as to whether an amortizing advance</textblock>
    <textblock>structure is required to assure that the subsidy amount incurred</textblock>
    <textblock>by the Bank as an AHP expense matches the amount of the subsidy</textblock>
    <textblock>actually received by a sponsor. In addition, the Board requests</textblock>
    <textblock>comments as to whether there are alternative appropriate methods</textblock>
    <textblock>to deal with the discrepancy in the subsidy amounts where such</textblock>
    <textblock>advances are used to fund amortizing loans.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Verification at Initial Disbursement of Subsidized</textblock>
    <textblock>Advances or Direct Subsidies</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
