<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00072</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Another option would be that where funds other than funds</textblock>
    <textblock>provided under the AHP are the predominant source of financing for</textblock>
    <textblock>an AHP-assisted rental housing project and the monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>activities of such other funding source are sufficient to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine the project's compliance with the requirements of the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP, as committed to in the AHP application, the monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement would be deemed to be fulfilled. However, if the</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring activities of such other funding source are not</textblock>
    <textblock>sufficient to determine the project's compliance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of the AHP, as committed to in the AHP application,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank would be required to monitor the project by conducting</textblock>
    <textblock>inspections, at least on a sample basis, as determined by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank, based on the amount of the funds received by the project</textblock>
    <textblock>under the AHP, the type and complexity of the project, or other</textblock>
    <textblock>factors deemed relevant by the Bank. In the alternative, if the</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring activities of such other funding source are not</textblock>
    <textblock>sufficient to determine the project's compliance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of the AHP, as committed to in the AHP application,</textblock>
    <textblock>could the Bank rely on monitoring activities of the predominant</textblock>
    <textblock>funding source as long as it is monitoring for compliance with</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements that are substantially similar to the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements?</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board specifically requests comments on how random sampling</textblock>
    <textblock>could be used to monitor AHP-assisted rental housing projects to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine whether, during the long-term period committed to in the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP application, the project's units continue to be affordable for</textblock>
    <textblock>and occupied by households with incomes at or below the levels</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application. For example, sampling could</textblock>
    <textblock>involve monitoring a portion of AHP-assisted rental projects at</textblock>
    <textblock>fixed intervals. The sampling method could be devised so that</textblock>
    <textblock>each project is monitored at least once during the long-term</textblock>
    <textblock>period committed to in the AHP application. Alternatively, the</textblock>
    <textblock>sampling method might be structured so that some, but not all,</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP-assisted rental projects are monitored during the long-term</textblock>
    <textblock>period committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Act requires that the AHP regulation must ensure that the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP will be used only to assist projects for which adequate</textblock>
    <textblock>long-term monitoring is available to guarantee that affordability</textblock>
    <textblock>standards and other requirements of the Act are satisfied. See</textblock>
    <textblock>12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(9)(C). The Board requests comments as to</textblock>
    <textblock>whether it is appropriate to interpret this requirement in a</textblock>
    <textblock>manner that permits monitoring to be done by sampling that could</textblock>
    <textblock>result in some AHP-assisted rental projects not being monitored</textblock>
    <textblock>during the long-term period committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, the Board specifically requests comments on whether</textblock>
    <textblock>there are sampling techniques that would ensure that each project</textblock>
    <textblock>is monitored in satisfaction of the monitoring requirement in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring of special needs projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(f) of the proposed rule sets forth the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for monitoring a project that commits to meet a</textblock>
    <textblock>special need pursuant to proposed ยง960.10(d)(3), either through</textblock>
    <textblock>providing units for persons with a special need or through</textblock>
    <textblock>providing a special service to occupants, as defined in the Bank's</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP implementation plan. If an applicant commits to fund a</textblock>
    <textblock>project that provides owner-occupied or rental housing units for</textblock>
    <textblock>persons with a special need, as defined in the Bank's AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation plan, ยง960.14(f)(1) of the proposed rule requires</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank or its designee to obtain a certification from the</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor or the owner upon completion and occupancy of the project</textblock>
    <textblock>that the project's units, or portion thereof, are occupied by</textblock>
    <textblock>persons with such special need.</textblock>
    <textblock>If an applicant in its AHP application commits to fund a</textblock>
    <textblock>project that will provide a continuing special service to its</textblock>
    <textblock>occupants, as defined in the Bank's AHP implementation plan, such</textblock>
    <textblock>as child care, job training, medical care, or other services</textblock>
    <textblock>designed to meet the special needs of occupants, then</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.14(f)(1) of the proposed rule provides that the Bank or its</textblock>
    <textblock>designee shall obtain a certification from the sponsor or owner</textblock>
    <textblock>upon completion and occupancy of the project that the special</textblock>
    <textblock>service is being provided to the occupants, as committed to in the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(f)(2) of the proposed rule provides that, where</textblock>
    <textblock>an applicant in its AHP application commits to fund a housing</textblock>
    <textblock>project that will provide a continuing special service, the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>or its designee shall monitor the project, as determined by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank in its AHP implementation plan, for at least one year from</textblock>
    <textblock>the date of initial full occupancy of the project to verify that</textblock>
    <textblock>the special service continues to be provided to the occupants, as</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
