<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00065</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Board's existing AHP regulation also includes as a</textblock>
    <textblock>threshold requirement the ability of the project to begin using</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank assistance within 12 months. See 12 CFR 960.5(a)(2)(iv).</textblock>
    <textblock>Since this involves the use of funds after a project has been</textblock>
    <textblock>approved for funding, it does not belong as a threshold</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement and has been omitted in this section of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule. The requirements under the proposed rule for use of funds</textblock>
    <textblock>under the AHP within a reasonable period of time after approval of</textblock>
    <textblock>the application are discussed below in the use and verification</textblock>
    <textblock>section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Finally, it has been suggested that a threshold criterion</textblock>
    <textblock>should be added requiring that the project costs set forth in the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP application are reasonable and appropriate for the type and</textblock>
    <textblock>location of the housing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 10(j)(9)(F) of the Act requires the Board to establish</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum subsidy limitations under the AHP. 12 U.S.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>1430(j)(9)(F). Section 10(j)(9)(D) of the Act also requires the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board to ensure that a preponderance of assistance provided under</textblock>
    <textblock>the AHP is ultimately received by low- and moderate-income</textblock>
    <textblock>households.</textblock>
    <textblock>Id</textblock>
    <textblock>. Section 1430(j)(9)(D). Requiring that project costs be</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonable is one way of controlling the amount of AHP subsidies</textblock>
    <textblock>that fund a project in order to keep the project from being</textblock>
    <textblock>over-subsidized, and to ensure that a preponderance of the funds</textblock>
    <textblock>are being received by the ultimate households by lowering their</textblock>
    <textblock>housing costs and not providing undue benefit to the</textblock>
    <textblock>intermediaries in the development process.</textblock>
    <textblock>A project costs requirement is not explicitly prescribed in the</textblock>
    <textblock>threshold requirements under the Board's existing AHP regulation,</textblock>
    <textblock>although some Banks do currently review project costs to determine</textblock>
    <textblock>if they are reasonable under the feasibility requirement in the</textblock>
    <textblock>existing regulation. See 12 CFR 960.5(a)(2)(ii). The feasibility</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement as defined in the proposed rule would not incorporate</textblock>
    <textblock>a project costs limit requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board specifically requests comments on how the Banks</textblock>
    <textblock>currently deal with applications with excessive project costs,</textblock>
    <textblock>whether the project costs option discussed above should be</textblock>
    <textblock>required as a threshold criterion in approving AHP applications,</textblock>
    <textblock>and how such a requirement could be implemented by the Banks.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Scoring of AHP Applications</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.10(a) of the proposed rule provides that the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall score AHP applications that satisfy all of the threshold</textblock>
    <textblock>criteria in proposed ยง960.9 according to the scoring methodology</textblock>
    <textblock>set forth in proposed ยง960.10, which shall be included in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank's approved AHP implementation plan. Section 960.10 of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule modifies the existing scoring methodology, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board specifically requests comments on this proposed new scoring</textblock>
    <textblock>methodology.</textblock>
    <textblock>a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Priority treatment and scoring.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.10(b) of the proposed rule provides that each application is first evaluated to determine if it will receive priority treatment. The Board's existing AHP regulation contains</textblock>
    <textblock>seven priorities: Homeownership projects; rental projects;</textblock>
    <textblock>projects using government properties; projects with a non-profit</textblock>
    <textblock>or public agency sponsor; projects promoting empowerment; homeless</textblock>
    <textblock>housing projects; and projects meeting a Bank priority. Under the</textblock>
    <textblock>existing AHP regulation, an application must meet at least three</textblock>
    <textblock>of the seven priorities to receive priority treatment. The</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule would contain only five priorities. The proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule would eliminate the priorities for homeownership and rental</textblock>
    <textblock>properties because a project must be either a rental or</textblock>
    <textblock>homeownership project in order to qualify for AHP funding. The</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule would replace the empowerment and homeless housing</textblock>
    <textblock>priorities with a priority for ``special needs'' housing. In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition, the proposed rule would add a new priority for projects</textblock>
    <textblock>promoting economic mobility.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under ยง960.10(b) of the proposed rule, for purposes of</textblock>
    <textblock>determining priority, an application can receive a maximum of</textblock>
    <textblock>eight points for each of the five priority categories described</textblock>
    <textblock>below. A Bank in its AHP implementation plan shall define more</textblock>
    <textblock>specifically each of the five priority categories and explain</textblock>
    <textblock>specifically how points will be awarded for satisfying each</textblock>
    <textblock>category. An application will be deemed to meet a particular</textblock>
    <textblock>priority category if it is awarded at least four points for that</textblock>
    <textblock>priority category. Applications meeting at least two priority</textblock>
    <textblock>categories shall receive priority treatment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.10(c) of the proposed rule provides that</textblock>
    <textblock>applications that qualify for such priority treatment shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>scored before applications that do not qualify for priority</textblock>
    <textblock>treatment. The applications that do not qualify for priority</textblock>
    <textblock>treatment will not be scored unless there are insufficient</textblock>
    <textblock>priority treatment applications to utilize the total AHP funding</textblock>
    <textblock>amount for the funding cycle. Under the proposed rule, the total</textblock>
    <textblock>points available for the priorities would be increased from 25 to</textblock>
    <textblock>40. Section 960.10(d) of the proposed rule provides that the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall total the points received by each applicant for purposes of</textblock>
    <textblock>determining priority for all of the five priority categories and</textblock>
    <textblock>shall award 40 points to the application(s) that receive the</textblock>
    <textblock>highest number of total points, and the remaining application</textblock>
    <textblock>scores shall be adjusted and awarded points on a declining scale</textblock>
    <textblock>basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>The five priority categories are set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Government-owned properties. Applications for projects that finance the purchase or rehabilitation of housing owned or held by the United States Government or any agency or instrumentality of the United States,</textblock>
    <textblock>including but not limited to HUD, the RTC, Farmers Home Administration, Veterans Administration, Federal National Mortgage Association, or Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation. (See proposed ยง960.10(d)(1).)</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
