<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00025</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[C-333-502]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Deformed Steel Concrete Reinforcing Bar From Peru; Determination Not To Revoke Countervailing Duty Order</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>International Trade Administration/Import Administration,</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of determination not to revoke countervailing</textblock>
    <textblock>duty order.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Commerce is notifying the public of its determination not to revoke the countervailing duty order on deformed steel concrete reinforcing bar from Peru.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Kelly Parkhill, Office of Countervailing Compliance, International Trade Administration, U.S. Department of Commerce, Washington, DC 20230; telephone: (202) 482-2786.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On November 19, 1993, the Department of Commerce (the Department) published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 61069) its intent to revoke the countervailing duty order on deformed steel concrete reinforcing bar from Peru (50 FR 48819; November 27, 1985).</textblock>
    <textblock>Under 19 CFR 355.25(d)(4)(iii), the Secretary of Commerce will conclude that an order is no longer of interest to interested parties and will revoke the order if no domestic interested party objects to revocation or no interested party requests an administrative review by the last day of the fifth anniversary month.</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 3, 1993, Florida Steel Corporation and Chaparral Steel Co., domestic producers and petitioners in the original investigation, objected to our intent to revoke the order. Accordingly, the requirements of 19 CFR 355.25(d)(4)(iii) have not been met, and we will not revoke the order.</textblock>
    <textblock>This determination is in accordance with 19 CFR 355.25(d)(4).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 30, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Roland L. MacDonald,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>for Compliance.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-517 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DS-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
