<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00071</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(e)(1)(ii)(A) of the proposed rule provides that</textblock>
    <textblock>during the required long-term period applicable to an</textblock>
    <textblock>owner-occupied housing unit assisted by a grant provided under the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP, the Bank or its designee shall monitor the unit to determine</textblock>
    <textblock>whether it has been sold to a household with an income that</textblock>
    <textblock>exceeds the level committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board requests comments on two proposed options for</textblock>
    <textblock>implementing this requirement. These options incorporate the use</textblock>
    <textblock>of sampling to monitor AHP-assisted projects. The Board</textblock>
    <textblock>recognizes that as the number of AHP-assisted projects in</textblock>
    <textblock>existence grows, the costs of monitoring these projects may place</textblock>
    <textblock>an undue financial burden on the Banks and the AHP. Monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP-assisted projects on a sample basis may be one way to minimize</textblock>
    <textblock>the costs of monitoring while continuing to meet the monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(e)(1)(ii)(B) of the proposed rule proposes that</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring shall include, but is not limited to, periodic review</textblock>
    <textblock>of relevant reports or certifications obtained from the sponsor,</textblock>
    <textblock>including any reports or certifications received pursuant to</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.15(c)(1)(ii) of the proposed rule and, at least on a sample</textblock>
    <textblock>basis, periodic review of land title records at intervals</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by the Bank, based on the amount of funds received by</textblock>
    <textblock>the project pursuant to the AHP, the type and complexity of the</textblock>
    <textblock>project, or other factors deemed relevant by the Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>An alternative option would be to require that the Bank only</textblock>
    <textblock>would have to review land title records on a sample basis, as</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by the Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Rental housing projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(e)(2)(i) of the proposed rule provides that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank shall require an AHP-assisted rental housing project to be</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to a deed restriction or other legally enforceable</textblock>
    <textblock>mechanism which requires that upon sale of the project prior to</textblock>
    <textblock>the end of the long-term period during which the project's rental</textblock>
    <textblock>units, or portion thereof, must remain affordable for and occupied</textblock>
    <textblock>by households with incomes at or below the level committed to in</textblock>
    <textblock>the AHP application, the Bank or its designee must receive notice</textblock>
    <textblock>of the sale, and:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The project's rental units, or portion thereof, must</textblock>
    <textblock>continue to be affordable for and occupied by households with</textblock>
    <textblock>incomes at or below the levels committed to in the AHP application</textblock>
    <textblock>for the remainder of the long-term period committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application, and the purchaser agrees to be subject to the same</textblock>
    <textblock>restrictions on resale that applied to the seller; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If the purchaser does not satisfy the requirements in (1)</textblock>
    <textblock>above, and if the Bank provided a direct subsidy to the applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>which was passed on as a grant to the seller, the seller must</textblock>
    <textblock>repay a pro rata portion of the grant to the applicant, as</textblock>
    <textblock>provided in ยง960.16(d)(1) of the proposed rule; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) If the purchaser does not satisfy the requirements in (1)</textblock>
    <textblock>above, and if the Bank provided a subsidized advance to the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant which in turn provided a below market rate loan to the</textblock>
    <textblock>seller, then the provisions of ยง960.16(d)(2) shall apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(e)(2)(ii) of the proposed rule provides that</textblock>
    <textblock>upon initial full occupancy of the units in an AHP-assisted rental</textblock>
    <textblock>housing project or one year after initial disbursement of the</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advance or direct subsidy, whichever occurs first, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank or its designee shall obtain a certification from the sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>or the owner that the project's units, or portion thereof, are</textblock>
    <textblock>affordable for and occupied by households with incomes at initial</textblock>
    <textblock>occupancy at or below the levels committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(e)(2)(iii)(A) of the proposed rule provides that</textblock>
    <textblock>during the long-term period for which the units, or portion</textblock>
    <textblock>thereof, of a rental housing project must remain affordable for</textblock>
    <textblock>and occupied by households with incomes at or below the levels</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application, the Bank or its designee</textblock>
    <textblock>shall monitor the project to determine whether the project's</textblock>
    <textblock>units, or portion thereof, remain affordable for and occupied by</textblock>
    <textblock>households with incomes at or below the levels committed to in the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP application. The Board requests comments on several options</textblock>
    <textblock>for implementing this requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(e)(2)(iii)(B) of the proposed rule proposes that</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring shall include, but is not limited to, periodic review</textblock>
    <textblock>of relevant household income and rent reports or certifications</textblock>
    <textblock>obtained from the sponsor or the owner and, at least on a sample</textblock>
    <textblock>basis, periodic inspections of the project at intervals to be</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by the Bank, based on the amount of AHP assistance</textblock>
    <textblock>received by the project, the type and complexity of the project,</textblock>
    <textblock>and other factors deemed relevant by the Bank.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
