<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00116</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Radio Broadcasting Services; Douglas and Unionville, GA</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>47 CFR Part 73</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[MM Docket No. 93-316, RM-8403]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document requests comments on a petition by Orchon Media, Inc., permittee of Station WKZZ(FM), Channel 223A, Douglas, Georgia, requesting the substitution of Channel 223C3 for Channel 223A at Douglas, Georgia, and the reallotment of Channel 223C3 from Douglas to Unionville, Georgia, and the modification of the construction permit for Station WKZZ(FM) to specify Unionville as its community of license, in accordance with Section 1.420(i) of the Commission's rules. The coordinates for Channel 223C3 at Unionville are North Latitude 31-31-05 and West Longitude 83-20-43.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be filed on or before February 25, 1994, and reply comments on or before March 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission, Washington, DC 20554. In addition to filing comments with the FCC, interested parties should serve the petitioner, or its counsel or consultant, as follows: Robert S. Stone, McCampbell &amp; Young, 2021 Plaza Tower, P.O. Box 550, Knoxville, TN 37901-0550 (Attorney for petitioner).</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nancy J. Walls, Mass Media Bureau, (202) 634-6530.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a synopsis of the Commission's Notice of Proposed Rule Making, MM Docket No. 93-316, adopted December 13, 1993, and released January 4, 1994. The full text of this Commission decision is available for inspection and copying during normal business hours in the FCC Reference Center (room 239), 1919 M Street NW., Washington, DC. The complete text of this decision may also be purchased from the Commission's copy contractor, International Transcription Service, Inc., (202) 857-3800, 1919 M Street, NW., room 246, or 2100 M Street, NW., suite 140, Washington, DC 20037.</textblock>
    <textblock>Provisions of the Regulatory Flexibility Act of 1980 do not apply to this proceeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>Members of the public should note that from the time a Notice of Proposed Rule Making is issued until the matter is no longer subject to Commission consideration or court review, all</textblock>
    <textblock>ex parte</textblock>
    <textblock>contacts are prohibited in Commission proceedings, such as this one, which involve channel allotments. See 47 CFR 1.1204(b) for rules governing permissible</textblock>
    <textblock>ex parte</textblock>
    <textblock>contacts.</textblock>
    <textblock>For information regarding proper filing procedures for comments, see 47 CFR 1.415 and 1.420.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 47 CFR Part 73</textblock>
    <textblock>Radio broadcasting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John A. Karousos,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Chief, Allocations Branch, Policy and Rules Division, Mass Media Bureau.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-472 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
