<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00048</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Affordable Housing Program</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL HOUSING FINANCE BOARD</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>12 CFR Part 960</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[No. 93-94]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Housing Finance Board.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Housing Finance Board (Board) is proposing</textblock>
    <textblock>to amend in its entirety its regulation governing the operation of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Affordable Housing Program (AHP or Program). The proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule modifies or carries forward requirements of the Board's</textblock>
    <textblock>existing AHP regulation, adds new provisions, and incorporates,</textblock>
    <textblock>with modifications, the provisions of the Board's existing policy</textblock>
    <textblock>guidelines governing the award of funds to loan funds and loan</textblock>
    <textblock>consortia.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this proposed rule must be received in writing</textblock>
    <textblock>on or before March 11, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be mailed to: Federal Housing Finance</textblock>
    <textblock>Board, Executive Secretary, 1777 F Street, NW., Washington, DC</textblock>
    <textblock>20006. Comments will be available for public inspection at this</textblock>
    <textblock>address.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Diane E. Dorius, Deputy</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, or Sylvia C. Martinez, Director, Housing Finance</textblock>
    <textblock>Directorate, (202) 408-2576, or Sharon B. Like, Attorney-Advisor,</textblock>
    <textblock>(202) 408-2930, or Brandon B. Straus, Attorney-Advisor, (202)</textblock>
    <textblock>408-2589, Office of Legal &amp; External Affairs-Legal Division,</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Housing Finance Board, 1777 F Street, NW., Washington,</textblock>
    <textblock>DC 20006.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Statutory and Regulatory Background</textblock>
    <textblock>A. General</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 10(j)(1) of the Federal Home Loan Bank Act (Act)</textblock>
    <textblock>requires each Federal Home Loan Bank (Bank) to establish a Program</textblock>
    <textblock>to subsidize the interest rate on advances to members of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Home Loan Bank System (Bank System) engaged in lending for</textblock>
    <textblock>long-term, low- and moderate-income, owner-occupied and affordable</textblock>
    <textblock>rental housing at subsidized interest rates. The Board is</textblock>
    <textblock>required to promulgate regulations governing the Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(1). The Board's existing regulation governing the operation of the AHP appears at part 960 of the Board's</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations. 12 CFR part 960.</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposed rule amends the Board's existing AHP regulation</textblock>
    <textblock>to address operational issues that have arisen during the three</textblock>
    <textblock>and one-half years that the AHP has been in existence. The</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed amendments are intended to make the AHP more responsive</textblock>
    <textblock>to low-income housing needs in each of the twelve Federal Home</textblock>
    <textblock>Loan Bank Districts (Districts), to increase efficiency in the</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of the Program, and to enhance coordination of the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP with other housing programs whose funds are used in</textblock>
    <textblock>conjunction with AHP funds. These issues are discussed in greater</textblock>
    <textblock>detail below in the Analysis of Proposed Rule section.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Analysis of Proposed Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>A. AHP Application Approval Process</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule makes a fundamental change to the AHP by</textblock>
    <textblock>vesting the Banks, instead of the Board, with the authority to</textblock>
    <textblock>approve AHP applications. The current application approval</textblock>
    <textblock>process implemented by the Board's existing AHP regulation may be</textblock>
    <textblock>briefly described as follows. The Banks receive AHP applications</textblock>
    <textblock>and first evaluate them for satisfaction of certain threshold</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements contained in the existing regulation. See 12 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>960.5(a)(1), (2). Those applications meeting the threshold</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements are evaluated by the Banks to determine if they meet at least three of the priorities contained in the existing</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation. If they do, they are scored by the Banks on the</textblock>
    <textblock>priorities and on other scoring objectives contained in the</textblock>
    <textblock>existing regulation before applications that meet fewer than three</textblock>
    <textblock>priorities. See</textblock>
    <textblock>id.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.5(a)(3), (b) through (e). Under the</textblock>
    <textblock>existing regulation, the Bank then forwards to the Board the</textblock>
    <textblock>highest scoring applications, and submits a summary of such</textblock>
    <textblock>applications. See</textblock>
    <textblock>id.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.5(f)(1), (2). The Board reviews the</textblock>
    <textblock>applications to ensure consistency with the threshold, priorities</textblock>
    <textblock>and scoring requirements, and makes final funding decisions on the</textblock>
    <textblock>applications. See</textblock>
    <textblock>id.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.5(f)(3).</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
