<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00006</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to its authority under the Foreign-Trade Zones Act of June 18, 1934, as amended (19 U.S.C. 81a-81u), the Foreign-Trade Zones Board (the Board) adopts the following Order: Removal of Restriction, Maytag Corp., (Household Refrigerators), Subzone 133A, Galesburg, Illinois.</textblock>
    <textblock>Whereas, pursuant to ยง400.32(b)(1) of the Board's regulations, the Maytag Corporation, operator of FTZ Subzone 133A in Galesburg, Illinois (Maytag refrigerator manufacturing plant), has requested removal of Restriction</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>2 of Board Order 448 (filed 6-4-93 as A(32b1)-2-93; Doc. 61-93 was assigned 12-10-93);</textblock>
    <textblock>Whereas, Board Order 448 (54 FR 47246; 11-13-89) approving Subzone 133A included Restriction</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>2 requiring the election of privileged foreign status on foreign compressors (the restriction was temporarily suspended until 12-31-93, Board Order 485, 55 FR 37341, 9-11-90);</textblock>
    <textblock>Whereas, pursuant to ยง400.32(b)(1), the Commerce Department's Assistant Secretary for Import Administration has the authority to act for the Board in making decisions relating to changes in manufacturing/processing activity within existing zones in situations where the proposed activity is similar to that recently approved by the Board; and,</textblock>
    <textblock>Whereas, the FTZ Staff reviewed the proposal, pursuant to said provision and found that there is no longer a reason for the restriction, and the Executive Secretary concurs in the staff report recommending approval;</textblock>
    <textblock>Now, therefore, the Acting Assistant Secretary for Import Administration, acting for the Board pursuant to ยง400.32(b)(1), concurs in the recommendation and hereby approves the request subject to the Act and the Board's regulations, including ยง400.28.</textblock>
    <textblock>Signed at Washington, DC, this 23rd day of December 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Order No. 675]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Maytag Corp., Galesburg, Illinois; Application</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Barbara R. Stafford,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Import Administration, Chairman, Committee of Alternates, Foreign-Trade Zones Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>Attest:</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John J. Da Ponte, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Executive Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-510 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DS-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
