<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00059</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Board has determined that an estimate for reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>utility costs should be included in the determination of rents</textblock>
    <textblock>charged to households under this section, if they are not already</textblock>
    <textblock>included in the projected rents. Including utility costs would</textblock>
    <textblock>reduce the housing cost burden for very low-income households</textblock>
    <textblock>under the AHP, and would allow all rental projects to be treated</textblock>
    <textblock>equally, since some projects include the cost of utilities in the</textblock>
    <textblock>rent, while others do not include such costs in the rent.</textblock>
    <textblock>Including utility costs would be consistent with the treatment of</textblock>
    <textblock>rents in other federal housing programs, such as HUD's Section 8</textblock>
    <textblock>program and the LIHTC program. It also would be consistent with</textblock>
    <textblock>the treatment of rents under the AHP's 20 percent requirement,</textblock>
    <textblock>which is currently an interim rule of the Board, and which is</textblock>
    <textblock>incorporated in §960.9(c) of this proposed rule. (See discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>of 20 percent requirement below.)</textblock>
    <textblock>The definition of ``affordable for low- or moderate-income</textblock>
    <textblock>households'' in §960.1 of the proposed rule is similar to the</textblock>
    <textblock>above definition, except that the household must have an income of</textblock>
    <textblock>80 percent, instead of 50 percent, of the median income for the</textblock>
    <textblock>area, since the Act defines a ``low- or moderate-income household''</textblock>
    <textblock>as any household which has an income of 80 percent or less of the</textblock>
    <textblock>area median. 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(13)(A).</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Sale of AHP-assisted rental housing project.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.5(a)(3) of the proposed rule provides that an owner</textblock>
    <textblock>of an AHP-assisted rental housing project may sell the project</textblock>
    <textblock>prior to the end of the long-term period during which the</textblock>
    <textblock>project's rental units, or applicable portion thereof, must remain</textblock>
    <textblock>affordable for and occupied by households with incomes at or below</textblock>
    <textblock>the levels committed to in the AHP application; however, either:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. The purchaser must agree to continue the project's rental</textblock>
    <textblock>units, or applicable portion thereof, as affordable for and</textblock>
    <textblock>occupied by households with incomes at or below the levels</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application for the remainder of the</textblock>
    <textblock>long-term period committed to in the AHP application, and must</textblock>
    <textblock>agree to be subject to the same restrictions on resale that</textblock>
    <textblock>applied to the seller; or</textblock>
    <textblock>b. If the purchaser does not satisfy the requirements in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph a. above, and if the Bank provided a direct subsidy to</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicant which was passed on as a grant to the seller, the</textblock>
    <textblock>seller must repay a</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of the grant as provided in</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.16(d)(1); or</textblock>
    <textblock>c. If the purchaser does not satisfy the requirements in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph a. above, and if the Bank provided a subsidized advance</textblock>
    <textblock>to the applicant which in turn provided a below market rate loan</textblock>
    <textblock>to the seller, then the provisions of §960.16(d)(2) shall apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §960.5(b) further provides that the Bank's AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation plan shall permit the owner of an AHP-assisted</textblock>
    <textblock>rental housing project to sell such project as provided for in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (a)(3).</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Establishment of AHP Funding Cycles and Available AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>Subsidies</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.6(a)(1) of the proposed rule requires each Bank to</textblock>
    <textblock>establish at least two but no more than four AHP funding cycles</textblock>
    <textblock>per year during which applications for AHP subsidized advances or</textblock>
    <textblock>direct subsidies will be accepted. This is a change from the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board's existing AHP regulation, which provides that the Banks may</textblock>
    <textblock>accept AHP applications during two of four quarterly periods each</textblock>
    <textblock>year. See 12 CFR 960.4(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.6(a)(1) of the proposed rule also provides that the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP funding cycle schedule, including application due dates, is to</textblock>
    <textblock>be determined by the Bank in its discretion, but shall allow for</textblock>
    <textblock>sufficient time intervals to ensure an adequate pool of applicants</textblock>
    <textblock>to compete in each funding cycle. The funding cycles schedule,</textblock>
    <textblock>including application due dates, shall be described in detail in</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank's AHP implementation plan. This is also a change from</textblock>
    <textblock>the Board's existing AHP regulation, which sets forth specific</textblock>
    <textblock>application due dates. See 12 CFR 960.4(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.6(a)(2) of the proposed rule provides that each</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank shall inform the general public and its members of the number</textblock>
    <textblock>and dates of its AHP funding cycles for the year and the</textblock>
    <textblock>approximate amount of available AHP subsidies for each funding</textblock>
    <textblock>cycle at least 45 calendar days before the due date for AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>applications for the first funding cycle for the year. This is a</textblock>
    <textblock>change from the Board's existing AHP regulation, which requires</textblock>
    <textblock>each Bank to announce its funding cycles by December 1 of the</textblock>
    <textblock>preceding year, and to notify only its members of the approximate</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of AHP subsidies to be offered in each funding cycle. See</textblock>
    <textblock>12 CFR 960.4(a), (b).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
