<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00068</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00054</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[AK-930-4410-02-2410-P]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Availability of Proposed Resource Management Plan and Final Environmental Impact Statement; Fort Greely, Alaska</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management, DOI.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability of Fort Greely Proposed Resource Management Plan and Final Environmental Impact Statement.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the Military Lands Withdrawal Act of 1986 (Pub. L. 99-606), the Department of the Interior, Bureau of Land Management, Steese/White Mountains District has prepared a Proposed Resource Management Plan (PRMP)/Final Environmental Impact Statement (FEIS) for the Fort Greely military withdrawal, which is located near Delta Junction, Alaska, southeast of Fairbanks. The U.S. Army's 6th Infantry Division (Light) assisted in drafting the plan. The document addresses planning for nonmilitary use of the withdrawal. It addresses questions such as access, recreation, timber and fuel wood harvesting, and wildlife habitat and cultural resource protection. Although mining is discussed, none would be allowed in the immediate future because of potential conflicts with the military's mission.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Protests on the PRMP/FEIS must be postmarked by February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Protests on the PRMP/FEIS should be sent to: Bureau of Land Management, Division of Planning and Environmental Coordination (WO-760), 1849 C Street NW. (406 L St.), Washington, DC 20240.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Jim Ducker, Military Withdrawals Planning Team Leader, Bureau of Land Management, Alaska State Office, 222 W. 7th Avenue, Anchorage, Alaska 99513; phone (907) 271-3369.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The PRMP/FEIS is available by contacting Jim Ducker at the address or phone number listed above.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Proposed Plan refines the Preferred Alternative presented in the Draft Resource Management Plan/Draft Environmental Impact Statement (DRMP/DEIS). These refinements are the result of comments from the public and the availability of information developed since the distribution of the draft.</textblock>
    <textblock>The PRMP/FEIS describes the Proposed Plan and its impacts in full and presents summaries of five alternatives and their impacts. Complete descriptions of the alternatives and their impacts can be found in the DRMP/DEIS which are available at the main public libraries in Fairbanks, Delta Junction, and Anchorage, and at the Steese/White Mountains District Office in Fairbanks and the Alaska State Office in Anchorage.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 29, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Roger Bolstad,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>District Manager, Steese/White Mountains District.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-417 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-JA-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
