<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00049</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>While section 10(j) of the Act requires each Bank to establish</textblock>
    <textblock>an AHP, and vests in the Board broad authority to regulate the</textblock>
    <textblock>Banks' AHP activities through regulations implementing the Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>section 10(j) does not specifically assign the responsibility of</textblock>
    <textblock>operating the AHP to the Board. See 12 U.S.C. 1430(j). The Board</textblock>
    <textblock>does have other statutorily designated duties, including issuing</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations that specify activities eligible to receive subsidized</textblock>
    <textblock>advances under the AHP, ensuring advances are used to assist</textblock>
    <textblock>projects for which adequate long-term monitoring is available,</textblock>
    <textblock>ensuring that a preponderance of assistance provided under the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>is ultimately received by low- and moderate-income households, and</textblock>
    <textblock>ensuring that AHP subsidies provided by Banks to members are</textblock>
    <textblock>passed on to the ultimate borrower. See</textblock>
    <textblock>id.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1430(j)(9) (A), (C),</textblock>
    <textblock>(D), (E). However, section 10(j) does not specify what entity is</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible for administering the AHP, and what entity is</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible for determining which AHP applications are approved</textblock>
    <textblock>for funding.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the following reasons, the Board is proposing that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Banks assume the responsibility for determining which AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>applications are approved for funding. First, the Banks have had</textblock>
    <textblock>three and one-half years of experience with the AHP, which</textblock>
    <textblock>experience has included processing AHP applications, scoring the</textblock>
    <textblock>applications, and recommending applications for approval to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board as described above. Consequently, the Banks are already</textblock>
    <textblock>processing and reviewing applications under the existing system.</textblock>
    <textblock>Second, decentralization of the AHP is consistent with the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>System's Strategic Plan, which calls for decentralization of a</textblock>
    <textblock>number of functions currently conducted by the Board, with the</textblock>
    <textblock>exception of those Board activities involving oversight and</textblock>
    <textblock>supervision of the Banks. See ``System 2000: A Long-Term Strategic</textblock>
    <textblock>Plan For The Federal Home Loan Bank System.''</textblock>
    <textblock>The details of the proposed new application approval process</textblock>
    <textblock>are discussed further below.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board specifically requests comments as to whether the</textblock>
    <textblock>Banks should be given the authority to approve and disapprove AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>applications.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule also revises the Board's existing AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation by allowing each Bank to define more specifically its</textblock>
    <textblock>own priorities and scoring criteria, subject to certain overall</textblock>
    <textblock>priority and scoring parameters established in the proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bank would be required to include such proposed priorities and</textblock>
    <textblock>scoring criteria in its AHP implementation plan which must be</textblock>
    <textblock>approved by the Board. Under the Board's existing AHP regulation,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Banks have much less flexibility in defining priorities and</textblock>
    <textblock>scoring criteria. See 12 CFR 960.5 (a) through (e). In addition,</textblock>
    <textblock>under the proposed rule, certain point values for scoring</textblock>
    <textblock>categories would be revised.</textblock>
    <textblock>The details of the proposed revisions for adopting priorities</textblock>
    <textblock>and scoring criteria are discussed further below under the scoring</textblock>
    <textblock>of AHP applications section.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Bank Establishment of AHP and Adoption of AHP Implementation</textblock>
    <textblock>Plan</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.2(a) of the proposed rule generally reiterates the</textblock>
    <textblock>statement in ยง960.2(a) of the Board's existing AHP regulation</textblock>
    <textblock>that it is the policy of the Board and the Banks to promote decent</textblock>
    <textblock>and safe affordable housing and to address critical affordable</textblock>
    <textblock>housing needs through providing subsidized advances and direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidies to members pursuant to the AHP. See 12 CFR 960.2(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.2(b) of the proposed rule provides that each Bank's</textblock>
    <textblock>board of directors shall establish an AHP, which shall be funded</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to the requirements of ยง960.18 of the proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>(See discussion below under the required annual AHP contributions</textblock>
    <textblock>section.) The Bank is required to make subsidized advances to</textblock>
    <textblock>applicants pursuant to its AHP and to operate its AHP in</textblock>
    <textblock>conformity with an annual AHP implementation plan and the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of this part. Direct subsidies provided by a Bank to</textblock>
    <textblock>applicants pursuant to its AHP also shall be provided in</textblock>
    <textblock>conformity with the Bank's AHP implementation plan and the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of this part. Each Bank's AHP implementation plan</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be approved by the Board before it is effective.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.2(b) of the proposed rule further provides that the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP implementation plan must meet the requirements of this part,</textblock>
    <textblock>and shall include:</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
