<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00004</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>§58.2426</textblock>
    <textblock>Butter.</textblock>
    <textblock>The food product usually known as butter, and which is made</textblock>
    <textblock>exclusively from milk or cream, or both, with or without common</textblock>
    <textblock>salt, with or without additional coloring matter, and containing</textblock>
    <textblock>not less than 80 percent by weight of milkfat, all tolerances</textblock>
    <textblock>having been allowed for.</textblock>
    <textblock>§58.2427</textblock>
    <textblock>Cream.</textblock>
    <textblock>The term</textblock>
    <textblock>cream</textblock>
    <textblock>when used in this subpart G means cream</textblock>
    <textblock>separated from milk produced by healthy cows. The cream shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>pasteurized at a temperature of not less than 165</textblock>
    <textblock>○F and held</textblock>
    <textblock>continuously in a vat at such temperature for not less than 30</textblock>
    <textblock>minutes; or pasteurized at a temperature of not less than 185</textblock>
    <textblock>○F</textblock>
    <textblock>for not less than 15 seconds; or pasteurized by other approved</textblock>
    <textblock>methods giving equivalent results.</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Grades</textblock>
    <textblock>§58.2428</textblock>
    <textblock>Nomenclature of U.S. grades.</textblock>
    <textblock>The nomenclature of U.S. grades is as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) U.S. Grade AA.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) U.S. Grade A.</textblock>
    <textblock>§58.2429</textblock>
    <textblock>Basis for determination of U.S. grade.</textblock>
    <textblock>The U.S. grade of whipped butter is determined on the basis</textblock>
    <textblock>of classifying first the flavor characteristics and then the</textblock>
    <textblock>characteristics in body, color, and salt of a representative</textblock>
    <textblock>sample. Flavor is the basic quality factor in grading whipped</textblock>
    <textblock>butter and is determined organoleptically by smell and taste.</textblock>
    <textblock>The flavor characteristic and intensity is identified and rated</textblock>
    <textblock>according to the applicable classification contained in Table I</textblock>
    <textblock>in §58.2430. When more than one flavor characteristic is</textblock>
    <textblock>discernible in a sample of whipped butter, the flavor</textblock>
    <textblock>classification of the sample shall be established on the basis of</textblock>
    <textblock>the flavor that carries the lowest rating. Body, color, and salt</textblock>
    <textblock>characteristics are then noted and disratings are made in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with the established classification in Table II in</textblock>
    <textblock>§58.2430. The final U.S. grade for the sample is then</textblock>
    <textblock>established in accordance with the flavor classification, subject</textblock>
    <textblock>to permitted disratings for body, color, and salt as outlined in</textblock>
    <textblock>§58.2431.</textblock>
    <textblock>§58.2430</textblock>
    <textblock>Specifications for U.S. grades.</textblock>
    <textblock>The specifications for the U.S. grades of whipped butter are</textblock>
    <textblock>as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Grade AA.</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Grade AA whipped butter conforms to</textblock>
    <textblock>the following: Shall possess a fine and highly pleasing butter</textblock>
    <textblock>flavor. Whipped butter may also have a lactic culture flavor.</textblock>
    <textblock>May possess a slight feed, or a definite cooked flavor. The</textblock>
    <textblock>permitted disratings in body, color, and salt characteristics are</textblock>
    <textblock>limited to one-half (1/2). For detailed specifications and</textblock>
    <textblock>classification of flavor characteristics, see Table I of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section. For body, color, and salt disratings, see Table II of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Grade A.</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Grade A whipped butter conforms to</textblock>
    <textblock>the following: Shall possess a pleasing and desirable butter</textblock>
    <textblock>flavor. Whipped butter may also have a lactic culture flavor.</textblock>
    <textblock>May possess to a slight degree the following flavors: acid,</textblock>
    <textblock>aged, bitter, coarse, flat, smothered, and storage. May possess</textblock>
    <textblock>a definite feed flavor. The permitted disratings in body, color,</textblock>
    <textblock>and salt characteristics are limited to one-half (1/2). For</textblock>
    <textblock>detailed specifications and classification of flavor</textblock>
    <textblock>characteristics, see Table I of this section. For body, color,</textblock>
    <textblock>and salt disratings, see Table II of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>General.</textblock>
    <textblock>Whipped butter of all U.S. grades shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>free from foreign materials and visible mold. When total</textblock>
    <textblock>disratings exceed the permitted amount, the final U.S. grade</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be lowered one grade level for each additional one-half (1/2)</textblock>
    <textblock>disrating.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
