<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00098</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(b) A request for a modification of an approved AHP application</textblock>
    <textblock>must include, at a minimum:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A description of how the proposed modification differs from</textblock>
    <textblock>the original application;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The reason for the proposed modification; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Any other information that the Bank determines is</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to review the proposed modification.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)(1) The Bank shall review the request for modification,</textblock>
    <textblock>shall re-score the application as proposed to be modified</textblock>
    <textblock>according to the scoring criteria used in the AHP funding cycle in</textblock>
    <textblock>which the application was originally approved, and may approve</textblock>
    <textblock>such request if the following factors are satisfied:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The project as proposed to be modified continues to meet</textblock>
    <textblock>all of the requirements of this part; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The project as proposed to be modified continues to score</textblock>
    <textblock>high enough that it would have been approved in its AHP funding</textblock>
    <textblock>cycle.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If the application does not satisfy the requirements in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (c)(1) of this section, the Bank in its discretion may</textblock>
    <textblock>approve the request for modification if the reason for the</textblock>
    <textblock>modification is due to circumstances outside the control of the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant or sponsor.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) The Bank shall forward to the Board a detailed summary of</textblock>
    <textblock>any modification of an AHP application approved by the Bank,</textblock>
    <textblock>including how the Bank re-scored the project, within 30 calendar</textblock>
    <textblock>days of the approval of such modification.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart F_Use and Verification at Initial Disbursement of AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>Subsidized Advances or Direct Subsidies</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.12</textblock>
    <textblock>Use of AHP subsidized advances or direct subsidies</textblock>
    <textblock>within reasonable period of time and verification of reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>progress.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The Bank shall in its AHP implementation plan identify what</textblock>
    <textblock>constitutes reasonable progress by the sponsor towards using</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advances or direct subsidies within a reasonable period</textblock>
    <textblock>of time after the approval of an AHP application for different</textblock>
    <textblock>types of projects, and explain how it intends to verify such</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonable progress.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The sponsor must demonstrate that reasonable progress is</textblock>
    <textblock>being made towards using the requested funds within a reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>period of time after approval of the AHP application, as</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by the Bank under paragraph (a) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The Bank shall verify the efforts of the sponsor to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine whether it has satisfied the requirement in paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) If the sponsor fails to satisfy the requirement in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (b) of this section, the Bank shall cancel the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>award, and shall not disburse any subsidized advances or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidies through the applicant to the sponsor, and the full</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of any previously disbursed subsidized advances or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidies shall be returned to the Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.13</textblock>
    <textblock>Verification at initial disbursement of AHP subsidized</textblock>
    <textblock>advances or direct subsidies.</textblock>
    <textblock>At the time of initial disbursement of a subsidized advance or</textblock>
    <textblock>a direct subsidy by a Bank for an approved AHP application, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank shall verify in writing that the project complies with all</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable requirements contained in ยง960.9 and all obligations</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the approved AHP application. The Bank shall</textblock>
    <textblock>verify the amount of subsidy being provided in connection with the</textblock>
    <textblock>application and being charged against the AHP fund. The Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall include in its AHP implementation plan its verification</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures for such purposes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart G_Monitoring and Reporting Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.14</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring by the Banks.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each Bank has the responsibility</textblock>
    <textblock>to monitor the projects funded through its AHP according to the</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring requirements described in this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each Bank shall include in its AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation plan an explanation of how it intends to meet the</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring requirements of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring by Bank's designee.</textblock>
    <textblock>A Bank may contract with an</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant, a state housing finance agency, or other entity to</textblock>
    <textblock>perform the tasks required to meet the monitoring requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>described in paragraphs (e) through (h) of this section; however,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank remains ultimately responsible for compliance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring requirements of this section.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
