<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00102</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>ยง960.17</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP applications involving loan funds and loan</textblock>
    <textblock>consortia.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>General.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) An applicant may use a subsidized advance or</textblock>
    <textblock>a direct subsidy to make a loan or a grant to a loan fund or loan</textblock>
    <textblock>consortium as provided in paragraph (c) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) AHP applications involving the use of loans or grants by</textblock>
    <textblock>loan funds or loan consortia pursuant to the AHP are governed by</textblock>
    <textblock>the provisions of this part, except as otherwise provided in this</textblock>
    <textblock>section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP application approval requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>The requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>for approval of an AHP application that proposes to use subsidized</textblock>
    <textblock>advances or direct subsidies to make a loan or a grant to a loan</textblock>
    <textblock>fund or a loan consortium are governed by the provisions of</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.8, except that:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The application will be scored on the criteria that the</textblock>
    <textblock>loan fund or loan consortium proposes to use to select projects</textblock>
    <textblock>that will ultimately receive a loan or grant from the loan fund or</textblock>
    <textblock>loan consortium that is subsidized by the AHP; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The Bank shall review and shall require the applicant to</textblock>
    <textblock>review each new rental housing project funded by a loan fund or</textblock>
    <textblock>loan consortium prior to disbursing the loan or grant to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>that:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The project meets the threshold requirements of ยง960.9;</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The project meets the criteria committed to in the approved</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Use of funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Subsidized advances.</textblock>
    <textblock>If an applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>receives a subsidized advance and uses the proceeds of the advance</textblock>
    <textblock>to make a loan to a loan fund or loan consortium, the loan fund or</textblock>
    <textblock>loan consortium shall extend credit to the borrower at a rate of</textblock>
    <textblock>interest equal to the rate of interest charged on the subsidized</textblock>
    <textblock>advance plus a reasonable interest rate spread approved by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank. The applicant and the loan fund or loan consortium may</textblock>
    <textblock>determine between themselves what proportion of the interest rate</textblock>
    <textblock>spread the applicant and the loan fund or loan consortium will</textblock>
    <textblock>share.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Direct subsidies.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) If an applicant receives a direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy from a Bank and in turn provides a grant to a loan fund or</textblock>
    <textblock>loan consortium, the loan fund or loan consortium must either:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Pass the entire grant on to the recipient;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Use the entire grant to lower the interest rate on a loan</textblock>
    <textblock>to the borrower; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Lend the entire grant to the borrower to finance a rental</textblock>
    <textblock>housing project for a term of not less than 30 years, with all</textblock>
    <textblock>principal and interest payments deferred until the end of such</textblock>
    <textblock>term. If such loan is repaid before the end of the 30-year term,</textblock>
    <textblock>the entire amount of the grant must be repaid to the applicant,</textblock>
    <textblock>which in turn must forward the funds to the Bank to be used for</textblock>
    <textblock>additional AHP projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) If a loan fund or loan consortium provides both a loan and</textblock>
    <textblock>a grant to a borrower and the loan fund or loan consortium charges</textblock>
    <textblock>an origination fee for providing the loan, then any fee charged by</textblock>
    <textblock>the loan fund or loan consortium for providing the grant may not</textblock>
    <textblock>be paid with AHP subsidized advances or direct subsidies.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
