<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00055</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>10. Sections 472.30 and 472.31 are redesignated as §§472.32 and 472.33, respectively.</textblock>
    <textblock>11. A new §472.30 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§472.30</textblock>
    <textblock>What are the reporting requirements?</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A recipient of a grant or cooperative agreement under this program shall submit to the Secretary performance and financial reports.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) These reports must be submitted at times required by the Secretary and at least semi-annually.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) These reports must contain information required by the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1211(a))</textblock>
    <textblock>12. A new §472.31 and ``NOTE to §472.31'' are added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§472.31</textblock>
    <textblock>What are the evaluation requirements?</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Each recipient of a grant or cooperative agreement under this program shall provide and budget for an independent evaluation of project activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The evaluation must be both formative and summative in nature.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The evaluation must be based on student learning gains and the effects on job advancement, job performance (including, for example, such elements as productivity, safety, and attendance), and project and product spread and transportability.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) A proposed project evaluation design for the entire project period, expanding on the plans outlined in the application pursuant to §472.22(f), must be submitted to the Secretary for review and approval prior to the end of the first year of the project period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) A summary of evaluation activities and results that can be reviewed by the Department's Program Effectiveness Panel, as</textblock>
    <textblock>described in 34 CFR parts 785-789, must be submitted to the Secretary during the last year of the project period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) If a grantee cooperates in a Federal evaluation of its project, the Secretary may determine that the grantee fully or partially meets the evaluation requirements of this section and the reporting requirements in §472.30.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Approved by Office of Management and Budget under OMB control number 1830-0522)</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1211(a))</textblock>
    <textblock>Note to §472.31: As used in §472.31(c)_</textblock>
    <textblock>``</textblock>
    <textblock>Spread</textblock>
    <textblock>'' means the degree to which_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Project activities and results are demonstrated to others;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Technical assistance is provided to others to help them replicate project activities and results;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Project activities and results are replicated at other sites; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Information and material about or resulting from the project are disseminated; and</textblock>
    <textblock>``</textblock>
    <textblock>Transportability</textblock>
    <textblock>'' means the ease by which project activities and results may be replicated at other sites, such as through the development and use of guides or manuals that provide step-by-step directions for others to follow in order to initiate similar efforts and reproduce comparable results.</textblock>
    <textblock>13. Section 472.32, as redesignated, is amended by revising paragraphs (b), (d)(1), and (e) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§472.32</textblock>
    <textblock>What other requirements must be met under this</textblock>
    <textblock>program?</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)(1) The project period may include a start-up period, not to exceed six months, during which the project is being established and prior to the time services are provided to adult workers.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Applicants shall minimize the start-up period, if any, proposed for their projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) 100 percent of the administrative costs incurred in establishing a project during the start-up period described in paragraph (b) of this section by an SEA, LEA, or other entity described in §472.2(a), that receives a grant under this part; and</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Each recipient of an award under this program shall provide for a project director.</textblock>
    <textblock>14. A new §472.34 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§472.34</textblock>
    <textblock>Under what circumstances may a project continue if a</textblock>
    <textblock>partner withdraws?</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A project may continue despite the withdrawal of a partner that is unable to perform its role as outlined in the grant award document if all of the following conditions are met:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Written approval is given by the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The partnership continues to meet the requirements in §472.2(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The partnership will be able to complete the remainder of the project.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The partner's withdrawal will not cause a change in the scope or objectives of the grant or cooperative agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) In determining that the condition in paragraph (a)(4) of this section is satisfied, the Secretary considers such factors as whether_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A similar new partner will sign the partnership agreement and agree to carry out the role of the withdrawing partner as described in the grant agreement;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) One or more of the remaining partners will agree to carry out the role of the withdrawing partner as described in the grant agreement; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) One or more of the remaining partners will expand its activities as approved under the grant in order to compensate for the activities that would have been carried out under the grant agreement by the partner that is withdrawing without a change in the project's scope or objectives.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1211(a))</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-442 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4000-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
