<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00044</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00030</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 4, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 30, 1993, CNG Transmission Corporation (CNG) tendered for filing as part of its FERC Gas Tariff, Second Revised Volume No. 1, the tariff sheets listed on Appendix A to the filing, to become effective on February 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>CNG states the proposed rate changes would increase CNG's revenues by $106.6 million based on a test period cost of service for the twelve months ended September 30, 1993, as adjusted for known and measurable changes through June 30, 1994. CNG states that increased rates are necessary primarily to recover increased operation and maintenance expenses, increased costs of material and supplies, increased costs of transportation by others, increased depreciation expense, increased taxes, stranded costs, and increased plant investment. The filed rate of return is based on a capitalization of 65.73 percent common equity and 34.27 percent debt with an equity return of 14 percent.</textblock>
    <textblock>CNG's filing includes primary and alternate tariff sheets. CNG states that the primary tariff sheets reflect the end of CNG's gathering rate moratorium and the establishment of a two-part gathering rate. The alternate tariff sheets reflect continuation of the gathering rate moratorium that was approved for CNG in Docket No. RP88-211.</textblock>
    <textblock>CNG states that it has posted and served its filing in accordance with ยง154.16 of the regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rules 214 and 211 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (18 CFR 385.214 and 385.211). All motions or protests should be filed on or before January 11, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. RP94-96-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>CNG Transmission Corp.; Proposed Changes in FERC Gas Tariff</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-436 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
