<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00062</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00048</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The companies listed in this notice have applied for the Board's approval under section 3 of the Bank Holding Company Act (12 U.S.C. 1842) and  225.14 of the Board's Regulation Y (12 CFR 225.14) to become a bank holding company or to acquire a bank or bank holding company. The factors that are considered in acting on the applications are set forth in section 3(c) of the Act (12 U.S.C. 1842(c)).</textblock>
    <textblock>Each application is available for immediate inspection at the Federal Reserve Bank indicated. Once the application has been accepted for processing, it will also be available for inspection at the offices of the Board of Governors. Interested persons may express their views in writing to the Reserve Bank or to the offices of the Board of Governors. Any comment on an application that requests a hearing must include a statement of why a written presentation would not suffice in lieu of a hearing, identifying specifically any questions of fact that are in dispute and summarizing the evidence that would be presented at a hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Unless otherwise noted, comments regarding each of these applications must be received not later than January 31, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond</textblock>
    <textblock>(Lloyd W. Bostian, Jr., Senior Vice President) 701 East Byrd Street, Richmond, Virginia 23261:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Triangle Bancorp, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Raleigh, North Carolina; to acquire 100 percent of the voting shares of Roanoke Valley Savings Bank, Inc., SSB, formerly known as Roanoke Valley Savings Bank, SSB, Roanoke Rapids, North Carolina.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta</textblock>
    <textblock>(Zane R. Kelley, Vice President) 104 Marietta Street, N.W., Atlanta, Georgia 30303:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Bank Corporation of Georgia</textblock>
    <textblock>, Macon, Georgia; to acquire 49.7 percent of the voting shares of AmeriCorp, Inc., Savannah, Georgia, and thereby indirectly acquire Ameribank, N.A., Savannah, Georgia.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. 1st United Bancorp</textblock>
    <textblock>, Boca Raton, Florida; to acquire 99.72 percent of the voting shares of Suburban Bank, Lake Worth, Florida.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago</textblock>
    <textblock>(James A. Bluemle, Vice President) 230 South LaSalle Street, Chicago, Illinois 60690:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Community Grain Company</textblock>
    <textblock>, Coon Rapids, Iowa; to acquire 100 percent of the voting shares of Farmers National Bank, Bayard, Iowa.</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis</textblock>
    <textblock>(Randall C. Sumner, Vice President) 411 Locust Street, St. Louis, Missouri 63166:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. First Banks, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>, St. Louis, Missouri; to acquire 100 percent of the voting shares of Heritage National Bank, St. Louis, Missouri.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Independent Southern Bancshares, Inc. Employee Stock Ownership Plan and Trust</textblock>
    <textblock>, Brownsville, Tennessee; to become a bank holding company by acquiring at least 25 percent of the voting shares of Independent Southern Bancshares, Inc., Brownsville, Tennessee, and thereby indirectly acquire Brownsville Bank, Brownsville, Tennessee; Union Savings Bank, Covington, Tennessee; and Tennessee Bank and Trust, Millington, Tennessee.</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis</textblock>
    <textblock>(James M. Lyon, Vice President) 250 Marquette Avenue, Minneapolis, Minnesota 55480:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Avon State Bank Employee Stock Ownership Plan and Trust</textblock>
    <textblock>, Avon, Minnesota; to become a bank holding company by acquiring an additional 15.31 percent of the voting shares of Avon Bancshares, Inc., Avon, Minnesota, for a total of 30.58 percent, and thereby indirectly acquire Avon State Bank, Avon, Minnesota.</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas</textblock>
    <textblock>(Genie D. Short, Vice President) 2200 North Pearl Street, Dallas, Texas 75201-2272:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Bancrecer, S.A.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Mexico City, Mexico; to become a bank holding company by acquiring 100 percent of the voting shares of United Bank &amp; Trust, N.A., Dallas, Texas.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Extraco Bankshares, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Waco, Texas; to acquire 94.97 percent of the voting shares of Guaranty Bank and Trust Company, Gatesville, Texas.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Grupo Financiero Bancrecer, S.A., De C.V.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Mexico City, Mexico; to become a bank holding company by acquiring 100 percent of the voting shares of United Bank &amp; Trust, N.A., Dallas, Texas.</textblock>
    <textblock>G. Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco</textblock>
    <textblock>(Kenneth R. Binning, Director, Bank Holding Company) 101 Market Street, San Francisco, California 94105:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Grupo Financiero Bancomer, S.A.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Mexico, D.F., Mexico; to become a bank holding company by acquiring 100 percent of the voting shares of Bancomer, S.A., Mexico City, Mexico; Bancomer Holding Company (Antilles) N.V., Curacao, Netherlands Antilles; Bancomer Holding Company (Netherlands) B.V., Rotterdam, Netherlands; Bancomer Holding Company, Los Angeles, California; and Grossmont Bank, La Mesa, California.</textblock>
    <textblock>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, January 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Triangle Bancorp, Inc., et al.; Formations of; Acquisitions by; and Mergers of Bank Holding Companies</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jennifer J. Johnson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Secretary of the Board.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-469 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6210-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
