<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00092</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(d) The Bank's AHP implementation plan adopted pursuant to this</textblock>
    <textblock>section shall be made available by the Bank to the public upon</textblock>
    <textblock>request.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) The Board will approve or disapprove proposed amendments to</textblock>
    <textblock>a Bank's approved AHP implementation plan submitted by the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>within 60 calendar days of receipt.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart C_Authorized and Required Uses of AHP Subsidized Advances</textblock>
    <textblock>or Direct Subsidies</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.3</textblock>
    <textblock>Authorized uses of AHP subsidized advances or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidies.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>General.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicants may use subsidized advances or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidies received from a Bank pursuant to this part only for the</textblock>
    <textblock>uses set forth in paragraphs (b) and (c) of this section and</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to the long-term requirements set forth in ยง960.5.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Owner-occupied housing units.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicants may use</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advances or direct subsidies received from a Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to this part to finance the purchase, construction or</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitation of owner-occupied housing units by or for low- or</textblock>
    <textblock>moderate-income households.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rental housing units.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicants may use subsidized</textblock>
    <textblock>advances or direct subsidies received from a Bank pursuant to this</textblock>
    <textblock>part to finance the purchase, construction or rehabilitation of</textblock>
    <textblock>rental housing units, at least 20 percent of the units of which</textblock>
    <textblock>will be occupied by and affordable for very low-income households.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.4</textblock>
    <textblock>Specific use requirements for AHP subsidized advances or</textblock>
    <textblock>direct subsidies.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Examples of specific authorized and unauthorized uses.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Authorized uses of subsidized advances or direct subsidies</textblock>
    <textblock>include, but are not limited to, the following costs related to</textblock>
    <textblock>the purchase, construction or rehabilitation of housing:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Real property purchase and improvement costs;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Construction or rehabilitation costs, including labor and</textblock>
    <textblock>materials, and contractor profit and overhead allowances;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Costs integral to the purchase or development of housing</textblock>
    <textblock>including, but not limited to, project-related: Architectural,</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection and engineering fees; local building permit and</textblock>
    <textblock>planning fees; accounting costs; survey costs; appraisal fees;</textblock>
    <textblock>title insurance and other insurance costs; performance bond and</textblock>
    <textblock>other bond fees; recording fees; credit report fees; property</textblock>
    <textblock>taxes; residential relocation costs where such costs are part of a</textblock>
    <textblock>relocation plan; legal fees; syndication fees; costs of</textblock>
    <textblock>translating resident documents to another language; loan</textblock>
    <textblock>commitment, loan origination and other loan financing fees for</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative costs other than costs of administering the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>award; developer's fees; and marketing costs;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Prepayment fees imposed by the Bank on an applicant for a</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advance that is prepaid in connection with the</textblock>
    <textblock>purchase, construction or rehabilitation of housing, if the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant requires the borrower to pay such fee;</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) Capitalization of reserve fund(s) necessary for the</textblock>
    <textblock>successful operation of rental housing projects, including</textblock>
    <textblock>replacement reserves, rent-up reserves, operating deficit</textblock>
    <textblock>reserves, and sinking fund reserves used for the transfer of the</textblock>
    <textblock>project to nonprofit ownership when associated with a low income</textblock>
    <textblock>housing tax credit transaction (26 U.S.C. 42);</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) Cancellation fees imposed by the Bank on an applicant for</textblock>
    <textblock>a subsidized advance commitment that is canceled and converted to</textblock>
    <textblock>and disbursed as a direct subsidy in connection with the purchase,</textblock>
    <textblock>construction or rehabilitation of housing, if the applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>requires the borrower to pay such fee;</textblock>
    <textblock>(vii) Refinancing of an existing loan in conjunction with the</textblock>
    <textblock>purchase, construction or rehabilitation of housing, provided the</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advance or direct subsidy and the proceeds of the</textblock>
    <textblock>refinancing are used only to retire existing debt and to benefit</textblock>
    <textblock>low- or moderate-income households and, in the case of refinancing</textblock>
    <textblock>in order to rehabilitate a project, there is a minimum of $2,500</textblock>
    <textblock>per unit spent on such rehabilitation; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(viii) Tenant services, tenant counseling and homeowner</textblock>
    <textblock>counseling costs that are a condition imposed by a lender to</textblock>
    <textblock>obtain financing from such lender and which are necessary for the</textblock>
    <textblock>successful operation of the project.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Uses of subsidized advances or direct subsidies that are</textblock>
    <textblock>not authorized include, but are not limited to, AHP administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>costs of the applicant or the Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Use of funds requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)(i) The total amount of a</textblock>
    <textblock>direct subsidy provided by the Bank to an applicant under this</textblock>
    <textblock>section must be passed on by the applicant to the recipient.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) An applicant receiving a subsidized advance from a Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall extend credit to the borrower at a rate of interest equal to</textblock>
    <textblock>the rate of interest charged on the subsidized advance plus an</textblock>
    <textblock>interest rate spread approved by the Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If an applicant receives a subsidized advance or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy from a Bank or prepayment of a loan originally made under</textblock>
    <textblock>the AHP, any interest or other income earned by the applicant on</textblock>
    <textblock>such funds, not including any approved fee or interest rate spread</textblock>
    <textblock>charged to the borrower, must be forwarded to the Bank to be used</textblock>
    <textblock>for additional AHP projects, except for interest or other income</textblock>
    <textblock>earned by the applicant within 30 calendar days of receiving the</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advance or direct subsidy or of receiving prepayment of</textblock>
    <textblock>a loan originally made under the AHP.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) A direct subsidy received by an applicant from a Bank that</textblock>
    <textblock>is provided by such applicant to a sponsor may be lent by the</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor in connection with an AHP rental housing project involving</textblock>
    <textblock>low-income housing tax credits, provided the subsidy is lent by</textblock>
    <textblock>the sponsor for a term of not less than 30 years, with all</textblock>
    <textblock>principal and interest payments deferred until the end of such</textblock>
    <textblock>term. If such a loan is repaid before the end of the 30-year</textblock>
    <textblock>term, the entire amount of the direct subsidy must be repaid to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) If an applicant receives a subsidized advance or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy from a Bank, and in turn provides both a loan and a grant</textblock>
    <textblock>to a borrower and charges an origination fee for providing the</textblock>
    <textblock>loan, then any fee charged by the applicant for providing the</textblock>
    <textblock>grant may not be paid with the AHP subsidized advance or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
