<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00056</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In addition, as set forth in the Board's proposed amendment,</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.1 of this proposed rule defines ``very low-income household''</textblock>
    <textblock>as a household which has an income of 50 percent or less of the</textblock>
    <textblock>median income for the area, as adjusted and published by HUD,</textblock>
    <textblock>except in areas where the Secretary adjusts this figure downward</textblock>
    <textblock>because of prevailing construction costs, low housing costs, or</textblock>
    <textblock>unusually high household incomes. For areas where the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>makes this downward adjustment, ``very low-income household'' would</textblock>
    <textblock>be defined to mean a household which has an income of 50 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>or less of the median income for the area, as published by HUD,</textblock>
    <textblock>with adjustment for household size, but without the adjustments</textblock>
    <textblock>made by the Secretary for prevailing construction costs, low</textblock>
    <textblock>housing costs, or unusually high household incomes.</textblock>
    <textblock>While HUD publishes tables with adjusted income information</textblock>
    <textblock>that incorporates the adjustments for family size, prevailing</textblock>
    <textblock>construction costs, low housing costs, and unusually high family</textblock>
    <textblock>incomes, it does not publish tables with income information that</textblock>
    <textblock>adjusts only for family size and not these other factors.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, as set forth in the Board's proposed amendment, §960.1</textblock>
    <textblock>of this proposed rule adds a definition of ``adjustment for</textblock>
    <textblock>household size'' in order to provide additional guidance in</textblock>
    <textblock>calculating this adjustment.</textblock>
    <textblock>An adjustment for household size is made by taking a specified</textblock>
    <textblock>percentage of the income limit of a four-person household for a</textblock>
    <textblock>particular area, according to the following scale:</textblock>
    <textblock>For each person in excess of eight, eight percent of the four-person household base income limit should be added to the</textblock>
    <textblock>income limit for an eight-person household for the area. These</textblock>
    <textblock>adjustment factors are the same as those used by HUD in</textblock>
    <textblock>administering its housing programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.1 of the proposed rule retains the definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>``area'' from the Board's existing AHP regulation. See 12 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>960.1(c). ``Area'' means, for purposes of defining ``median income</textblock>
    <textblock>for the area,'' a metropolitan statistical area, a county, or a</textblock>
    <textblock>nonmetropolitan area, as established by the U.S. Office of</textblock>
    <textblock>Management and Budget. Consistent with the proposed amendment,</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.1 of this proposed rule does not include a definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>``median income'' because it is included in the proposed definitions</textblock>
    <textblock>of ``very low-income household'' and ``low- or moderate-income</textblock>
    <textblock>household.''</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Definition of ``income''. The Act is silent on how to define the term ``income,''</textblock>
    <textblock>i.e.,</textblock>
    <textblock>what are eligible sources of household income that should be</textblock>
    <textblock>considered in determining whether the household satisfies the</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of ``low- or moderate-income household'' or ``very</textblock>
    <textblock>low-income household.'' The Board has determined not to define the</textblock>
    <textblock>term ``income'' in the proposed rule. Homeownership projects</textblock>
    <textblock>typically involve the participation of a lender which provides</textblock>
    <textblock>permanent financing for the homeowner over an extended period of</textblock>
    <textblock>time. The lender generally verifies a household's income prior to</textblock>
    <textblock>issuing a financing commitment during the underwriting of the</textblock>
    <textblock>loan. Eligible sources of income are identified by the lender</textblock>
    <textblock>during the mortgage underwriting process. Identifying eligible</textblock>
    <textblock>sources of income in the rule could cause inconsistency with</textblock>
    <textblock>lenders' customary and usual underwriting practices, or with the</textblock>
    <textblock>standards applied by the entity providing the major source of</textblock>
    <textblock>financing for the project.</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rental housing units.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.5(a)(1) of the proposed rule provides generally that at least 20 percent of the rental housing units in a project financed under the AHP with subsidized advances or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidies shall remain affordable for and occupied by very</textblock>
    <textblock>low-income households for a minimum period of 30 years or, at the</textblock>
    <textblock>election of the sponsor, the remaining useful life of such units.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1No. persons</textblock>
    <textblock>1Percent adjustment</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>70. 2</textblock>
    <textblock>80. 3</textblock>
    <textblock>90. 4</textblock>
    <textblock>Base. 5</textblock>
    <textblock>108. 6</textblock>
    <textblock>116. 7</textblock>
    <textblock>124. 8</textblock>
    <textblock>132.</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
