<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00052</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Cancellation fees identified in paragraph (vi) above, where</textblock>
    <textblock>there is purchase, construction or rehabilitation of housing and</textblock>
    <textblock>the borrower is required to pay the fee, are a cost of financing</textblock>
    <textblock>such purchase, construction or rehabilitation and therefore are</textblock>
    <textblock>authorized uses of funds under the AHP. Because the advance would</textblock>
    <textblock>be converted to a direct subsidy, such cancellation fees would be</textblock>
    <textblock>payable only if the application also meets the requirements for</textblock>
    <textblock>modification of applications contained in ยง960.11 of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule. (These requirements are discussed in greater detail in the</textblock>
    <textblock>modification section below.) However, AHP subsidized advances or</textblock>
    <textblock>direct subsidies may not be used to pay for cancellation fees in</textblock>
    <textblock>situations where the cancellation of the advance is not part of a</textblock>
    <textblock>restructuring that results in the purchase, construction or</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitation of housing.</textblock>
    <textblock>The conditions identified in paragraph (vii) above on the use</textblock>
    <textblock>of funds under the AHP for refinancing are intended to ensure that</textblock>
    <textblock>the funds are not used by the borrower to take out its equity in</textblock>
    <textblock>the project and to ensure that the funds are used for authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes under the AHP. The Board specifically requests comments</textblock>
    <textblock>on whether the $2,500 minimum per unit is a reasonable minimum</textblock>
    <textblock>amount to be required to be spent on rehabilitation in conjunction</textblock>
    <textblock>with a refinancing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Questions have arisen as to whether funds under the AHP should</textblock>
    <textblock>be used to pay for pre-development costs that may or may not</textblock>
    <textblock>result in the purchase, construction or rehabilitation of AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>housing. Pre-development costs are costs incurred prior to the</textblock>
    <textblock>closing of a purchase, construction or rehabilitation loan for the</textblock>
    <textblock>purpose of determining the feasibility of a proposed project.</textblock>
    <textblock>Examples of pre-development costs include architectural and</textblock>
    <textblock>engineering fees, legal fees, the costs of surveys and appraisals,</textblock>
    <textblock>local building permit and planning fees, and earnest money</textblock>
    <textblock>deposits. Since AHP applications are required to meet the</textblock>
    <textblock>threshold feasibility requirement provided in proposed ยง960.9(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>in order to be scored, authorizing the use of funds for</textblock>
    <textblock>pre-development costs raises the question how applications for</textblock>
    <textblock>such costs can or should be scored since the funds would be</textblock>
    <textblock>disbursed to applicants before the feasibility of a proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>project could be established.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, there is a greater likelihood that costs incurred</textblock>
    <textblock>during the pre-feasibility period, rather than during the</textblock>
    <textblock>post-feasibility period, will not result in the purchase,</textblock>
    <textblock>construction or rehabilitation of housing. Thus, if applications</textblock>
    <textblock>for AHP funds to finance pre-development costs are approved, AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>funds in perhaps significant amounts could go towards</textblock>
    <textblock>pre-development costs that do not result in the financing or</textblock>
    <textblock>production of housing. If such costs are authorized, one option</textblock>
    <textblock>for dealing with this concern could be to cap the total amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP funds that may be used for pre-development costs at a specific</textblock>
    <textblock>dollar amount or percentage, such as the lesser of $200,000 or 5</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of the Bank's total AHP contributions for the year. These</textblock>
    <textblock>funds could be set aside and disbursed in a separate competitive</textblock>
    <textblock>process.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board specifically requests comments on whether funds under</textblock>
    <textblock>the AHP should be used for pre-development costs, how applications</textblock>
    <textblock>for such costs can or should be scored, and what limits, if any,</textblock>
    <textblock>should be placed on the amount of funds used for such purposes</textblock>
    <textblock>under the AHP.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Use of Funds Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.4(b)(1)(i) of the proposed rule provides that the</textblock>
    <textblock>total amount of a direct subsidy provided by the Bank to an</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant under the AHP must be passed on by the applicant to the</textblock>
    <textblock>recipient. Consistent with ยง960.9(c) of the Board's existing AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation, ยง960.4(b)(1)(ii) of the proposed rule provides that</textblock>
    <textblock>an applicant receiving a subsidized advance shall extend credit to</textblock>
    <textblock>the borrower at a rate of interest equal to the rate of interest</textblock>
    <textblock>charged on the subsidized advance plus an interest rate spread</textblock>
    <textblock>approved by the Bank. See 12 CFR 960.9(c). These provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>implement section 10(j)(9)(E) of the Act, which provides that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board's AHP regulation shall ensure that AHP subsidies provided by</textblock>
    <textblock>Banks to applicants are passed on to the ultimate borrower. See</textblock>
    <textblock>12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(9)(E).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.4(b)(2) of the proposed rule provides that if an</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant receives a subsidized advance or direct subsidy from a</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank or prepayment of a loan originally made under the AHP, any</textblock>
    <textblock>interest or other income earned by the applicant on such funds,</textblock>
    <textblock>not including any approved fee or interest rate spread charged to</textblock>
    <textblock>the borrower, must be forwarded to the Bank to be used for</textblock>
    <textblock>additional AHP projects, except for interest or other income</textblock>
    <textblock>earned by the applicant within 30 calendar days of receiving the</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advance or direct subsidy or of receiving prepayment of</textblock>
    <textblock>a loan originally made under the AHP.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.4(b)(3) of the proposed rule provides that a direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy received by an applicant from a Bank that is provided by</textblock>
    <textblock>such applicant to a sponsor may be lent by the sponsor in</textblock>
    <textblock>connection with an AHP rental housing project involving low-income</textblock>
    <textblock>housing tax credits (LIHTC), provided the subsidy is lent by the</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor for a term of not less than 30 years, with all principal</textblock>
    <textblock>and interest payments deferred until the end of such term. If</textblock>
    <textblock>such a loan is repaid before the end of the 30-year term, the</textblock>
    <textblock>entire amount of the direct subsidy must be repaid to the Bank.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
