<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00081</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 960.19(a)(1) of the proposed rule provides that if a</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank finds that the contributions required pursuant to proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.18 are contributing to the financial instability of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank, the Bank shall notify the Board promptly, and may apply in</textblock>
    <textblock>writing to the Board for a temporary suspension of such</textblock>
    <textblock>contributions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.19(a)(2) of the proposed rule provides that a</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank's application for a temporary suspension of contributions</textblock>
    <textblock>shall:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) State the period of time for which the Bank seeks a</textblock>
    <textblock>suspension;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) State the grounds for a suspension;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Include a plan for returning the Bank to a financially</textblock>
    <textblock>stable position; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Be accompanied by the Bank's preceding year's annual</textblock>
    <textblock>financial report, if available, and the Bank's most recent</textblock>
    <textblock>quarterly and monthly financial statements and any other financial</textblock>
    <textblock>data the Bank wishes the Board to consider.</textblock>
    <textblock>The requirement in paragraph (ii) above is not explicitly</textblock>
    <textblock>required in the Board's existing AHP regulation. See 12 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>960.11(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>Paragraph (iv) above adds to the Board's existing regulation</textblock>
    <textblock>that the Bank may include any other financial data it wishes the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board to consider.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Board Review of Application for Temporary Suspension</textblock>
    <textblock>a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Grounds for approval of application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.19(b)(1) of the proposed rule provides that, in</textblock>
    <textblock>reviewing a Bank's application for a temporary suspension of</textblock>
    <textblock>contributions to determine the Bank's financial instability, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board shall consider the following factors:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Whether the Bank's earnings are severely depressed. This</textblock>
    <textblock>language was added to track the statutory standard in section</textblock>
    <textblock>10(j)(6) of the Act. See 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(6). In addition, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board shall consider the extent to which the Bank's quarterly or</textblock>
    <textblock>annual net earnings have decreased from the preceding quarter or</textblock>
    <textblock>year, and whether such decline is projected to continue;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Whether there has been a substantial decline in the Bank's</textblock>
    <textblock>membership capital. The Board shall consider the extent to which</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank's paid-in membership capital has declined in any given</textblock>
    <textblock>quarter or year, and whether such decline is projected to</textblock>
    <textblock>continue;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
