<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00005</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to its authority under the Foreign-Trade Zones Act of June 18, 1934, as amended (19 U.S.C. 81a-81u), the Foreign-Trade Zones Board (the Board) adopts the following Order: Expansion of Foreign-Trade Zone 79, Tampa, Florida.</textblock>
    <textblock>Whereas, an application from the City of Tampa, Florida, grantee of Foreign-Trade Zone No. 79, for authority to expand its general-purpose zone in Tampa, Florida, within the Tampa Customs port of entry, was filed by the Foreign-Trade Zones (FTZ) Board on April 20, 1992, (Docket 12-92, 57 FR 19596, 5/7/92) (Amendments: 58 FR 31362, 6/2/93; 58 FR 36932, 7/9/93);</textblock>
    <textblock>Whereas, notice inviting public comment was given in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>and the application has been processed pursuant to the FTZ Act and the Board's regulations; and,</textblock>
    <textblock>Whereas, the Board has found that the requirements of the Act and the regulations are satisfied, and that approval is in the public interest;</textblock>
    <textblock>Now, therefore, the Board hereby orders:</textblock>
    <textblock>The grantee is authorized to expand its zone as requested in the application, as amended, subject to the Act and the Board's regulations, including ยง400.28.</textblock>
    <textblock>Signed at Washington, DC, this 29th day of December 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Foreign-Trade Zones Board</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Order No. 676]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Tampa, Florida; Expansion of Foreign-Trade Zone 79</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Barbara R. Stafford,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Import Administration, Chairman, Committee of Alternates, Foreign-Trade Zones Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>Attest:</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John J. Da Ponte, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Executive Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-512 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DS-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
