<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00095</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(2) The board of directors of each Bank shall have the</textblock>
    <textblock>authority to approve or disapprove AHP applications received, and</textblock>
    <textblock>may delegate such authority to the president or other senior</textblock>
    <textblock>officers of the Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Within 30 calendar days of each Bank's approval of the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>applications for a given AHP funding cycle, the Bank shall forward</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Board a summary of each approved AHP application. The</textblock>
    <textblock>summary shall:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Briefly describe the project, including the applicant, the</textblock>
    <textblock>loan fund or loan consortium, if applicable, and the sponsor_</textblock>
    <textblock>whether nonprofit, for-profit or public agency, the type of</textblock>
    <textblock>housing, the location, the long-term period committed to, the</textblock>
    <textblock>number of housing units including the number of units affordable</textblock>
    <textblock>for very low-, low- or moderate-income households or for</textblock>
    <textblock>households at any other income levels committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application, the development cost, other financing sources, and</textblock>
    <textblock>special needs populations served;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) State the reason for the points awarded under each of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank's scoring criteria for the project;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Indicate whether a subsidized advance or direct subsidy</textblock>
    <textblock>was approved by the Bank for the project, the use of such funds,</textblock>
    <textblock>and the amount of such funds approved; if a subsidized advance was</textblock>
    <textblock>approved, the summary shall indicate the amount of the advance,</textblock>
    <textblock>the advance rate, the amortization schedule for the advance, the</textblock>
    <textblock>term to maturity, the applicable cost of funds, and the date as of</textblock>
    <textblock>which the cost of funds was determined;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Indicate whether the project received approval in a prior</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP funding cycle, or if the project is an extension, expansion,</textblock>
    <textblock>continuation or reconfiguration of a previously approved AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>project;</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) Describe how the project will be monitored and by what</textblock>
    <textblock>entity;</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) Describe the legal mechanisms to be used to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance by the project with the long-term requirement contained</textblock>
    <textblock>in §960.5;</textblock>
    <textblock>(vii) Include a summary in chart form showing all AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>applications received by the Bank in the particular AHP funding</textblock>
    <textblock>cycle, with the score each application received for each scoring</textblock>
    <textblock>criterion, and the total score received by each project; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(viii) Include any other information required by the Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart E_Requirements for Approval of AHP Applications</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.8</textblock>
    <textblock>General requirements for approval of AHP applications.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Each Bank shall evaluate the AHP applications received to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine if they satisfy the threshold criteria in §960.9. All</textblock>
    <textblock>applications that meet the threshold criteria shall be scored</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to the criteria contained in §960.10, as set forth in</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank's approved AHP implementation plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The Bank shall approve the applications in descending order</textblock>
    <textblock>starting with the highest scoring application until the total AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>funding amount for the particular funding cycle, except for any</textblock>
    <textblock>amount insufficient to fund the next highest scoring project, has</textblock>
    <textblock>been allocated. The Bank also may approve the next four highest</textblock>
    <textblock>scoring applications as alternates and, within one year of</textblock>
    <textblock>approval by the Bank, may fund such alternates if any previously</textblock>
    <textblock>committed AHP funds become available.</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.9</textblock>
    <textblock>Threshold criteria for approval of AHP applications.</textblock>
    <textblock>Threshold criteria.</textblock>
    <textblock>An AHP application must meet all of the</textblock>
    <textblock>threshold criteria set forth in this section in order to be</textblock>
    <textblock>considered for scoring under §960.10 and for AHP funding</textblock>
    <textblock>approval.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Authorized and required uses requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>The AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application must indicate that the use of the subsidized advance</textblock>
    <textblock>or direct subsidy set forth in the AHP application for the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed project will comply with the requirements for authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>and required uses of such funds contained in §§960.3, 960.4 and</textblock>
    <textblock>960.5.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Fair housing law requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>The AHP application must</textblock>
    <textblock>indicate that the project sponsor will comply with any applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>fair housing law requirements and must indicate how the sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes to affirmatively further compliance with such</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Twenty percent requirement and alternatives.</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>General.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Except as provided in paragraph (c)(2) of this section, a Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall not offer subsidized advances or direct subsidies to</textblock>
    <textblock>applicants in excess of that amount needed to reduce the monthly</textblock>
    <textblock>housing costs (as defined in paragraph (c)(1)(ii) of this section)</textblock>
    <textblock>for income-eligible households, as committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application, to 20 percent of the household's gross monthly</textblock>
    <textblock>income. In projects where other forms of federal, state, local or</textblock>
    <textblock>private subsidized assistance are being used in conjunction with</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP subsidized advances or direct subsidies, the total amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized assistance, including funds provided under the AHP,</textblock>
    <textblock>shall not be in excess of the amount needed to reduce the monthly</textblock>
    <textblock>housing costs (as defined in paragraph (c)(1)(ii) of this section)</textblock>
    <textblock>for the income-eligible households, as committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application, to 20 percent of the household's gross monthly</textblock>
    <textblock>income.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) For purposes of paragraph (c)(1) of this section, monthly</textblock>
    <textblock>housing costs are defined as:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) For households in AHP-assisted owner-occupied housing</textblock>
    <textblock>units, mortgage principal and interest payments, real property</textblock>
    <textblock>taxes, homeowners' insurance, a reasonable estimate of utility</textblock>
    <textblock>costs excluding telephone service, and for households in</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP-assisted condominium, cooperative, mutual housing or other</textblock>
    <textblock>housing projects involving common ownership, those portions of any</textblock>
    <textblock>regular operating assessment or fee allocated for principal and</textblock>
    <textblock>interest payments, taxes, insurance and a reasonable estimate of</textblock>
    <textblock>utilities attributable to the household's share of the common area</textblock>
    <textblock>and/or the individual unit; and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
