<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00108</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Small Business Size Standards; Waiver of the Nonmanufacturer Rule</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>SMALL BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>13 CFR Part 121</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Small Business Administration.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of intent to terminate waivers of the Nonmanufacturer Rule for several classes of metal products.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Small Business Administration (SBA) intends to terminate existing waivers of the Nonmanufacturer Rule for: (1) Bars and rods, high nickel alloy; (2) plate sheet, strip and foil, stainless steel and high nickel alloy; (3) wire, nonelectrical, high nickel alloy; (4) bars and rods, high nickel alloy, aluminum, nickel-copper, nickel-copper-aluminum, copper, copper-nickel, aluminum-bronze, and naval brass; (5) plate, sheet and strip, nickel-copper, nickel-copper-aluminum, copper-nickel, and copper; (6) sheet and plate aluminum products; and (7) structural shapes, angles, channels, tees and zees, aluminum and high nickel alloy. SBA's intent to terminate these waivers of the Nonmanufacturer Rule is based on our recent discovery of small business manufacturers for these classes of products. Terminating these waivers will require recipients of contracts set aside for small or 8(a) businesses to provide the products of small business manufacturers or processors on such contracts.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before February 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments should be addressed to Mr. Robert J. Moffitt, Associate Administrator for Procurement Assistance, U.S. Small Business Administration, Mail Code 6250, 409 3rd Street SW., Washington, DC 20416.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>James Parker, Procurement Analyst, phone (703) 695-2435.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Law 100-656, enacted on November 15, 1988, incorporated into the Small Business Act the previously existing regulation that recipients of Federal contracts set aside for small businesses or SBA 8(a) Program procurements must provide the products of small business manufacturers or processors. The SBA regulations imposing this requirement are found at 13 CFR 121.906(b) and 121.1106(b). Section 210 of Public Law 101-574 further amended the law to allow for waivers for classes of products for which there are no small business manufacturers or processors ``available to participate in the Federal procurement market.'' The actions which the SBA is proposing to take with respect to existing waivers and the reasons for those actions follow:</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
