<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00046</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(1) Offerors may not supply a nondesignated country end product unless it is a qualifying country end product, NAFTA country end product, or Caribbean Basin country end product, or a national interest waiver has been granted under section 302 of the Trade Agreements Act of 1979 (see FAR 25.402(c)).</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) An offer certifying that a qualifying country end product, a designated country end product, a NAFTA country end product, or a Caribbean Basin country end product will be supplied, requires the Contractor to supply a qualifying country end product, a designated country end product, a NAFTA country end product, or a Caribbean Basin country end product, whichever is certified, or, at the Contractor's option, a U.S. made end product.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) The offered price of end products listed and certified under paragraphs (c)(2)(i) and (vi) of the Buy American Act_Trade Agreements_Balance of Payments Program Certificate provision of the solicitation must include all applicable duty. The offered price of qualifying country end products, designated country end products, NAFTA country end products, and Caribbean Basin country end products for line items subject to the Trade Agreements Act or the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act, should not include customer fees or duty. (End of clause)</textblock>
    <textblock>16. Section 252.225-7010 is amended by revising the introductory text to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>252.225-7010</textblock>
    <textblock>Duty Free Entry_Additional Provisions.</textblock>
    <textblock>As prescribed in 225.605-70(d), use the following clause:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>17. A new section 252.225-7035 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>252.225-7035</textblock>
    <textblock>Buy American Act_North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act_Balance of Payments Program Certificate.</textblock>
    <textblock>As prescribed in 225.408(a)(3), use the following provision:</textblock>
    <textblock>Buy American Act_North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act_Balance of Payments Program Certificate (Jan. 1994)</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Domestic end product, qualifying country end product,</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. made end product</textblock>
    <textblock>have the meanings given in the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act or Buy American Act and Balance of Payments Program clauses of this solicitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Evaluation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Offers will be evaluated by giving preference to U.S. made end products, qualifying country end products, or NAFTA country end products over other end products.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Certifications.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The Offeror certifies that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Each end product, except the end products listed in paragraph (c)(2) of this provision, is a domestic end product (as defined in the Buy American Act and Balance of Payments Program clause of this solicitation); and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Components of unknown origin are considered to have been mined, produced, or manufactured outside the United States or a qualifying country.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The Offeror must identify and certify all end products that are not domestic end products.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The Offeror certifies that the following supplies qualify as ``U.S. made end products'' but do not meet the definition of ``domestic end product'':</textblock>
    <textblock>(insert line item number).</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The Offeror certifies that the following supplies are qualifying country end products:</textblock>
    <textblock>(insert line item number) (insert country of origin).</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The Offeror certifies that the following supplies qualify as NAFTA country end products:</textblock>
    <textblock>(insert line item number (insert country of origin).</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The Offeror certifies that the following supplies are other non-NAFTA country end products:</textblock>
    <textblock>(insert line item number) (insert country of origin).</textblock>
    <textblock>(End of provision)</textblock>
    <textblock>18. A new section 252.225-7036 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>252.225-7036</textblock>
    <textblock>North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>As prescribed in 225.408(a)(4), use the following clause:</textblock>
    <textblock>North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act (Jan. 1994)</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Components, domestic end product, end product, nonqualifying country, qualifying country,</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>qualifying country end product</textblock>
    <textblock>have the meanings given in the Buy American Act and Balance of Payments Program clause of this contract.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) country</textblock>
    <textblock>means Canada or Mexico.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>NAFTA country end product</textblock>
    <textblock>means an article that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Is wholly the growth, product, or manufacture of a NAFTA country; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Has, in the case of an article which consists in whole or in part of materials from another country or instrumentality, been substantially transformed in a NAFTA country into a new and different article of commerce with a name, character, or use distinct from that of the article or articles from which it was so transformed. The term includes services (except transportation services) incidental to its supply, provided that the value of those incidental services does not exceed the value of the product itself. It does not include service contracts as such.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>Non-NAFTA country end product</textblock>
    <textblock>means any end product which is not a U.S. made end product or a NAFTA country end product.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>means the United States, its designated possessions, Puerto Rico, and any other place subject to its jurisdiction, but does not include leased bases or trust territories.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6)</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. made end product</textblock>
    <textblock>means an article which is_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Wholly the growth, product or manufacture of the United States, or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) In the case of an article which consists in whole or in part of materials from another country or instrumentality, has been substantially transformed in the United States into a new and distinct article of commerce with a name, character, or use distinct from that of the article or articles from which it was so transformed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) This clause implements the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act of 1993 by providing a preference for U.S. made end products and NAFTA country end products over non-NAFTA country end products, except non-NAFTA country end products which are qualifying country end products.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The Contractor agrees to deliver under this contract only U.S. made end products unless, in its offer, it specified delivery of qualifying country, NAFTA country, or non-NAFTA country end products in the Buy American Act_North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act_Balance of Payments Program Certificate provision. An offer certifying that a qualifying country end product or a NAFTA country end product will be supplied requires the Contractor to supply a qualifying country end product or a NAFTA country end product, whichever is certified, or, at the Contractor's option, a U.S. made end produce.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) The offered price of end products listed and certified under paragraphs (c)(2)(i) and (iv) of the Buy American Act_North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act-Balance of Payments Program Certificate provision of the solicitation must include all applicable duty. The offered price of qualifying country end products or NAFTA country end products for line items subject to the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act, should not include custom fees or duty. (End of clause)</textblock>
    <textblock>19. A new section 252.225-7037 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>252.225-7037</textblock>
    <textblock>Duty-Free Entry_NAFTA Country End Products and Supplies.</textblock>
    <textblock>As prescribed in 225.605-70(c), use the following clause:</textblock>
    <textblock>Duty-Free Entry_NAFTA Country End Products and Supplies (Jan. 1994)</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
