<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00032</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00019</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>for Remedial Action at the Tonawanda Site, Tonawanda, NY</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Draft Feasibility Study/Proposed Plan-Environmental Impact Statement</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Energy (DOE).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension of public comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>DOE, in response to public comments received to date, has decided to extend to February 10, 1994, the public comment period on the draft feasibility study/proposed plan-environmental impact statement (FS/PP-EIS) for remedial action at the Tonawanda Site, Tonawanda, New York (DOE/EIS-0191D, EPA EIS No. 930393).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on the draft FS/PP-EIS should be postmarked by February 10, 1994, to ensure consideration. Comments postmarked after that date will be considered to the extent practicable.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments or requests for copies of the draft FS/PP-EIS should be addressed to: Ron Kirk, New York Site Manager, Former Sites Restoration Division, U.S. Department of Energy, Oak Ridge Operations Office,</textblock>
    <textblock>P.O. Box 2001, Oak Ridge, Tennessee 37831. Telephone: (615) 576-7477. Fax number (615) 576-0956.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>For further information on the Tonawanda Site, contact Ron Kirk at the above address. For further information on DOE's National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) procedures, contact: Carol Borgstrom, Director, Office of NEPA Oversight (EH-25), U.S. Department of Energy, 1000 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20585. Telephone: (202) 586-4600 or leave a message at (800) 472-2756. For further information on DOE's Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (CERCLA) procedures, contact: Randall Kaltreider, Acting Director, Office of Environmental Compliance (EH-22), U.S. Department of Energy, 1000 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20585. Telephone: (202) 586-4440.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On November 12, 1993, the Environmental Protection Agency published a notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 60022) announcing the availability of the draft FS/PP-EIS (DOE/EIS-0191D, EPA EIS No. 930393) and the close of the public comment period scheduled for January 11, 1994. DOE's draft FS/PP-EIS for the Tonawanda Site integrates NEPA values with the procedural and documentation requirements of CERCLA, whenever practicable pursuant to DOE Order 5400.4. In response to requests from several parties to extend the comment period, and to ensure that all interested parties have the opportunity to comment, DOE is extending the comment period to February 10, 1994. Comments should be postmarked by February 10, 1994, to ensure consideration; comments postmarked after that date will be considered to the extent practicable.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, January 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Tara O'Toole,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary, Environment, Safety and Health.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-499 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
