<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00054</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>If an owner-occupied unit assisted by a loan under the AHP were</textblock>
    <textblock>sold prior to the end of the 30-year period or the remaining</textblock>
    <textblock>useful life of the unit, as the case may be, to a household that</textblock>
    <textblock>was not a low- or moderate-income household, then the applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>would have to either: (1) Repay to the Bank that portion of the</textblock>
    <textblock>advance used to make the loan to the seller, or (2) convert that</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of the advance used to make the loan to the seller to a</textblock>
    <textblock>market rate advance with an interest rate equal to the market rate</textblock>
    <textblock>of interest at the time the advance was made, and any unused AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy which had been set aside by the Bank to subsidize that</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of the advance used to make the loan to the seller would</textblock>
    <textblock>be made available by the Bank for additional AHP projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>If an owner-occupied unit assisted by a grant under the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>were sold prior to the end of the 30-year period or the remaining</textblock>
    <textblock>useful life of the unit, as the case may be, to a household that</textblock>
    <textblock>was not a low- or moderate-income household, then the seller would</textblock>
    <textblock>have to repay to the applicant a</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of the grant</textblock>
    <textblock>from any profit realized upon the sale of the unit, and any amount</textblock>
    <textblock>repaid to the applicant would have to be forwarded to the Bank and</textblock>
    <textblock>made available for additional AHP projects. The Bank would have</textblock>
    <textblock>the discretion to waive this recapture requirement if imposition</textblock>
    <textblock>of the requirement would cause undue hardship on the seller, as</textblock>
    <textblock>defined in the Bank's AHP implementation plan. In addition, for</textblock>
    <textblock>owner-occupied units assisted by a grant, the Bank would have to</textblock>
    <textblock>monitor the unit during the required long-term period by reviewing</textblock>
    <textblock>land title records or reports or certifications from the sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>or a regulatory agency, as determined by each Bank in its AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation plan, to determine whether the unit had been sold</textblock>
    <textblock>to a household whose income exceeded a low-or moderate-income.</textblock>
    <textblock>As an alternative to requiring that each owner-occupied unit</textblock>
    <textblock>assisted by a grant be subject to a restriction on transfer, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank could have a legally binding agreement with the sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>providing that if such unit were sold prior to the end of the</textblock>
    <textblock>required long-term period to a household that was not a low- or</textblock>
    <textblock>moderate-income household, the sponsor would make another unit</textblock>
    <textblock>available to a low- or moderate-income household.</textblock>
    <textblock>Option B.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under option B, the long-term requirement would be met by</textblock>
    <textblock>providing that an owner-occupied unit assisted by a grant or a</textblock>
    <textblock>loan under the AHP must be affordable for the initial household</textblock>
    <textblock>for the duration of that household's occupancy of the unit.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, to minimize opportunities for speculation, the unit would</textblock>
    <textblock>have to be subject to a deed restriction or other legally</textblock>
    <textblock>enforceable mechanism restricting transfer of the unit to a low-</textblock>
    <textblock>or moderate-income household if the unit were sold within five</textblock>
    <textblock>years of the purchase, construction, or rehabilitation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>unit.</textblock>
    <textblock>As under option A, a household purchasing such a unit under</textblock>
    <textblock>option B would have to qualify as a low- or moderate-income</textblock>
    <textblock>household only at the time of purchase or at the time of closing</textblock>
    <textblock>on the financing for the unit, and a household rehabilitating a</textblock>
    <textblock>unit would have to qualify as a low- or moderate-income household</textblock>
    <textblock>only at the time the household received a commitment for funding</textblock>
    <textblock>through the AHP.</textblock>
    <textblock>If an owner-occupied unit assisted by a loan under the AHP were</textblock>
    <textblock>sold prior to the end of the five-year period to a household that</textblock>
    <textblock>was not a low- or moderate-income household, then the applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>would have to either: (1) Repay to the Bank that portion of the</textblock>
    <textblock>advance used to make the loan to the seller, or (2) convert that</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of the advance used to make the loan to the seller to a</textblock>
    <textblock>market rate advance with an interest rate equal to the market rate</textblock>
    <textblock>of interest at the time the advance was made, and any unused AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy which had been set aside by the Bank to subsidize that</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of the advance used to make the loan to the seller would</textblock>
    <textblock>be made available by the Bank for additional AHP projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>If an owner-occupied unit assisted by a grant under the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>were sold prior to the end of the five-year period to a household</textblock>
    <textblock>that was not a low- or moderate-income household, then the seller</textblock>
    <textblock>would have to repay to the applicant a</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of the</textblock>
    <textblock>grant from any profit realized upon the sale of the unit, and any</textblock>
    <textblock>amount repaid to the applicant would have to be forwarded to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank and made available for additional AHP projects. The Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>would have the discretion to waive this recapture requirement if</textblock>
    <textblock>imposition of the requirement would cause undue hardship on the</textblock>
    <textblock>seller, as defined in the Bank's AHP implementation plan. In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition, for owner-occupied units assisted by a grant, the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>would have to monitor the unit during the required long-term</textblock>
    <textblock>period by reviewing land title records or reports or</textblock>
    <textblock>certifications from the sponsor or a regulatory agency, as</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by each Bank in its AHP implementation plan, to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine whether the unit had been sold to a household whose</textblock>
    <textblock>income exceeded a low or moderate income.</textblock>
    <textblock>As under option A, as an alternative to requiring that each</textblock>
    <textblock>owner-occupied unit assisted by a grant be subject to a</textblock>
    <textblock>restriction on transfer, the Bank under option B could have a</textblock>
    <textblock>legally binding agreement with the sponsor providing that if such</textblock>
    <textblock>unit were sold prior to the end of the required long-term period</textblock>
    <textblock>to a household that was not a low- or moderate-income household,</textblock>
    <textblock>the sponsor would make another unit available to a low- or</textblock>
    <textblock>moderate-income household.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
