<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00078</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00063</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Agency Clearance Office_John J. Lane, (202) 942-8800.</textblock>
    <textblock>Upon written request copy available from: Securities and Exchange Commission, Office of Filings, Information and Consumer Services, Washington, DC 20549.</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 19d-2</textblock>
    <textblock>File No. 270-204</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that pursuant to the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. 34501</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>), the Securities and Exchange Commission (``Commission'') has submitted for extension of Office of Management and Budget approval Rule 19d-2 under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (15 U.S.C. 78</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>). Rule 19d-2 prescribes the form and content of applications to the Commission for stays of final disciplinary sanctions and summary actions of self-regulatory organizations. It is anticipated that approximately 30 respondents will spend a total of 90 hours complying with Rule 19d-2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Direct general comments to Gary Waxman at the address below. Direct any comments concerning the accuracy of the estimated average burden hours for compliance with the Commission rules and forms to John J. Lane, Associate Executive Director, Securities and Exchange Commission, 450 Fifth Street, NW., Washington, DC 20549 and Gary Waxman, Clearance Officer, Office of Management and Budget, (3235-0205), room 3208, New Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>SECURITIES AND EXCHANGE COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Requests Under Review by Office of Management and Budget</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-482 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
