<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00073</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>c.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring of District Bank priority or priorities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(g) of the proposed rule sets forth the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement for monitoring compliance with the District Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>priority or priorities established pursuant to proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.10(d)(4). Section 960.14(g)(1) of the proposed rule</textblock>
    <textblock>provides that if an applicant in its AHP application commits to</textblock>
    <textblock>fund a project that meets a District Bank priority or priorities,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank or its designee shall monitor the project to verify that</textblock>
    <textblock>it continues to meet the priority or priorities. Section</textblock>
    <textblock>960.14(g)(2) of the proposed rule provides that the Bank shall set</textblock>
    <textblock>forth in its AHP implementation plan the nature, frequency and</textblock>
    <textblock>duration for monitoring compliance with the District Bank priority</textblock>
    <textblock>or priorities.</textblock>
    <textblock>d.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring of economic mobility priority.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(h) of the proposed rule sets forth the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement for monitoring compliance with the economic mobility</textblock>
    <textblock>priority set forth under §960.5(d)(5) of the proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.14(h) provides that if an applicant in its AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application commits to fund a project that meets the requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>of §960.5(d)(5), the Bank or its designee shall obtain a</textblock>
    <textblock>certification from the sponsor or the owner upon completion and</textblock>
    <textblock>full occupancy of the project, as required under §960.15(c)(4),</textblock>
    <textblock>that the sponsor or the owner has met such requirements, as</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>J. Reporting Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.15 of the proposed rule sets forth the reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for the Banks, the applicants, and the sponsors or</textblock>
    <textblock>owners of AHP-assisted projects. Section 960.15(a) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule provides that each Bank shall provide accurate and</textblock>
    <textblock>timely reports and documentation to, and in the format requested</textblock>
    <textblock>by, the Board concerning the Bank's AHP, as the Board may from</textblock>
    <textblock>time to time require. See 12 CFR 960.6(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Applicant Reporting Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.15(b)(1) of the proposed rule carries forward the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement in the Board's existing AHP regulation that each Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall require an applicant receiving a subsidized advance or</textblock>
    <textblock>direct subsidy to report at least annually to the Bank on the</textblock>
    <textblock>manner in which it has used the funds, with such reports</textblock>
    <textblock>continuing until the funds have been fully disbursed by the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant. See 12 CFR 960.6(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule eliminates the requirement in the Board's</textblock>
    <textblock>existing AHP regulation that the applicant certify that the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy has been passed through to the borrower and continues to</textblock>
    <textblock>be used for approved purposes because, as discussed previously in</textblock>
    <textblock>the section on monitoring requirements, under the proposed rule</textblock>
    <textblock>applicants are not required to monitor the use of a subsidy in</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP-assisted projects, except during the period when a subsidized</textblock>
    <textblock>advance or direct subsidy is used to finance construction or</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitation of a project or where the applicant has agreed to</textblock>
    <textblock>undertake monitoring. See 12 CFR 960.6(c).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.15(b)(2) of the proposed rule adds a new</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement that if subsidized advances or direct subsidies are</textblock>
    <textblock>used to finance construction or rehabilitation of an AHP-assisted</textblock>
    <textblock>project, the Bank shall require the applicant to report to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank at reasonable intervals determined by the Bank, and described</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Bank's AHP implementation plan, on the progress of the</textblock>
    <textblock>construction or rehabilitation, until completion. This reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement coincides with the requirement in §960.14(d) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule that the Bank shall require the applicant to monitor</textblock>
    <textblock>the construction or rehabilitation of an AHP-assisted project and</textblock>
    <textblock>make progress reports to the Bank where AHP subsidized advances or</textblock>
    <textblock>direct subsidies are used to finance such construction or</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Sponsor and Owner Reporting Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.15(c) of the proposed rule sets forth the reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for sponsors and owners. These requirements coincide</textblock>
    <textblock>with the monitoring requirements set forth in §960.14(e) through</textblock>
    <textblock>(h) of the proposed rule. Section 960.15(c)(1)(i) of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule provides that where a subsidized advance or direct subsidy is</textblock>
    <textblock>used to finance the purchase of an owner-occupied housing unit,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank shall require the sponsor to certify at the time a</textblock>
    <textblock>household enters into a purchase contract for such unit or at the</textblock>
    <textblock>closing on the financing for such unit that the unit has been sold</textblock>
    <textblock>to a household with an income at or below the level committed to</textblock>
    <textblock>in the AHP application. Where a subsidized advance or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy is used to finance the rehabilitation of an owner-occupied</textblock>
    <textblock>housing unit, the Bank shall require the sponsor to certify at the</textblock>
    <textblock>time a loan or grant is committed to fund such rehabilitation that</textblock>
    <textblock>the household that owns and occupies the unit has an income at or</textblock>
    <textblock>below the level committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.15(c)(1)(ii) of the proposed rule provides that if</textblock>
    <textblock>an owner-occupied housing unit assisted by a grant provided under</textblock>
    <textblock>the AHP is not subject to a deed restriction or other legally</textblock>
    <textblock>enforceable mechanism restricting transfer of ownership to a</textblock>
    <textblock>household with an income at or below the level committed to in the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP application, the Bank shall require the sponsor to report to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank or its designee, at least annually for the required</textblock>
    <textblock>long-term period, the number of any such units that are sold to</textblock>
    <textblock>households whose incomes exceed the level committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application, and to certify to the Bank that it is continuing to</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfy its commitment pursuant to its legally binding agreement</textblock>
    <textblock>with the Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.15(c)(2) of the proposed rule provides that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank shall require the sponsor or the owner to certify upon</textblock>
    <textblock>initial full occupancy of the units in an AHP-assisted rental</textblock>
    <textblock>housing project, but no later than one year after initial</textblock>
    <textblock>disbursement of the subsidized advance or direct subsidy, and</textblock>
    <textblock>annually thereafter, that the project's units, or portion thereof,</textblock>
    <textblock>are affordable for and occupied by households with incomes at or</textblock>
    <textblock>below the levels committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.15(c)(3) of the proposed rule provides that if an</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant in its AHP application commits to fund a project that</textblock>
    <textblock>will provide housing units for persons with a special need, or</textblock>
    <textblock>will provide a continuing special service to occupants pursuant to</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.10(d)(3) of the proposed rule, the Bank shall require the</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor or the owner to certify upon completion and full occupancy</textblock>
    <textblock>of the project that the project's units, or portion thereof, are</textblock>
    <textblock>occupied by persons with such special needs or that a special</textblock>
    <textblock>service is being provided to occupants, as committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.15(c)(4) of the proposed rule provides that if an</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant in its AHP application commits to fund a housing project</textblock>
    <textblock>that meets the requirements of the economic mobility priority</textblock>
    <textblock>under §960.10(d)(5) of the proposed rule, the Bank shall require</textblock>
    <textblock>the sponsor or the owner to certify upon completion and full</textblock>
    <textblock>occupancy of the project that the sponsor or owner has met such</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements, as committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
