<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00057</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Proposed ยง960.5(a)(1) implements section 10(j)(2)(B) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Act, which provides that Bank members may use subsidized advances</textblock>
    <textblock>received from the Banks to finance the purchase, construction, or</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitation of rental housing, at least 20 percent of the units</textblock>
    <textblock>of which will be occupied by and affordable for very low-income</textblock>
    <textblock>households for the remaining useful life of such housing or the</textblock>
    <textblock>mortgage term. 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(2)(B).</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed ยง960.5(a)(1) provides that the applicant and project</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor shall state in the AHP application their commitment</textblock>
    <textblock>regarding satisfaction of the long-term income-eligibility,</textblock>
    <textblock>affordability and income-targeting requirements. In addition, an</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant may commit to maintain additional units as affordable</textblock>
    <textblock>for and occupied by low- or moderate-income households, which</textblock>
    <textblock>commitment shall be a minimum period of 30 years or, at the</textblock>
    <textblock>election of the sponsor, the remaining useful life of such units.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Long-term requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 10(j) of the Act does not define ``remaining useful life'' as used in section 10(j)(2)(B) of the Act. See 12 U.S.C. 1430(j). However, the legislative history of section 21A(c) of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Act regarding residential properties sold by the Resolution</textblock>
    <textblock>Trust Corporation (RTC), which was enacted as part of the same</textblock>
    <textblock>legislation that enacted section 10(j), states that the remaining</textblock>
    <textblock>useful life of such RTC property is intended to cover the property</textblock>
    <textblock>as long as it is habitable and assumes good faith efforts by the</textblock>
    <textblock>purchaser to maintain the property and to rehabilitate it as</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary. See Joint Explanatory Statement of the Committee of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Conference, H.R. Conf. Rep. No. 101-222, 101st Cong., 1st</textblock>
    <textblock>Sess., 419 (1989) (FIRREA Conference Report); 12 U.S.C. 1441a(c).</textblock>
    <textblock>The RTC has in fact adopted a specific uniform period of useful</textblock>
    <textblock>life for all buildings instead of a period of useful life based on</textblock>
    <textblock>physical habitability. See 12 CFR 1609.2(kk). The legislative</textblock>
    <textblock>history of a recently enacted affordable housing statute, the Low</textblock>
    <textblock>Income Housing Preservation and Residential Homeownership Act</textblock>
    <textblock>(LIHPRHA), provides further support for a definition of ``remaining</textblock>
    <textblock>useful life'' based on the period of physical habitability of a</textblock>
    <textblock>property by explicitly rejecting the RTC's regulatory definition.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, ยง960.1 of the proposed rule defines ``remaining</textblock>
    <textblock>useful life'' as the period during which the housing remains in a</textblock>
    <textblock>condition suitable for occupancy, assuming normal maintenance and</textblock>
    <textblock>repairs are made and major systems and capital components are</textblock>
    <textblock>replaced or repaired as becomes necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 10(j) of the Act does not define ``mortgage term'' as</textblock>
    <textblock>used in section 10(j)(2)(B) of the Act. See 12 U.S.C. 1430(j).</textblock>
    <textblock>The legislative history of section 10(j) states that the conferees</textblock>
    <textblock>expect that the Board will encourage the use of the longest</textblock>
    <textblock>practicable mortgage term in order to aid in making the housing</textblock>
    <textblock>affordable for very low-income households. See FIRREA Conference</textblock>
    <textblock>Report at 431. Accordingly, the Board believes that ``mortgage</textblock>
    <textblock>term'' should be defined as the mortgage term only of long-term</textblock>
    <textblock>mortgage loans and believes that 30 years is consistent with</textblock>
    <textblock>Congress' intent in section 10(j)(2)(B) of the Act to ensure that</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP-assisted rental housing projects remain occupied by and</textblock>
    <textblock>affordable for income-eligible households for a long-term period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Definitions of ``low- or moderate-income household'' and</textblock>
    <textblock>``very low-income household''.</textblock>
    <textblock>The definitions of ``low- or moderate-income household'' and</textblock>
    <textblock>``very low-income household'' discussed above for AHP-assisted</textblock>
    <textblock>owner-occupied housing projects apply for AHP-assisted rental</textblock>
    <textblock>housing projects as well.</textblock>
    <textblock>With respect to the definition of ``income,'' rental housing</textblock>
    <textblock>projects typically have multiple providers of financing, each of</textblock>
    <textblock>which may specify the eligible sources of income, which sometimes</textblock>
    <textblock>conflict with each other. However, as with AHP-assisted</textblock>
    <textblock>owner-occupied housing projects, the Board has determined that the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule should not specify the eligible sources of income</textblock>
    <textblock>for rental housing projects, but rather that applicants should be</textblock>
    <textblock>permitted to follow their usual underwriting guidelines, or may</textblock>
    <textblock>follow those of the predominant source of financing in the</textblock>
    <textblock>project.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
