<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00062</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 960.7(b)(3) of the proposed rule provides that within</textblock>
    <textblock>30 calendar days of each Bank's approval of the AHP applications</textblock>
    <textblock>for a given AHP funding cycle, the Bank shall forward to the Board</textblock>
    <textblock>a summary of each approved AHP application. The summary shall:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Briefly describe the project, including the applicant, the</textblock>
    <textblock>loan fund or loan consortium, if applicable, and the sponsor_</textblock>
    <textblock>whether nonprofit, for-profit or public agency, the type of</textblock>
    <textblock>housing, the location, the long-term period committed to, the</textblock>
    <textblock>number of housing units including the number of units affordable</textblock>
    <textblock>for very low-, low- or moderate-income households or for</textblock>
    <textblock>households at any other income levels committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application, the development cost, other financing sources, and</textblock>
    <textblock>special needs populations served;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) State the reason for the points awarded under each of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank's scoring criteria for the project;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Indicate whether a subsidized advance or direct subsidy</textblock>
    <textblock>was approved by the Bank for the project, the use of such funds,</textblock>
    <textblock>and the amount of such funds approved; if a subsidized advance was</textblock>
    <textblock>approved, the summary shall indicate the amount of the advance,</textblock>
    <textblock>the advance rate, the amortization schedule for the advance, the</textblock>
    <textblock>term to maturity, the applicable cost of funds, and the date as of</textblock>
    <textblock>which the cost of funds was determined;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Indicate whether the project received approval in a prior</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP funding cycle, or whether the project is an extension,</textblock>
    <textblock>expansion, continuation or reconfiguration of a previously</textblock>
    <textblock>approved AHP project;</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) Describe how the project will be monitored and by what</textblock>
    <textblock>entity;</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) Describe the legal mechanisms to be used to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance by the project with the long-term requirement contained</textblock>
    <textblock>in §960.5 of the proposed rule;</textblock>
    <textblock>(vii) Include a summary in chart form showing all AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>applications received by the Bank in the particular AHP funding</textblock>
    <textblock>cycle, with the score each application received for each scoring</textblock>
    <textblock>criterion, and the total score received by each project; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(viii) Include any other information required by the Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board has general oversight responsibility over the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>under section 10(j) of the Act. See 12 U.S.C. 1430(j). In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition, section 10(j)(12)(A) of the Act requires the Board to</textblock>
    <textblock>monitor and report annually to the Congress and the Advisory</textblock>
    <textblock>Council for each Bank the support of low-income housing and</textblock>
    <textblock>community development by the Banks and the utilization of advances</textblock>
    <textblock>for these purposes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Id.</textblock>
    <textblock>§1430(j)(12)(A). Since the Board would</textblock>
    <textblock>no longer be receiving and approving AHP applications under the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule, the Board would no longer have these applications</textblock>
    <textblock>as a source of data to assist the Board in exercising its</textblock>
    <textblock>oversight and monitoring responsibilities and preparing the annual</textblock>
    <textblock>report to the Congress and the Advisory Councils. Accordingly,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Board will need the Banks to provide this additional</textblock>
    <textblock>information to the Board in the summary, as required in proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.7(b)(3).</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Requirements For Approval of AHP Applications</textblock>
    <textblock>1. General</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.8(a) of the proposed rule provides that each Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall evaluate the AHP applications received to determine if they</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfy the threshold criteria in proposed §960.9. All</textblock>
    <textblock>applications that meet the threshold criteria shall be scored</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to the criteria contained in proposed §960.10 as set</textblock>
    <textblock>forth in the Bank's approved AHP implementation plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.8(b) of the proposed rule provides that the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall approve the applications in descending order starting with</textblock>
    <textblock>the highest scoring application until the total AHP funding amount</textblock>
    <textblock>for the particular funding cycle, except for any amount</textblock>
    <textblock>insufficient to fund the next highest scoring project, has been</textblock>
    <textblock>allocated. The Bank also may approve the next four highest</textblock>
    <textblock>scoring applications as alternates and, within one year of</textblock>
    <textblock>approval by the Bank, may fund such alternates if any previously</textblock>
    <textblock>committed AHP funds become available.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Threshold Criteria for Approval of AHP Applications</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.9 of the proposed rule provides that an AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application must meet all of the threshold criteria set forth in</textblock>
    <textblock>a. through f. below in order to be considered for scoring under</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed §960.10 and for AHP funding approval. These criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>are discussed in detail below.</textblock>
    <textblock>a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authorized and required uses requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>The AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application must indicate that the use of the subsidized advance</textblock>
    <textblock>or direct subsidy set forth in the AHP application for the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed project will comply with the requirements for authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>and required uses of such funds contained in proposed §§960.3,</textblock>
    <textblock>960.4 and 960.5. See proposed §960.9(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposed provision is consistent with the intent of</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.5(a)(1) of the Board's existing AHP regulation. See 12 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>960.5(a)(1).</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Fair housing law requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>The AHP application must</textblock>
    <textblock>indicate that the project sponsor will comply with any applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>fair housing law requirements and must indicate how the sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes to affirmatively further compliance with such</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements. See proposed §960.9(b).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
