<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00096</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(B) For households in AHP-assisted rental housing units, rent</textblock>
    <textblock>payments, and where they are not already included in rent</textblock>
    <textblock>payments, a reasonable estimate of utility costs excluding</textblock>
    <textblock>telephone service.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) A household subject to the 20 percent requirement set</textblock>
    <textblock>forth in paragraph (c)(1) of this section is required to meet such</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement only at the time it initially purchases or occupies a</textblock>
    <textblock>unit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Alternative requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The requirement in paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)(1) of this section shall not apply where a Bank provides</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advances or direct subsidies to an applicant for a</textblock>
    <textblock>rental housing project, which project also receives funds from a</textblock>
    <textblock>federal or state rental housing program that requires qualifying</textblock>
    <textblock>households to pay as rent a certain percentage of their monthly</textblock>
    <textblock>income or a designated amount, provided that the household meets</textblock>
    <textblock>the housing payment requirements of the other program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The requirement in paragraph (c)(1) of this section shall</textblock>
    <textblock>not apply where:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The total amount of the AHP funds provided through a</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advance or direct subsidy used to finance</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitation of a housing unit by a very low-income household</textblock>
    <textblock>that already owns and occupies the housing unit is $10,000 or less</textblock>
    <textblock>per such household; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The total amount of the AHP funds provided through a</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidized advance or direct subsidy used to finance the purchase</textblock>
    <textblock>of a housing unit by a very low-income household is $5,000 or less</textblock>
    <textblock>per such household.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The requirement in paragraph (c)(1) of this section shall</textblock>
    <textblock>not apply where the total amount of the AHP funds provided through</textblock>
    <textblock>a subsidized advance or direct subsidy used to finance</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitation or purchase of a housing unit by a low- or</textblock>
    <textblock>moderate-income household is $5,000 or less per such household.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The requirement in paragraph (c)(1) of this section shall</textblock>
    <textblock>not apply where a Bank provides subsidized advances or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidies ultimately benefiting a household with an income at or</textblock>
    <textblock>below the level committed to in the AHP application, which is</textblock>
    <textblock>participating in a self-help, sweat equity or similar housing</textblock>
    <textblock>program that requires the household to contribute its skilled or</textblock>
    <textblock>unskilled labor valued at a minimum of $2,000 per household,</textblock>
    <textblock>working cooperatively with others, to construct or rehabilitate</textblock>
    <textblock>housing which the household or other program participants are</textblock>
    <textblock>purchasing or already own and occupy, and that involves</textblock>
    <textblock>supervision of the work performed by skilled builders or</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitators.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Project feasibility.</textblock>
    <textblock>The AHP application must indicate</textblock>
    <textblock>that the proposed project is feasible in that, based on an</textblock>
    <textblock>analysis of project sources and uses of funds, project multi-year</textblock>
    <textblock>operating pro formas for rental housing projects, projections of</textblock>
    <textblock>sales and prices for owner-occupied housing units, and local</textblock>
    <textblock>market conditions, the project is financially viable and likely to</textblock>
    <textblock>be completed within a reasonable period of time, and is likely to</textblock>
    <textblock>operate or sell and remain affordable to the designated</textblock>
    <textblock>income-eligible households over the long-term period committed to</textblock>
    <textblock>in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Qualifications of sponsor.</textblock>
    <textblock>The AHP application must</textblock>
    <textblock>indicate that the sponsor has the qualifications and ability to</textblock>
    <textblock>perform its responsibilities as committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Creditworthiness of applicant.</textblock>
    <textblock>The applicant must have the</textblock>
    <textblock>ability to qualify for an advance from the Bank to fund the</textblock>
    <textblock>project described in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.10</textblock>
    <textblock>Scoring of AHP applications.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>General.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bank shall score AHP applications that satisfy all of</textblock>
    <textblock>the threshold criteria in ยง960.9 according to the scoring</textblock>
    <textblock>methodology set forth in this section which shall be included in</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank's approved AHP implementation plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Priority treatment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each application is first evaluated to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine if it will receive priority treatment. For purposes of</textblock>
    <textblock>determining priority, an application can receive a maximum of</textblock>
    <textblock>eight points for each of the five priority categories set forth in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (d) of this section. A Bank in its AHP implementation</textblock>
    <textblock>plan shall define more specifically each of the five priority</textblock>
    <textblock>categories and explain specifically how points will be awarded for</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfying each category. An application will be deemed to meet a</textblock>
    <textblock>particular priority category if it is awarded at least four points</textblock>
    <textblock>for that priority category. Applications meeting at least two</textblock>
    <textblock>priority categories shall receive priority treatment.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Order of scoring.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications that qualify for priority treatment pursuant</textblock>
    <textblock>to paragraph (b) of this section shall be scored before</textblock>
    <textblock>applications that do not qualify for priority treatment. The</textblock>
    <textblock>applications that do not qualify for priority treatment will not</textblock>
    <textblock>be scored unless there are insufficient priority treatment</textblock>
    <textblock>applications to utilize the total AHP funding amount for the</textblock>
    <textblock>funding cycle.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Priorities_40 point category.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bank shall total the</textblock>
    <textblock>points received by each applicant for purposes of determining</textblock>
    <textblock>priority for all of the five priority categories set forth in this</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (d); it shall award 40 points to the application(s) that</textblock>
    <textblock>receive the highest number of total points, and the remaining</textblock>
    <textblock>application scores shall be adjusted and awarded points on a</textblock>
    <textblock>declining scale basis. The five priority categories are as set</textblock>
    <textblock>forth in the following paragraphs (d)(1) through (5) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Government-owned properties.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications for projects</textblock>
    <textblock>that finance the purchase or rehabilitation of housing owned or</textblock>
    <textblock>held by the United States Government or any agency or</textblock>
    <textblock>instrumentality of the United States, including but not limited to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Department of Housing and Urban Development, Resolution Trust</textblock>
    <textblock>Corporation, Farmers Home Administration, Veterans Administration,</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal National Mortgage Association, or Federal Home Loan</textblock>
    <textblock>Mortgage Corporation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Nonprofit or state or local government sponsored projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications for projects that finance the purchase, construction</textblock>
    <textblock>or rehabilitation of housing the sponsor of which is a nonprofit</textblock>
    <textblock>organization, a state or political subdivision of a state, a local</textblock>
    <textblock>housing authority or a state housing finance agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Special needs projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications for projects that</textblock>
    <textblock>address special needs, which shall be defined by the Bank in its</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP implementation plan, which special needs may include but are</textblock>
    <textblock>not limited to:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Empowering the households or residents through programs</textblock>
    <textblock>such as resident management of the property, self-help housing,</textblock>
    <textblock>homesteading, and sweat equity;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
