<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00015</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(iii) Flowage or flood easements acquired by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers or other authorities that are subject to inundation when water is released under the course of normal operations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Land located in old or new channels of a stream, creek, river, or other similar body of water or on any of the inside banks unless approved by DASCO. Facilities in irrigation canals or on their inside banks may be approved if the canal is not a channel subject to flooding;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Land in greenhouses or other confined areas; and (5) Land on which poor farming practices, such as failure to farm on the contour, have materially contributed to damaging the land.</textblock>
    <textblock>§701.202</textblock>
    <textblock>Eligibility of person and land.</textblock>
    <textblock>Person and land eligibility requirements are the same as for the ACP as provided in §§701.104 and 701.105 except in cases of severe drought conditions then cost-share assistance is limited to supplying:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Emergency livestock water, including measures to assist confined livestock operations, and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Water for existing irrigation systems serving orchards and vineyards.</textblock>
    <textblock>§701.203</textblock>
    <textblock>Emergency Conservation Program practices.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Except for severe drought and wind erosion, cost-share assistance may be offered for emergency conservation practices only to replace or restore farmland to a condition similar to that existing before the natural disaster. Cost-share assistance may not be offered for the solution of conservation problems existing before the disaster.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) ECP practices for which cost-share assistance may be authorized are:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Removing debris from farmland.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Grading, shaping, releveling, or similar measures.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Restoring permanent fences.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Restoring structures and other installations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Emergency wind control measures.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Drought emergency measures.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Other emergency conservation measures.</textblock>
    <textblock>§701.204</textblock>
    <textblock>Practice approval.</textblock>
    <textblock>Practices listed in §701.203 (b)(1) through (b)(5) may be approved by COC's. Authorization to offer practices at §701.203 (b)(6) and (b)(7) shall be approved by the Deputy Administrator.</textblock>
    <textblock>§701.205</textblock>
    <textblock>Extent of cost-share assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The maximum payment under this subpart per person, per disaster, is limited to $200,000 including the amount of any payment received by such person as the result of the disaster under a pooling agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The cost-share payments which may be made by ASCS for a practice under the program shall, subject to the maximum</textblock>
    <textblock>payment amount specified in paragraph (a) of this section and any other limitation as may apply, be further limited to the level of cost-share assistance established by the COC not to exceed:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Sixty four (64) percent of the first $62,500 of the eligible cost of restoring the loss;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Forty (40) percent of the second $62,500 of the eligible cost of restoring the loss; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Twenty (20) percent of the eligible cost above $125,000 to restore the loss.</textblock>
    <textblock>§701.206</textblock>
    <textblock>Eligible costs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Upon determination that a person is eligible for ECP assistance, cost-share assistance may be authorized for all reasonable costs incurred in the completion of the practice. Such costs may include personal labor, equipment, and other such costs which are determined by the COC to be related to the costs of performing the practice. COC's shall limit costs for the use of personal equipment to an amount that reflects out-of-pocket expenses. Expenses for personal labor and personal equipment shall be less than rates charged by contractors who expect to make a profit for their efforts.</textblock>
    <textblock>§701.207</textblock>
    <textblock>Filing requests.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The COC shall establish an enrollment period for filing cost-sharing requests immediately after the COC's authorization or the Deputy Administrator's authorization in cases of drought to implement the ECP in the county. Such periods shall be at least 30 days in length. Late-filed requests may be accepted by the COC in justifiable cases.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Costs will not be shared for practices or components of practices that are started before a request is filed with the county office.</textblock>
    <textblock>§701.208</textblock>
    <textblock>Approving requests.</textblock>
    <textblock>COC's shall issue practice approvals only when:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Funds are available;</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The requested practice has been determined eligible for cost-share assistance; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The eligible person has indicated a readiness to start the practice.</textblock>
    <textblock>§701.209</textblock>
    <textblock>Pooling agreements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pooling agreements may be used on the same basis as provided for at §701.115.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
