<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00078</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 960.17(c)(3) of the proposed rule provides that any</textblock>
    <textblock>interest or other income earned by a loan fund or loan consortium</textblock>
    <textblock>on a loan or a grant received from an applicant, other than any</textblock>
    <textblock>approved fee or interest rate spread charged to the borrower,</textblock>
    <textblock>either (i) must be used by the loan fund or loan consortium to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide funds for additional projects meeting the threshold</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements in §960.9 of the proposed rule and the criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the approved AHP application, or (ii) must be</textblock>
    <textblock>forwarded to the applicant, which in turn must forward the funds</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Bank to be used for additional AHP projects. This is a</textblock>
    <textblock>change from the provision in the Board's existing policy</textblock>
    <textblock>guidelines that allows loan funds and loan consortia to earn and</textblock>
    <textblock>retain</textblock>
    <textblock>de minimis</textblock>
    <textblock>amounts of income on loans or grants received</textblock>
    <textblock>from applicants. The Board believes that accounting for</textblock>
    <textblock>de</textblock>
    <textblock>minimis</textblock>
    <textblock>amounts of interest or other income earned on loans or</textblock>
    <textblock>grants received from an applicant is no less of an administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>burden than accounting for all such interest or other income</textblock>
    <textblock>earned. Therefore, the proposed rule requires all interest or</textblock>
    <textblock>other income earned on loans or grants received from an applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>to be used by the loan fund or loan consortium for additional AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>projects or returned to the applicant.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.17(c)(4) of the proposed rule provides that if</textblock>
    <textblock>loans or grants received by a loan fund or loan consortium</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to one AHP funding cycle are combined with loans or</textblock>
    <textblock>grants received by such entity pursuant to another AHP funding</textblock>
    <textblock>cycle in a single rental housing project, the loan fund or loan</textblock>
    <textblock>consortium shall require the recipient of the funds to follow the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for the use of such funds from the AHP funding cycle</textblock>
    <textblock>that is more restrictive as to the approved AHP criteria. This</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement does not apply when loans or grants received by a loan</textblock>
    <textblock>fund or loan consortium pursuant to separate AHP funding cycles</textblock>
    <textblock>are combined to finance a single owner-occupied housing project.</textblock>
    <textblock>The reason for this provision is that funds are more easily</textblock>
    <textblock>traceable to separate units in an owner-occupied housing project</textblock>
    <textblock>than to separate units in a rental housing project. Therefore,</textblock>
    <textblock>for purposes of owner-occupied housing projects, it is possible to</textblock>
    <textblock>use loans or grants from different AHP funding cycles according to</textblock>
    <textblock>the different criteria approved by the Bank in each of the</textblock>
    <textblock>respective funding cycles. However, the loan fund or loan</textblock>
    <textblock>consortium in its discretion may require the recipient of the</textblock>
    <textblock>funds to follow the requirements for the use of such funds from</textblock>
    <textblock>the AHP funding cycle that is more restrictive as to the approved</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP criteria.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.17(c)(5) of the proposed rule provides that any</textblock>
    <textblock>loans provided by a loan fund or loan consortium pursuant to the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP that are repaid to such entity must be re-lent or provided as</textblock>
    <textblock>grants by such entity within a reasonable period of time after</textblock>
    <textblock>such repayments, or must be repaid to the applicant, which in turn</textblock>
    <textblock>must repay such funds to the Bank, and must be made available by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank for additional AHP projects. The Bank shall in its AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation plan identify what constitutes a reasonable period</textblock>
    <textblock>of time for such purposes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.17(d) of the proposed rule sets forth the</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring and reporting requirements where an applicant makes</textblock>
    <textblock>loans or grants pursuant to the AHP to a loan fund or loan</textblock>
    <textblock>consortium which uses the funds to finance owner-occupied or</textblock>
    <textblock>rental housing units. Section 960.17(d)(1)(i) of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule requires the Bank to monitor such units, according to the</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring requirements of §960.14(e) through (h) of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule, to determine compliance with the long-term requirements, as</textblock>
    <textblock>well as compliance with the special needs priority, the District</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank priority or priorities, and the economic mobility priority,</textblock>
    <textblock>where applicable. In addition, §960.17(d)(1)(ii) of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule provides that the Bank shall require the sponsor or owner of</textblock>
    <textblock>a project receiving a loan or grant from the loan fund or loan</textblock>
    <textblock>consortium to submit to the Bank such reports and certifications</textblock>
    <textblock>as are required under §960.15(c) of the proposed rule. Section</textblock>
    <textblock>960.17(d)(1)(iii) of the proposed rule provides that the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall require the loan fund or loan consortium to report to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank any new loan or grant made using repayments of loans by the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower. If a loan fund or loan consortium receives loans or</textblock>
    <textblock>grants from an applicant pursuant to separate AHP funding cycles,</textblock>
    <textblock>the use of such funds must be reported separately.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.17(d)(2) of the proposed rule provides that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank may contract with either the applicant or the loan fund or</textblock>
    <textblock>loan consortium to meet the monitoring requirements of §960.14(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>through (h). Under §960.17(d)(2)(i) of the proposed rule, if the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank contracts with the applicant to meet such monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements, the Bank shall require the applicant to monitor the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP-assisted housing units according to the monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of §960.14(e) through (h) of the proposed rule. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank also shall require the applicant to require the sponsor or</textblock>
    <textblock>owner of the project to submit to the applicant such reports and</textblock>
    <textblock>certifications as are required under §960.15(c) of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule. In addition, the applicant shall require the loan fund or</textblock>
    <textblock>loan consortium to report to the applicant any new loan or grant</textblock>
    <textblock>made using repayments of loans by the borrower. If a loan fund or</textblock>
    <textblock>loan consortium receives loans or grants from an applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to separate AHP funding cycles, the use of such funds</textblock>
    <textblock>must be reported separately.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
