<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00005</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>701.301␣Designated counties.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.302␣Eligible person, land, and ownerships.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.303␣Program funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.304␣Eligible practices and cost-share assistance requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.305␣The national FIP.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.306␣Development of State FIP.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.307␣Development of county FIP.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.308␣Adaptation of practices.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.309␣Levels and rates of cost-share assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.310␣Prior approval for cost-share assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.311␣Methods of approval.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.312␣Long-term agreements.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.313␣Restoration of practices.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.314␣FIP maximum cost-share assistance limitations.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.315␣Completion of practice.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.316␣Time of filing payment application.</textblock>
    <textblock>701.317-701.399␣[Reserved]</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 590d, 590g-590o, 590p(a), 590q, 1501-1510, 1606, 2101-2111, 2201-2205, 3831; 48 U.S.C. 1469d(c).</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart A_General Provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>§701.1 Background.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Through the conservation and environmental programs administered by the Department of Agriculture, the Federal Government will share with farmers, ranchers, and other eligible private landowners in the United States and the applicable territories and possessions of the United States, the cost of performing:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Approved soil and water conservation, water quality, and pollution abatement practices including related wildlife conservation practices.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Emergency conservation measures.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Approved forestry practices.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The Federal Government will provide incentive payments to farmers, ranchers, and other private landowners in applicable areas of the United States to establish Water Quality Incentive Projects (WQIP) practices.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Cost-share assistance or incentive payments may be made available to eligible program participants by the Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service (ASCS) for:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Soil and water conservation, water quality, and pollution abatement practices under the Agricultural Conservation Program (ACP) which includes WQIP.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Practices to correct damage to land or conservation practices caused by natural disaster under the Emergency Conservation Program (ECP).</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Installation of water conservation measures under the ECP during periods of severe drought.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Forestry practices under the ACP and the Forestry Incentives Program (FIP).</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Information on the practices for which costs will be shared, the exact specifications and rates of cost-share assistance for such practices, and the eligibility</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for participating in the programs, may be obtained from the County Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation (ASC) Committee (county committee) for the county in which the farm, ranch, or other eligible land is administered or from the State ASC committee (State committee) for the State in which such county is located.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) The provisions at subpart A apply to the programs specified in subparts B through D.</textblock>
    <textblock>§701.2</textblock>
    <textblock>Administration.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The regulations in this part will be administered under the general supervision of the Administrator, ASCS and shall be carried out in the field by State and county Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation committees (State and county ASC committees).</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) State and county ASC committees, and representatives and employees thereof do not have the authority to modify or waive any of the provisions of the regulations of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The State ASC committee shall take any action required by these regulations which has not been taken by the county ASC committee. The State ASC committee shall also:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Correct, or require a county ASC committee to correct any action taken by such county ASC committee which is not in accordance with the regulations of this part, or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Require a county ASC committee to withhold taking any action which is not in accordance with the regulations of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) No provision or delegation herein to a State or county ASC committee shall preclude the Administrator, ASCS, or a designee, from determining any question arising under the regulations of this part or from reversing or modifying any determination made by a State or county ASC committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>§701.3</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The terms defined in part 719 of this chapter shall be applicable to this part and all documents issued in accordance with this part, except as otherwise provided in this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The following definitions shall apply to this part:</textblock>
    <textblock>ACP</textblock>
    <textblock>means the Agricultural Conservation Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>means a person who submits to ASCS an intention to participate in a cost-share program.</textblock>
    <textblock>ASCS</textblock>
    <textblock>means the Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service of the United States Department of Agriculture.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
