<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00054</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(1) Develop or use curriculum materials for adults based on literacy skills needed in the workplace;</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Provide, and document for others, a program of training for staff including, but not limited to, techniques of curriculum development and special methods of teaching that are appropriate for workplace environments.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Plan of operation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(15 points) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) A realistic time table for accomplishing project objectives;</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant's experience and quality of key personnel.</textblock>
    <textblock>(8 points) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The qualifications, in relation to project requirements, of the project director;</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Evaluation plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(10 points) The Secretary reviews each application to determine the quality of the plan for an independent evaluation of the project, including the extent to which the applicant's methods of evaluation_</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Will yield results that can be summarized and submitted to the Secretary for review by the Department's Program Effectiveness Panel.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note to §472.22(f)(6): The Program Effectiveness Panel (PEP) is a mechanism the Department has developed for validating the effectiveness of educational programs developed by schools, universities, and other agencies. The PEP is composed of experts in the evaluation of educational programs and in other areas of education, at least two-thirds of whom are non-Federal employees who are appointed by the Secretary. Regulations governing the PEP are codified in 34 CFR parts 785-789. Specific criteria for PEP review are found in 34 CFR 786.12 or 787.12.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Budget and cost-effectiveness.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7 points) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(h)</textblock>
    <textblock>Demonstration.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5 points) The Secretary reviews each application to determine the quality of the applicant's plan, during the grant period, to disseminate the results of the project, including_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Demonstrating promising practices used by the project to others interested in implementing these techniques;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Conducting workshops or delivering papers at national conferences or professional meetings; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Making available material that will help others implement promising practices developed in the project.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Commitment.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5 points) The Secretary reviews each application to determine the quality of the applicant's plan to institutionalize learning in the workplace based on promising practices demonstrated in the project. In making this determination, the Secretary considers_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The general, but realistic, forecast of literacy needs of members of the partnership and the capacity of the partners;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Activities that will increase, during the grant period, the capacity of partners to provide a coherent program of learning in the workplace; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Activities that will lead to the continued provision or expansion of work-based literacy services built on successful</textblock>
    <textblock>outcomes of the project. For example, the partners could_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Integrate workplace literacy services into the long-term planning of partner organizations;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Create and implement policies and practices that encourage worker participation in workplace literacy and other education and training opportunities;</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Provide training that will enable partners to build a capacity to furnish necessary workplace literacy services in the future;</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) Establish relationships within the partnership or with other entities that will continue provision of necessary workplace literacy services after the project ends; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(E) Plan, after the project has ended, to expand services to other locations, divisions, or suppliers of the business or industry partners or labor organizations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under OMB control number 1830-0521)</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
