<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00006</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-0-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>§58.2431</textblock>
    <textblock>Relationship of U.S. grade of whipped butter to the flavor classifications as affected by disratings in body, color, and salt characteristics.</textblock>
    <textblock>When the disratings for body, color, and salt exceed the permitted amount of (1/2) for any flavor classification, the final U.S. grade shall be lowered accordingly:</textblock>
    <textblock>§58.2432</textblock>
    <textblock>Optional tests.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) There are optional tests (not mandatory for grade designation) that may be made on whipped butter that can be requested by the buyer or seller. If requested, the product must comply with the microbiological and keeping-quality specifications as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proteolytic count_not more than 50 per gram</textblock>
    <textblock>Yeast and mold count_not more than 10 per gram</textblock>
    <textblock>Coliform count_not more than 10 per gram</textblock>
    <textblock>Keeping-quality test_satisfactory after 7 days at 70</textblock>
    <textblock>○F.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) All required tests, and optional tests when specified, shall be performed in accordance with the test methods identified in §58.2434.</textblock>
    <textblock>§58.2433</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. grade not assignable.</textblock>
    <textblock>Whipped butter shall not be assigned a U.S. grade for one or more of the following reasons:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The butter fails to meet or exceed the requirements for U.S. Grade A.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The butter, when tested, does not comply with the provisions of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, or the minimum milkfat requirements of 80.0 percent.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The butter is produced in a plant that is rated ineligible for USDA grading service or is not USDA-approved.</textblock>
    <textblock>§58.2434</textblock>
    <textblock>Test methods.</textblock>
    <textblock>Testing methods contained in the latest edition of the ``Standard Methods for the Examination of Dairy Products'' or the ``Official Methods of Analysis of the Association of Official Analytical Chemists'' are used to determine bacterial estimates and milkfat content.</textblock>
    <textblock>Explanation of Terms</textblock>
    <textblock>§58.2435</textblock>
    <textblock>Explanation of terms.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) With respect to flavor intensity and characteristics:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Slight.</textblock>
    <textblock>Detected only upon critical examination.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Definite.</textblock>
    <textblock>Not intense but detectable.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Acid.</textblock>
    <textblock>Lacks a delicate flavor or aroma and is associated with an acid condition but there is no indication of sourness.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>Aged.</textblock>
    <textblock>Characterized by lack of freshness.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)</textblock>
    <textblock>Bitter.</textblock>
    <textblock>Astringent, similar to taste of quinine and produces a puckery sensation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6)</textblock>
    <textblock>Coarse.</textblock>
    <textblock>Lacks a fine, delicate, smooth flavor.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7)</textblock>
    <textblock>Cooked.</textblock>
    <textblock>Smooth, nutty-like characteristic resembling a custard flavor.</textblock>
    <textblock>(8)</textblock>
    <textblock>Feed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Aromatic flavor characteristic of the feed eaten by cows.</textblock>
    <textblock>(9)</textblock>
    <textblock>Flat.</textblock>
    <textblock>Lacks natural butter flavor.</textblock>
    <textblock>(10)</textblock>
    <textblock>Smothered.</textblock>
    <textblock>Suggestive of improperly cooked cream.</textblock>
    <textblock>(11)</textblock>
    <textblock>Storage.</textblock>
    <textblock>Characterized by a lack of freshness and more intensified than ``aged'' flavor.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) With respect to body:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Free moisture.</textblock>
    <textblock>``Free moisture'' is present when beads of moisture are visible on the surface of the sample. The intensity is described as ``slight'' when the droplets or beads of moisture are barely visible, few in number, and about the size of a pinhead; and ``definite'' when the moisture droplets are clearly visible, more numerous, and are somewhat larger in size.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Mealy or grainy.</textblock>
    <textblock>A ``mealy'' or ``grainy'' condition imparts a granular consistency when the whipped butter is melted on the tongue. The intensity is described as ``slight'' when the mealiness or graininess is barely detectable; and ``definite'' when the mealiness or graininess is clearly detectable.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) With respect to color:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Mottled.</textblock>
    <textblock>``Mottled'' appears as a dappled condition with spots of lighter and deeper shades of yellow. The intensity is described as ``slight'' when the small spots of different shades of yellow, irregular in shape, are barely discernible on the sample of whipped butter; and ``definite'' when the mottles are more clearly discernible.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Color specks.</textblock>
    <textblock>``Specks'' usually appear in whipped butter as small white or yellow spots. The intensity is described as ``slight'' when the spots are few in number; and ``definite'' when they are noticeable in larger numbers.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Wavy.</textblock>
    <textblock>``Wavy'' color in whipped butter is an unevenness in the color that appears as waves of different shades of yellow. The intensity is described as ``slight'' when the waves are barely discernible; and ``definite'' when they are readily noticeable.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) With respect to salt:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Gritty.</textblock>
    <textblock>A ``gritty'' salt condition imparts a sand-like feeling on the tongue due to grains of undissolved salt. The intensity is described as ``slight'' when only a few grains of undissolved salt are detected; and ``definite'' when the condition is more readily noticeable.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Sharp.</textblock>
    <textblock>``Sharp'' salt is characterized by taste sensations suggestive of salt. The intensity is described as ``slight'' when the salt taste predominates in flavor; and ``definite'' when the taste distinctly predominates in flavor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table</textblock>
    <textblock>III</textblock>
    <textblock>1Flavor classification</textblock>
    <textblock>1Total disratings</textblock>
    <textblock>1U.S. grade</textblock>
    <textblock>AA</textblock>
    <textblock>␣1/2</textblock>
    <textblock>AA</textblock>
    <textblock>AA</textblock>
    <textblock>␣1</textblock>
    <textblock>A</textblock>
    <textblock>AA</textblock>
    <textblock>␣11/2</textblock>
    <textblock>(*)</textblock>
    <textblock>A</textblock>
    <textblock>␣1/2</textblock>
    <textblock>A</textblock>
    <textblock>A</textblock>
    <textblock>␣1</textblock>
    <textblock>(*)</textblock>
    <textblock>(*)</textblock>
    <textblock>=</textblock>
    <textblock>No U.S. grade assigned.</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lon Hatamiya,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-425 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
