<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00114</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 20 CFR Part 422</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedure, Freedom of information, Organization and functions (government agencies), Social security.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: September 1, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lawrence H. Thompson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Principal Deputy Commissioner of Social Security.</textblock>
    <textblock>Approved: December 22, 1993.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna E. Shalala,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of Health and Human Services.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set out in the preamble, we propose to amend part 422 of chapter III of title 20 of the Code of Federal Regulations as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 422_ORGANIZATION AND PROCEDURES</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for Subpart C continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Secs. 205, 221, 1102, 1869, and 1871 of the Social Security Act; 42 U.S.C. 405, 421, 1302, 1395ff, and 1395hh; sec. 413(b) of the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977; 30 U.S.C. 923(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 422.205 is amended by revising paragraph (c) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง422.205</textblock>
    <textblock>Review by Appeals Council.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The denial of a request for review of a hearing decision concerning a determination under ยง422.203(a)(1) shall be by such appeals officer or appeals officers or by such member or members of the Appeals Council as may be designated in the manner prescribed by the Chair or Deputy Chair. The denial of a request for review of a hearing dismissal, the dismissal of a request for review, or the refusal of a request to reopen a hearing or Appeals Council decision concerning a determination under ยง422.203(a)(1) shall be by such member or members of the Appeals Council as may be designated in the manner prescribed by the Chair or Deputy Chair.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-481 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4190-29-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
