<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00101</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(ii) The applicant shall have in place either:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) A legally binding agreement or other legally enforceable</textblock>
    <textblock>mechanism that permits it to recover from the sponsor or owner the</textblock>
    <textblock>full amount of the AHP subsidy provided to the project in the</textblock>
    <textblock>event of a sponsor's or owner's fraud or willful non-compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>with respect to the requirements of this part; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) If the Bank agrees and such an agreement is legally</textblock>
    <textblock>enforceable, a three-party agreement that includes the Bank, the</textblock>
    <textblock>sponsor or owner and the applicant that permits the Bank to</textblock>
    <textblock>recover from the sponsor or owner the full amount of the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy provided to the project in the event of a sponsor's or</textblock>
    <textblock>owner's fraud or willful non-compliance with respect to the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The Board in its discretion may grant a waiver of any</textblock>
    <textblock>required remedial actions under this paragraph (a) upon written</textblock>
    <textblock>request by the Bank, applicant, sponsor or owner.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Other types of non-compliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the event of an</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant's, sponsor's or owner's non-compliance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of this part that is not willful, such as due to</textblock>
    <textblock>inadvertent errors by such party or changes in circumstances that</textblock>
    <textblock>are outside such party's control, the Bank shall provide the party</textblock>
    <textblock>a reasonable period of time in which to take reasonable efforts,</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to a compliance plan approved by the Bank, to remedy the</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance. The Bank in its discretion may exclude the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant, sponsor or owner from participation in the AHP while</textblock>
    <textblock>such party is under a compliance plan, or in its discretion may</textblock>
    <textblock>require the applicant to increase the long-term period committed</textblock>
    <textblock>to in its AHP application for the project by the amount of time</textblock>
    <textblock>the project has been in non-compliance. If the applicant, sponsor or owner takes no reasonable efforts to comply with the compliance plan, then such party is in willful</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance with the requirements of this part and is subject</textblock>
    <textblock>to the remedial actions contained in paragraph (a) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section. If the applicant, sponsor or owner takes reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>efforts pursuant to the compliance plan to remedy the</textblock>
    <textblock>non-compliance under this paragraph (b) and such efforts are</textblock>
    <textblock>unsuccessful, the applicant, sponsor or owner would be subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>the remedial actions contained in paragraph (a) of this section,</textblock>
    <textblock>but may apply to the Bank for a waiver of any such required</textblock>
    <textblock>remedial actions. The Bank shall report to the Board in writing</textblock>
    <textblock>on any waivers approved pursuant to this paragraph (b) within 30</textblock>
    <textblock>calendar days of such approval.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Sale of AHP-assisted owner-occupied housing unit to</textblock>
    <textblock>income-ineligible household.</textblock>
    <textblock>Except as provided in paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)(3) of this section, in the event that a household sells its</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP-assisted owner-occupied housing unit to a household whose</textblock>
    <textblock>income exceeds the level committed to in the AHP application prior</textblock>
    <textblock>to the end of the required long-term period, then the provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>of either paragraph (c)(1) or (2) of this section shall apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) If the Bank provided a direct subsidy to the applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>which was passed on as a grant to the seller, the Bank shall</textblock>
    <textblock>require the seller to repay a</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>share, except for</textblock>
    <textblock>de</textblock>
    <textblock>minimis</textblock>
    <textblock>amounts, of the grant received by such seller, reduced for</textblock>
    <textblock>every year the seller owned the unit, to be repaid from any net</textblock>
    <textblock>gain from the sale of the unit after deduction for sales expenses,</textblock>
    <textblock>and to be returned to the Bank, except that the Bank in its</textblock>
    <textblock>discretion may waive such requirement if the imposition of such</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement will cause undue hardship on the seller, as defined by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Bank in its AHP implementation plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If the Bank provided a subsidized advance to the applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>and the applicant provided a below market rate loan to the seller,</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicant shall either repay to the Bank that portion of the</textblock>
    <textblock>advance used to make the loan to the seller or the Bank shall</textblock>
    <textblock>convert that portion of the advance used to make the loan to the</textblock>
    <textblock>seller to a market rate advance with an interest rate equal to the</textblock>
    <textblock>market rate of interest at the time the advance was made, and any</textblock>
    <textblock>unused AHP subsidy which had been set aside by the Bank to</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidize that portion of the advance used to make the loan to the</textblock>
    <textblock>seller shall be made available by the Bank for additional AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The requirements of paragraphs (c)(1) and (2) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section shall not apply provided the sponsor, pursuant to a</textblock>
    <textblock>legally binding agreement with the Bank, assists another household</textblock>
    <textblock>with an income at or below the level committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application in the manner originally committed to in the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Sale of AHP-assisted rental housing project.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the event</textblock>
    <textblock>that the owner of an AHP-assisted rental housing project sells the</textblock>
    <textblock>project prior to the end of the long-term period during which the</textblock>
    <textblock>project's rental units, or portion thereof, must remain affordable</textblock>
    <textblock>for and occupied by households with incomes at or below the levels</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application, and the purchaser does not</textblock>
    <textblock>agree to maintain the project according to such commitments and to</textblock>
    <textblock>be subject to the same restrictions on resale that applied to the</textblock>
    <textblock>seller, then the provisions of either paragraph (d)(1) or (2) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section shall apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) If the Bank provided a direct subsidy to the applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>which was passed on as a grant to the seller, the Bank shall</textblock>
    <textblock>require the seller to repay a</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>share, except for</textblock>
    <textblock>de</textblock>
    <textblock>minimis</textblock>
    <textblock>amounts, of the grant received by such seller, reduced for</textblock>
    <textblock>every year the seller owned the unit, to be repaid from any net</textblock>
    <textblock>gain from the sale of the project after deduction for sales</textblock>
    <textblock>expenses, and to be returned to the Bank, except that the Bank in</textblock>
    <textblock>its discretion may waive such requirement if the imposition of</textblock>
    <textblock>such requirement will cause undue hardship on the seller, as</textblock>
    <textblock>defined by the Bank in its AHP implementation plan; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If the Bank provided a subsidized advance to the applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>and the applicant provided a below market rate loan to the seller,</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicant shall either repay the advance to the Bank or the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank shall convert the advance to a market rate advance with an</textblock>
    <textblock>interest rate equal to the market rate of interest at the time the</textblock>
    <textblock>advance was made, and any unused AHP subsidy which had been set</textblock>
    <textblock>aside by the Bank to subsidize the advance shall be made available</textblock>
    <textblock>by the Bank for additional AHP projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart I_AHP Applications Involving Loan Funds and Loan</textblock>
    <textblock>Consortia</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
