<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00055</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(2) Definitions of ``low- or moderate-income household'' and</textblock>
    <textblock>``very low-income household''. Section 10(j)(13)(A) of the Act defines the term ``low- or</textblock>
    <textblock>moderate-income household'' as a household which has an income of</textblock>
    <textblock>80 percent or less of the area median. 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(13)(A).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 10(j)(13)(B) of the Act defines the term ``very low-income</textblock>
    <textblock>household'' as a household that has an income of 50 percent or less</textblock>
    <textblock>of the area median.</textblock>
    <textblock>Id.</textblock>
    <textblock>section 1430(j)(13)(B). Thus, the term low- or moderate-income household incorporates households that meet the</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of very low-income household.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board's existing AHP regulation defines ``low- and</textblock>
    <textblock>moderate-income households'' as households for which the aggregate</textblock>
    <textblock>income is 80 percent or less of the area median income, and ``very</textblock>
    <textblock>low-income households'' as households for which the aggregate</textblock>
    <textblock>income is 50 percent or less of the area median income. See</textblock>
    <textblock>12 CFR 960.1(g), (o). ``Median income'' is defined as ``the median</textblock>
    <textblock>family income for an area as determined and published by the U.S.</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Housing and Urban Development.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Id.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.1(h).</textblock>
    <textblock>``Area'' is defined as ``a metropolitan statistical area, a county,</textblock>
    <textblock>or a nonmetropolitan area, as established by the U.S. Office of</textblock>
    <textblock>Management and Budget.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Id.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.1(c).</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Adjustments of income limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>On November 5, 1993, the Board published a proposed rule to</textblock>
    <textblock>amend the definitions of these terms. See 58 FR 58988</textblock>
    <textblock>(November 5, 1993). As discussed in the preamble to the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>amendment, under section 3 of the United States Housing Act of</textblock>
    <textblock>1937, the Secretary of the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban</textblock>
    <textblock>Development (Secretary) establishes income limits to be used in</textblock>
    <textblock>determining whether a family qualifies as a ``low-income family'' or</textblock>
    <textblock>as a ``very low-income family'' that is eligible to receive</textblock>
    <textblock>assistance under the Department of Housing and Urban Development's</textblock>
    <textblock>(HUD) housing programs. See 42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)(2). These income</textblock>
    <textblock>limits are calculated as a percentage of the median income of a</textblock>
    <textblock>four-person family living in a particular area. In general, the</textblock>
    <textblock>income limit for qualifying as a ``low-income family'' is set at 80</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of the area median income, and the income limit for</textblock>
    <textblock>qualifying as a ``very low-income family'' is set at 50 percent of</textblock>
    <textblock>the area median income.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary may adjust the income limits for very low-income</textblock>
    <textblock>families and low-income families upward or downward to take into</textblock>
    <textblock>account unusually high or low family incomes in an area. See</textblock>
    <textblock>id.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, the income limit for low-income families may be</textblock>
    <textblock>adjusted to take into account prevailing levels of construction</textblock>
    <textblock>costs. See</textblock>
    <textblock>id.</textblock>
    <textblock>Then an adjustment in this figure is made to</textblock>
    <textblock>establish the comparable income limits for larger and smaller</textblock>
    <textblock>families living in the area. See</textblock>
    <textblock>id.</textblock>
    <textblock>In 31 higher-income metropolitan statistical areas (MSAs) and</textblock>
    <textblock>18 counties, the Secretary adjusts the area-based income limit for</textblock>
    <textblock>a four-person, low-income family downward if it would otherwise</textblock>
    <textblock>exceed the U.S. median income for a four-person family. In these</textblock>
    <textblock>areas, the Secretary caps the income limit for a four-person,</textblock>
    <textblock>low-income family at the U.S. median income for a four-person</textblock>
    <textblock>family.</textblock>
    <textblock>In four MSAs and 107 counties, the Secretary adjusts the</textblock>
    <textblock>area-based income limit for four-person, very low- and low-income</textblock>
    <textblock>families downward because housing costs are low compared to</textblock>
    <textblock>incomes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Adjusting the income limit downward decreases the number of</textblock>
    <textblock>households in an area that are eligible to receive assistance</textblock>
    <textblock>under HUD's housing programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>As discussed in the proposed amendment, the Board believes that</textblock>
    <textblock>affordable housing financed through the AHP should be available to</textblock>
    <textblock>the greatest number of households possible, within the limits</textblock>
    <textblock>established by the Act. Further, households should not be</textblock>
    <textblock>excluded from affordable housing in a particular local market on</textblock>
    <textblock>the basis that housing costs are lower or household incomes are</textblock>
    <textblock>higher in that market than in other regions of the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applying the income limits that have been adjusted downward for</textblock>
    <textblock>prevailing construction costs, low housing costs, or unusually</textblock>
    <textblock>high household incomes for purposes of administering the AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>reduces the number of households eligible to live in affordable</textblock>
    <textblock>housing financed through the AHP. This limits a member's ability</textblock>
    <textblock>to use funds under the AHP to fulfill its obligation under the</textblock>
    <textblock>Community Reinvestment Act. See 12 U.S.C. 2901 et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>It also</textblock>
    <textblock>limits a member's ability to use funds under the AHP to meet the</textblock>
    <textblock>``community investment or service'' requirement of section 10(g) of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Act, 12 U.S.C. 1430(g), and the Board's Community Support</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulation, 12 CFR part 936.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, the Board is proposing that in administering the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP and in defining the standards governing the ``community</textblock>
    <textblock>investment or service'' requirement of the Act, the income limits</textblock>
    <textblock>used to determine whether a household in a particular area</textblock>
    <textblock>qualifies as a ``very low-income household'' or as a ``low- or</textblock>
    <textblock>moderate-income household'' should not be adjusted downward based</textblock>
    <textblock>on prevailing construction costs, low housing costs, or unusually</textblock>
    <textblock>high household incomes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, as set forth in the Board's proposed amendment,</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.1 of this proposed rule defines ``low- or moderate-income</textblock>
    <textblock>household'' as a household which has an income of 80 percent or</textblock>
    <textblock>less of the median income for the area, as adjusted and published</textblock>
    <textblock>by HUD, except in areas where the Secretary adjusts this figure</textblock>
    <textblock>downward because of prevailing construction costs, low housing</textblock>
    <textblock>costs, or unusually high household incomes. For areas where the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary makes this downward adjustment, ``low- or moderate-income</textblock>
    <textblock>household'' would be defined to mean a household which has an</textblock>
    <textblock>income of 80 percent or less of the median income for the area, as</textblock>
    <textblock>published by HUD, with adjustment for household size, but without</textblock>
    <textblock>the adjustments made by the Secretary for prevailing construction</textblock>
    <textblock>costs, low housing costs, or unusually high household incomes.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
