<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00053</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>For various tax reasons, sponsors prefer to structure LIHTC</textblock>
    <textblock>projects so that the AHP direct subsidy is lent to the project for</textblock>
    <textblock>a specific long-term period, with principal and interest payments</textblock>
    <textblock>deferred until the end of such term. The lending of a direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy by a sponsor raises the question whether the subsidy is</textblock>
    <textblock>being passed on to the ultimate recipient, as required under</textblock>
    <textblock>section 10(j)(9)(E) of the Act and proposed §960.4(b)(1)(i),</textblock>
    <textblock>since the subsidy ultimately is being repaid to the Bank. See</textblock>
    <textblock>12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(9)(E). The Board believes that the lending of a</textblock>
    <textblock>direct subsidy for the long-term period of income eligibility and</textblock>
    <textblock>affordability required by §960.5 of the proposed rule, with all</textblock>
    <textblock>principal and interest payments deferred until the end of such</textblock>
    <textblock>term, satisfies section 10(j)(9)(E) and proposed §960.4(b)(1)(i),</textblock>
    <textblock>because the project will have had the use of such funds for the</textblock>
    <textblock>period the project must remain occupied by and affordable for low-</textblock>
    <textblock>or moderate-income households, even though the funds may be repaid</textblock>
    <textblock>at the end of such term. As discussed below, §960.5(a)(1) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule defines this long-term period generally as not less</textblock>
    <textblock>than 30 years for rental housing projects. Accordingly, the</textblock>
    <textblock>direct subsidy must be lent for a term of 30 years or more, with</textblock>
    <textblock>all principal and interest payments deferred until the end of such</textblock>
    <textblock>term.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.4(b)(4) of the proposed rule provides that if an</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant receives a subsidized advance or a direct subsidy from a</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank, and in turn provides both a loan and a grant to a borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>and charges an origination fee for providing the loan, then any</textblock>
    <textblock>fee charged by the applicant for providing the grant may not be</textblock>
    <textblock>paid with the AHP subsidized advance or direct subsidy. The fee</textblock>
    <textblock>may not be paid with the AHP subsidized advance because the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant has already covered the underwriting costs for the loan</textblock>
    <textblock>and the grant in its origination fee for the loan. The fee may</textblock>
    <textblock>not be paid with the direct subsidy because otherwise the entire</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of the AHP subsidy would not be passed through to the</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower, as required by section 10(j)(9)(E) of the Act and</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed §960.4(b)(1)(i). See 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(9)(E).</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Long-term Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Owner-occupied housing units.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Long-term requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 10(j)(1) of the Act states that pursuant to regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>promulgated by the Board, each Bank shall establish a Program to</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidize the interest rate on advances to members engaged in</textblock>
    <textblock>lending for long-term, low- and moderate-income, owner-occupied</textblock>
    <textblock>housing at subsidized interest rates.</textblock>
    <textblock>Id.</textblock>
    <textblock>§1430(j)(1). In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition, section 10(j)(2)(A) of the Act states that the Board's</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations shall permit Bank members to use subsidized advances</textblock>
    <textblock>received from the Banks to finance homeownership by families with</textblock>
    <textblock>incomes at or below 80 percent of the median income for the area.</textblock>
    <textblock>Id.</textblock>
    <textblock>§1430(j)(2)(A).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Act permits more than one possible interpretation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement that owner-occupied housing must be ``long-term.'' One</textblock>
    <textblock>way to interpret this requirement is that owner-occupied housing</textblock>
    <textblock>units assisted under the AHP must be added to and retained as part</textblock>
    <textblock>of the stock of affordable housing for a long-term period.</textblock>
    <textblock>Alternatively, the Act may be interpreted to require that under</textblock>
    <textblock>the AHP, assistance must be provided to low- or moderate-income</textblock>
    <textblock>households to make owner-occupied housing units affordable to such</textblock>
    <textblock>households for as long as they own the unit. These two possible</textblock>
    <textblock>interpretations are incorporated in options A and B described</textblock>
    <textblock>below. The Board specifically requests comments on these two</textblock>
    <textblock>options.</textblock>
    <textblock>Option A. Under option A, the long-term requirement would be met by</textblock>
    <textblock>providing that owner-occupied housing units be required to be</textblock>
    <textblock>retained as affordable units for 30 years or, at the election of</textblock>
    <textblock>the sponsor, the remaining useful life of the units, regardless of</textblock>
    <textblock>changes in occupancy. In order to enforce this retention</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement, owner-occupied units assisted with a loan or a grant</textblock>
    <textblock>under the AHP would have to be subject to a deed restriction or</textblock>
    <textblock>other legally enforceable mechanism restricting transfer of the</textblock>
    <textblock>unit to a low- or moderate-income household if the unit were sold</textblock>
    <textblock>within 30 years of the purchase, construction, or rehabilitation</textblock>
    <textblock>or prior to the end of the remaining useful life of the unit, as</textblock>
    <textblock>the case may be.</textblock>
    <textblock>A household purchasing such a unit would have to qualify as a</textblock>
    <textblock>low- or moderate-income household only at the time of purchase or</textblock>
    <textblock>at the time of closing on the financing for the unit. A household</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitating a unit would have to qualify as a low- or</textblock>
    <textblock>moderate-income household only at the time the household received</textblock>
    <textblock>a commitment for funding through the AHP.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
