<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00061</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(7) A disclosure of whether or not the applicant has a direct</textblock>
    <textblock>or indirect interest in the property or project. If the applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>has an interest in the property and the application is approved,</textblock>
    <textblock>then prior to the transfer of AHP funds to the project, an</textblock>
    <textblock>independent current appraisal of the fair market value of such</textblock>
    <textblock>property must be provided, unless the applicant demonstrates that</textblock>
    <textblock>the property is being sold or otherwise transferred to the sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>at a price substantially below the fair market value;</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) A statement of the project's costs; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) A certification from the applicant's, the sponsor's and the</textblock>
    <textblock>loan fund's or loan consortium's board of directors, or president</textblock>
    <textblock>or senior officer if so delegated by the board of directors, that</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicant, the sponsor and the loan fund or loan consortium</textblock>
    <textblock>will comply with all requirements of this part and all obligations</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.4(c) of the Board's existing AHP regulation also</textblock>
    <textblock>generally requires an applicant to include in its AHP application</textblock>
    <textblock>the information identified in paragraphs (3) through (6) above, as</textblock>
    <textblock>well as any other information the Bank may require. See 12 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>960.4(c).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.4(c)(6) of the Board's existing AHP regulation also</textblock>
    <textblock>requires an applicant to disclose in its AHP application any</textblock>
    <textblock>direct or indirect interest of the applicant in the property or project. See 12 CFR 960.4(c)(6). Under §960.7(a)(7) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule, if such an interest exists and the application is</textblock>
    <textblock>approved, then prior to the transfer of AHP funds to the project,</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicant generally is required to provide an appraisal of the</textblock>
    <textblock>property or project. This is to ensure that the sales price of</textblock>
    <textblock>such property or project owned by the applicant has not been</textblock>
    <textblock>inflated and that the applicant is not receiving the benefit of</textblock>
    <textblock>the AHP subsidy.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.4(c)(7) of the Board's existing AHP regulation</textblock>
    <textblock>requires the applicant to include in its AHP application an</textblock>
    <textblock>explanation of how the applicant intends to monitor the use of any</textblock>
    <textblock>funds received under the AHP, including an explanation of how the</textblock>
    <textblock>structure of the project ensures that a preponderance of the</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidy is ultimately received by the targeted beneficiaries. See</textblock>
    <textblock>12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(9)(D); 12 CFR 960.4(c)(7). As discussed in</textblock>
    <textblock>greater detail in the monitoring section below, as long as</textblock>
    <textblock>adequate monitoring is otherwise provided for, the proposed rule</textblock>
    <textblock>does not require the applicant in all instances to monitor the</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP-assisted project for compliance with the long-term requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>of the proposed rule. Accordingly, this provision of the existing</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation is deleted in the proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.4(c)(8) of the Board's existing AHP regulation</textblock>
    <textblock>requires the applicant to certify that the maximum subsidy</textblock>
    <textblock>limitation requirements of the AHP rule will not be violated. See</textblock>
    <textblock>12 CFR 960.4(c)(8). However, since the maximum subsidy limitation</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements are threshold requirements that all AHP applications</textblock>
    <textblock>must satisfy (see discussion below of the 20 percent requirement),</textblock>
    <textblock>this requirement is incorporated into proposed §960.7(a)(9),</textblock>
    <textblock>which provides generally that the applicant and sponsor must</textblock>
    <textblock>certify that all requirements of the AHP regulation will be</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfied.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.4(c)(8) of the Board's existing AHP regulation also</textblock>
    <textblock>requires the applicant to explain in its AHP application how any</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP subsidy that exceeds the maximum subsidy requirements will be</textblock>
    <textblock>recaptured. See 12 CFR 960.4(c)(8). Since AHP applications must</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfy the threshold maximum subsidy limitation requirements at</textblock>
    <textblock>the outset in order to be scored and approved for AHP funding,</textblock>
    <textblock>this issue does not arise and therefore has been deleted in the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>As discussed above, the requirement in §960.4(c)(9) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board's existing AHP regulation that the applicant's managing</textblock>
    <textblock>officer must certify that the AHP subsidy shall be only for</textblock>
    <textblock>authorized uses is expanded in proposed §960.7(a)(9) to require a</textblock>
    <textblock>certification by the applicant, the sponsor and the loan fund or</textblock>
    <textblock>loan consortium not only that funds received under the AHP will be</textblock>
    <textblock>used for authorized uses, but also a certification of compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>with all requirements of the AHP regulation and all obligations</textblock>
    <textblock>committed to in the AHP application. See 12 CFR 960.4(c)(9). In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition, the proposed rule requires the applicant, the sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>and the loan fund or loan consortium, not just the applicant, as</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Board's existing AHP regulation, to make the certification</textblock>
    <textblock>in the AHP application. This change is proposed because the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicant, the sponsor and the loan fund or loan consortium are</textblock>
    <textblock>all subject to specific requirements under the AHP and therefore</textblock>
    <textblock>should be required to certify that they will comply with such</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Action on Applications</textblock>
    <textblock>As discussed above, the proposed rule makes a major change in</textblock>
    <textblock>the Board's existing AHP regulation by taking the Board out of the</textblock>
    <textblock>approval process for AHP applications. Section 960.7(b)(1) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule provides that each Bank shall review, score and take</textblock>
    <textblock>action on an AHP application pursuant to the requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>contained in proposed §§960.8, 960.9 and 960.10, and shall notify</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicant of such action no later than 60 calendar days after</textblock>
    <textblock>the application due date for the AHP funding cycle. Section</textblock>
    <textblock>960.5(f)(1) of the existing regulation requires the Banks to</textblock>
    <textblock>forward to the Board their recommended applications no later than</textblock>
    <textblock>30 days after each offering deadline. See 12 CFR 960.5(f)(1).</textblock>
    <textblock>Since the Banks would have greater responsibilities in the</textblock>
    <textblock>approval process under the proposed rule, the 30-day period is</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed to be extended to 60 calendar days.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.7(b)(2) of the proposed rule provides specifically</textblock>
    <textblock>that the board of directors of each Bank shall have the authority</textblock>
    <textblock>to approve or disapprove AHP applications received, and may</textblock>
    <textblock>delegate such authority to the president or other senior officers</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Bank.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
