<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00026</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Draft Fishery Management Plan for Corals, Plants, and Associated Invertebrates for Puerto Rico and the U.S. Virgin Islands</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[I.D. 010394B]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of public hearings and request for comments.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Caribbean Fishery Management Council will hold public hearings on the Draft Fishery Management Plan for Corals, Plants, and Associated Invertebrates for Puerto Rico and the U.S. Virgin Islands (FMP).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments on the draft FMP should be submitted on or before February 15, 1994. See</textblock>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION</textblock>
    <textblock>for dates, time, and location of the public hearings.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send written comments to Miguel A. Rolón, Executive Director, Caribbean Fishery Management Council, 268 Muñoz Rivera Avenue, suite 1108, San Juan, Puerto Rico 0918-2577.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Miguel A. Rolón, (809) 753-6910.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The draft FMP proposes the following management measures: (1) Prohibit the harvest or possession of stony corals, whether dead or alive, except for legally permitted research, education, and restoration programs; (2) prohibit the harvest or possession of sea fans and gorgonians (octocorals) and any species in the fishery management unit if attached or existing upon live-rock, live or dead, except for legally permitted research, education, and restoration programs; (3) prohibit the sale or possession of any prohibited species unless the specimen entered the management area in interstate or international commerce and is fully documented as to point of origin; (4) prohibit the use of chemical, plants or plant-derived toxins, and explosives to harvest organisms in the coral fishery management unit, except for legally permitted research, education, and restoration programs; (5) limit harvest of fishery management unit organisms except for those listed in Appendix A, to hand-held dip-nets, slurp guns, hand and other non-habitat destructive gear, except for legally permitted research, education, and restoration programs; (6) require an annual permit to harvest or possess organisms in the fishery management unit; (7) require collectors, dealers, and exporters of species managed under the coral plan to acquire an annual permit, to submit monthly records and report harvest, shipments, and unit cost; and (8) establish a Marine Conservation District (MCD) in the exclusive economic zone, due south of St. John, U.S. Virgin Islands, within the coordinates specified below; no possession while moored, fishing, or harvesting of any organisms will be allowed in the MCD; no anchoring will be allowed in the MCD. Exceptions to the above restrictions are allowed for legally permitted research, education, and restoration programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>All hearings will be held from 7 p.m. to 10 p.m. and are scheduled on the following dates at the following locations:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Tuesday, February 1, 1994_Conference Room, Legislature Building, Charlotte Amalie, St. Thomas, U.S. Virgin Islands.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Wednesday, February 2, 1994_Boulon Center, Legislature Room, St. John, U.S. Virgin Islands.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Thursday, February 3, 1994_Conference Room, Legislature Building, Christiansted, St. Croix, U.S. Virgin Islands.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Tuesday, February 8, 1994_Conference Room, Hotel Antibes, Cabo Rojo, Puerto Rico.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Wednesday, February 9, 1994_Restaurant Mesón Criollo, Road 987 Km 3.2, Las Croabas, Fajardo, Puerto Rico.</textblock>
    <textblock>Testimony may be presented at any of the hearings. Copies of the draft FMP are available (see</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 5, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <table>
    <textblock>Proposed Coordinates for Marine Conservation District</textblock>
    <textblock>1Point</textblock>
    <textblock>1Latitude</textblock>
    <textblock>1Longitude</textblock>
    <textblock>A</textblock>
    <textblock>18</textblock>
    <textblock>○15.3</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N.</textblock>
    <textblock>64</textblock>
    <textblock>○46.9</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W.</textblock>
    <textblock>B</textblock>
    <textblock>18</textblock>
    <textblock>○15.0</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N.</textblock>
    <textblock>64</textblock>
    <textblock>○42.2</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W.</textblock>
    <textblock>C</textblock>
    <textblock>18</textblock>
    <textblock>○10.0</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N.</textblock>
    <textblock>64</textblock>
    <textblock>○42.2</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W.</textblock>
    <textblock>D</textblock>
    <textblock>18</textblock>
    <textblock>○10.0</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N.</textblock>
    <textblock>64</textblock>
    <textblock>○46.9</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W.</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David S. Crestin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Office of Fisheries Conservation and Management, National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-504 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
