<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00002</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-2-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Summer Food Service Program for Children; Program Reimbursement for 1994</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Food and Nutrition Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Food and Nutrition Service, USDA.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice informs the public of the annual adjustments to the reimbursement rates for meals served in the Summer Food Service Program for Children (SFSP). These adjustments reflect changes in the Consumer Price Index and are required by the statute governing the Program.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Robert M. Eadie, Chief, Policy and Program Development Branch, Child Nutrition Division, Food and Nutrition Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Alexandria, Virginia 22302, (703) 305-2620.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This action is not a rule as defined by the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. 601-612) and thus is exempt from the provisions of that Act. In accordance with the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. 3507), no new recordkeeping or reporting requirements have been included that are subject to approval from the Office of Management and Budget.</textblock>
    <textblock>This program is listed in the Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance under No. 10.559 and is subject to the provisions of Executive Order 12372 which requires intergovernmental consultation with State and local officials, (7 CFR part 3015, subpart V, and final rule related notice published at 48 FR 29114, June 24, 1983).</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions</textblock>
    <textblock>The terms used in this Notice shall have the meaning ascribed to them in the regulations governing the Summer Food Service Program for Children (7 CFR part 225).</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 13 of the National School Lunch Act (42 U.S.C. 1761) and the regulations governing the SFSP (7 CFR part 225), notice is hereby given of adjustments in Program payments for meals served to children participating in the SFSP during the 1994 Program. Adjustments are based on changes in the food away from home series of the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers for the period November 1992 through November 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>The new 1994 reimbursement rates in dollars are as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>The total amount of payments to State agencies for disbursement to Program sponsors will be based upon these Program reimbursement rates and the number of meals of each type served. The above reimbursement rates, before being rounded-off to the nearest quarter-cent, represent a 1.91 per cent increase during 1993 (from 141.5 in November 1992 to 144.2 in November 1993) in the food away from home series of the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers, published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor. Because of the relatively small adjustment, the Department points out that several of the new administrative rates are identical to the rates in effect for the 1993 Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Secs. 9, 13 and 14, National School Lunch Act, as amended (42 U.S.C. 1758, 1761 and 1762a).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <table>
    <textblock>Maximum Per Meal Reimbursement Rates</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Operating Costs:</textblock>
    <textblock>Breakfast</textblock>
    <textblock>1.1600</textblock>
    <textblock>Lunch or Supper</textblock>
    <textblock>2.0825</textblock>
    <textblock>Supplement</textblock>
    <textblock>.5450</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative Costs:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. For meals served at rural or self-preparation sites:</textblock>
    <textblock>Breakfast</textblock>
    <textblock>.1075</textblock>
    <textblock>Lunch or Supper</textblock>
    <textblock>.1975</textblock>
    <textblock>Supplement</textblock>
    <textblock>.0525</textblock>
    <textblock>b. For meals served at other types of sites:</textblock>
    <textblock>Breakfast</textblock>
    <textblock>.0850</textblock>
    <textblock>Lunch or Supper</textblock>
    <textblock>.1650</textblock>
    <textblock>Supplement</textblock>
    <textblock>.0425</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>George A. Braley,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Administrator, Food and Nutrition Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-478 Filed 1-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-30-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
