<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00050</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(1) The Bank's AHP funding cycle schedule, including</textblock>
    <textblock>application due dates, as required by proposed §960.6(a)(1);</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The Bank's priorities, and scoring criteria for</textblock>
    <textblock>applications, as required by proposed §§960.8(a) and 960.10;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The Bank's procedures to ensure satisfaction of the</textblock>
    <textblock>long-term requirement, as required by proposed §960.5 (a)(1) and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b);</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The Bank's requirements for and verification procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>concerning (i) the use of subsidized advances or direct subsidies</textblock>
    <textblock>within a reasonable period of time after approval of an AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>application, as required by proposed §960.12(a), or (ii) the use of loans or grants within a</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonable period of time after repayment of such funds to a loan</textblock>
    <textblock>fund or loan consortium, as required by proposed §960.17(c)(5);</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) The Bank's verification procedures upon initial</textblock>
    <textblock>disbursement of subsidized advances or direct subsidies, as</textblock>
    <textblock>required by proposed §960.13;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) The Bank's monitoring plan, as required by proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.14(b);</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) The Bank's reporting requirements for applicants during the</textblock>
    <textblock>construction or rehabilitation phase, as required by proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.15(b)(2);</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) An explanation of circumstances justifying undue hardship</textblock>
    <textblock>waivers by the Bank of imposition of remedial actions, as required</textblock>
    <textblock>by proposed §960.16 (c)(1) and (d)(1); and</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) The Bank's determination regarding the number of persons</textblock>
    <textblock>that may serve on the Bank's Advisory Council and their terms, as</textblock>
    <textblock>required by proposed §960.21(a)(1) and (4).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.2(c) of the proposed rule provides that the Bank's</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed AHP implementation plan shall be submitted to its</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council at least 45 calendar days before it is considered</textblock>
    <textblock>by the Bank's board of directors. The Advisory Council shall</textblock>
    <textblock>review the proposed plan and submit its recommendations to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank's board of directors at least seven calendar days before the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank's board of directors is scheduled to vote on the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>plan. The Bank's board of directors shall vote on the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP implementation plan, and shall submit its approved plan to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Board for action. The Board shall approve or disapprove the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed plan within 60 calendar days of receipt. The Bank's plan</textblock>
    <textblock>is not effective until it is approved by the Board, and it must</textblock>
    <textblock>become effective at least 45 calendar days before the due date for</textblock>
    <textblock>AHP applications established by the Bank. Each Bank must submit</textblock>
    <textblock>its AHP implementation plan to the Board for approval no later</textblock>
    <textblock>than 180 calendar days after the publication of this rule as a</textblock>
    <textblock>final rule in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.2(d) of the proposed rule provides that the Bank's</textblock>
    <textblock>approved AHP implementation plan shall be made available by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bank to the public upon request.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.2(e) of the proposed rule provides that the Board</textblock>
    <textblock>will approve or disapprove proposed amendments to a Bank's</textblock>
    <textblock>approved AHP implementation plan submitted by the Bank within 60</textblock>
    <textblock>calendar days of receipt.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Authorized and Required Uses of AHP Subsidized Advances or</textblock>
    <textblock>Direct Subsidies</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.3 of the proposed rule states the general</textblock>
    <textblock>authorized uses of AHP subsidized advances and direct subsidies by</textblock>
    <textblock>applicants, §960.4 provides specific examples of such authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>and unauthorized uses and other use requirements, and §960.5 sets</textblock>
    <textblock>forth the long-term income-eligibility, affordability and</textblock>
    <textblock>income-targeting requirements for such uses. These proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>sections are discussed further below.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Authorized Uses of Subsidized Advances or Direct</textblock>
    <textblock>Subsidies</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.3 of the proposed rule, consistent with</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.3(b) (1) and (2) of the Board's existing AHP regulation,</textblock>
    <textblock>provides that applicants may use subsidized advances or direct</textblock>
    <textblock>subsidies received from a Bank under the AHP to either:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Finance the purchase, construction or rehabilitation of</textblock>
    <textblock>owner-occupied housing units by or for low- or moderate-income</textblock>
    <textblock>households; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Finance the purchase, construction or rehabilitation of</textblock>
    <textblock>rental housing units, at least 20 percent of the units of which</textblock>
    <textblock>will be occupied by and affordable for very low-income households.</textblock>
    <textblock>See 12 CFR 960.3(b) (1) and (2).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Specific Use Requirements for Subsidized Advances or</textblock>
    <textblock>Direct Subsidies</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.3(c) of the Board's existing AHP regulation</textblock>
    <textblock>provides that ``Program funds may only be used for direct costs</textblock>
    <textblock>required to produce and/or finance affordable housing units.''</textblock>
    <textblock>12 CFR 960.3(c). A number of questions have arisen as to whether</textblock>
    <textblock>specific types of costs associated with the financing or</textblock>
    <textblock>production of housing may be considered ``direct costs'' for</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of the Board's regulation. Because of the confusion in</textblock>
    <textblock>this area, the Board believes that it would be helpful to set</textblock>
    <textblock>forth in the rule examples of specific types of costs it considers</textblock>
    <textblock>to be authorized and unauthorized for AHP purposes. Accordingly,</textblock>
    <textblock>§960.4(a) (1) and (2) of the proposed rule sets forth examples of</textblock>
    <textblock>specific costs related to the purchase, construction or</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitation of housing that are authorized and unauthorized</textblock>
    <textblock>uses of AHP subsidized advances or direct subsidies. However,</textblock>
    <textblock>because it is impossible to anticipate all types of costs that may</textblock>
    <textblock>arise in the course of financing or producing housing, the list of</textblock>
    <textblock>authorized and unauthorized costs in proposed §960.4(a) is not</textblock>
    <textblock>exclusive. Other costs not included arguably may or may not</textblock>
    <textblock>qualify as costs of financing the purchase, construction or</textblock>
    <textblock>rehabilitation of housing. If an applicant seeks to use funds</textblock>
    <textblock>under the AHP to pay for costs not specifically included in this</textblock>
    <textblock>rule, it should consult with the Bank before submitting its</textblock>
    <textblock>application for approval. The Board specifically asks for</textblock>
    <textblock>comments as to whether these authorized and unauthorized costs are</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
