<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00084</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940110-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Proposed ยง960.20(c) provides that by January 31 of each year,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Board will notify the Banks of the total amount of funds, if</textblock>
    <textblock>any, available in the Affordable Housing Reserve Fund.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.12(d) of the Board's existing regulation governing</textblock>
    <textblock>how any Reserve Funds would be made available to the Banks, is</textblock>
    <textblock>deleted in the proposed rule. See 12 CFR 960.12(d). The Act</textblock>
    <textblock>states that such provisions would be determined pursuant to</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations issued by the Board. See 12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(7). Since</textblock>
    <textblock>there currently are no Reserve Funds and it is not anticipated</textblock>
    <textblock>that there will be any Reserve Funds in the near future, it is not</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary at this time to include provisions in the proposed rule</textblock>
    <textblock>dealing with this issue. The Board can issue regulations on this</textblock>
    <textblock>issue at a future date if such eventuality should arise.</textblock>
    <textblock>P. Advisory Councils</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.21 of the proposed rule sets forth provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>governing the appointment, operation, and responsibilities of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Councils to the Banks.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.21(a)(1) of the proposed rule carries forward the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement in the Board's existing AHP regulation that each Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>shall appoint an Advisory Council of seven to 15 persons who shall</textblock>
    <textblock>reside in the Bank's District and shall be drawn from community</textblock>
    <textblock>and nonprofit organizations actively involved in providing or</textblock>
    <textblock>promoting low- or moderate-income housing in the Bank's District.</textblock>
    <textblock>See 12 CFR 960.14(a). In addition, ยง960.21(a)(1) of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule provides that the size of the Advisory Council shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>stated in the Bank's AHP implementation plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.21(a)(2) of the proposed rule carries forward the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement in the Board's existing AHP regulation that the Bank</textblock>
    <textblock>must actively solicit nominations from Bank members and community</textblock>
    <textblock>and nonprofit organizations and shall allow sufficient time for</textblock>
    <textblock>response, so that the nomination and appointment process is as</textblock>
    <textblock>broad and as participatory as possible. See 12 CFR 960.14(b),</textblock>
    <textblock>(d). The Bank also should solicit nominations from any other</textblock>
    <textblock>interested parties. In addition, ยง960.21(a)(3) of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule provides that Advisory Council members shall be appointed by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Banks giving consideration to the size of the District and the</textblock>
    <textblock>diversity of low-income housing needs within the District.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board's existing AHP regulation provides that officials of</textblock>
    <textblock>state and local housing finance agencies may serve as members of</textblock>
    <textblock>an Advisory Council, provided that such officials do not</textblock>
    <textblock>constitute an undue proportion of the membership of the Advisory</textblock>
    <textblock>Council. See 12 CFR 960.14(c). It has been suggested that such</textblock>
    <textblock>officials should only be able to serve as non-voting members of an</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council, unless the officials also are employed or</textblock>
    <textblock>associated with a private community or nonprofit organization</textblock>
    <textblock>actively involved in providing or promoting low- or</textblock>
    <textblock>moderate-income housing in the Bank's District. This suggestion</textblock>
    <textblock>is based on the view that the Advisory Councils are intended to</textblock>
    <textblock>serve as vehicles for private sector community and nonprofit</textblock>
    <textblock>organizations, not public agencies, to advise the Banks on low-</textblock>
    <textblock>and moderate-income housing programs and needs in the District and</textblock>
    <textblock>on the utilization of Bank advances for such purposes. See</textblock>
    <textblock>12 U.S.C. 1430(j)(11). While acknowledging that officials of</textblock>
    <textblock>state and local housing finance agencies make valuable</textblock>
    <textblock>contributions to the Advisory Councils, the supporters of this</textblock>
    <textblock>viewpoint argue that these agencies have opportunities to</textblock>
    <textblock>influence the allocation of housing finance credit through means</textblock>
    <textblock>other than by voting representation on the Advisory Councils.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board specifically requests comments on whether or not</textblock>
    <textblock>officials of state and local housing finance agencies should be</textblock>
    <textblock>able to vote on the Advisory Councils and whether their</textblock>
    <textblock>representation should be limited so that it does not constitute an</textblock>
    <textblock>undue proportion of the Advisory Council membership.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.21(a)(4) of the proposed rule provides that</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council members shall serve for terms of two or three</textblock>
    <textblock>years, as determined by the Bank and set forth in its AHP</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation plan. The Board is proposing to give the Banks the</textblock>
    <textblock>option of appointing Advisory Council members for three-year terms</textblock>
    <textblock>in order to allow the Banks to benefit from the experience and</textblock>
    <textblock>familiarity with the AHP that Advisory Council members develop the</textblock>
    <textblock>longer they serve on an Advisory Council. In addition,</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง960.21(a)(4) of the proposed rule carries forward the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement in the Board's existing AHP regulation that terms of</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council members shall be staggered to provide continuity</textblock>
    <textblock>and experience in service. See 12 CFR 960.14(f). The proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule requires the Banks to explain in their AHP implementation</textblock>
    <textblock>plans how Advisory Council member terms will be staggered.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 960.21(a)(4) of the proposed rule contains a new</textblock>
    <textblock>provision limiting an Advisory Council member to six years of</textblock>
    <textblock>consecutive service. The Bank may set its own limits on</textblock>
    <textblock>consecutive terms within the six-year limit. This provision is</textblock>
    <textblock>intended to ensure that the membership of the Advisory Councils</textblock>
    <textblock>reflects the diverse and changing viewpoints of private sector</textblock>
    <textblock>community and nonprofit organizations on the low-income housing</textblock>
    <textblock>programs and needs of the Bank Districts.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
