<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00046</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00042</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>General Leasing Policies in the Central and Western Gulf of Mexico Planning Areas Under the Comprehensive Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) Natural Gas and Oil Resource Management Program for 1992-1997</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Minerals Management Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Minerals Management Service (MMS), Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension of comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 7, 1993 (58 FR 64409), MMS published a Call for Public Comment on general policies for leasing natural gas and oil resources in the Central and Western Gulf of Mexico planning areas. Comments were to be received by February 7, 1994. Through this notice, MMS extends the end of the comment period by 30 days, to March 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Responses will be accepted through March 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Responses should be mailed to the Program Director, Office of Program Development and Coordination, Minerals Management Service (MS-4430), 381 Elden Street, Herndon, VA 22070. Hand deliveries may be made at 381 Elden Street, Room 1324, Herndon, Virginia (dial 1215 at lobby telephone). Envelopes or packages should be marked ``Comments on Alternative Leasing Policies for the Gulf of Mexico.'' If any privileged or proprietary information is submitted that the respondent wishes to be treated as confidential, both the envelope and the contents should be marked ``Confidential Information.''</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>For information pertaining to this Call for Public Comment, telephone Paul Stang or Kim Coffman, Program Development and Planning Branch, at (703) 787-1215, or Dan Henry, Leasing Coordination Branch, at (703) 787-1192.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The basic leasing policies for the Central and Western Gulf of Mexico Planning Areas were established a little more than a decade ago. Since that time, many of the conditions facing the OCS program have changed, and MMS and the Department of the Interior are re-evaluating leasing policies for the Central and Western Gulf of Mexico sales remaining under the Comprehensive OCS Natural Gas and Oil Resource Management Program for 1992-1997. Comments will be considered for sales to be held subsequent to Sale 147, which is planned for Spring 1994, and will be factored into studies to determine the effectiveness of the existing system of leasing and what alternatives are most appropriate. Neither MMS nor the Department of the Interior has preferred alternatives, and no decisions have been made to change the existing leasing system.</textblock>
    <textblock>Several parties have requested that the comment period be extended by 60 days. Upon consideration of these requests, MMS has decided that an extension of 30 days, to a total of 92 days, is appropriate. This Call for Public Comment is only part of a continuing opportunity for correspondence and dialog between MMS and interested parties, and it should be noted that the decision process for individual sales explicitly includes consideration of comments from outside parties.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Tom Fry,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Minerals Management Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1065 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-MR-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
