<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00132</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00078</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>VI. Miscellaneous</textblock>
    <textblock>Empowerment Zone designation does not constitute a Federal action for provisions of the Uniform Relocation Act. However, any activity constituting a Federal action that may result from such a designation may be subject to the provision of this Act, as well as any other statutory or regulatory provisions governing the particular Federal action.</textblock>
    <textblock>VII. Other Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The information collection requirements contained in this Notice have been submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) under the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. 3501-3520). No person may be subjected to a penalty for failure to comply with these information collection requirements until they have been approved and assigned an OMB control number. The OMB control number, when assigned, will be announced by separate notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register.</textblock>
    <textblock>Information on the estimated public reporting burden is provided in the preamble of the interim rule implementing this program (7 CFR part 25) published elsewhere in today's</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 12, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Bob J. Nash,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Under Secretary, Small Community and Rural Development.</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix A: EZ/EC State Contacts</textblock>
    <textblock>Alabama</textblock>
    <textblock>Richard Jones, FmHA State Office, 4121 Carmichael Road, Suite 601, Montgomery AL 36106-3683, Ph: 205-279-3400, Fax: 205-279-3484</textblock>
    <textblock>Alaska</textblock>
    <textblock>Darwin Betts, FmHA State Office, 634 S. Bailey, Suite 103, Palmer AK 99645, Ph: 907-745-2176, Fax: 907-745-5398</textblock>
    <textblock>Arkansas</textblock>
    <textblock>Shirley Tucker, FmHA State Office, 700 W. Capitol St., P.O. Box 2778, Little Rock AR 72203, Ph: 501-324-6281, Fax: 501-324-6346</textblock>
    <textblock>Arizona</textblock>
    <textblock>Clark Dierks, FmHA State Office, 3003 N Central Ave, Suite 900, Phoenix AZ 85012, Ph: 602-280-8700, Fax: 602-280-8770</textblock>
    <textblock>California</textblock>
    <textblock>Paula Galvan, FmHA State Office, 194 West Main Street, Suite F, Woodland CA 95695-2915, Ph: 916-668-2000, Fax: 916-668-2055</textblock>
    <textblock>Colorado</textblock>
    <textblock>Judy Jacklich, 655 Parfet Street, Room E 100, Lakewood CO 80215, Ph: 303-236-2806, Fax: 303-236-2854</textblock>
    <textblock>Delaware</textblock>
    <textblock>James Waters, 4611 So Dupont Highway, PO Box 400, Camden DE 19934-9998, Ph: 302-697-4324, Fax: 302-697-4388</textblock>
    <textblock>Florida</textblock>
    <textblock>Jeanie Graham, 4440 N.W. 25th Pl, Gainesville FL 32614-7010, Ph: 904-338-3400, Fax: 904-338-3405</textblock>
    <textblock>Georgia</textblock>
    <textblock>Eugene Carr, 355 E. Hancock Ave., Stephens Federal Bldg., Athens GA 30610, Ph: 706-546-2165, Fax: 706-546-2152</textblock>
    <textblock>Hawaii</textblock>
    <textblock>Ted Matsuo, 154 Waianuenue Ave, Federal Building Rm 311, Hilo HI 89701, Ph: 808-933-3009, Fax: 808-935-1590</textblock>
    <textblock>Idaho</textblock>
    <textblock>Larry Spindler, 3232 Elder St., Boise ID 83705, Ph: 208-334-1836, Fax: 208-334-1712</textblock>
    <textblock>Illinois</textblock>
    <textblock>Charles Specht, 1817 S Neil Street, Suite 103, Champaign IL 61820, Ph: 217-398-5235, Fax: 217-398-5337</textblock>
    <textblock>Indiana</textblock>
    <textblock>Joseph Steele, 5975 Lakeside Blvd., Indianapolis IN 46278, Ph: 317-290-3109, Fax: 317-290-3127</textblock>
    <textblock>Iowa</textblock>
    <textblock>Dorman Otte, 210 Walnut Street, Federal Bldg Rm 873, Des Moines IA 50309, Ph: 515-284-4152, Fax: 515-284-4859</textblock>
    <textblock>Kansas</textblock>
    <textblock>William Kirk, 1200 SW Executive Dr, P.O. Box 4653, Topeka KS 66604, Ph: 913-271-2708, Fax: 913-271-2700</textblock>
    <textblock>Kentucky</textblock>
    <textblock>Robert Letton, FmHA State Office, 771 Corporate Plaza, Suite 200, Lexington KY 40503, Ph: 606-224-7336, Fax: 606-224-7340</textblock>
    <textblock>Louisiana</textblock>
    <textblock>Michael Taylor, RDA Delta Region, 1221 Washington Street, Vicksburg, MS 39180, Ph: 601-631-3920, Fax: 601-631-3931</textblock>
    <textblock>Maine</textblock>
    <textblock>Daniel E. McAllister, Jr., FmHA State Office, 444 Stillwater Avenue, Suite 2, P.O. Box 405, Bangor ME 04402-0405, Ph: 207-990-9125, Fax: 207-990-9170</textblock>
    <textblock>Massachusetts</textblock>
    <textblock>Craig L. Dore, FmHA State Office, 451 West Street, Amherst MA 01002, Ph: 413-253-4340, Fax: 413-253-4347</textblock>
    <textblock>Michigan</textblock>
    <textblock>James Trumbell, FmHA State Office, 3001 Coolidge Road, Suite 200, East Lansing MI 48823, Ph: 517-337-6635, Fax: 517-337-6913</textblock>
    <textblock>Minnesota</textblock>
    <textblock>Deborah Slipek, FmHA State Office, 410 Farm Credit Services Bldg, 375 Jackson Street, St. Paul MN 55101-1853, Ph: 612-290-3866, Fax: 612-290-3834</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
