<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00023</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Mead Corporation, Paper Publishing Division; Availability of Environmental Assessment</textblock>
    <textblock>January 11, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission's (Commission's) regulations, 18 CFR part 380 (Order No. 486, 52 FR 47897), the Office of Hydropower Licensing has reviewed the application for major license for the existing Escanaba Hydroelectric Project located on the Escanaba River in Marquette and Delta Counties, near Escanaba, Michigan, and has prepared a draft Environmental Assessment (EA) for the proposed project.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the EA are available for review in the Public Reference Branch, room 3104 the Commission's offices at 941 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be filed within 45 days from the date of this notice and should be addressed to Lois D. Cashell, Secretary, Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426. Please affix Project No. 2506-002 to all comments. For further information, please contact Nancy Beals, Environmental Assessment Coordinator, at (202) 219-2178.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Project No. 2506-002; Michigan]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1069 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
