<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00019</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>251.72␣Determination of controversy.</textblock>
    <textblock>251.73␣Declaration of controversy: Initiation of arbitration proceeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>251.74␣Deduction of costs of distribution proceedings.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>17 U.S.C. 801-803.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart A_Organization</textblock>
    <textblock>§251.1</textblock>
    <textblock>Official address.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copyright Office, Copyright Arbitration Royalty Panels, Library of Congress, Washington, DC 20557-6400, (202) 707-8150</textblock>
    <textblock>§251.2</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose of Copyright Arbitration Royalty Panels.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Librarian of Congress, upon the recommendation of the Register of Copyrights, may appoint and convene a Copyright Arbitration Royalty Panel (CARP) for the following purposes:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) To make determinations concerning copyright royalty rates for the cable compulsory license, 17 U.S.C. 111.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) To make determinations concerning copyright royalty rates for the making and distributing of phonorecords, 17 U.S.C. 115.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) To make determinations concerning copyright royalty rates for coinoperated phonorecord players (jukeboxes) whenever a negotiated license authorized by 17 U.S.C. 116 expires or is terminated and is not replaced by another such license agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) To make determinations concerning royalty rates and terms for the use by noncommercial educational broadcast stations of certain copyrighted works, 17 U.S.C. 118.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) To distribute cable television, satellite carrier and digital audio recording devices and media royalty fees under 17 U.S.C. 111, 119, and chapter 10, respectively, deposited with the Register of Copyrights.</textblock>
    <textblock>§251.3</textblock>
    <textblock>Arbitrator lists.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Any professional arbitration association or organization may submit, before March 1, 1994 and before January 1 of each year thereafter, a list of its members qualified to serve as arbitrators on a Copyright Arbitration Royalty Panel. Such list shall contain the following for each member:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The full name, address and telephone number of the member.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The current position and name of the member's employer, if any, along with a brief summary of the member's employment history.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) A brief description of the educational background of the member, including teaching positions and membership in professional associations, if any.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) A description of the facts and information which qualify the member to serve as an arbitrator under §251.4.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Any other information which the professional arbitration association or organization may consider relevant.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) After March 1, 1994, and after January 1 of each year thereafter, the Librarian of Congress shall publish in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>a list of all the members of professional arbitration associations and organizations submitted to the Librarian who satisfy the qualifications and requirements of this subchapter and can reasonably be expected to be available to serve as an arbitrator to a Copyright Arbitration Royalty Panel during that calendar year.</textblock>
    <textblock>§251.4</textblock>
    <textblock>Arbitrator lists: Objections.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) In the case of a rate adjustment proceeding, any party to the proceeding may, during the 90-day period specified in §251.63, file an objection with the Librarian of Congress to one or more of the persons contained on the arbitrator list for that proceeding. Such objection shall plainly state the grounds and reasons for each person found to be objectionable.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
