<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00045</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Hybrid PFD's; Establishment of Approval Requirements</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Coast Guard</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>46 CFR Parts 25 and 160</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[CGD 78-174]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 2115-AA29</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Coast Guard, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Supplemental notice of proposed rulemaking.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>On August 22, 1985 the Coast Guard published an interim final rule (IFR) in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(50 FR 33923) which established structural and performance standards and procedures for approval of hybrid inflatable personal flotation devices (PFD). This IFR allowed the approval of several hybrid PFD's but not enough devices were made and sold to make a significant difference in the number of lives saved by this superior performing and more comfortable PFD. The changes proposed are designed to make hybrid PFD's more affordable and attractive to recreational boaters. The changes include lowering manufacturing costs by reducing the amount of repetitive testing required. Increases in buoyancy are proposed to compensate for removing of the Type V criteria of being ``REQUIRED TO BE WORN'' to allow approval of hybrids a Type I, II, and III. Types I, II, and III are proposed in addition to the existing Type V category. This SNPRM also proposes approval of hybrids for youths and small children. These proposals are in hopes that hybrid PFD's will be more widely used and potentially save more lives.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before April 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Comments may be mailed to the Executive Secretary, Marine Safety Council (G-LRA-2/3406) (CGD 78-174), U.S. Coast Guard, 2100 Second Street, SW., Washington, DC 20593-0001, or may be delivered to room 3406 at the above address between the hours of 8 a.m. and 4 p.m. Monday through Friday. The telephone number is (202) 267-1477 for further information about submitting comments. The Executive Secretary maintains the public docket for this rulemaking. Comments will become part of this docket and will be available for inspection or copying at room 3406, U.S. Coast Guard Headquarters.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Copies of the Coast Guard Auxiliary Study, ``Inflatable Personal Flotation Device Study,'' discussed in this document are available from the National Technical Information Service, Springfield, VA 22151 by referring to the publication number. The publication number for Report No. CG-M-5-81 is AD A107941.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Copies of The Boat/U.S. Foundation for Boating Safety study, ``Inflatable Personal Flotation Device Study: An Examination of Inflatable PFD Performance and Reliability in Public Use'' dated March 11, 1993, can be obtained at the address mentioned under</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT</textblock>
    <textblock>in this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) UL Standard 1517 may be obtained from Underwriters Laboratories, Publications Stock, 333 Pfingsten Road, Northbrook, IL 60062.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Samuel E. Wehr or Lieutenant Junior Grade Roger A. Smith, Office of Marine Safety, Security, and Environmental Protection, Attn: G-MVI-3/14, 2100 Second Street SW., Washington, DC 20593-0001, (202) 267-1444.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Request for Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to participate in this supplemental notice of proposed rulemaking (SNPRM) by submitting written views, data, or arguments. Persons submitting comments should include their name and address, identify this SNPRM (CGD78-174) and the specific section or paragraph of this proposal to which each comment applies, and give reasons for each comment. Persons wanting acknowledgment of receipt of comments should enclose a stamped self-adddressed postcard or envelope.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard will consider all written comments received during the comment period. It may change this proposal in view of the comments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard plans no public hearing. Persons may request a public hearing by writing to the Marine Safety Council at the address under</textblock>
    <textblock>``ADDRESSES.''</textblock>
    <textblock>If it determines that the opportunity for oral presentations will aid this rulemaking, the Coast Guard will hold a public hearing at a time and place announced by a later notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Drafting Information</textblock>
    <textblock>The principal persons involved in drafting this document are Mr. Samuel E. Wehr and Lieutenant Junior Grade Roger A. Smith, Office of Marine Safety, Security, and Environmental Protection, and LT Ralph L. Hetzel, Office of Chief Counsel.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
