<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00033</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(a) They are received in the offices of the Copyright Office during normal business hours during the month of July, or</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) They are properly addressed to the Copyright Office,</textblock>
    <textblock>see</textblock>
    <textblock>§251.1, and they are deposited with sufficient postage with the United States Postal Service and bear a July U.S. postmark. Claims dated only with a business meter that are received after July 31 will not be accepted as having been filed during the month of July. No claim may be filed by facsimile transmission.</textblock>
    <textblock>§257.5</textblock>
    <textblock>Proof of fixation of works.</textblock>
    <textblock>In any proceeding for the distribution of satellite carrier royalty fees, the Copyright Office shall not require the filing by claimants of tangible fixations of works in whole or in part. In the event that a controversy concerning the actual fixation of a work in a tangible medium of expression as required by the Copyright Code, the Copyright Arbitration Royalty Panel conducting the distribution proceeding shall resolve such controversy on the basis of affidavits by appropriate operational personnel and other appropriate documentary evidence, and by such oral testimony as the Panel may deem necessary. Affidavits submitted by claimants should establish that the work for which the claim was submitted was fixed in its entirety, and should state the nature of the work, the title of the program, the duration of the program, and the date of fixation. No such affidavits need be filed with a CARP unless requested by that Panel.</textblock>
    <textblock>§257.6</textblock>
    <textblock>Separate claims required.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a party intends to file claims for both cable compulsory license and satellite carrier compulsory license royalty fees during the same month of July, that party must file separate claims with the Copyright Office. Any single claim which purports to file for both cable and satellite carrier royalty fees will be dismissed.</textblock>
    <textblock>28. Part 310 of chapter III is transferred to subchapter B of chapter II and is redesignated as part 258.</textblock>
    <textblock>29. The heading for part 258 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 258_ADJUSTMENT OF ROYALTY FEE FOR SECONDARY TRANSMISSIONS BY SATELLITE CARRIERS</textblock>
    <textblock>29a. The authority citation for part 258 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>17 U.S.C. 119(c)(3)(F).</textblock>
    <textblock>§258.1</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>30. Section 258.1 is amended by removing ``310'' and adding ``258''.</textblock>
    <textblock>§258.2</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>31. Section 258.2 is amended by removing ``§310(3)(b)'' and adding ``§258(3)(b)''.</textblock>
    <textblock>32. Part 311 of chapter III is transferred to subchapter B of chapter II and is redesignated as Part 259.</textblock>
    <textblock>33. The heading for part 259 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 259_FILING OF CLAIMS TO DIGITAL AUDIO RECORDING DEVICES AND MEDIA ROYALTY PAYMENTS</textblock>
    <textblock>33a. The authority citation for part 259 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>17 U.S.C. 1007(a)(1).</textblock>
    <textblock>§259.1</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>34. Section 259.1 is amended by removing ``Copyright Royalty Tribunal'' and adding ``Copyright Office''.</textblock>
    <textblock>§259.2</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>35. Section 259.2 is amended by removing ``Copyright Royalty Tribunal'' each place it appears and adding ``Copyright Office''.</textblock>
    <textblock>§259.3</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>36. Section 259.3 is amended by removing ``Copyright Royalty Tribunal'' each place it appears and adding ``Copyright Office''.</textblock>
    <textblock>§259.4</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>37. Section 259.4 is amended by removing ``Copyright Royalty Tribunal'' each place it appears and adding ``Copyright Office''.</textblock>
    <textblock>§259.5</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>38. Section 259.5 is amended by removing ``Copyright Royalty Tribunal'' each place it appears and adding ``Copyright Office''.</textblock>
    <textblock>§259.5b</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>39. Section 259.5(b) is amended by removing ``1825 Connecticut Avenue, NW., suite 918, Washington, DC 20009'' and adding ``Copyright Office,</textblock>
    <textblock>see</textblock>
    <textblock>§251.1.''.</textblock>
    <textblock>§259.6</textblock>
    <textblock>[Removed]</textblock>
    <textblock>40. Section 259.6 is removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 11, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Barbara A. Ringer,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Register of Copyrights.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>James H. Billington,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>The Librarian of Congress.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1199 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 1410-09-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
