<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00064</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(ii) is not complying substantially with, or has failed to make satisfactory progress in achieving the benchmarks set forth in the strategic plan prepared pursuant to §25.200(d) of this part; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Requesting a reply from all involved parties within 90 days of the receipt of this letter of warning.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of revocation.</textblock>
    <textblock>After allowing 90 days from the date of receipt of the letter of warning for response, and after making a determination pursuant to paragraph (a) of this section, the Secretary may issue a final notice of revocation of the designation of the rural area as an Empowerment Zone or Enterprise Community.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice to affected Federal agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>USDA will notify all affected Federal agencies providing assistance in a rural Empowerment Zone or Enterprise Community of its determination to revoke any designation pursuant to this section or to modify a designation pursuant to §25.402 of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart F_Special Rules</textblock>
    <textblock>§25.500</textblock>
    <textblock>Indian reservations.</textblock>
    <textblock>No rural Empowerment Zone or Enterprise Community may include any area within an Indian reservation.</textblock>
    <textblock>§25.501</textblock>
    <textblock>Governments.</textblock>
    <textblock>If more than one State or local government seeks to nominate an area under this part, any reference to or requirement of this part shall apply to all such governments.</textblock>
    <textblock>§25.502</textblock>
    <textblock>Nominations by economic development corporations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any rural area nominated by an economic development corporation chartered by a State and qualified to do business in the state in which it is located, shall be treated as nominated by a State and local governments.</textblock>
    <textblock>§25.503</textblock>
    <textblock>Use of census data.</textblock>
    <textblock>Population and poverty rate data shall be determined by the 1990 Census Data.</textblock>
    <textblock>§25.504</textblock>
    <textblock>Rural areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>What constitutes ``rural''.</textblock>
    <textblock>A rural area may consist of any area that lies outside the boundaries of a Metropolitan Area, as designated by the Office of Management and Budget, or, as an area that is primarily rural and has at least 50 percent of the population of the nominated area residing outside of a Metropolitan Area. For the purpose of this section, the 1993 Census Bureau definition of Metropolitan Area is applied.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Exceptions to the definition.</textblock>
    <textblock>On a case by case basis, the Secretary will grant requests for waiver from the above definition of ``rural'' upon a showing of good cause. Applicants seeking to apply for a rural designation who do not satisfy the above subsection, must submit a request for waiver in writing to the Rural Development Administration, Empowerment Zone Office, Department of Agriculture, AG Box 3202, 14th Street and Independence Avenue SW., Washington, DC 20250-3200. Requests must include:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The name, address and daytime phone number of the contact person for the applicant seeking the waiver; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Sufficient information regarding the area that would support the infrequent exception from the definition.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>The waiver process.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary, in consultation with the Department of Commerce, will have discretion to permit rural applications for communities that do not meet the above rural criteria.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 12, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Bob J. Nash,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Under Secretary, Small Community and Rural Development.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1147 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-07-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
