<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00031</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>4. Section 644.32 (Recordkeeping)</textblock>
    <textblock>The language in ยง644.32(d)(1) has been modified to lessen the recordkeeping burden on grantees.</textblock>
    <textblock>Intergovernmental Review</textblock>
    <textblock>This program is subject to the requirement of Executive Order 12372 and the regulations in 34 CFR part 79. The objective of the Executive order is to foster an intergovernmental partnership and a strengthened federalism by relying on processes developed by State and local governments for coordination and review of proposed Federal financial assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the order, this document is intended to provide early notification of the Department's specific plans and actions for this program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Assessment of Educational Impact</textblock>
    <textblock>In the notice of proposed rulemaking, the Secretary requested comments on whether the proposed regulations would require transmission of information that is being gathered by or is available from any other agency or authority of the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>Based on the response to the proposed rules and on its own review, the Department has determined that the regulations in this document do not require transmission of information that is being gathered or is available from any other agency or authority of the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 34 CFR Part 644</textblock>
    <textblock>Colleges and Universities, Education of disadvantaged, Grant programs_education, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Secondary education.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Number 84.066 Educational Opportunity Centers Program.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard W. Riley,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of Education.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
