<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00030</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Tuesday</textblock>
    <textblock>January 18, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part III</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education</textblock>
    <textblock>34 CFR Part 644</textblock>
    <textblock>Educational Opportunity Centers Program; Final Rule and Notice Inviting Applications</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 11␣/␣Tuesday, January 18, 1994␣/␣Rules and Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>Educational Opportunity Centers</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>34 CFR Part 644</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1840-AB65</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final regulations.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary amends the regulations governing the Educational Opportunity Centers program. The Educational Opportunity Centers program is authorized under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA), and these final regulations implement changes made to the HEA by the Higher Education Amendments of 1992. In addition to incorporating statutory changes, the regulations also clarify and simplify requirements governing the program and revise one funding criterion.</textblock>
    <textblock>The purposes and allowable activities of the Educational Opportunity Centers program support the National Education Goals. Specifically, the program funds projects designed to improve the academic competency of program participants (Goal</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>3).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>These regulations take effect either 45 days after publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>or later if the Congress takes certain adjournments. If you want to know the effective date of these regulations, call or write to the Department of Education contact person. A document announcing the effective date will be published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicability:</textblock>
    <textblock>The criteria listed under §644.22 will apply on and after June 1, 1994. Until June 1, 1994, the existing criteria will continue to apply.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Margaret A. Wingfield, U.S. Department of Education, 400 Maryland Avenue, SW., room 5065, Washington, DC 20202-5249. Telephone: (202) 708-4804. Individuals who use a telecommunications device for the deaf (TDD) may call the Federal Information Relay Service (FIRS) at 1-800-877-8339 between 8 a.m. and 8 p.m., Eastern time, Monday through Friday.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>These regulations implement the Higher Education Amendments of 1992 (Pub. L. 102-325, enacted July 23, 1992). The Educational Opportunity Centers program provides grants to institutions of higher education; public and private agencies and organizations; combinations of institutions, agencies, and organizations; and secondary schools under special circumstances. The purposes of the program are to (1) provide information regarding financial and academic assistance available for individuals who desire to pursue a program of postsecondary education; and (2) assist individuals in applying for admission to institutions that offer programs of postsecondary education, including preparing necessary applications for use by admissions and financial aid officers.</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 26, 1993, the Secretary published a notice of proposed rulemaking (NPRM) for this program in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 57704). The NPRM included a summary of regulations proposed to implement statutory changes and other regulations proposed to clarify and simplify requirements governing the program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Analysis of Comments and Changes</textblock>
    <textblock>In response to the Secretary's invitation in the NPRM, 45 persons submitted comments on the proposed regulations. An analysis of the comments and the changes that have been made in the regulations since publication of the NPRM is published as an appendix to these final regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Major Changes in the Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>The major differences between the NPRM and these final regulations are as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Section 644.21 (Selection Criteria_Plan of Operation)</textblock>
    <textblock>The criterion listed under §644.21(c)(5) has been modified to encourage applicants to include information about their plan to coordinate with other projects for disadvantaged students.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 644.30 (Allowable Costs)</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 644.30 has been revised to include, as allowable costs, transportation, lodging, and meals for project participants and staff during visits to postsecondary institutions or for participation in ``College Day'' and career awareness activities. Also, fees for college admissions applications and college entrance examination fees are now permissible under certain circumstances.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Section 644.31 (Unallowable Costs)</textblock>
    <textblock>This section has been revised to conform to the changes made in the allowable costs section.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
