<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00048</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Department is also adopting as a final rule the proposed amendment to the reach range requirement for ATMs. As stated in the Department's NPRM, all timely comments received by the Access Board on the proposed transportation and ATM rules have been analyzed by the Department in connection with this final rule. An analysis of these comments is contained in the final rules issued by the Access Board and referenced above, and the Department concurs with the Access Board's analysis. In addition to the comments previously received by the Access Board, the Department directly received seven comments in response to its NPRM. Of these seven comments, three substantially duplicated comments on the proposed revisions to ATM requirements previously sent to the Access Board by the same commenters, and two addressed issues not covered by the NPRM. Of the two new comments on issues raised by the NPRM, one expressed support for both the proposed transportation and the proposed ATM provisions without discussing any rationable for such support, and on comment, submitted by an advocacy group, opposed the changes to ATM reach range requirements on the ground that the changes would not make ATMs readily accessible to and usable by individuals with disabilities, but did not include any additional documentation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Process Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department has determined that this final rule is not a major rule under E.O. 12291. Accordingly, a regulatory impact statement is not required.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department has determined that this final rule will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small business entities. Therefore, it is not subject to the Regulatory Flexibility Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department also has determined that there are no Federalism impacts sufficient to warrant the preparation of a Federalism assessment under Executive Order 12612.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 28 CFR Part 36</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedure, Alcoholism, Americans with disabilities, Buildings and facilities, Business and industry, Civil rights, Consumer protection, Drug abuse, Historic preservation, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 5, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the authority vested in me as Attorney General by 28 U.S.C. 509, 510, 5 U.S.C. 301, and section 306(b) of the Americans with Disabilities Act, Pub. L. 101-336, and for the reasons set forth in the preamble, chapter I of title 28 of the Code of Federal Regulations is amended as follows:</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Janet Reno,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Attorney General.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
