<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00007</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00003</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Delegation of Authority To Accept Checks and Waive</textblock>
    <textblock>Penalties</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>27 CFR Part 70</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[T.D. ATF-353; CRT-92-07]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1512-AB26</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (ATF), Treasury.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Treasury decision, final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority delegation. This Treasury decision</textblock>
    <textblock>expands the responsibilities of the ``Chief, Tax Processing</textblock>
    <textblock>Center'' by giving the chief the authority to accept checks</textblock>
    <textblock>and waive penalties. It also removes certain regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>dealing with tax collection activities under 27 CFR part</textblock>
    <textblock>70 that have been determined to be outside of the</textblock>
    <textblock>authority of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nancy Bryce, Tax</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance Branch, Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and</textblock>
    <textblock>Firearms, 650 Massachusetts Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20226, (202-927-8220).</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On July 1, 1972, the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and</textblock>
    <textblock>Firearms (ATF) was established by Treasury Department</textblock>
    <textblock>Order No. 120-01 (formerly Order No. 221). This Order</textblock>
    <textblock>transferred from the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to the</textblock>
    <textblock>newly-formed Bureau the functions, powers and duties</textblock>
    <textblock>relating to alcohol, tobacco, firearms and explosives</textblock>
    <textblock>laws. The Order specifically stated that ``all existing</textblock>
    <textblock>activities relating to the collection, processing,</textblock>
    <textblock>depositing, or accounting for taxes *␣*␣* shall continue</textblock>
    <textblock>to be performed by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue to</textblock>
    <textblock>the extent not now performed by the Alcohol, Tobacco and</textblock>
    <textblock>Firearms Division *␣*␣* until the Director shall otherwise</textblock>
    <textblock>provide with the approval of the Secretary.'' ATF assumed</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility for the collection of taxes imposed by</textblock>
    <textblock>subtitle E of the Internal Revenue Code in July 1987, by</textblock>
    <textblock>means of Treasury Decision (T.D.) ATF-251, and adopted</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions in 27 CFR part 70 similar to those found in 26</textblock>
    <textblock>CFR part 301 which concerned the deposit and assessment of</textblock>
    <textblock>taxes. The remaining collection functions with respect to</textblock>
    <textblock>taxes administered by ATF were transferred by way of T.D.</textblock>
    <textblock>ATF-301, at which time ATF adopted regulations similar to</textblock>
    <textblock>those used by IRS relating to the examination, assessment,</textblock>
    <textblock>and collection functions. These provisions are also found</textblock>
    <textblock>in 27 CFR part 70. Under existing regulations, the</textblock>
    <textblock>regional directors (compliance) are authorized to accept</textblock>
    <textblock>checks and waive penalties associated with the collection</textblock>
    <textblock>of taxes administered by ATF. This final rule amends</textblock>
    <textblock>27 CFR part 70 by vesting the authority to accept checks</textblock>
    <textblock>and waive penalties with the Chief, Tax Processing Center,</textblock>
    <textblock>in addition to the regional directors (compliance), in</textblock>
    <textblock>order to ease the burden on the regional directors</textblock>
    <textblock>(compliance), simplify the waiver process for taxpayers,</textblock>
    <textblock>and permit the more efficient functioning of ATF's tax</textblock>
    <textblock>collection activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>This final rule also removes the following</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations dealing with tax collection activities that</textblock>
    <textblock>have been determined to fall outside of ATF's authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>27 CFR 70.166(a), 70.201, 70.211, 70.212 and 70.487.</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act of</textblock>
    <textblock>1980, Public Law 96-511, 44 U.S.C. chapter 35, and its</textblock>
    <textblock>implementing regulations, 5 CFR part 1320, do not apply to</textblock>
    <textblock>this final rule because no requirement to collect</textblock>
    <textblock>information is imposed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The provisions of the Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>relating to a final regulatory flexibility analysis</textblock>
    <textblock>(5 U.S.C. 604) are not applicable to this final rule</textblock>
    <textblock>because the agency was not required to publish a general</textblock>
    <textblock>notice of proposed rulemaking under 5 U.S.C. 553 or any</textblock>
    <textblock>other law. A copy of this final rule was submitted to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business</textblock>
    <textblock>Administration in accordance with 26 U.S.C. 7805(f). No</textblock>
    <textblock>comments were received.</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12866</textblock>
    <textblock>It has been determined that this rule is not a</textblock>
    <textblock>significant regulatory action, because (1) it will not</textblock>
    <textblock>have an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or</textblock>
    <textblock>more or adversely affect in a material way the economy, a</textblock>
    <textblock>sector of the economy, productivity, competition, jobs,</textblock>
    <textblock>the environment, public health or safety, or State, local</textblock>
    <textblock>or tribal governments or communities; (2) Create a serious</textblock>
    <textblock>inconsistency or otherwise interfere with an action taken</textblock>
    <textblock>or planned by another agency; (3) Materially alter the</textblock>
    <textblock>budgetary impact of entitlements, grants, user fees, or</textblock>
    <textblock>loan programs or the rights and obligations of recipients</textblock>
    <textblock>thereof; or (4) Raise novel legal or policy issues arising</textblock>
    <textblock>out of legal mandates, the Presidents priorities, or the</textblock>
    <textblock>principles set forth in Executive Order 12866.</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative Procedures Act</textblock>
    <textblock>Because this final rule is a rule of agency</textblock>
    <textblock>management that merely transfers the authority relating to</textblock>
    <textblock>the acceptance of checks and waiver of penalties, it is</textblock>
    <textblock>unnecessary to issue this Treasury decision with notice</textblock>
    <textblock>and public procedure thereon under 5 U.S.C. 553(a)(2) and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)(B) or subject to the effective date limitation in 5</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S.C. 553(d)(3).</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
