<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00037</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Costs that are unallowable under the Educational Opportunity Centers program include, but are not limited to, the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Tuition, fees, stipends, and other forms of direct financial support for participants.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Research not directly related to the evaluation or improvement of the project.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Construction, renovation, and remodeling of any facilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1070a-11 and 1070a-16)</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง644.32</textblock>
    <textblock>What other requirements must a grantee meet?</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Eligibility of participants.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A grantee shall determine the eligibility of each participant in the project at the time that the individual is selected to participate.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A grantee shall determine the status of a low-income individual on the basis of the documentation described in section 402A(e) of the HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Number of participants.</textblock>
    <textblock>In each budget period, a grantee shall serve a minimum of 1,000 participants who reside in the target area. However, the Secretary may reduce the minimum number of these participants if the amount of the grant for the budget period is less than $180,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Recordkeeping.</textblock>
    <textblock>For each participant, a grantee shall maintain a record of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The basis for the grantee's determination that the participant is eligible to participate in the project under ยง644.3;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The services that are provided to the participant; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The specific educational benefits received by the participant.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Project director.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A grantee shall employ a full-time project director unless paragraph (d)(3) of this section applies.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The grantee shall give the project director sufficient authority to administer the project effectively.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The Secretary waives the requirement in paragraph (d) (1) of this section if the applicant demonstrates that the requirement will hinder coordination_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Among the Federal TRIO Programs (sections 402A through 402F of the HEA); or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Between the programs funded under sections 402A through 410 of the HEA and similar programs funded through other sources.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number 1840-0065)</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1070a-11 and 1070a-16).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
