<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00019</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>COMMITTEE FOR THE IMPLEMENTATION OF TEXTILE AGREEMENTS</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Announcement of an Import Restraint Limit for Certain Cotton and Man-Made Fiber Textile Products Produced or Manufactured in the Republic of Korea</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements (CITA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Issuing a directive to the Commissioner of Customs establishing a limit.</textblock>
  </action>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 19, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ross Arnold, International Trade Specialist, Office of Textiles and Apparel, U.S. Department of Commerce, (202) 482-4212. For information on the quota status of this limit, refer to the Quota Status Reports posted on the bulletin boards of each Customs port or call (202) 927-6707. For information on embargoes and quota re-openings, call (202) 482-3715.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 11651 of March 3, 1972, as amended; section 204 of the Agricultural Act of 1956, as amended (7 U.S.C. 1854).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bilateral Textile Agreement, effected by exchange of notes dated November 21 and December 4, 1986, as amended and extended, between the Governments of the United States and the Republic of Korea establishes a specific limit for cotton and man-made fiber woven pile fabric in Category 224-V (currently 224pt.) for the period beginning on January 1, 1994 and extending through December 31, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>A description of the textile and apparel categories in terms of HTS numbers is available in the CORRELATION: Textile and Apparel Categories with the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (see</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice 58 FR 62645, published on November 29, 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>The letter to the Commissioner of Customs and the actions taken pursuant to it are not designed to implement all of the provisions of the bilateral agreement, but are designed to assist only in the implementation of certain of its provisions.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rita D. Hayes,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements</textblock>
    <textblock>January 10, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Commissioner of Customs,</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Treasury, Washington, DC 20229.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dear Commissioner: This directive amends, but does not cancel, the directive issued to you on December 13, 1993, by the Chairman, Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements. That directive concerns imports of certain cotton, wool, man-made fiber, silk blend and other vegetable fiber textiles and textile products, produced or manufactured in Korea and exported during the twelve-month period which began on January 1, 1994 and extends through December 31, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective on January 19, 1994, you are directed to establish a limit at 10,774,382 square meters for part-Category 224-V (currently 224pt.)</textblock>
    <textblock>for the period January 1, 1994 through December 31, 1994. Part-Category 224-V shall remain subject to the Group I limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>Imports charged to the category limit for the period January 1, 1993 through December 31, 1993, shall be charged against that level of restraint to the extent of any unfilled balance. In the event the limit established for that period has been exhausted by previous entries, such goods shall be subject to the level set forth in this directive.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements has determined that this action falls within the foreign affairs exception of the rulemaking provisions of 5 U.S.C. 553(a)(1).</textblock>
    <textblock>Sincerely,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Category 224-V: only HTS numbers 5801.21.0000, 5801.23.0000, 5801.24.0000, 5801.25.0010, 5801.25.0020, 5801.26.0010, 5801.26.0020, 5801.31.0000, 5801.33.0000, 5801.34.0000, 5801.35.0010, 5801.35.0020, 5801.36.0010 and 5801.36.0020.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rita D. Hayes,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1137 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DR-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
