<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00039</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00035</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(b) Schedule RC-N, which collects past due and nonaccrual data, would see the addition of new items for interest rate, foreign exchange rate, and other commodity and equity contracts that are past due 30 through 89 days or past due 90 days or more. Banks would report the book value of amounts carried as assets on the balance sheet for such past due contracts as well as the replacement cost of those past due contracts with a positive replacement cost. Consistent with the existing treatment of Schedule RC-N data, individual bank information on contracts past due 30 through 89 days would be treated as confidential.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) On Schedule RC-C, part I, ``Loans and Leases,'' a single total would be reported for ``Obligations (other than securities and leases) of states and political subdivisions in the U.S.'' and the separate items for taxable and tax-exempt obligations would be eliminated.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Memorandum items 1 and 2 on Schedule RC-L, ``Off-Balance Sheet Items,'' which collect data on certain loan sales and purchases during the quarter would be deleted.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, the general Call Report instruction precluding assets and liabilities from being offset or otherwise netted unless specifically required by the instructions would be modified to allow on-balance sheet amounts associated with conditional and exchange contracts (e.g., forwards, interest rate swaps, and options) to be offset in accordance with Financial Accounting Standards Board Interpretation No. 39. This would be an interim treatment pending clarification of an interpretive issue under Interpretation No. 39.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 11, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Robert E. Feldman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Executive Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1085 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6714-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
