<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00037</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00035</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL DEPOSIT INSURANCE CORPORATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Information Collection Submitted to OMB for Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of information collection submitted to OMB for review and approval under the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with requirements of the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. chapter 35), the FDIC hereby gives notice that it has submitted to the Office of Management and Budget a request for OMB review of the information collection system described below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Review:</textblock>
    <textblock>Revision of a currently approved collection.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Consolidated Reports of Condition and Income (Insured State Nonmember Commercial and Savings Banks).</textblock>
    <textblock>Form Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>FFIEC 031, 032, 033, 034.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>3064-0052.</textblock>
    <textblock>Expiration Date of OMB Clearance:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 31, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Insured state nonmember commercial and savings banks.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Quarterly.</textblock>
    <textblock>Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>7,310.</textblock>
    <textblock>Number of Responses per Respondent:</textblock>
    <textblock>4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Total Annual Responses:</textblock>
    <textblock>29,240.</textblock>
    <textblock>Average Number of Hours per Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>26.28.</textblock>
    <textblock>Total Annual Burden Hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>768,374.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB Reviewer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Gary Waxman, (202) 395-7340, Office of Management and Budget, Paperwork Reduction Project 3064-0052, Washington, DC 20503.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDIC Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Steven F. Hanft, (202) 898-3907, Office of the Executive Secretary, Room F-400, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, 550 17th Street NW., Washington, DC 20429.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this collection of information are welcome and should be submitted before March 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the submission may be obtained by calling or writing the FDIC contact listed above. Comments regarding the submission should be addressed to both the OMB reviewer and the FDIC contact listed above.</textblock>
  </address>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FDIC is submitting for OMB review changes to the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council (FFIEC) Consolidated Reports of Condition and Income (Call Reports) filed quarterly by insured state nonmember commercial and savings banks. The Federal Reserve Board (FRB) and the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC) are also submitting these changes for OMB review for the banks under their supervision.</textblock>
    <textblock>The revisions to the Call Reports that are the subject of this request were approved by the FFIEC on December 16, 1993, and are scheduled to take effect as of March 31, 1994. Unless otherwise indicated, these Call Report changes apply to all four sets of report forms (FFIEC 031, 032, 033, and 034). Nonetheless, as is customary for Call Report changes, banks will be advised that they may provide reasonable estimates for any of the new items in their March 31, 1994, Call Reports for which the requested information is not readily available. The changes for which OMB approval is requested are summarized as follows:</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
