<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00072</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to amend title 34 of the Code of Federal Regulations by amending part 600 and by removing part 601 as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 600_INSTITUTIONAL ELIGIBILITY UNDER THE HIGHER EDUCATION</textblock>
    <textblock>ACT OF 1965, AS AMENDED</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 600 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>20 U.S.C. 1082, 1085, 1088, 1094, and 1141, unless otherwise noted.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. A new subpart E is added to part 600 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart E_Eligibility of Foreign Institutions To Apply To Participate in the Federal Family Education Loan (FFEL) Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec.</textblock>
    <textblock>600.51␣Purpose and scope.</textblock>
    <textblock>600.52␣Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>600.53␣Requesting an eligibility determination.</textblock>
    <textblock>600.54␣Criteria for determining whether a foreign institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>eligible to apply to participate in the FFEL programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>600.55␣Additional criteria for determining whether a foreign graduate medical school is eligible to apply to participate in the FFEL programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>600.56␣Duration of eligibility determination.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart E_Eligibility of Foreign Institutions To Apply To Participate in the Federal Family Education Loan (FFEL) Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>§600.51</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose and scope.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A foreign institution is eligible to apply to participate in the Federal Family Education Loan (FFEL) programs if it is comparable to an eligible institution of higher education located in the United States and has been approved by the Secretary in accordance with the provisions of this subpart.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) This subpart E contains the procedures and criteria under which a foreign institution may be deemed eligible to apply to participate in the FFEL programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) This subpart E does not include the procedures and criteria by which a foreign institution that is deemed eligible to apply to participate in the FFEL programs actually applies for that participation. Those procedures and criteria are contained in the FFEL programs regulations, 34 CFR 682.600.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1082, 1088)</textblock>
    <textblock>§600.52</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following definitions apply to this subpart E:</textblock>
    <textblock>Foreign graduate medical school</textblock>
    <textblock>: A foreign institution that qualifies to be listed in, and is listed as a medical school in, the most current edition of the World Directory of Medical Schools published by the World Health Organization (WHO).</textblock>
    <textblock>Foreign institution</textblock>
    <textblock>: An institution that is not located in a State.</textblock>
    <textblock>Passing score</textblock>
    <textblock>: The minimum passing score as defined by the Educational Commission for Foreign Medical Graduates (ECFMG).</textblock>
    <textblock>Secondary school</textblock>
    <textblock>: A school that provides secondary education as determined under the laws of the country in which the school is located.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1082, 1088)</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
