<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00008</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 4-94]</textblock>
    <textblock>Foreign-Trade Subzone 59A_Lincoln, NE; Request for Expanded Manufacturing Authority;</textblock>
    <textblock>Kawasaki Motors Manufacturing Corporation, U.S.A., Plant</textblock>
    <textblock>(Utility Work Trucks)</textblock>
    <textblock>An application has been submitted to the Foreign-Trade Zones Board (the Board) by the Kawasaki Motors Manufacturing Corporation, U.S.A. (KMM), operator of FTZ Subzone 59A, at the KMM manufacturing facilities, Lincoln, Nebraska, requesting authority to manufacture utility work trucks under zone procedures. The application was submitted pursuant to the provisions of the Foreign-Trade Zones Act, as amended (19 U.S.C. 81a-81u), and the regulations of the Board (15 CFR part 400). It was formally filed on January 10, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subzone 59A was approved by the FTZ Board in 1980 with activity granted for the manufacture of motorcycles, jet skis, and four wheel all terrain vehicles (Board Order 163, 45 FR 58637, 9-4-80). An application for expansion of the subzone is currently pending (Doc. 56-93, 58 FR 63335, 12-1-93).</textblock>
    <textblock>KMM is now requesting subzone authority for the manufacture of certain off-road, gasoline engine utility work trucks (called ``Mules'') (payload capacity up to 1,200 pounds) for the U.S. market and export. Foreign-sourced components and subassemblies comprise approximately 40 percent of the finished vehicles' material value and include: engines, transmissions, calipers, wheels, and tires (duty rate range: free-15.4%). All steel mill products will be sourced domestically.</textblock>
    <textblock>Zone procedures would exempt KMM from Customs duty payments on the foreign components used in export production. On its domestic</textblock>
    <textblock>sales, the company would be able to choose the duty rate that applies</textblock>
    <textblock>to the finished work trucks (HTSUS</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>8709.19.0030, duty free) for the foreign components noted above. The application indicates that the savings from zone procedures would help improve KMM's international competitiveness.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the Board's regulations, a member of the FTZ Staff has been appointed examiner to investigate the application and report to the Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public comment on the application is invited from interested parties. Submissions (original and three copies) shall be addressed to the Board's Executive Secretary at the address below. The closing period for their receipt is on March 21, 1994. Rebuttal comments in response to material submitted during the foregoing period may be submitted during the subsequent 15-day period (to April 4, 1994).</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the application and the accompanying exhibits will be available for public inspection at each of the following locations:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Department of Commerce District Office,</textblock>
    <textblock>11133 ``O'' Street,</textblock>
    <textblock>Omaha, Nebraska 68137.</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the Executive Secretary,</textblock>
    <textblock>Foreign-Trade Zones Board,</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Department of Commerce, room 3716,</textblock>
    <textblock>14th Street &amp; Constitution Avenue, NW.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20230.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 12, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Foreign-Trade Zones Board</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock/>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John J. Da Ponte, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Executive Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1140 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DS-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
