<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00009</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>37 CFR Parts 251</textblock>
    <textblock>, 252</textblock>
    <textblock>, 253</textblock>
    <textblock>, 254</textblock>
    <textblock>, 255</textblock>
    <textblock>, 256</textblock>
    <textblock>, 257</textblock>
    <textblock>, 258</textblock>
    <textblock>, 259</textblock>
    <textblock>, 301</textblock>
    <textblock>, 302</textblock>
    <textblock>, 303</textblock>
    <textblock>, 304</textblock>
    <textblock>, 305</textblock>
    <textblock>, 306</textblock>
    <textblock>, 307</textblock>
    <textblock>, 308</textblock>
    <textblock>, 309</textblock>
    <textblock>, 310, and 311</textblock>
    <textblock>Copyright Arbitration Royalty Panels; Rules and Regulations</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>LIBRARY OF CONGRESS</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Copyright Office</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. RM94-1]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copyright Office, Library of Congress.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of proposed rulemaking and announcement of open meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 22, 1993, the Copyright Office of the Library of Congress in accordance with the Copyright Royalty Tribunal Reform Act of 1993, adopted in their entirety the rules and regulations of the former Copyright Royalty Tribunal. The Office stated at that time that it was adopting the rules on an interim basis, and that it would soon commence a rulemaking proceeding to update and revise those rules. Today's action commences that proceeding by publishing a set of proposed rules and announcing a public meeting to discuss the proposed regulations.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments should be received on or before February 15, 1994. The open meeting will be held on February 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ten copies of written comments should be addressed, if sent by mail, to: Copyright Office, Library of Congress, Department 17, Washington, DC 20540. If delivered by hand, copies should be brought to: Office of the General Counsel, Copyright Office, room LM-407, James Madison Memorial Building, 101 Independence Avenue, SE., Washington, DC 20540. In order to ensure prompt receipt of these time sensitive documents, the Office recommends that the comments be delivered by a private messenger service.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be in Hearing Room 921, 9th Floor, 1825 Connecticut Avenue, NW., Washington, DC beginning at 10 a.m. Parties need not inform the Copyright Office of their intention to participate.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Marybeth Peters, Acting General Counsel, U.S. Copyright Office, Library of Congress, Washington, DC 20540, (202) 707-8380.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Copyright Office of the Library of Congress is proposing new regulations under 17 U.S.C. 802(d), supplementing and superseding the former Copyright Royalty Tribunal's rules and regulations which were adopted on December 22, 1993. 58 FR 67690 (1993). The Office is also proposing a course of action for dealing with rate adjustment and distribution matters which were pending before the Tribunal at the time of its elimination. A meeting open to the public will be held on February 1, 1994 at 10 a.m. to discuss all issues related to today's publication.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 17, 1993, the President signed into law the Copyright Royalty Tribunal Reform Act of 1993 (``Reform Act''). Public Law No. 103-198, 107 Stat. 2304. Effective immediately upon enactment, the Reform Act amends the Copyright Act, 17 U.S.C., by eliminating the Copyright Royalty Tribunal and transferring its responsibilities and duties to ad hoc Copyright Arbitration Royalty Panels (CARPs), to be administered by the Library of Congress and the Copyright Office. As directed by the new act, the Librarian of Congress will convene Copyright Arbitration Royalty Panels for the purpose of adjusting rates and distributing royalties. See 17 U.S.C. 111, 115, 116, 118, 119 and chapter 10.</textblock>
    <textblock>Immediately upon enactment of the Reform Act the Copyright Office issued a notice adopting the full text of the former Tribunal's rules and regulations on an interim basis. 58 FR 67690 (1993). This action was required by new section 802(d) of the Copyright Code, which provides:</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective on the date of the enactment of the Copyright Royalty Tribunal Reform Act of 1993, the Librarian of Congress shall adopt the rules and regulations set forth in chapter 3 of title 37 of the Code of Federal Regulations to govern proceedings under this chapter. Such rules and regulations shall remain in effect unless and until the Librarian, upon the recommendation of the Register of Copyrights, adopts supplemental or superseding regulations under subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5.</textblock>
    <textblock>17 U.S.C. 802(d). The Copyright Office made only slight technical changes to the former Tribunal's rules, stating that it intended to review and revise the rules during the course of a future rulemaking. 58 FR at 67690 (1993). The Office now commences that proceeding to conform the rules to the new system of Copyright Arbitration Royalty Panels.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Matters Pending Before the Former Tribunal</textblock>
    <textblock>A major issue facing the Copyright Office of Library of Congress at the outset of today's proposed rulemaking is the resolution of rate adjustments and distributions, and related matters, which were pending before the Copyright Royalty Tribunal at the time of its demise. Some of these proceedings, such as distribution of 1990 cable royalties, had already commenced hearings, while others were awaiting determination of controversies or rulings on procedural issues. Since the Office is proposing new rules and regulations which will govern and shape rate adjustment and distribution proceedings under the new system, the Office must first decide how to handle the Tribunal's old business.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
