<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00003</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Interested persons were again afforded an</textblock>
    <textblock>opportunity to comment on the proposed action. Due</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration has been given to the five comments</textblock>
    <textblock>received.</textblock>
    <textblock>Two commenters concur with the proposed rule as</textblock>
    <textblock>written.</textblock>
    <textblock>Another commenter (Collins) states that there are</textblock>
    <textblock>two errors in the part numbers referenced in the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed AD: (1) part number (P/N)</textblock>
    <textblock>622-4540-022 was referenced as P/N 622-4540-22 in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicability section of the AD; and (2) in the chart</textblock>
    <textblock>in paragraph (c) of the proposed AD, the sentence that</textblock>
    <textblock>consists of the following words: ``All applicable DME-700 Units, Converts -022, -021, or -022 to -023.'' should be changed to ``All applicable DME-700 Units, Converts -020, -021, or -022 to -023.'' The FAA</textblock>
    <textblock>concurs and has changed the proposed AD accordingly.</textblock>
    <textblock>One commenter reports that the Airbus Model A330</textblock>
    <textblock>airplane is not yet certificated, and should not be</textblock>
    <textblock>included in the list of affected airplane models. The</textblock>
    <textblock>FAA concurs that this airplane is not certificated and</textblock>
    <textblock>has deleted it from the list of possible affected</textblock>
    <textblock>airplanes. However, the Applicability section of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed AD is worded as ``DME equipment that is</textblock>
    <textblock>installed on, but not limited to, the following model</textblock>
    <textblock>airplanes (all serial numbers), certificated in any</textblock>
    <textblock>category:''. If this airplane would become</textblock>
    <textblock>certificated for operation with the Collins DME-700</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment, then this action would apply to these</textblock>
    <textblock>airplanes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Another commenter states that these DME units were</textblock>
    <textblock>never certificated on Boeing Model B757 airplanes, and</textblock>
    <textblock>should therefore be removed from the applicability of</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed AD. The FAA concurs and has revised the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed AD accordingly.</textblock>
    <textblock>This same commenter suggests several minor</textblock>
    <textblock>editorial revisions and corrections to increase the</textblock>
    <textblock>understanding of the proposed AD. The FAA concurs that</textblock>
    <textblock>these changes would improve clarity and has revised the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed AD accordingly.</textblock>
    <textblock>After careful review of all available information</textblock>
    <textblock>including the comments noted above, the FAA has</textblock>
    <textblock>determined that air safety and the public interest</textblock>
    <textblock>require the adoption of the rule as proposed except for</textblock>
    <textblock>the changes referenced above and minor editorial</textblock>
    <textblock>corrections. The FAA has determined that these changes</textblock>
    <textblock>and corrections will not change the meaning of the AD</textblock>
    <textblock>nor add any additional burden upon the public than was</textblock>
    <textblock>already proposed.</textblock>
    <textblock>The condition specified by the required action is</textblock>
    <textblock>not caused by actual hours time-in-service (TIS) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>airplane that the equipment is installed in. There is</textblock>
    <textblock>no correlation between improper operation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment and the age or number of times the equipment</textblock>
    <textblock>is utilized. Based on this, the compliance time of</textblock>
    <textblock>this AD is presented in calendar time instead of hours</textblock>
    <textblock>TIS.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA estimates that 518 DME-700 units installed</textblock>
    <textblock>on airplanes in the U.S. registry will be affected by</textblock>
    <textblock>this AD, that it will take approximately 7 workhours</textblock>
    <textblock>per unit to accomplish the required action, and that</textblock>
    <textblock>the average labor rate is approximately $55 an hour.</textblock>
    <textblock>Parts will be provided by the manufacturer at no cost</textblock>
    <textblock>to the owner/operator. Based on these figures, the</textblock>
    <textblock>total cost impact of this AD on U.S. operators is</textblock>
    <textblock>estimated to be $199,430. This cost figure is based on</textblock>
    <textblock>the assumption that none of the affected airplane</textblock>
    <textblock>owners/operators have accomplished the required action.</textblock>
    <textblock>The regulations adopted herein will not have</textblock>
    <textblock>substantial direct effects on the States, on the</textblock>
    <textblock>relationship between the national government and the</textblock>
    <textblock>States, or on the distribution of power and</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibilities among the various levels of</textblock>
    <textblock>government. Therefore, in accordance with Executive</textblock>
    <textblock>Order 12612, it is determined that this final rule does</textblock>
    <textblock>not have sufficient federalism implications to warrant</textblock>
    <textblock>the preparation of a Federalism Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons discussed above, I certify that</textblock>
    <textblock>this action (1) is not a ``significant regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>action'' under Executive Order 12866; (2) is not a</textblock>
    <textblock>``significant rule'' under DOT Regulatory Policies and</textblock>
    <textblock>Procedures (44 FR 11034, February 26, 1979); and (3)</textblock>
    <textblock>will not have a significant economic impact, positive</textblock>
    <textblock>or negative, on a substantial number of small entities</textblock>
    <textblock>under the criteria of the Regulatory Flexibility Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the final evaluation prepared for this action</textblock>
    <textblock>is contained in the Rules Docket. A copy of it may be</textblock>
    <textblock>obtained by contacting the Rules Docket at the location</textblock>
    <textblock>provided under the caption ``</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>''.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 14 CFR Part 39</textblock>
    <textblock>Air transportation, Aircraft, Aviation safety,</textblock>
    <textblock>Incorporation by reference, Safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>Adoption of the Amendment</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, pursuant to the authority delegated</textblock>
    <textblock>to me by the Administrator, the Federal Aviation</textblock>
    <textblock>Administration amends 14 CFR part 39 of the Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Aviation Regulations as follows:</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
