<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00139</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00080</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Tuesday</textblock>
    <textblock>January 18, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part IX</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Defense</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Navy</textblock>
    <textblock>CNO Executive Panel; Meeting; Notice</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 11␣/␣Tuesday, January 18, 1994␣/␣Notices</textblock>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</textblock>
    <textblock>CNO Executive Panel; Closed Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App. 2), notice is hereby given that the Chief of Naval Operations (CNO) Executive Panel Intelligence Update will meet January 18, 1994, 9 a.m. to 3 p.m. at the Center for Naval Analyses.  This session will be closed to the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of this meeting is to provide an update of significant foreign intelligence developments which will affect future Navy planning.  The agenda will consist of a series of sensitive all source briefings by the Office of Naval Intelligence with questions and discussion of subject matter following each briefing.  These matters constitute classified information that is specifically authorized by Executive order</textblock>
    <textblock>to be kept secret in the interest of national defense and are,</textblock>
    <textblock>in fact, properly classified pursuant to such Executive order.  Accordingly, the Secretary of the Navy has determined in writing that the public interest requires that all sessions of the meeting be closed to the public because they will be concerned with matters listed in section 552b(c)(1) of title 5, United States Code.</textblock>
    <textblock>For further information concerning this meeting, contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>J.   Kevin Mattonen, Executive Secretary to the Executive Panel</textblock>
    <textblock>, 4401  Ford Avenue, room 601, Alexandria, VA  22302-0268, Phone (703) 756-1205.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated:  December 16, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Department of the Navy</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Michael P. Rummel,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>LCDR, JAGC, USN, Federal Register Liaison Officer.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1290 Filed 1-14-94; 8:56 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3810-AE-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
