<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00098</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00060</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 10, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Introduction</textblock>
    <textblock>On February 28, 1992, the American Stock Exchange, Inc. (``Amex'' or ``Exchange'') submitted to the Securities and Exchange Commission (``SEC'' or ``Commission''), pursuant to section 19(b)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (``Act'' or ``Exchange Act'')</textblock>
    <textblock>and Rule 19b-4 thereunder,</textblock>
    <textblock>a proposal to amend various exchange rules. On May 4, 1992, the Amex submitted to the Commission Amendment No. 1 to the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>On June 2, 1992, the Amex submitted to the Commission Amendment No. 2 to the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>On June 25, 1993, the Amex submitted to the Commission Amendment No. 3 to the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of the proposal appeared in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on July 9, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>No comments were received on the proposal. This order approves the proposed rule changes.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Discussion and Findings</textblock>
    <textblock>The Exchange conducted a review of its rules and determined that certain revisions were necessary to conform the Amex rules to recent changes to comparable NYSE rules or to update certain rules which contain provisions which are no longer applicable or which fail to address current concerns.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Release No. 34-33448; File No. SR-Amex-92-10]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Self-Regulatory Organizations; American Stock Exchange, Inc.; Order Approving Proposed Rule Change Relating to Various Rule Revisions</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(1) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 240.19b-4 (1991).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The Amex submitted a letter to the Commission adding proposed Commentary .03(d) to Rule 111, Restrictions on Registered Traders, to state that members who are not regular members (as defined in Article IV of the Amex Constitution) may enter orders in accordance with Commentary .03, as described below, only in securities which members of their class are otherwise entitled to trade while on the Floor of the Exchange. Amendment No. 1 also would amend Rule 950(c), Floor Rules Applicable to Options, to provide that Rule 111 and certain of its commentaries shall apply to options transactions. See letter from Geraldine Brindisi, Corporate Secretary, Amex, to Mary Revell, Branch Chief, Exchange Branch, Division of Market Regulation, Commission, dated May 1, 1992.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The Amex submitted a letter to the Commission requesting that its proposed amendment to Rule 170, Commentary .02, which would permit specialists to liquidate positions in specialty stocks on zero destabilizing ticks without Floor Official approval, be withdrawn from the instant proposed rule change. See letter from Claudia Crowley, Special Counsel, Legal and Regulatory Policy Division, Amex, to Mary Revell, Branch Chief, Exchange Branch, Division of Market Regulation, Commission, dated May 29, 1992. Proposed Rule 170 was refiled in File No. SR-Amex-92-26.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Amendment No. 3 proposes additional changes to Rules 7, 108(c), 115 and 131(h). The proposed changes include: minor revisions to Rule 7, Commentary .01, in order to conform the reprint of Exchange Act Rule 10a-1 contained in the rule to its actual text; changes to Amex Rule 108(c), to include a citation to Section 11(a) of the Exchange Act; minor revisions to Rule 115, Commentary .02, to conform the reprint of Exchange Act Rule 11Ac1-1 to its actual text; minor clarifying language changes to Amex Rule 131(h). See letter from Geraldine Brindisi, Corporate Secretary, Amex, to Diana Luka-Hopson, Branch Chief, Exchange Branch, Division of Market Regulation, Commission, dated June 24, 1993.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See Securities Exchange Act Release No. 32572 (July 1, 1993), 58 FR 37041 (July 9, 1993).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The Exchange proposed various revisions to Rules 2, 6, 7, 22, 103, 108, 110, 111, 115, 124, 126, 131, 134, 135, 154, 155, 156, 178, 179, 419, 420, 550, 560, 950 and 959.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
