<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00002</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Agricultural Marketing Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[TMD-93-00-4]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Program Continuation</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Agricultural Marketing Service, USDA.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice inviting applications for fiscal year 1994 grant funds under the Federal-State Marketing Improvement Program.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the Federal-State Marketing Improvement Program (FSMIP) was allocated $1,300,000 in the Federal budget for Fiscal Year 1994. Funds remain available for this program. States interested in obtaining funds under the program are invited to submit proposals for marketing studies. Only State Departments of Agriculture or State Agencies are eligible for funds.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications will be accepted through June 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposals may be sent to Dr. Harold S. Ricker, Assistant Director, Transportation and Marketing Division, Agricultural Marketing Service (AMS), USDA, room 4006 South Building, P.O. Box 96456, Washington, DC 20090-6456.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Harold S. Ricker, (202) 720-2704.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>FSMIP is authorized under section 204(b) of the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 (7 U.S.C. 1621</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>). The program is a matching fund program designed to assist State Departments of Agriculture in conducting feasibility studies related to the marketing of agricultural products. Organizations interested in conducting a marketing study should contact their State Department of Agriculture Marketing Division to discuss their proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Mutually acceptable proposals must be submitted through the State Office and be accompanied by a completed SF 424 and detailed budget statement. FSMIP funds may not be used for advertising or the purchase of equipment or facilities. Guidelines may be obtained from your State Departments of Agriculture or the above AMS contact.</textblock>
    <textblock>In terms of objectives, the States are encouraged to submit proposals regarding:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Studies to identify new crops, markets, and marketing systems for agricultural products, both domestically and internationally;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) studies to improve efficiency of the marketing system to enhance competitiveness and profitability; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) studies to help maintain product quality through new handling, processing, and distribution techniques. Proposals addressing other marketing objectives will also receive consideration.</textblock>
    <textblock>FSMIP is listed in the ``Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance'' under number 10.156 and subject agencies must adhere to title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, which bars discrimination in all Federally assisted programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lon Hatamiya,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1124 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
