<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00107</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00060</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Commission believes that this amendment to Rule 156 should be approved because ``switch orders'' are appropriately defined under the category of ``representation of orders,'' and because allowing ``switch orders'' to be handled on a ``best efforts'' basis reflects current market realities, thereby helping to ensure efficient execution of securities transactions pursuant to section 11A(a)(1) of the Act. The NYSE has similarly revised its comparable rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 950(c)_Floor Rules Applicable to Options_Rules of General Applicability: This paragraph provides that, with certain exceptions, the restrictions on Registered Traders as imposed by Rule 111 will apply to the trading of options. The Amex proposes to extend the proposed amendment to Rule 111, to permit members while on the Floor to enter orders in a manner that permits them to be deemed ``off-Floor'' orders, to options trading. The Exchange states that because it has determined that there is no reason why the proposed revisions to Rule 111 should not be applicable to transactions in non-equity securities as well as equity securities, the Exchange proposes to revise Rule 950(c) accordingly.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission agrees that there is no reason to distinguish between options and equities with respect to ``off-floor'' orders. And, this equal treatment of equities and options will promote just and equitable principles of trade in accordance with section 6(b)(5) of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 950(e)_Floor Rules Applicable to Options_Rules of General Applicability: This provision sets forth the types of orders, in addition to the orders in Rule 131, that apply to options transactions. The Amex proposes to add a commentary to Rule 950(e) to clarify that ``at the opening'' orders in options are executable in whole or in part at the opening rotation in the pertinent option and that any such order or the portion thereof not so executed is to be treated as cancelled.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission believes that the addition of Commentary .01 to Rule 950(e) is appropriate as it will clarify the manner in which ``at the opening'' orders in options are executable. This change will therefore serve to promote just and equitable principles of trade in accordance with section 6(b)(5) of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 950(h), Commentary .05_Floor Rules Applicable to Options_Rules of General Applicability: Paragraph (h) of Rule 950 makes the specialist financial requirements contained in Rule 171 applicable to options trading. Commentary .05 to Rule 950(h), which details how the financial requirements are computed for options specialists, requires an option specialist to maintain twenty option contracts for each class of options in which he or she is registered. Rule 171, however, was revised several years ago to require specialists to ``maintain a cash or liquid asset position in the amount of $600,000 or an amount sufficient to assume a position of sixty trading units of each security in which such specialist is registered *␣*␣*.''</textblock>
    <textblock>That rule previously required specialists to assume a position of twenty trading units. The Exchange states that, because Rule 171 now refers to sixty rather than twenty trading units, Commentary .05 should be amended accordingly. The Amex, therefore, proposes to amend Commentary .05 to require that a specialist maintain sixty options contracts of each class of options in which he or she is registered.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission believes that the change to Rule 950(h) is necessary in order to conform this rule with previous changes to Rule 171 thereby promoting just and equitable principles of trade in accordance with section 6(b)(5) of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 959_Accommodation Transactions. This rule provides a ``cabinet'' trading facility for the trading of options which are out of the money to the extent that there is no buying interest at the minimum price at which options trade (1/16 of $1 or $.06-1/2 per underlying share). Orders to sell at $1 per contract ($.01 per underlying share) may be entered in the cabinet subject to a number of restrictions, including the requirement that only closing orders may be entered in the ``cabinet.'' Because the rule applies only to orders left in the ``cabinet,'' opening orders may be crossed in the crowd. The Rule, however, does not provide for this type of transaction. The Amex therefore, proposes that the rule be amended to provide that opening or closing purchase and sell orders may be executed in the crowd in the absence of closing purchase or sale orders in the cabinet.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission believe that this is an appropriate clarifying amendment to Rule 959.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Conclusion</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission has reviewed carefully the Exchange's proposed rule changes and concludes that, for the above stated reasons, the proposal is consistent with the requirements of the Act and the rules and regulations thereunder applicable to a national securities exchange. The Commission believes that the proposals developed by the Exchange appropriately balance the competing concerns of various Exchange constituencies in a manner consistent with just and equitable principles of trade. Given the dynamic nature of competitive forces shaping the national market system, the Commission strongly supports the Amex's efforts to review and update the structure of market trading regulation in order to maintain an efficient and meaningful regulatory program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, based upon the aforementioned factors, the Commission finds that the Exchange's proposed rule change updating its market regulation rules is consistent with sections 6(b)(5), 6(b)(8), 11(b), and 11A(a)(1) of the Act</textblock>
    <textblock>and the rules and regulations thereunder applicable to a national securities exchange.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is therefore ordered, pursuant to section 19(b)(2) of the Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>that the proposed rule change (File No. SR-Amex-92-10) be, and hereby is, approved.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Commission, by the Division of Market Regulation, pursuant to delegated authority.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>42</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The Amex states that the proposed amendment is based on NYSE Rule 13.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>42</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>43</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The Amex originally proposed to revise Rule 111 to apply only to equity trading. The Amex, in amendment No. 1 to the rule filing, proposed to provide that, with certain exceptions, Rule 111 and its commentaries should apply to options transactions.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>43</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>44</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See</textblock>
    <textblock>supra</textblock>
    <textblock>footnote 12.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>44</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>45</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See</textblock>
    <textblock>supra</textblock>
    <textblock>footnote 12.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>45</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>46</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>47</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See Securities Exchange Act Release No. 25863 (June 28, 1988), 53 FR 25225 (July 5, 1988) (File No. SR-Amex-88-14).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>46</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The Amex also proposes to renumber Commentary .05 to .01 as it is the only commentary under Rule 950(h).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>47</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>48</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See</textblock>
    <textblock>supra</textblock>
    <textblock>footnote 12.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>48</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>49</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78f(b)(5), 78f(b)(8), 78k(b), and 78k-1(a)(1) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>49</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>50</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(2) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>50</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>51</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See 17 CFR 200.30-3(a)(12) (1990).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>51</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1101 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
