<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00065</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>This PFD must be maintained, stowed, and used only in accordance with the owner's manual.</textblock>
    <textblock>Try this PFD in the water to see if it will float you without inflation.</textblock>
    <textblock>[</textblock>
    <textblock>For Type V only</textblock>
    <textblock>] When inflated this PFD provides performance equivalent to a (</textblock>
    <textblock>see paragraph (h) of this section for exact test to be used here).</textblock>
    <textblock>When new, this PFD provides a minimum buoyant force of [see Table 160.077-17(b)(9) for appropriate value to be used here</textblock>
    <textblock>] uninflated and [</textblock>
    <textblock>see Table 160.077-17(b)(9) for appropriate value to be used here</textblock>
    <textblock>] when inflated.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) [Reserved]</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Flotation material buoyancy loss</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Foam.</textblock>
    <textblock>When flotation foam having a V factor of less than 94 is used, the statement ``As explained in the owner's manual, test at least annually for buoyancy loss.'' must follow the minimum buoyant force statement in paragraph (c) or (d) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(h)</textblock>
    <textblock>Type equivalence.</textblock>
    <textblock>The exact text to be inserted for Type V hybrid PFD's will be one of the following type equivalents as noted on the Approval Certificate.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(j)</textblock>
    <textblock>Approved use.</textblock>
    <textblock>Unless the Commandant has authorized omitting the display of approved use, the exact text to be inserted will be one or more of the following statements as noted on the approval certificate.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) ``uninspected commercial vessels,''</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) ``Type I Hybrid PFD'' or</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) ``Type V Hybrid PFD_required to be worn to meet Coast Guard carriage requirements (except for persons in enclosed spaces as explained in owner's manual).''</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(k)</textblock>
    <textblock>Statement of minimum uninflated buoyancy.</textblock>
    <textblock>Instead of the statement concerning minimum buoyancy required by paragraphs (c) and (d) of this section, a hybrid PFD may be marked with a minimum buoyant force of greater than the values on Table 160.077-15(b)(14) for recreational hybrid PFD's or Table 160.077-17(b)(10) for commercial hybrid PFD's, if specified on the approved plans and specifications.</textblock>
    <textblock>(l)</textblock>
    <textblock>Size ranges.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Adult</textblock>
    <textblock>_For persons weighing more than 40 kg (90 lb).</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Youth</textblock>
    <textblock>_For persons weighing 23-40 kg (50-90 lb).</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Child Small</textblock>
    <textblock>_For persons weighing 14-23 kg (30-50 lb).</textblock>
    <textblock>20. Section</textblock>
    <textblock>160.077-33</textblock>
    <textblock>is redesignated §160.077-6, and in newly redesignated §160.077-6 paragraphs (b), introductory text, and (c)(1) are revised, and paragraph (a)(3)(vi) is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§160.077-6</textblock>
    <textblock>Approval Procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) The intended size range of wearer.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Waiver of tests.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a manufacturer requests that any test in this subpart be waived, one of the following must be provided to the Commandant as justification for the waiver:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Meets other requirements prescribed by the Commandant in place of or in addition to requirements in this subpart; and</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>21. Section 160.077-35 is redesignated §160.077-7 and in newly redesignated §160.077-7, paragraphs (a) and (b) are revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§160.077-7</textblock>
    <textblock>Procedure for approval of design or material revision.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Each change in design, material, or construction of an approved PFD must be approved by the Commandant before being used in any production of PFD's.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Determinations of equivalence of design, construction, and materials may be made only by the Commandant.</textblock>
    <textblock>22. Section 160.077-37 is redesignated §160.077-9 and is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§160.077-9</textblock>
    <textblock>Independent laboratories.</textblock>
    <textblock>A list of independent laboratories which have been accepted by the Commandant for conduction or supervision the tests and inspections required by this subpart, and for making material certifications required by §160.077-11, may be obtained from the Commandant.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 11, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>A.E. Henn,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Rear Admiral, U.S. Coast Guard, Chief, Office of Marine Safety, Security and Environmental Protection.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1135 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-14-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
