<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00053</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00047</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Stipulation</textblock>
    <textblock>Judge Sporkin</textblock>
    <textblock>In the matter of United States of America, Plaintiff; v. Baroid Corp., Baroid Drilling Fluids, Inc., DB Stratabit (USA) Inc., and Dresser Industries, Inc., Defendants. [Civil Action No. 93-2621; Filed: December 23, 1993.]</textblock>
    <textblock>It is stipulated by and between the undersigned parties, by their respective attorneys, that:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The Court has jurisdiction over the subject matter of this action and over each of the parties thereto, and venue of this action is proper in the District of Columbia;</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The parties consent that a Final Judgment in the form hereto attached may be filed and entered by the Court, upon motion of any party or upon the Court's own motion, at any time after compliance with the requirements of the Antitrust Procedures and Penalties Act (15 U.S.C. 16), and without further notice to any party or other proceedings, provided that plaintiff has not withdrawn consent, which it may do at any time before the entry of the proposed Final Judgment by serving notice thereof on Defendants and by filing that notice with the Court;</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The parties shall abide by and comply with the provisions of the Final Judgment pending its entry, and shall, from the date of the filing of this Stipulation, comply with all the terms and provisions thereof as though the same were in full force and effect as an order of the Court;</textblock>
    <textblock>4. In the event Plaintiff withdraws its consent or if the proposed Final Judgment is not entered pursuant to this Stipulation, this Stipulation shall be of no effect whatever, and the making of this Stipulation shall be without prejudice to any party in this or any other proceeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 23, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>For Plaintiff United States of America:</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Anne K. Bingaman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Attorney General.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Constance K. Robinson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Director of Operations.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Roger W. Fones,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Transportation, Energy &amp; Agriculture Section, U.S. Department of Justice, Antitrust Division</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Angela L. Hughes,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Denise L. Diaz,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Theodore R. Bolema,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Attorneys, U.S. Department of Justice, Antitrust Division, room 9104, 555 4th Street, NW., Washington, DC 20001, 202/307-6410.</textblock>
    <textblock>For Defendant Dresser Industries, Inc.: Akin, Gump, Strauss, Hauer, &amp; Feld, L.L.P.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Paul B. Hewitt,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>A Member of the Firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>1333 New Hampshire Avenue, NW., Suite 100, Washington, DC 20036, (202) 887-4000.</textblock>
    <textblock>For Defendants Baroid Corporation, D8 Stratabit (USA) Inc., and Baroid Drilling Fluids, Inc.: Kirkland &amp; Ellis.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Tefft W. Smith,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>A Member of the Firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>200 E. Randolph Dr., Chicago, Illinois 60601, (312) 861-2000.</textblock>
    <textblock>Stipulation Approved for Filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Done this</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>day of</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>, 199</textblock>
    <textblock>XX</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>United States District Judge.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
