<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00036</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(ii) Achieving its objectives at the end of the project period (a summative evaluation); and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Provide for the disclosure of unanticipated project outcomes, using quantifiable measures if appropriate.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number 1840-0065)</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1070a-16)</textblock>
    <textblock>§644.22</textblock>
    <textblock>How does the Secretary evaluate prior experience?</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) In the case of an application described in §644.20(a)(2)(i), the Secretary reviews information relating to an applicant's performance under its expiring Educational Opportunity Centers project. This information includes performance reports, audit reports, site visit reports, and project evaluation reports.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The Secretary evaluates the applicant's prior experience in delivering services on the basis of the following criteria:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) (3 points) (i) Whether the applicant provided services to the required number of participants who resided in the target area; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Whether two-thirds of all participants served were low-income individuals and potential first-generation college students.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) (6 points) The extent to which the applicant met or exceeded its objectives regarding the provision of assistance to individuals in applying for admission to, or financial aid for, programs of postsecondary education.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) (6 points) The extent to which the applicant met or exceeded its objectives regarding the admission or reentry of participants to programs of postsecondary education.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number 1840-0065)</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1070a-16)</textblock>
    <textblock>§644.23</textblock>
    <textblock>How does the Secretary set the amount of a grant?</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The Secretary sets the amount of a grant on the basis of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) 34 CFR 75.232 and 75.233, for new grants; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) 34 CFR 75.253, for the second and subsequent years of a project period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) If the circumstances described in section 402A(b)(3) of the HEA exist, the Secretary uses the available funds to set the amount of the grant beginning in fiscal year 1994 at the lesser of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) $180,000; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The amount requested by the applicant.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1070a-11)</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart D_What Conditions Must Be Met by a Grantee?</textblock>
    <textblock>§644.30</textblock>
    <textblock>What are allowable costs?</textblock>
    <textblock>The cost principles that apply to the Educational Opportunity Centers program are in 34 CFR part 74, subpart Q. Allowable costs include the following if they are reasonably related to the objectives of the project:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Transportation, meals, and, with specific prior approval of the Secretary, lodging for participants and staff for_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Visits to postsecondary educational institutions to obtain information relating to the admission of participants to those institutions;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Participation in ``College Day'' activities; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Field trips to observe and meet with people who are employed in various career fields in the target area and who can serve as role models for participants.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Purchase of testing materials.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Fees required for college admissions of entrance examinations if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A waiver is unavailable; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The fee is paid by the grantee to a third party on behalf of a participant.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) In-service training of project staff.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Rental of space if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Space is not available at the site of the grantee; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The rented space is not owned by the grantee.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) Purchase of computer hardware, computer software, or other equipment for student development, project administration, and recordkeeping, if the applicant demonstrates to the Secretary's satisfaction that the equipment is required to meet the objectives of the project more economically or efficiently.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1070a-11 and 1070a-16)</textblock>
    <textblock>§644.31</textblock>
    <textblock>What are unallowable costs?</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
