<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Approval and Promulgation of Air Quality Implementation Plans;</textblock>
    <textblock>Maryland; Technical Correction</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>40 CFR Part 52</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[MD29-1-6195; FRL-4826-8]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Correcting amendments.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document serves to correct the duplicate numbering of paragraphs found in the Identification of Plan Section of the Maryland State Implementation Plan (SIP). This technical correction is necessary so as to assign an individual paragraph number for a SIP revision approved by EPA on May 16, 1990.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule will become effective on February 17, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the documents relevant to this action are available for public inspection during normal business hours at the Air, Radiation, and Toxics Division, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region III, 841 Chestnut Building, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 19107; Public Information Reference Unit, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, 401 M Street, SW., Washington, DC 20460.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Harold A. Frankford, (215) 597-1325.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On May 16, 1990 (55 FR 20269), EPA approved a revision submitted by Maryland consisting of a bubble for the American Cyanamid plant in Havre de Grace. EPA's approval action was incorporated by reference (IBR'd) into the Identification of Plan section (40 CFR 52.1070) of the federally-approved Maryland SIP, and was assigned paragraph ยง52.1070(c)(87).</textblock>
    <textblock>Subsequently, it was discovered that 40 CFR 52.1070(c)(87) had already been assigned to a prior EPA approval action of a revision to the Maryland SIP. Accordingly, an editorial note was published in paragraph ยง52.1070(c)(87), explaining that EPA will correctly redesignate in a future notice the (c)(87) paragraph describing EPA's approval of the American Cyanamid bubble. By this action, EPA redesignates the IBR paragraph associated with the May 16, 1990 approval action as ยง52.1070(c)(91).</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 40 CFR Part 52</textblock>
    <textblock>Air pollution control, Carbon monoxide, Hydrocarbons, Incorporation by reference, Intergovernmental relations, Nitrogen dioxide, Ozone, Particulate matter, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Sulfur oxides.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Stanley L. Laskowski,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Administrator, Region III.</textblock>
    <textblock>40 CFR part 52, subpart V of chapter I, title 40 is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 52_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 52 continues to read</textblock>
    <textblock>as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 7401-7671q.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart V_Maryland</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 52.1070 is amended by redesignating the second paragraph currently identified as (c)(87) as paragraph (c)(91).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1060 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
