<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00116</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00069</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>THRIFT DEPOSITOR PROTECTION OVERSIGHT BOARD</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Regional Advisory Board Meetings for Regions 1-6</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Thrift Depositor Protection Oversight Board.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Meetings notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463), announcement is hereby published for the Series 15 Regional Advisory Board meetings for Regions 1 through 6. The meetings are open to the public.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The 1994 meetings are scheduled as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. February 1, 9 a.m. to 1 p.m., Baltimore, Md., Region 2 Advisory Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. February 2, 9 a.m. to 1 p.m., New Haven, Conn., Region 1 Advisory Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. February 15, 9 a.m. to 1 p.m., Denver, Colo., Region 5 Advisory Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. February 23, 9 a.m. to 1 p.m., Oklahoma City, Okla., Region 3 Advisory Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. March 2, 9 a.m. to 1 p.m., San Francisco, Calif., Region 3 Advisory Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. March 8, 9 a.m. to 1 p.m., New Orleans, La., Region 6 Advisory Board.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meetings will be held at the following locations:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Baltimore, Md._Hyatt Regency Baltimore, 300 Light Street.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. New Haven, Conn._The Colony, 1157 Chapel Street.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Denver, Colo._Hyatt Regency Denver, 1750 Welton Street.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Oklahoma City, Okla._Metro Tech Conference Center, 1900 Springlake Drive.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. San Francisco, Calif._ANA San Francisco Hotel, 50 Third Street.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. New Orleans, La._The Monteleone Hotel, 214 Royal Street.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>Jill Nevius, Committee Management Officer, Thrift Depositor Protection Oversight Board, 808 17th Street, NW., Washington, DC 20232, 202/416-2626.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 501(a) of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989, Public Law No. 101-73, 103 Stat. 183, 382-383, directed the Oversight Board to establish one national advisory board and six regional advisory boards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Regional Advisory Boards provide the Resolution Trust Corporation (RTC) with recommendations on the policies and programs for the sale of RTC owned real property assets.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agenda:</textblock>
    <textblock>Topics to be addressed at the six meetings will include: the impact of RTC property sales on local real estate market conditions; RTC's Small Investor Program; the status of Treasury Secretary Bentsen's RTC Management Reforms, RTC's affordable housing disposition programs and the RTC's environmentally significant property disposition programs. In addition, the Boards will look at the opportunity for the RTC to work with community development banks in its disposition of assets and RTC's efforts in transferring assets to its nearest regional office for management and disposition. The Boards will hear from the vice presidents of each of RTC's regional offices as well as from witnesses testifying on specific agenda topics.</textblock>
    <textblock>Statements:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons may submit to an Advisory Board written statements, data, information, or views on the issues pending before the Board prior to or at the meeting. The meetings will include a public forum for oral comments. Oral comments will be limited to approximately five minutes. Interested persons may sign up for the public forum at the meeting. All meetings are open to the public. Seating is available on a first come first served basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 12, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jill Nevius,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Committee Management Officer, Office of Advisory Board Affairs.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1130 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 2222-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
