<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Accordingly, pursuant to the rulemaking authority vested in the Attorney General in 5 U.S.C. 552(a) and delegated to the Director, Bureau of Prisons in 28 CFR 0.96(p), it is proposed to amend parts 540 and 543 in subchapter C of 28 CFR, chapter V as set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>SUBCHAPTER C_INSTITUTIONAL MANAGEMENT</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 540_CONTACT WITH PERSONS IN THE COMMUNITY</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for 28 CFR part 540 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>5 U.S.C. 301, 551, 552a; 18 U.S.C. 1791, 3621, 3622, 3624, 4001, 4042, 4081, 4082 (Repealed in part as to offenses committed on or after November 1, 1987), 5006-5024 (Repealed October 12, 1984 as to offenses committed after that date), 5039; 28 U.S.C. 509, 510; 28 CFR 0.95-0.99.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. In §540.71, paragraph (a) is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§540.71</textblock>
    <textblock>Procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)(1) At all Bureau institutions, an inmate may receive hardcover publications and newspapers only from the publisher, from a book club, or from a bookstore.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) At medium security, high security, and administrative institutions, an inmate may receive softcover publications only from the publisher, from a book club, or from a bookstore.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) At minimum security and low security institutions, an inmate may receive softcover publications (other than newspapers) from any source.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The Warden may make an exception to the provisions of paragraphs (a)(1) and (2) of this section if the publication is no longer available from the publisher, book club, or bookstore. The Warden may require that the inmate provide written documentation that the publication is no longer available from these sources. The approval or disapproval of any request for an exception is to be documented in writing.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 543_LEGAL MATTERS</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The authority citation for 28 CFR part 543 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>5 U.S.C. 301; 18 U.S.C. 3621, 3622, 3624, 4001, 4042, 4081, 4082 (Repealed in part as to offenses committed on or after November 1, 1987), 5006-5024 (Repealed October 12, 1984 as to offenses committed after that date), 5039; 28 U.S.C. 509, 510, 1346(b), 2671-80; 28 CFR 0.95-0.99, 0.172, 14.1-11.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. In §543.11, paragraph (d) is amended by revising the first sentence as follows and by removing the third and fourth sentences:</textblock>
    <textblock>§543.11</textblock>
    <textblock>Legal research and preparation of legal documents.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) An inmate may receive or purchase law materials from outside the institution in accordance with the provisions on the receipt of incoming publications (see §540.71 (a) of this chapter), but the Warden may reject material if there is a compelling reason in the interest of institution security, good order, or discipline.*␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1109 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-05-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
