<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00032</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary revises part 644 of title 34 of the Code of Federal Regulations to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 644_EDUCATIONAL OPPORTUNITY CENTERS</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart A_General</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec.</textblock>
    <textblock>644.1␣What is the Educational Opportunity Centers program?</textblock>
    <textblock>644.2␣Who is eligible for a grant?</textblock>
    <textblock>644.3␣Who is eligible to participate in a project?</textblock>
    <textblock>644.4␣What services may a project provide?</textblock>
    <textblock>644.5␣How long is a project period?</textblock>
    <textblock>644.6␣What regulations apply?</textblock>
    <textblock>644.7␣What definitions apply?</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart B_Assurances</textblock>
    <textblock>644.10␣What assurances must an applicant submit?</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart C_How Does the Secretary Make a Grant?</textblock>
    <textblock>644.20␣How does the Secretary decide which new grants to make?</textblock>
    <textblock>644.21␣What selection criteria does the Secretary use?</textblock>
    <textblock>644.22␣How does the Secretary evaluate prior experience?</textblock>
    <textblock>644.23␣How does the Secretary set the amount of a grant?</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart D_What Conditions Must Be Met by a Grantee?</textblock>
    <textblock>644.30␣What are allowable costs?</textblock>
    <textblock>644.31␣What are unallowable costs?</textblock>
    <textblock>644.32␣What other requirements must a grantee meet?</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>20 U.S.C. 1070a-11 and 1070a-16, unless otherwise noted.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart A_General</textblock>
    <textblock>§644.1</textblock>
    <textblock>What is the Educational Opportunity Centers program?</textblock>
    <textblock>The Educational Opportunity Centers program provides grants for projects designed to provide_</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Information regarding financial and academic assistance available for individuals who desire to pursue a program of postsecondary education; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Assistance to individuals in applying for admission to institutions that offer programs of postsecondary education, including assistance in preparing necessary applications for use by admissions and financial aid officers.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1070a-16)</textblock>
    <textblock>§644.2</textblock>
    <textblock>Who is eligible for a grant?</textblock>
    <textblock>The following are eligible for a grant to carry out an Educational Opportunity Centers project:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) An institution of higher education.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) A public or private agency or organization.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) A combination of the types of institutions, agencies, and organizations described in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) A secondary school, under exceptional circumstances such as if no institution, agency, or organization described in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section is capable of carrying out an Educational Opportunity Centers project in the target area to be served by the proposed project.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1070a-11)</textblock>
    <textblock>§644.3</textblock>
    <textblock>Who is eligible to participate in a project?</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) An individual is eligible to participate in an Educational Opportunity Centers project if the individual meets all of the following requirements:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)(i) Is a citizen or national of the United States;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Is a permanent resident of the United States;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Is in the United States for other than a temporary purpose and provides evidence from the Immigration and Naturalization Service of his or her intent to become a permanent resident;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Is a permanent resident of Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands (Palau); or</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) Is a resident of the Freely Associated States_the Federated States of Micronesia or the Republic of the Marshall Islands.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)(i) Is at least 19 years of age; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Is less than 19 years of age, and the individual cannot be appropriately served by a Talent Search project under 34 CFR part 643, and the individual's participation would not dilute the Educational Opportunity Centers project's services to individuals described in paragraph (a)(2)(i) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Expresses a desire to enroll, or is enrolled, in a program of postsecondary education, and requests information or assistance in applying for admission to, or financial aid for, such a program.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
