<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00084</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00051</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NATIONAL INDIAN GAMING COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Approval of Class III Tribal Gaming Ordinances</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Indian Gaming Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of approval of class III gaming ordinances.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of this notice is to inform the public of class III gaming ordinances approved by the Chairman of the National Indian Gaming Commission.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>Susan Carletta at (202) 632-7003 ext. 34, or by facsimile at (202) 632-7066 (not toll-free numbers).</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (IGRA) 25 U.S.C. 2701</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>., was signed into law on October 17, 1988. The IGRA established the National Indian Gaming Commission (the Commission). Section 2710 of the IGRA authorizes the Commission to approve class II and class III tribal gaming ordinances. Section 2710(d)(2)(B) of the IGRA as implemented by 25 CFR 522.8 (58 FR 5811 (January 22, 1993)), requires the Commission to publish, in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, approved class III gaming ordinances</textblock>
    <textblock>The IGRA requires all tribal gaming ordinances to contain the same requirements concerning ownership of the gaming activity, use of net revenues, annual audits, health and safety, background investigations and licensing of key employees. The Commission, therefore, believes that publication of each ordinance in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>would be redundant and result in an unnecessary cost to the Commission. The Commission believes that publishing a notice of approval of each class III gaming ordinance is sufficient to meet the requirements of 25 U.S.C. 2710(d)(2)(B). Also, the Commission will make copies of approved class III ordinances available to the public upon request. Requests can be made in writing to: National Indian Gaming Commission, 1850 M St. NW., suite 250, Washington, DC 20036.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Chairman has approved tribal gaming ordinances authorizing class III gaming for the following Indian tribes:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ak-Chin Indian Community</textblock>
    <textblock>Bois Forte Band of Chippewa Indians</textblock>
    <textblock>Confederated Tribes of the Chehalis Indian Reservation</textblock>
    <textblock>Fond du Lac Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians</textblock>
    <textblock>Fort McDowell Mohave-Apache Indian Community</textblock>
    <textblock>Klawock Cooperative Association</textblock>
    <textblock>Lac du Flambeau Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians</textblock>
    <textblock>Leech Lake Band of Chippewa Indians</textblock>
    <textblock>Northern Cheyenne Tribe</textblock>
    <textblock>Oneida Indian Nation of New York</textblock>
    <textblock>Robinson Rancheria of Pomo Indian</textblock>
    <textblock>Saginaw Chippewa Indian Tribe</textblock>
    <textblock>Twenty-Nine Palms Band of Mission Indians</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Anthony J. Hope,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1051 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7565-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
