<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00051</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00046</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that on December 30, 1993, a proposed consent decree in</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Maryland Sand, Gravel and Stone, et al.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Civ. A. No. HAR-89-2869, was lodged with the United States District Court for the District of Maryland.</textblock>
    <textblock>The complaint filed by the United States in October 1989 seeks to recover past, unreimbursed costs under Section 107 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation and Liability Act (``CERCLA''), 42 U.S.C. 9607, incurred by the United States in connection with response actions taken at the Maryland Sand, Gravel and Stone Superfund Site (``Site'') located in Elkton, Maryland. Maryland Sand, Gravel and Stone Company, (``Maryland Sand Company'') the owner and operator of the Site, was sued along with four other defendants. The proposed decree represents a partial settlement of this case, resolving only the United States' claims for past response costs against the Maryland Sand Company.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under this consent decree, the Maryland Sand Company will pay the United States $25,000 in partial reimbursement of the United States' unrecovered past response costs. The settlement is based on a demonstration by Maryland Sand Company of its inability to reimburse the United States for any additional response costs. Under the terms of the decree, Maryland Sand Company will also provide the United States and its representatives, including the United States Environmental Protection Agency, access to the Site for purposes of conducting and overseeing CERCLA response activities. The United States has specifically reserved its right to seek further relief from Maryland Sand Company on claims for future response costs, and for claims for natural resource damages, criminal liability and other claims that are outside of the scope of the complaint filed in this case.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Justice will receive comments relating to the proposed consent decree for a period of thirty days from the date of publication of this notice. Comments should be addressed to the Assistant Attorney General of the Environment and Natural Resources Division, Department of Justice, P.O. Box 7611, Ben Franklin Station, Washington, DC 20044, and should refer to</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Maryland Sand, Gravel and Stone, et al.,</textblock>
    <textblock>DOJ Reference No. 90-11-2-225(A).</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed consent decree may be examined at the Office of the United States Attorney for the District of Maryland, U.S. Courthouse, 101 Lombard Street, Baltimore, MD 21201; Regional III Office of the Environmental Protection Agency, 841 Chestnut Street, Philadelphia, PA.; and at the Consent Decree Library, 1120 ``G'' Street, NW., 4th Floor, Washington, DC 20005, (202) 624-0892. A copy of the proposed decree may be obtained in person or by mail from the Consent Decree Library at the address listed above. In requesting a copy, please refer to the referenced case and number, and enclose a check in the amount of $4.50 (25 cents per page reproduction costs), payable to the Consent Decree Library.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Lodging a Final Judgment by Consent Pursuant to the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation and Liability Act</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John C. Cruden,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Environmental Enforcement Section, Environment and Natural Resources Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1037 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
