<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00085</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00052</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463, as amended), the National Science Foundation announces the following meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>Name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee on Equal Opportunities in Science and Engineering (CEOSE) (1173).</textblock>
    <textblock>Date and Time:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 27, 1994; 8:30 a.m.-5:30 p.m. (Open); January 28, 1994; 8 a.m.-12 Noon (Open).</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>Rooms 375 and 380, National Science Foundation, 4201 Wilson Boulevard, Arlington, VA 22230.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>Open.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contact Person:</textblock>
    <textblock>Wanda E. Ward, Executive Secretary, CEOSE, National Science Foundation, 4201 Wilson Boulevard, room 815, Arlington, VA 22230. Telephone (703) 306-1633.</textblock>
    <textblock>Summary Minutes:</textblock>
    <textblock>May be obtained from the Executive Secretary at the above address.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose of Meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>To plan broader CEOSE participation in the federal sector and to review issues about and assessments of participation rates of all segments of society in science and engineering.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agenda:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 27: 8:30 a.m. to 12:15 p.m., rm. 375_Discussion of broader CEOSE participation in the federal sector; 12:15 p.m. to 5:30 p.m., rm. 380_Review of assessments of participation rates of all segments of society in science and engineering; January 28: 8 a.m. to 12 Noon, rm. 375_Discussion of issues about the participation rates of all segments of society in science and engineering, directions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Reason for Late Notice:</textblock>
    <textblock>Delay due to difficulty in identifying desired presenters for scheduled meeting date.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NATIONAL SCIENCE FOUNDATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Committee on Equal Opportunity in Science and Engineering; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>M. Rebecca Winkler,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Committee Management Officer.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1041 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7555-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
