<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00118</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Customs Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Public Meeting on Customs ``Mod Act''</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Customs Service, Treasury.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice announces that a 2-day public meeting will be held in Hearing Room B of the Interstate Commerce Commission in Washington, DC, commencing at 10 a.m. on Wednesday, February 9, 1994. The purpose of this meeting is to provide the public with a general briefing and invite informal discussion covering a variety of Customs modernization opportunities and requirements provided for under Title VI of the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act (Pub. L. 103-182). Because of the limitations on available seating, those planning to attend are requested to notify Customs in advance.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 9, 1994, from 10 a.m. to 5 p.m. and</textblock>
    <textblock>February 10, 1994, from 9 a.m. to 4 p.m.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interstate Commerce Commission Building, Hearing Room B, 12th Street &amp; Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dale Snell, ``Mod Act'' Task Force, U.S. Customs Service, Franklin Court, 1301 Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20229. Phone: (202) 482-6990;</textblock>
    <textblock>FAX: (202) 482-6994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 8, 1993, the President signed the ``North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act.'' The Customs modernization portion of this Act (Title VI of</textblock>
    <textblock>Pub. L. 103-182), popularly known as the Customs Modernization</textblock>
    <textblock>Act or ``Mod Act,'' became effective when it was signed. To</textblock>
    <textblock>provide the public with a general ``Mod Act'' briefing and invite informal dialogue relative to implementation plans and issues, Customs will hold an open meeting in Washington on February 9-10, 1994. Among the topics to be discussed at the meeting will be remote location filing, periodic processing (including Importer Activity Summary Statements and reconciliation), recordkeeping, regulatory audit procedures, and informed compliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because seating is limited, reservations will be required. Persons planning to attend are requested to notify Mr. Dale Snell by FAX at 202-482-6994 or by phone at 202-482-6990. Should demand for seats exceed capacity, Customs will schedule and hold a second meeting with an identical agenda.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John Durant,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, ``Mod Act'' Task Force.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1136 Filed 1-14-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4820-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
