<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00064</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Commercial Hybrid PFD.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) For a commercial hybrid PFD that is ``Required To Be Worn'' the manual must meet the requirements of paragraph (d) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For a commercial hybrid PFD approved as a ``Work Vest Only'' or Type I PFD the manual must meet the requirements of either paragraphs (f) (3) and (4) or of paragraph (c) of this section, titled Type I, II, or III Recreational Hybrid PFD.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Each commercial hybrid PFD approved with special purpose limitation must have a user's manual that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Explains in detail the proper care, maintenance, stowage, and use of the PFD; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Includes any other safety information as prescribed by the approval certificate.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) If the manual required in paragraph (f)(3) of this section calls for inspection or service by vessel personnel, the manual must_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Specify personnel training or qualifications needed;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Explain how to identify the PFDs that need to be inspected; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Have an inspection and service log, unless the information is otherwise recorded.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) If a PFD light approved under subpart 161.012 is not provided at time of sale, the manual must specify the recommended type of light to be used.</textblock>
    <textblock>18. In §160.077-30, paragraphs (a) and (b) are revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§160.077-30</textblock>
    <textblock>Spare operating components and temporary marking.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Spare operating components.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each recreational and commercial hybrid PFD must_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) If it has a manual or automatic inflation mechanism and is packaged and sold with one inflation medium cartridge loaded into the inflation mechanism, have at least two additional spare inflation cartridges packaged with it. If it is sold without an inflation medium cartridge loaded into the inflation mechanism, it must be packaged and sold with at least three cartridges; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If it has an automatic inflation mechanism and is packaged and sold with one water sensitive element loaded into the inflation mechanism, have at least two additional spare water sensitive elements packaged with it. If it is sold without a water sensitive element loaded into the inflation mechanism, it must be packaged and sold with at least three water sensitive elements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Temporary marking.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each recreational and commercial hybrid PFD which is sold_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) In a ready-to-use condition but, which has covers or restraints to inhibit tampering with the inflation mechanism prior to sale, must have any such covers or restraints conspicuously marked ``REMOVE IMMEDIATELY AFTER PURCHASE.'' or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Without an inflation medium cartridge, a water sensitive element, or both pre-loaded into the inflation mechanism, must include the markings required in §160.077-15(c)(3)(ii).</textblock>
    <textblock>19. In §160.077-31, paragraphs (c), (d), (g)(1), (h), (j), introductory text, (j)(1), and (k) are revised, paragraph (l) is added, and paragraph (e)(5) is removed and reserved to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§160.077-31</textblock>
    <textblock>PFD Marking.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Recreational Hybrid PFD.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each recreational hybrid PFD must be marked with the following text using capital letters where shown and be presented in the exact order shown:</textblock>
    <textblock>[</textblock>
    <textblock>see paragraph (l) of this section for exact text to be used here</textblock>
    <textblock>]</textblock>
    <textblock>Type [</textblock>
    <textblock>I, II, III, or V, as applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>] PFD: Recreational hybrid inflatable_Approved for use only on recreational boats. [</textblock>
    <textblock>For Type V only</textblock>
    <textblock>] REQUIRED TO BE WORN to meet Coast Guard carriage requirements (except for persons in enclosed spaces as explained in owner's manual).</textblock>
    <textblock>You May Have To Inflate This PFD To Float.</textblock>
    <textblock>This PFD requires maintenance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Try this PFD in the water to see if it will float you without inflation.</textblock>
    <textblock>[</textblock>
    <textblock>For Type V only</textblock>
    <textblock>] When inflated this PFD provides performance equivalent to a (</textblock>
    <textblock>see paragraph (h) of this section for exact test to be used here</textblock>
    <textblock>).</textblock>
    <textblock>When new, this PFD provides a minimum buoyant force of [</textblock>
    <textblock>see Table 160.077-15(b)(14) for appropriate value to be used here</textblock>
    <textblock>] uninflated and [</textblock>
    <textblock>see Table 160.077-15(b)(14) for appropriate value to be used here</textblock>
    <textblock>] when inflated.</textblock>
    <textblock>A pamphlet and owner's manual must be provided with this PFD.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Commercial Hybrid PFD.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each commercial hybrid PFD must be marked with the following text using capital letters where shown and be presented in the exact order shown:</textblock>
    <textblock>[</textblock>
    <textblock>see paragraph (l) (1) or (2) of this section for exact text to be used here</textblock>
    <textblock>]</textblock>
    <textblock>Type [</textblock>
    <textblock>``I'' or ``V Work Vest Only'', as applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>] PFD: Commercial hybrid inflatable_Approved for use on [</textblock>
    <textblock>see paragraph (j) of this section for exact text to be used here</textblock>
    <textblock>].</textblock>
    <textblock>You May Have To Inflate This PFD To Float.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
