<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00119</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940118-2-00072</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 11␣/␣Tuesday, January 18, 1994␣/␣Sunshine Act Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>Vol. 59, No. 11</textblock>
    <textblock>Tuesday, January 18, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>FEDERAL COMMUNICATIONS COMMISSION</textblock>
    <textblock>FCC To Hold Open Commission Meeting, Wednesday, January 19, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Communications Commission will hold an Open Meeting on the subjects listed below on Wednesday, January 19, 1994, which is scheduled to commence at 9 a.m., in room 856, at 1919 M Street, NW., Washington, DC.</textblock>
    <textblock>Item No., Bureau, and Subject</textblock>
    <textblock>1_Common Carrier_Title: Transport Rate Structure and Pricing (CC Docket No. 91-213). Summary: The Commission will consider adoption of a</textblock>
    <textblock>Second Report and Order</textblock>
    <textblock>regarding transport pricing.</textblock>
    <textblock>2_Common Carrier_Title: Price Cap Performance Review for Local Exchange Carriers. Summary: The Commission will consider adoption of a</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</textblock>
    <textblock>initiating the fourth year comprehensive review of the performance of local exchange carriers under price cap regulation.</textblock>
    <textblock>3_Common Carrier_Title: Amendment of the Commission's Rules to Establish Rules and Policies Pertaining to a Mobile Satellite Service in the 1610-1626.5/2483.5-2500 MHz Frequency Bands (CC Docket No. 92-166). Summary: The Commission will consider adoption of a</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</textblock>
    <textblock>concerning the establishment of a mobile-satellite service in the 1610-1626.5/2483.5-2500 MHz frequency bands.</textblock>
    <textblock>4_Common Carrier_Title: Amendment of Parts 1 and 21 of the Commission's Rules to Redesignate the 27.5-29.5 GHz Frequency Band and to Establish Rules and Policies for Local Multipoint Distribution Service (CC Docket No. 92-297, RMs-7872 and 7722). Summary: The Commission will consider adoption of a</textblock>
    <textblock>Second Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</textblock>
    <textblock>regarding proposals to redesignate the 27.5-29.5 GHz frequency band from the Point-to-Point Microwave Radio Service to a point-to-multipoint service, and regarding fixed satellite use of the band.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>The summaries listed in this notice are intended for the use of the public attending open Commission meetings. Information not summarized may also be considered at such meetings. Consequently these summaries should not be interpreted to limit the Commission's authority to consider any relevant information.</textblock>
    <textblock>This meeting may be continued the following work day to allow the Commission to complete appropriate action.</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional information concerning this meeting may be obtained from Steve Svab, Office of Public Affairs, telephone number (202) 632-5050.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William F. Caton,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1193 Filed 1-13-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
