<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00048</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00033</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Los Angeles County Metropolitan Transportation Authority_Abandonment Exemption_Between Arcadia and Los Angeles, CA, et al.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>INTERSTATE COMMERCE COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. AB-409 (Sub-No. 1X); Docket No. AB-52 (Sub-No. 75X)]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interstate Commerce Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of exemption.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission exempts from the prior approval requirements of 49 U.S.C. 10903-10904 the abandonment by the Los Angeles County Metropolitan Transportation Authority and discontinuance of service by The Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company, over 15.97 miles of rail line extending between milepost 124.2 near Arcadia Station, and milepost 140.05 near Mission Tower, in Los Angeles County, CA., subject to environmental and standard labor protective conditions. The transactions were also exempted from the offer of financial assistance and public use procedures of 49 U.S.C. 10905 and 10906, respectively.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>This exemption will be effective on February 14, 1994. Petitions to reopen must be filed by March 11, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send pleadings referring to Docket Nos. AB-409 (Sub-No. 1X) and AB-52 (Sub-No. 75X) to: (1) Office of the Secretary, Case Control Branch, Interstate Commerce Commission, Washington, DC 20423, (2) David J. Marchant, One Maritime Plaza, San Francisco, CA 94111, and (3) Dennis W. Wilson, The Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company, 1700 East Golf Road, Schaumburg, IL 60173-5860.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Beryl Gordon, (202) 927-5610. [TDD for hearing impaired: (202) 927-5721.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional information is contained in the Commission's decision. To purchase a copy of the full decision, write to, call, or pick up in person from: Dynamic Concepts, Inc., room 2229, Interstate Commerce Commission Building, Washington, DC 20423. Telephone: (202) 289-4357/4359. [Assistance for the hearing impaired is available through TDD services (202) 927-5721.]</textblock>
    <textblock>Decided: February 7, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Commission, Chairman McDonald, Vice Chairman Phillips, Commissioners Simmons and Philbin.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Sidney L. Strickland, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3365 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7035-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
