<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-1-00041</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-1-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>VIII. Regulatory Impact Statement</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Introduction</textblock>
    <textblock>We generally prepare a regulatory flexibility analysis</textblock>
    <textblock>that is consistent with the Regulatory Flexibility Act (RFA)</textblock>
    <textblock>(5 U.S.C. 601 through 612) unless the Secretary certifies</textblock>
    <textblock>that a proposed rule would not have a significant economic</textblock>
    <textblock>impact on a substantial number of small entities. For</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of the RFA, all ESRD facilities are considered to</textblock>
    <textblock>be small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also, section 1102(b) of the Act requires the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>to prepare a regulatory impact analysis if a proposed rule</textblock>
    <textblock>may have a significant impact on the operations of a</textblock>
    <textblock>substantial number of small rural hospitals. This analysis</textblock>
    <textblock>must conform to the provisions of section 603 of the RFA.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of section 1102(b) of the Act, we define a</textblock>
    <textblock>small rural hospital as a hospital that is located outside</textblock>
    <textblock>of a Metropolitan Statistical Area and has fewer than 50</textblock>
    <textblock>beds.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the provisions of Executive Order</textblock>
    <textblock>12866 this proposed rule was reviewed by the Office of</textblock>
    <textblock>Management and Budget.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Water Quality Standards</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule would incorporate into regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>existing industry standards on the quality of water used in</textblock>
    <textblock>dialysis to enable surveyors to accurately assess a</textblock>
    <textblock>facility's compliance with the standard on water quality.</textblock>
    <textblock>The AAMI standards are the result of a collaborative effort</textblock>
    <textblock>by health professionals and industry representatives to</textblock>
    <textblock>respond to clinical needs and to help ensure patient health</textblock>
    <textblock>and safety. It is our understanding that AAMI's recommended</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum levels for water contaminants have been clearly</textblock>
    <textblock>defined and supported by scientific literature and developed</textblock>
    <textblock>through industry consensus. Under the AAMI water standard,</textblock>
    <textblock>the supplier/manufacturer of dialysis water treatment</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment is responsible for assuring that the water</textblock>
    <textblock>produced by the system routinely does not exceed the maximum</textblock>
    <textblock>allowable chemical contaminant levels. Because AAMI's</textblock>
    <textblock>acceptable contamination levels have been in effect since</textblock>
    <textblock>1982 and are recognized as medically acceptable standards,</textblock>
    <textblock>we believe that manufacturers have been producing, and</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities purchasing, equipment capable of meeting these</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements. We understand that technology is in place for</textblock>
    <textblock>all facilities to meet the AAMI water standard and solicit</textblock>
    <textblock>comments on this understanding. While variations in water</textblock>
    <textblock>quality do typically occur, any changes that occur will be</textblock>
    <textblock>handled through consultation with State and local water</textblock>
    <textblock>authorities and safe purity levels ensured through continued</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring by the physician in charge of dialysis. Although</textblock>
    <textblock>contaminants in water used in dialysate may cause adverse</textblock>
    <textblock>patient reactions, actual documented adverse incidents are</textblock>
    <textblock>rare when water is monitored properly. Because the AAMI</textblock>
    <textblock>water quality standard represents long-standing acceptable</textblock>
    <textblock>medical practice, we believe the vast majority of facilities</textblock>
    <textblock>already comply with this standard. Incorporation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>AAMI standard into regulations will help ensure patient</textblock>
    <textblock>health and safety by providing surveyors with a measurable</textblock>
    <textblock>standard with which they may assess facility compliance,</textblock>
    <textblock>especially in the few facilities that do not voluntarily</textblock>
    <textblock>conform to the water quality guidelines adopted by the</textblock>
    <textblock>industry.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Reuse of Hemodialyzers</textblock>
    <textblock>The AAMI ``Recommended Practice on Reuse'' does not</textblock>
    <textblock>promote either single use or reuse of dialyzers. The</textblock>
    <textblock>guidelines were developed to acknowledge the widespread</textblock>
    <textblock>practice of reprocessing and provide recommendations for</textblock>
    <textblock>optimal hemodialyzer reprocessing. In January 1993, HCFA's</textblock>
    <textblock>Health Standard and Quality Bureau canvassed the 2,345</textblock>
    <textblock>Medicare certified ESRD facilities to determine if they</textblock>
    <textblock>practiced reuse, and if so, the disinfecting protocols used.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sixty-five percent (1,532) of the facilities reported</textblock>
    <textblock>practicing reuse. Of these facilities, approximately 51</textblock>
    <textblock>percent use renalin as the germicide, with two-thirds of</textblock>
    <textblock>these facilities using an automated disinfecting system.</textblock>
    <textblock>Approximately 40 percent of the facilities reported using</textblock>
    <textblock>formalin/formaldehyde as the germicide, with manual and</textblock>
    <textblock>automated systems receiving equal use. Approximately 9</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of the facilities practicing reuse reported using</textblock>
    <textblock>glutaraldehyde as the germicide, with the majority of these</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities using an automated disinfecting system. Less</textblock>
    <textblock>than 1 percent of the facilities use other disinfecting</textblock>
    <textblock>methods.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because the 1993 AAMI guidelines do not differ</textblock>
    <textblock>significantly from the 1986 guidelines (which all Medicare</textblock>
    <textblock>participating facilities practicing reuse already must</textblock>
    <textblock>meet), we believe that the great majority of the facilities</textblock>
    <textblock>practicing reuse would be in compliance with the new</textblock>
    <textblock>standards proposed in this regulation. The 1993 AAMI</textblock>
    <textblock>standards were developed through a public forum and their</textblock>
    <textblock>adoption was well publicized. They reflect the most</textblock>
    <textblock>up-to-date reuse procedures already practiced by many of the</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities, and we do not believe that incorporating the</textblock>
    <textblock>1993 guidelines into our regulations, in and of itself,</textblock>
    <textblock>would prompt any facility to begin or discontinue reuse.</textblock>
    <textblock>We expect that each facility would respond to these new</textblock>
    <textblock>standards based on the relationship of these standards to</textblock>
    <textblock>its current reuse practices and to factors such as whether</textblock>
    <textblock>or not a facility presently meets the standards or can meet</textblock>
    <textblock>them without extensive changes, and whether or not the</textblock>
    <textblock>facility can buy new filters in quantity less expensively</textblock>
    <textblock>than it can upgrade its reuse practices. As we said above,</textblock>
    <textblock>65 percent of the facilities are already reusing dialyzers.</textblock>
    <textblock>The major effect of this proposed rule would be to assure</textblock>
    <textblock>that Medicare standards for reuse reflect safe and effective</textblock>
    <textblock>practices.</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Conclusion</textblock>
    <textblock>Because we are unable to predict the decisions</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities would make in response to this regulation, we are</textblock>
    <textblock>unable to quantify the potential effect it would have. Some</textblock>
    <textblock>beneficiaries may be reassured that HCFA has adopted</textblock>
    <textblock>specific water quality standards and updated its standards</textblock>
    <textblock>for reuse of hemodialyzers to ensure their health and</textblock>
    <textblock>safety. However, we expect that there would be a negligible</textblock>
    <textblock>effect on most beneficiaries and facilities since we believe</textblock>
    <textblock>these revisions would make no major changes in current</textblock>
    <textblock>facility operation or patient experience. This proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule is not expected to result directly in any increases or</textblock>
    <textblock>reductions in Medicare program expenditures.</textblock>
    <textblock>For these reasons, we have determined, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary certifies that this proposed rule would not have a</textblock>
    <textblock>significant economic impact on a substantial number of small</textblock>
    <textblock>entities and would not have a significant economic impact on</textblock>
    <textblock>the operations of a substantial number of small rural</textblock>
    <textblock>hospitals. Therefore, we are not preparing analyses for</textblock>
    <textblock>either the RFA or section 1102(b) of the Act.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
