<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00077</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>6. We believe that this brief extension of the freeze will ensure that local regulators have been afforded a sufficient opportunity to file for certification and prepare for rate regulation under any modified rules that may be adopted. This extension should provide sufficient time for local regulators to become familiar with their rights and obligations under any such new regulations before cable operators are free to raise rates absent regulation. We emphasize that we will continue to provide cable operators the opportunity to file petitions for relief which demonstrate, in individual cases, that the freeze is causing severe economic hardship or threatens the viability of continued provision of cable service. Throughout the duration of the rate freeze, we have received only five such petitions for relief. Thus, we conclude that only a small percentage of cable operators believe that the freeze has imposed hardship sufficient to compel them to seek relief from the freeze.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. We also note that the Commission has acted expeditiously in addressing petitions for reconsideration of its rate regulation rules. In adopting rate regulations for the cable television industry, the Commission recognized that the rules would require further refinement based on survey data of the cable television industry to be gathered and analyzed by the Commission. Shortly after the new rules became effective, the Commission conducted a survey to collect the data necessary to help it assess the rate regulations. The Commission has analyzed this survey data and is now in a position to resolve the pending petitions for reconsideration by the end of this month. In addition to analyzing the survey data during the period since adoption of the rate rules, the Commission has accommodated the requests of numerous cable operators, franchise authorities, programmers and many other interested parties, to meet with the Commission's new Chairman, who assumed office on November 29, 1993, for the purpose of expressing their views on the issues which the Commission will address on reconsideration of the rate rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. We find good cause under the Administrative Procedure Act to make this freeze effective with less than 30 days advance publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. As explained, an extension of the freeze from February 15, 1994 until May 15, 1994 is necessary to afford local franchising authorities a sufficient period in which to familiarize themselves with any revised regulations governing regulated cable service rates that the Commission may adopt on reconsideration later this month. We will make this</textblock>
    <textblock>Order</textblock>
    <textblock>and implementing rule changes effective upon publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>to prevent an expiration of the freeze that would otherwise occur with 30 days advance publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. Such a result would seriously undermine the statutory goals of cable rate regulation and would be contrary to the public interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Ordering Clauses</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Accordingly,</textblock>
    <textblock>it is ordered,</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to sections 4(i), 303(r), and 623 of the Communications Act of 1934, as amended, 47 U.S.C. 154(i), 303(r), and 543, that the freeze of cable service rates established in</textblock>
    <textblock>Order</textblock>
    <textblock>, 8 FCC Rcd 2921, 58 FR 17530 (April 5, 1993),</textblock>
    <textblock>clarified,</textblock>
    <textblock>8 FCC Rcd 2917, 58 FR 21929 (April 26, 1993),</textblock>
    <textblock>extended,</textblock>
    <textblock>FCC 93-304 (released June 15, 1993), 58 FR 33560 (June 18, 1993),</textblock>
    <textblock>extended,</textblock>
    <textblock>FCC 93-494 (released November 10, 1993), 58 FR 60141, is extended until May 15, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>10.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is further ordered,</textblock>
    <textblock>That ยง76.1090 of the Commission's rules, 47 CFR 76.1090, is amended as set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>11.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is further ordered,</textblock>
    <textblock>That this Order is effective February 14, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 47 CFR Part 76</textblock>
    <textblock>Cable television.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William F. Caton,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 76 of chapter I of title 47 of the Code of Federal Regulations is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 76_CABLE TELEVISION SERVICE</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 76 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Secs. 2, 3, 4, 301, 303, 307, 308, 309, 48 Stat., as amended, 1064, 1065, 1066, 1081, 1082, 1083, 1084, 1085, 1101; 47 U.S.C. 152, 153, 154, 301, 303, 307, 308, 309, 532, 533, 535, 542, 543, 552, as amended, 106 Stat. 1460.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The effectiveness of section 76.1090 is extended until May 15, 1994, and the section is amended by revising paragraph (a) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง76.1090</textblock>
    <textblock>Temporary Freeze of Cable Rates.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The average monthly subscriber bill for services provided by cable operators subject to regulation under section 623 of the Communications Act shall not increase above the average monthly subscriber bill determined under rates in effect on April 5, 1993, until May 15, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3355 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
