<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00069</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Airworthiness Directives; Canadair Model CL-215-1A10 Series Airplanes</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 39</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 94-NM-09-AD; Amendment 39-8826; AD 93-16-06 R1]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule; request for comments.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This amendment revises an existing airworthiness directive (AD), applicable to certain Canadair Model CL-215-1A10 series airplanes, that currently requires modification of the right aileron and aileron tab. That AD was prompted by an updated flutter analysis performed by the manufacturer, which revealed a potential flutter condition on these airplanes. The actions specified in that AD are intended to prevent potential flutter of the rudder-aileron interconnect tab, which could result in reduced controllability of the airplane. This amendment revises the applicability of the rule by adding additional airplanes that are subject to the addressed unsafe condition.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The incorporation by reference of Canadair Alert Service Bulletin 215-A435, dated August 14, 1990, listed in the regulations, was approved previously by the Director of the Federal Register as of October 4, 1993 (58 FR 46766, September 3, 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments for inclusion in the Rules Docket must be received on or before April 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Submit comments in triplicate to the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), Transport Airplane Directorate, ANM-103, Attention: Rules Docket No.</textblock>
    <textblock>94-NM-09-AD, 1601 Lind Avenue, SW., Renton, Washington 98055-4056.</textblock>
    <textblock>The service information referenced in this AD may be obtained from Bombardier, Inc., Canadair, Aerospace Group, P.O. Box 6087, Station A, Montreal, Quebec H3C 3G9, Canada. This information may be examined at the FAA, Transport Airplane Directorate, 1601 Lind Avenue, SW., Renton, Washington; or at the FAA, Engine and Propeller Directorate, New York Aircraft Certification Office, 181 South Franklin Avenue, room 202, Valley Stream, New York; or at the Office of the Federal Register, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., suite 700, Washington, DC.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Jeff Casale, Aerospace Engineer, Airframe Branch, ANE-172, FAA, Engine and Propeller Directorate, New York Aircraft Certification Office, 181 South Franklin Avenue, room 202, Valley Stream, New York 11581; telephone (516) 791-6220; fax (516) 791-9024.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On August 13, 1993, the FAA issued AD</textblock>
    <textblock>93-16-06, Amendment 39-8663 (58 FR 46766, September 3, 1993), applicable to certain Canadair Model CL-215-1A10 series airplanes, to require installing weights to the aileron balance weight mounting channel and installing washers to the interconnect tab mass balance arms. That modification will maintain an aileron control surface mass balance within specified limits. That action was prompted by an updated flutter analysis, performed by Canadair during the development of the Model CL-215-6B11 turboprop airplane, which revealed that a potential flutter condition affecting the rudder-aileron interconnect tab could occur on certain Canadair Model CL-215-1A10 series airplanes. (The Model CL-215-6B11 is a Model CL-215-1A10 that has been converted from piston engine power to turbopropeller power.) This flutter analysis further revealed that, if the rudder-aileron interconnect mechanism fails, a flutter condition could occur at pressure altitudes above 10,000 feet. The actions required by that AD are intended to prevent potential flutter of the rudder-aileron interconnect tab, which could result in reduced controllability of the airplane.</textblock>
    <textblock>AD 93-16-06 is applicable only to Canadair Model CL-215-1A10 series airplanes that are not equipped with powered ailerons. Since issuance of that AD, however, Transport Canada Aviation, which is the airworthiness authority for Canada, has advised that additional airplanes may be subject to the same unsafe condition addressed by the previous AD action. Further analysis has indicated that the flutter problems associated with the rudder-aileron interconnect tab may occur on all Canadair Model CL-215-1A10 series airplanes, including those equipped with powered ailerons.</textblock>
    <textblock>Transport Canada Aviation revised Canadian AD CF-90-11, dated June 26, 1990, to require installation of the aileron modification on all Model CL-215-1A10 series airplanes, thereby assuring the continued airworthiness of these airplanes in Canada.</textblock>
    <textblock>This airplane model is manufactured in Canada and is type certificated for operation in the United States under the provisions of ยง21.29 of the Federal Aviation Regulations and the applicable bilateral airworthiness agreement. Pursuant to this bilateral airworthiness agreement, Transport Canada Aviation has kept the FAA informed of the situation described above. The FAA has examined the findings of Transport Canada Aviation, reviewed all available information, and determined that AD action is necessary for products of this type design that are certificated for operation in the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>Since an unsafe condition has been identified that is likely to exist or develop on other airplanes of the same type design, this AD is being issued to prevent potential flutter of the rudder-aileron interconnect tab, which could result in reduced controllability of the airplane. This AD expands the applicability of the current rule to include all Model</textblock>
    <textblock>CL-215-1A10 series airplanes. The requirements of the current rule remain unchanged. (The AD requires modification of the right aileron and aileron tab.)</textblock>
    <textblock>There currently are no Model CL-215-1A10 series airplanes on the U.S. Register. All airplanes included in the revised applicability of this rule currently are operated by non-U.S. operators under foreign registry; therefore, they are not directly affected by this AD action. However, the FAA considers that the revision to the applicability of the rule is necessary to ensure that the unsafe condition is addressed in the event that any of these subject airplanes are imported and placed on the U.S. Register in the future.</textblock>
    <textblock>Should an affected airplane be imported and placed on the U.S. Register in the future, it would require approximately 20 work hours to accomplish the required actions, at an average labor charge of $55 per work hour. Based on these figures, the total cost impact of this AD would be $1,100 per airplane.</textblock>
    <textblock>Since this AD action does not affect any airplane that is currently on the U.S. register, it has no adverse economic impact and imposes no additional burden on any person. Therefore, notice and public procedures hereon are unnecessary and the amendment may be made effective in less than 30 days after publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
