<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00044</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00029</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Public Law 92-463, the National Center for Health Statistics (NCHS), Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), announces the following committee meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>Name:</textblock>
    <textblock>NCVHS Subcommittee on Health Statistics for Minority and Other Special Populations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Time and date:</textblock>
    <textblock>8:30 a.m.-12 noon, March 8, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 503A, Hubert H. Humphrey Building, 200 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20201.</textblock>
    <textblock>Status:</textblock>
    <textblock>Open.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose:</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the subcommittee meeting is to consider the implications of health care reform for the collection of minority health data within the Federal government, including the Social Security Administration, the Bureau of the Census, and CDC, in order to better understand these issues and to serve as a basis for future recommendations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contact person for more information:</textblock>
    <textblock>Substantive program information as well as summaries of the meeting and a roster of committee members may be obtained from Gail F. Fisher, Ph.D., Executive Secretary, NCVHS, NCHS, room 1100, Presidential Building, 6525 Belcrest Road, Hyattsville, Maryland 20782, telephone 301/436-7050.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Committee on Vital and Health Statistics (NCVHS) subcommittee on Health Statistics for Minority and Other Special Populations: Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Elvin Hilyer,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Director for Policy Coordination, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3347 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-18-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
