<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00073</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>NARA Research Room Hours</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>36 CFR Part 1253</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 3095-AA56</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Archives and Records Administration (NARA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>NARA is modifying the hours that the Central Research Room, the Microfilm Research Room, and the Motion Picture, Sound and Video Research Room in the National Archives Building are open for research use. This rule affects researchers who use these research rooms in the evening. NARA is taking this action so that resources will be available for staffing the research rooms at the new National Archives at College Park (Archives II) facility.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 16, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mary Ann Hadyka or Nancy Allard on 301-713-6730.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>NARA published a notice of proposed rulemaking on September 22, 1993 (58 FR 49251) proposing that certain research rooms in the National Archives Building that were open weekday evenings and on Saturday close at 8 p.m. instead of 10 p.m., Monday through Friday, and at 5 p.m. instead of 5:15 p.m. on Saturdays. Over 70 comments were received, most opposing the proposed change. Many of these commenters noted that the reduction in evening hours would adversely impact local researchers who conduct their research in the evening after their workday as well as visiting researchers who want to maximize their research time in as short a period as possible and local evening classes who visit the National Archives on night-time field trips. Commenters who use the Microfilm Research Room noted that the reduced hours would further limit access to microfilm readers, for which there is frequently a waiting period. Several commenters offered alternative research room schedules, such as a 9 p.m. weekday closing, later opening, or closing early on selected days of the week.</textblock>
    <textblock>Commenters who favored the proposed change were primarily audiovisual archives researchers. Most of these commenters stated that extending the research hours for still pictures, cartographic, electronic and Nixon holdings at the National Archives at College Park facility (Archives II) would compensate for shortened hours in other research rooms.</textblock>
    <textblock>After carefully considering all comments, NARA has developed a revised research room schedule that would accommodate the concerns of the commenters and provide adequate staff coverage in the research rooms. NARA held a public meeting on December 13, 1993, to discuss the comments received on the proposed rule and to solicit comments on the revised schedule. Notice of the meeting was provided individually to each commenter and a notice of the meeting was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on November 30, 1993 (58 FR 63133). Twenty-one persons, including members of the public and NARA staff, attended the meeting. In addition, NARA received seven letters and three telephone calls from individuals who could not attend the meeting. These comments were also considered in the preparation of this final rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>In this final rule, NARA is modifying research room hours in the Central Research Room and Microfilm Research Room in the National Archives Building to be 8:45 a.m. to 5 p.m., Monday and Wednesday; 8:45 a.m. to 9 p.m., Tuesday, Thursday, and Friday; and 8:45 a.m. to 4:45 p.m., Saturday. The hours for the Motion Picture, Sound, and Video Research Room have been deleted from this final rule because that research room will close for relocation to Archives II before the effective date of this final rule. (That research room will be covered by a separate rulemaking on research room hours at Archives II.)</textblock>
    <textblock>The days for 9 p.m. closing of the research rooms were chosen to include days when other research facilities, including the Library of Congress, do not have evening hours. To further minimize the impact of the changed hours on researchers in the Central and Microfilm Research Rooms, NARA will not invoke the 36 CFR 1254.12(a) provision that researchers must return records up to 15 minutes before closing time in those research rooms.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule is not a significant regulatory action for the purposes of Executive Order 12866 of September 30, 1993 and it has not been reviewed by the Office of Management and Budget. As required by the Regulatory Flexibility Act, it is hereby certified that this proposed rule will not have a significant impact on small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 36 CFR Part 1253</textblock>
    <textblock>Archives and records.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set forth in the preamble, chapter XII of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations, is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 1253_LOCATION OF RECORDS AND HOURS OF USE</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 1253 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>44 U.S.C. 2104(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 1253.1 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง1253.1</textblock>
    <textblock>National Archives Building.</textblock>
    <textblock>The National Archives Building is located at Seventh Street and Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20408. Hours: For the Central Research Room and Microfilm Research Room, 8:45 a.m. to 5 p.m., Monday and Wednesday; 8:45 a.m. to 9 p.m., Tuesday, Thursday, and Friday; 8:45 a.m. to 4:45 p.m. on Saturday. For other research rooms, 8:45 a.m. to 5 p.m., Monday through Friday.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Trudy Huskamp Peterson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Archivist of the United States.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3362 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7515-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
