<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00105</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00061</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Property Claims Against the Government of Hungary</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of State has recently received the following information from the Government of Hungary about filing claims for property restitution or compensation under Hungary's domestic laws remedying illegal expropriation.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Hungarian Parliament has reopened the period within which claims for property restitution or compensation may be filed with the Government of Hungary under existing Hungarian property restitution laws. Persons who did not recover under these laws because of their failure to file by the previous deadlines may now file a claim for compensation or restitution with appropriate Hungarian authorities. These claims must be filed between February 15, 1994 and March 15, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Apart from the new filing period, Hungary's property restitution laws remain unchanged. They continue to provide only partial compensation or restitution in the form of property coupons, and eligibility remains limited to persons who meet certain citizenship requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons desiring further information about these developments or assistance relating to the filing of a claim under Hungary's domestic laws should contact the Hungarian Embassy, 3910 Shoemaker Street, NW., Washington, DC 20008.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF STATE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of the Legal Adviser</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Public Notice 1948]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Ronald J. Bettauer,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Legal Adviser for International Claims and Investment Disputes.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3470 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4710-08-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
