<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-1-00008</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-1-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>6. Responsibility for section 416(b) program oversight in recipient countries falls to the resident or regional Agricultural Attache/Counselor or, in the absence thereof, a representative designated by the United States Department of Agriculture.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 7 CFR Part 1499</textblock>
    <textblock>Agricultural commodities, Exports, Foreign aid.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, title 7 of the Code of Federal Regulations is proposed to be amended by adding a new part 1499 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 1499_FOREIGN DONATION PROGRAMS</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.1␣Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.2␣General purpose and scope.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.3␣Eligibility requirements for cooperating sponsor.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.4␣Availability of commodities from CCC inventory.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.5␣Program agreements.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.6␣Criteria for entering into program agreements.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.7␣Apportionment of costs.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.8␣Ocean transportation.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.9␣Restrictions on commodity use and distribution.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.10␣Agreement between Cooperating Sponsor and Recipient Agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.11␣Liability of the Cooperating Sponsor.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.12␣Sales, barter, and use of monetized proceeds and program income.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.13␣Usual marketing requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.14␣Processing, packaging and labeling of section 416(b) commodities in the foreign country.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.15␣Arrangements for entry and handling in the foreign country.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.16␣Disposition of commodities unfit for authorized use.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.17␣Liability for loss, damage, or improper distribution of commodities_claims and procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.18␣Records and reporting requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.19␣Termination of program.</textblock>
    <textblock>1499.20␣Sample documents/guidelines for developing proposals and reports.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>7 U.S.C. 1431(b); 7 U.S.C. 1736o; E.O. 12752.</textblock>
    <textblock>§1499.1 Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Activity</textblock>
    <textblock>_An action undertaken by a Cooperating Sponsor involving the use of agricultural commodities donated under Program Agreements or the use of monetized proceeds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agricultural Counselor or Attache</textblock>
    <textblock>_A United States Department of Agriculture representative stationed abroad responsible for the country where agricultural commodities donated under Program Agreements are to be distributed.</textblock>
    <textblock>CCC</textblock>
    <textblock>_The Commodity Credit Corporation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Commodities</textblock>
    <textblock>_Agricultural commodities or products donated under Program Agreements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cooperating Sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>_An entity with which CCC enters into a Program Agreement, including both foreign government and private nongovernment entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, P.L. 480-OD</textblock>
    <textblock>_The Director, Pub. L. 83-480 Operations Division, Foreign Agricultural Service, USDA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, PAD</textblock>
    <textblock>_The Director, Program Analysis Division, Foreign Agricultural Service, USDA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, PDD</textblock>
    <textblock>_The Director, Program Development Division, Foreign Agricultural Service, USDA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Food for Progress Program</textblock>
    <textblock>_The donation of commodities under the authority of the Food for Progress Act of 1985.</textblock>
    <textblock>General Sales Manager</textblock>
    <textblock>_General Sales Manager and Associate Administrator, Foreign Agricultural Service, USDA, who is the Vice President, CCC.</textblock>
    <textblock>KCCO</textblock>
    <textblock>_Kansas City Commodity Office, Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service, USDA, P.O. Box 419205, Kansas City, Missouri, 64141-6205.</textblock>
    <textblock>KCFMO</textblock>
    <textblock>_Kansas City Financial Management Office, Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service, USDA, P.O. Box 419205, Kansas City, Missouri, 64141-6205.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monetization</textblock>
    <textblock>_The sale of commodities by Cooperating Sponsors.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monetized proceeds</textblock>
    <textblock>_The local currency proceeds generated from monetization.</textblock>
    <textblock>Plan of Operation</textblock>
    <textblock>_A description of the activities the Cooperating Sponsor will undertake utilizing the donated commodities or monetized proceeds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Program income</textblock>
    <textblock>_Money received by the Cooperating Sponsor as a result of carrying out approved activities, including voluntary contributions from recipients of agricultural commodities in the importing country or interest received on monetized proceeds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Program Agreement</textblock>
    <textblock>_A foreign donation agreement entered into between CCC and Cooperating Sponsors.</textblock>
    <textblock>Recipient agency</textblock>
    <textblock>_An entity located in the importing country which receives commodities or monetized proceeds from a Cooperating Sponsor for the purpose of carrying out responsibilities of the Cooperating Sponsor under a Program Agreement.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
