<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00100</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00059</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Rel. No. IC-20058; 812-8600]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Smith Barney Shearson Income Trust, et al.; Application for Exemption</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Securities and Exchange Commission (``SEC'' or ``Commission'').</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of application for exemption under the Investment Company Act of 1940 (the ``Act'').</textblock>
    <textblock>APPLICANTS:</textblock>
    <textblock>Smith Barney Shearson Income Trust (formerly Shearson Lehman Brothers Income Trust) (the ``Trust''), and Smith Barney Shearson Inc. (``Smith Barney Shearson'').</textblock>
    <textblock>RELEVANT ACT SECTIONS:</textblock>
    <textblock>Exemption requested under section 6(c) from sections 2(a)(32), 2(a)(35), 22(c), and 22(d) of the Act and rule 22c-1 thereunder.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY OF APPLICATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicants request an order that would amend a prior order that permitted the Trust to impose a contingent deferred sales charge (``CDSC'') on certain redemptions of Trust shares. The prior order was granted to the Trust and Shearson Lehman Brothers Inc. (``Shearson''), the Trust's former sponsor and distributor. Since the order was granted, Shearson's assets were sold to Primerica Corporation and its subsidiary Smith Barney Shearson, and Smith Barney Shearson became the sponsor and underwriter of the Trust. Applicants request to continue the relief granted in the prior order and to extend the relief to Smith Barney Shearson and certain investment companies for which Smith Barney Shearson serves as investment adviser or principal underwriter.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>FILING DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>The application was filed on October 4, 1993, and amended on January 14, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>HEARING OR NOTIFICATION OF HEARING:</textblock>
    <textblock>An order granting the application will be issued unless the SEC orders a hearing. Interested persons may request a hearing by writing to the SEC's Secretary and serving applicants with a copy of the request, personally or by mail. Hearing requests should be received by the SEC by 5:30 p.m. on March 4, 1994, and should be accompanied by proof of service on applicants, in the form of an affidavit or, for lawyers, a certificate of service. Hearing requests should state the nature of the writer's interest, the reason for the request, and the issues contested. Persons may request notification of a hearing by writing to the SEC's Secretary.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary, SEC, 450 5th Street NW., Washington, DC. 20549. Applicants, Two World Trade Center, New York, New York 10048.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Felice R. Foundos, Senior Attorney, at (202) 272-2190, or Robert A. Robertson, Branch Chief, at (202) 272-3018 (Division of Investment Management, Office of Investment Company Regulation).</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The following is a summary of the application. The complete application may be obtained for a fee at the SEC's Public Reference Branch.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
