<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00018</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>7. The Cincinnati Gas &amp; Electric Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-942-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 31, 1994, The Cincinnati Gas and Electric Company (CG&amp;E), tendered for filing a Short Term Transmission Service Agreement (Agreement) with the City of Hamilton, Ohio. During the term of the Agreement, Hamilton, will receive 25 MW of firm service from CG&amp;E to enable Hamilton to receive economic power and energy purchased from a third party source during 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>CG&amp;E requests waiver of the Commission's notice requirements and an effective date of February 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the filing were served upon the City of Hamilton, Ohio and the Public Utilities Commission of Ohio.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 18, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Robert J. Brown</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ID-2817-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 1, 1994, Robert J. Brown (Applicant) tendered for filing a supplemental application under Section 305(b) of the Federal Power Act to hold the following positions:</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, Duke Power Company.</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, First Union Corporation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 18, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. ER&amp;L White Sulphur Springs, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. QF94-70-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 28, 1994, ER&amp;L White Sulphur Springs, Inc. of 550 Water Street, Jacksonville, Florida 32202, submitted for filing an application for certification of a facility as a qualifying cogeneration facility pursuant to Section 292.207(b) of the Commission's Regulations. No determination has been made that the submittal constitutes a complete filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>According to the applicant, the topping-cycle cogeneration facility will be located in White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia, and will consist of a diesel engine/generator and heat recovery equipment. Thermal energy recovered from the facility will be used by The Greenbrier Hotel for heating and cooling purposes. The net electric power production capacity of the facility will be 3.15 MW. The primary energy source will be fuel oil. Installation of the facility is expected to commence in May 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>Thirty days after publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Register,</textblock>
    <textblock>in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard Paragraphs</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rules 211 and 214</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (18 CFR 385.211 and 18 CFR 385.214). All such motions or protests should be filed on or before the comment date. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3338 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
