<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00070</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Comments Invited</textblock>
    <textblock>Athough this action is in the form of a final rule and was not preceded by notice and opportunity for public comment, comments are invited on this rule. Interested persons are invited to comment on this rule by submitting such written data, views, or arguments as they may desire. Communications shall identify the Rules Docket number and be submitted in triplicate to the address specified under the caption ``</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>.'' All communications received on or before the closing date for comments will be considered, and this rule may be amended in light of the comments received. Factual information that supports the commenter's ideas and suggestions is extremely helpful in evaluating the effectiveness of the AD action and determining whether additional rulemaking action would be needed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments are specifically invited on the overall regulatory, economic, environmental, and energy aspects of the rule that might suggest a need to modify the rule. All comments submitted will be available, both before and after the closing date for comments, in the Rules Docket for examination by interested persons. A report that summarizes each FAA-public contact concerned with the substance of this AD will be filed in the Rules Docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Commenters wishing the FAA to acknowledge receipt of their comments submitted in response to this notice must submit a self-addressed, stamped postcard on which the following statement is made: ``Comments to Docket Number 94-NM-09-AD.'' The postcard will be date stamped and returned to the commenter.</textblock>
    <textblock>The regulations adopted herein will not have substantial direct effects on the States, on the relationship between the national government and the States, or on the distribution of power and responsibilities among the various levels of government. Therefore, in accordance with Executive Order 12612, it is determined that this final rule does not have sufficient federalism implications to warrant the preparation of a Federalism Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons discussed above, I certify that this action (1) is not a ``significant regulatory action'' under Executive Order 12866; (2) is not a ``significant rule'' under DOT Regulatory Policies and Procedures (44 FR 11034, February 26, 1979); and (3) will not have a significant economic impact, positive or negative, on a substantial number of small entities under the criteria of the Regulatory Flexibility Act. A final evaluation has been prepared for this action and it is contained in the Rules Docket. A copy of it may be obtained from the Rules Docket at the location provided under the caption ``</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>''.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 14 CFR Part 39</textblock>
    <textblock>Air transportation, Aircraft, Aviation safety, Incorporation by reference, Safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>Adoption of the Amendment</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, pursuant to the authority delegated to me by the Administrator, the Federal Aviation Administration amends 14 CFR part 39 of the Federal Aviation Regulations as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 39_AIRWORTHINESS DIRECTIVES</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 39 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>49 U.S.C. App. 1354(a), 1421 and 1423; 49 U.S.C. 106(g); and 14 CFR 11.89.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง39.13</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 39.13 is amended by removing amendment 39-8663 (58 FR 46766, September 3, 1993), and by adding a new airworthiness directive (AD), amendment 39-8826, to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>93-16-06 R1 Canadair:</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendment 39-8826. Docket 94-NM-09-AD. Revises AD 93-16-06, Amendment 39-8663.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicability:</textblock>
    <textblock>All Model CL-215-1A10 series airplanes, certificated in any category.</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance:</textblock>
    <textblock>Required as indicated, unless accomplished previously.</textblock>
    <textblock>To prevent potential flutter of the rudder-aileron interconnect tab, which could result in reduced controllability of the airplane, accomplish the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) For Model CL-215-1A10 series airplanes; serial numbers 1001 through 1125 inclusive, not equipped with powered ailerons: Within 12 months after October 4, 1993 (the effective date of AD 93-16-06, amendment 39-8663), on the right wing install weights to the aileron balance weight mounting channel and washers to the interconnect tab mass balance arms, in accordance with Canadair Alert Service Bulletin 215-A435, dated August 14, 1990.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) For all other airplanes not subject to paragraph (a) of this AD: Within 12 months after the effective date of this AD, on the right wing install weights to the aileron balance weight mounting channel and washers to the interconnect tab mass balance arms, in accordance with Canadair Alert Service Bulletin 215-A435, dated August 14, 1990.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) An alternative method of compliance or adjustment of the compliance time that provides an acceptable level of safety may be used if approved by the Manager, New York Aircraft Certification Office (ACO), FAA, Engine and Propeller Directorate. Operators shall submit their requests through an appropriate FAA Principal Maintenance Inspector, who may add comments and then send it to the Manager, New York ACO.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information concerning the existence of approved alternative methods of compliance with this AD, if any, may be obtained from the New York ACO.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Special flight permits may be issued in accordance with Federal Aviation Regulations (FAR) 21.197 and 21.199 to operate the airplane to a location where the requirements of this AD can be accomplished.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) The installation shall be done in accordance with Canadair Alert Service Bulletin 215-A435, dated August 14, 1990. The incorporation by reference of this document was approved previously by the Director of the Federal Register in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552(a) and 1 CFR part 51 as of October 4, 1993 (58 FR 46766, September 3, 1993). Copies may be obtained from Bombardier, Inc., Canadair, Aerospace Group, P.O. Box 6087, Station A, Montreal, Quebec H3C 3G9, Canada. Copies may be inspected at the FAA, Transport Airplane Directorate, 1601 Lind Avenue, SW., Renton, Washington; or at the FAA, Engine and Propeller Directorate, New York ACO, 181 South Franklin Avenue, room 202, Valley Stream, New York; or at the Office of the Federal Register, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., suite 700, Washington, DC.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) This amendment becomes effective on March 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Renton, Washington, on February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Darrell M. Pederson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Manager, Transport Airplane Directorate,</textblock>
    <textblock>Aircraft Certification Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3349 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
