<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00066</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Names and positions of individuals in the community who provided information for the study:</textblock>
    <textblock>I affirm that I, or an individual under contract to my company, have made a physical inspection of the market area and that information has been used in the full assessment of the need and demand for new rental units. I understand that misrepresentation of this statement may result in denial of further participation in the FmHA Section 515 program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Market Analyst</textblock>
    <textblock>25. Exhibit A-9 of subpart E is amended in the introductory text of paragraph 9 by revising the words ``Statement of Budget and Cash Flow'' to read ``Multiple Family Housing Project Budget'' and by revising the exhibit heading and paragraphs 2 and 5 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Exhibit A-9 of Subpart E_Information To Be Submitted With Application for Rural Rental Housing (RRH) and Rural Cooperative Housing (RCH) Loans</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Updated cost estimates on Form FmHA 1924-13, ``Estimate and Certificate of Actual Cost,'' will be submitted by all applicants, along with the updated estimates of associated costs specified in Exhibit A-7 of this subpart.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>5. If more than 12 months have transpired since the applicant submitted the market analysis, the State Director may require that it be updated if he/she determines it necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>26. Exhibit A-10 of subpart E is amended by adding paragraph II C to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Exhibit A-10 of Subpart E_Administrative Process for Combining Farmers Home Administration (FmHA) Assistance With Low-Income Housing Tax Credits</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
