<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00072</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00043</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Licensing Support System Advisory Review Panel; Renewal</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of renewal of the Licensing Support System Advisory Review Panel (LSSARP).</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Licensing Support System Advisory Review Panel was established by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission as a Federal Advisory Committee in 1989. Its purpose is to provide advice to (1) the Department of Energy on the fundamental issues of design and development of an electronic information management system to be used to store and retrieve documents relating to the licensing of a geologic repository for the disposal of high-level radioactive waste, and (2) the Nuclear Regulatory Commission on the operation and maintenance of the system. This electronic information management system is known as the Licensing Support System (LSS).</textblock>
    <textblock>Membership on the Panel is drawn from those interests that will be affected by the use of the LSS, including the Department of Energy, the NRC, the State of Nevada, Tribal interests, affected units of local governments in Nevada, and the nuclear industry. Federal agencies with expertise and experience in electronic information management systems also participate on the Panel.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Nuclear Regulatory Commission has determined that renewal of the charter for the LSSARP until December 19, 1994 is in the public interest in connection with duties imposed on the Commission by law. This action is being taken in accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act after consultation with the Committee Management Secretariat, General Services Administration.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>John Hoyle, Office of the Secretary, NRC, Washington, DC 20555; telephone: (301) 504-1968.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John C. Hoyle,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Advisory Committee Management Officer.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3374 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7590-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
