<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00093</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Waiting Period (Interim Provision)</textblock>
    <textblock>The Act provides that the waiting period provisions of</textblock>
    <textblock>the law become effective on February 28, 1994, and cease to</textblock>
    <textblock>apply on November 30, 1998. The Act imposes a waiting</textblock>
    <textblock>period of 5 business days (defined in the statute as days</textblock>
    <textblock>on which State offices are open) before a licensee may</textblock>
    <textblock>sell or deliver a handgun. As defined in the Act, the term</textblock>
    <textblock>``handgun'' means_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) a firearm which has a short stock and is designed</textblock>
    <textblock>to be held and fired by the use of a single hand; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) any combination of parts from which a firearm</textblock>
    <textblock>described in subparagraph (A) can be assembled.</textblock>
    <textblock>Basically, the waiting period provision makes it</textblock>
    <textblock>unlawful for any licensed firearms importer, manufacturer,</textblock>
    <textblock>or dealer to sell, deliver, or transfer a handgun to a</textblock>
    <textblock>nonlicensed individual (transferee), unless the licensee_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Obtains a statement of the transferee's intent</textblock>
    <textblock>to obtain a handgun containing the transferee's name,</textblock>
    <textblock>address, and date of birth appearing on a valid photo</textblock>
    <textblock>identification, a description of the identification</textblock>
    <textblock>document, a statement that the transferee is not a felon,</textblock>
    <textblock>under indictment, or otherwise prohibited from receiving or</textblock>
    <textblock>possessing the handgun under Federal law, and the date the</textblock>
    <textblock>statement is made;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Verifies the identity of the transferee by examining</textblock>
    <textblock>the identification document presented;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Within 1 day after the transferee furnishes the</textblock>
    <textblock>statement, contacts the chief law enforcement officer of</textblock>
    <textblock>the place of residence of the transferee and advises such</textblock>
    <textblock>officer of the contents of the statement;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Within 1 day after the transferee furnishes the</textblock>
    <textblock>statement, transmits to the chief law enforcement officer</textblock>
    <textblock>of the place of residence of the transferee a copy of the</textblock>
    <textblock>statement; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Waits 5 business days from the date the licensee</textblock>
    <textblock>furnished notice of the contents of the statement to the</textblock>
    <textblock>chief law enforcement officer before transferring the</textblock>
    <textblock>handgun to the transferee (during which period the licensee</textblock>
    <textblock>has not received information from the chief law enforcement</textblock>
    <textblock>officer that receipt or possession of the handgun by the</textblock>
    <textblock>transferee would be in violation of law); or receives</textblock>
    <textblock>notice from the chief law enforcement officer of the place</textblock>
    <textblock>of residence of the transferee that the officer has no</textblock>
    <textblock>information that the transferee's receipt or possession of</textblock>
    <textblock>the handgun would violate the law.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to the items in (1) above, the regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>request certain additional optional information about the</textblock>
    <textblock>transferee to facilitate the transfer of a handgun and</textblock>
    <textblock>assist law enforcement officials in verifying the</textblock>
    <textblock>transferee's eligibility to possess a handgun. This</textblock>
    <textblock>optional information includes the social security</textblock>
    <textblock>number, height, weight, sex, and place of birth of the</textblock>
    <textblock>transferee. The optional information will help minimize</textblock>
    <textblock>the misidentification of handgun purchasers as felons or</textblock>
    <textblock>other prohibited persons whose receipt and possession of</textblock>
    <textblock>firearms violate the law. For example, this information</textblock>
    <textblock>would distinguish the transferee from a prohibited buyer</textblock>
    <textblock>having the same name and date of birth as the transferee</textblock>
    <textblock>and, therefore, help expedite the transfer.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subsequent to the sale or transfer of the handgun, the</textblock>
    <textblock>law requires a licensee, who receives a report from the</textblock>
    <textblock>chief law enforcement officer containing information that</textblock>
    <textblock>receipt or possession of the handgun by the transferee</textblock>
    <textblock>violates Federal, State, or local law, shall within 1 day</textblock>
    <textblock>communicate any information the licensee has concerning the</textblock>
    <textblock>transfer to the chief law enforcement officer of the place</textblock>
    <textblock>of business of the licensee and to the chief law</textblock>
    <textblock>enforcement officer of the place of residence of the</textblock>
    <textblock>transferee.</textblock>
    <textblock>As provided in the Act, the term ``chief law enforcement</textblock>
    <textblock>officer'' means ``the chief of police, the sheriff, or an</textblock>
    <textblock>equivalent officer or the designee of any such individual.''</textblock>
    <textblock>The law requires that the chief law enforcement officer</textblock>
    <textblock>within 5 business days make a reasonable effort to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine whether the transferee is prohibited by law from</textblock>
    <textblock>receiving or possessing the handgun sought to be purchased.</textblock>
    <textblock>Except for records relating to a proposed handgun sale that</textblock>
    <textblock>would violate the law, law enforcement officers are</textblock>
    <textblock>required to destroy within 20 days the purchaser's</textblock>
    <textblock>statement, any record containing information derived from</textblock>
    <textblock>the statement, and any record created as a result of the</textblock>
    <textblock>notice referred to in (3) above. Furthermore, these</textblock>
    <textblock>records may only be used to carry out the purposes of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Act, and no information in the records may be conveyed to</textblock>
    <textblock>any person for purposes other than complying with the Act.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
