<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00014</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[I.D. 020794D]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Marine Mammals; Permits</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), NOAA, Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Receipt of application to modify Permit No. 867 (P540).</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that Dr. Frank Cipriano, Kewalo Marine Laboratory, 13 Ahui Street, Honolulu, HI 96813, has requested a modification to Permit No. 867.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The modification request and related documents are available for review upon written request or by appointment in the following office(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>Permits Division, Office of Protected Resources, NMFS, 1315 East-West Highway, room 13130, Silver Spring, MD 20910 (301/713-2289);</textblock>
    <textblock>Southwest Region, NMFS, 501 West Ocean Blvd., suite 4200, Long Beach, CA 90802-4213 (310/980-4015);</textblock>
    <textblock>Northwest Region, NMFS, 7600 Sand Point Way, NE., BIN C15700, Seattle, WA 98115;</textblock>
    <textblock>Alaska Region, NMFS, Federal Annex, P.O. Box 13668, Juneau, AK 99802 (907/586-7221);</textblock>
    <textblock>Southeast Region, NMFS, 9540 Koger Blvd., St. Petersburg,</textblock>
    <textblock>FL 33702 (813/893-3141); and</textblock>
    <textblock>Northeast Region, NMFS, One Blackburn Drive, Gloucester,</textblock>
    <textblock>MA 01930 (508/281-9200).</textblock>
    <textblock>Written data or views, or requests for a public hearing on this request should be submitted to the Director, Office of Protected Resources, NMFS, NOAA, U.S. Department of Commerce, 1315 East-West Highway, Silver Spring, MD 20910, within 30 days of the publication of this notice. Those individuals requesting a hearing should set forth the specific reasons why a hearing on this particular modification request would be appropriate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Concurrent with the publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, the Secretary of Commerce is forwarding copies of this application to the Marine Mammal Commission and its Committee of Scientific Advisors.</textblock>
  </address>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The subject modification to Permit No. 867, issued on July 20, 1993 (58 FR 40114) is requested under the authority of the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972, as amended 16 U.S.C. 1361 et seq.), the Regulations Governing the Taking and Importing of Marine Mammals (50 CFR part 216), the Endangered Species Act of 1973, as amended (16 U.S.C. 1531</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>) and the regulations governing the taking, importing, and exporting of endangered fish and wildlife (50 CFR parts 217-222).</textblock>
    <textblock>Permit No. 867 authorizes the Permit Holder to import samples from dusky dolphin</textblock>
    <textblock>L. obscurus</textblock>
    <textblock>and Pacific white-sided dolphin</textblock>
    <textblock>L. obliquidens,</textblock>
    <textblock>samples from each of white-beaked dolphin</textblock>
    <textblock>L. albirostris,</textblock>
    <textblock>Atlantic white-sided dolphin</textblock>
    <textblock>L. acutus,</textblock>
    <textblock>hourglass dolphin</textblock>
    <textblock>L. cruciger,</textblock>
    <textblock>and Peale's dolphin</textblock>
    <textblock>L. australis.</textblock>
    <textblock>The samples would be obtained opportunistically, from existing collections and museums, captive dolphins, Permitted researchers, and/or imported from Peru, Chile, Argentina, New Zealand, and South Africa.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Holder requests authorization to include an additional 54 odontocete species in his research. A small quantity (5 grams) of skin, heart, muscle or liver tissue will be obtained for genetic analysis. The samples may be obtained from available collections and museums in the United States, Argentina, Canada, Chile, France, Peru, New Zealand, South Africa, the United Kingdom. The additional samples are needed in the ongoing molecular-genetic study for outgroup analysis of relationships within</textblock>
    <textblock>Lagenorhynchus</textblock>
    <textblock>and assessment of the relationship of</textblock>
    <textblock>Lagenorhyncyhus</textblock>
    <textblock>to other dolphins.</textblock>
    <textblock>February 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William W. Fox, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Protected Resources,</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3346 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
