<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-1-00034</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Any person may obtain a copy of this NPRM by submitting a request to the FAA, Transport Airplane Directorate, ANM-103, Attention: Rules Docket No. 93-NM-198-AD, 1601 Lind Avenue, SW., Renton, Washington 98055-4056.</textblock>
    <textblock>Discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>The Civil Aviation Authority (CAA), which is the airworthiness authority for the United Kingdom, recently notified the FAA that an unsafe condition may exist on certain Jetstream Model 4101 airplanes. The CAA advises that the manufacturer found an abraded electrical power cable in the wiring harness at the wing rear spar on one airplane. The cause of this abrasion has been attributed to insufficient clearance between the electrical cable loom and the flap mechanism. Abrasion of these cables, if not corrected, could result in dormant failure of emergency fuel and hydraulic shutoff services.</textblock>
    <textblock>Jetstream Aircraft Limited has issued Service Bulletin J41-57-003, dated October 13, 1993, that describes procedures for installation of new fairlead assemblies and P-clips; visual inspection to detect damage of the wiring harnesses at the wing rear spars; verification of the positioning of the currently installed P-clips; and repositioning of improperly installed P-clips. The CAA classified this service bulletin as mandatory in order to assure the continued airworthiness of these airplanes in the United Kingdom.</textblock>
    <textblock>This airplane model is manufactured in the United Kingdom and is type certificated for operation in the United States under the provisions of ยง21.29 of the Federal Aviation Regulations and the applicable bilateral airworthiness agreement. Pursuant to this bilateral airworthiness agreement, the CAA has kept the FAA informed of the situation described above. The FAA has examined the findings of the CAA, reviewed all available information, and determined that AD action is necessary for products of this type design that are certificated for operation in the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>Since an unsafe condition has been identified that is likely to exist or develop on other airplanes of the same type design registered in the United States, the proposed AD would require installation of new fairlead assemblies and P-clips; visual inspection to detect damage of the wiring harnesses at the wing rear spars; verification of the positioning the of currently installed P-clips, and repositioning improperly installed P-clips. The actions would be required to be accomplished in accordance with the service bulletin described previously.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposal would also require that operators repair or replace damaged wiring harnesses.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA estimates that 12 airplanes of U.S. registry would be affected by this proposed AD, that it would take approximately 2 work hours per airplane to accomplish the proposed actions, and that the average labor rate is $55 per work hour. Required parts would be provided by the manufacturer at no cost to the operator. Based on these figures, the total cost impact of the proposed AD on U.S. operators is estimated to be $1,320, or $110 per airplane. This total cost figure assumes that no operator has yet accomplished the proposed requirements of this AD action.</textblock>
    <textblock>The regulations proposed herein would not have substantial direct effects on the States, on the relationship between the national government and the States, or on the distribution of power and responsibilities among the various levels of government. Therefore, in accordance with Executive Order 12612, it is determined that this proposal would not have sufficient federalism implications to warrant the preparation of a Federalism Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons discussed above, I certify that this proposed regulation (1) is not a ``significant regulatory action'' under Executive Order 12866; (2) is not a ``significant rule'' under the DOT Regulatory Policies and Procedures (44FR 11034, February 26, 1979); and (3) if promulgated, will not have a significant economic impact, positive or negative, on a substantial number of small entities under the criteria of the Regulatory Flexibility Act. A copy of the draft regulatory evaluation prepared for this action is contained in the Rules Docket. A copy of it may be obtained by contacting the Rules Docket at the location provided under the caption ``</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>.''</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 14 CFR Part 39</textblock>
    <textblock>Air transportation, Aircraft, Aviation safety, Safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Proposed Amendment</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, pursuant to the authority delegated to me by the Administrator, the Federal Aviation Administration proposes to amend 14 CFR part 39 of the Federal Aviation Regulations as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 39_AIRWORTHINESS DIRECTIVES</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 39 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>49 U.S.C. App. 1354(a), 1421 and 1423; 49 U.S.C. 106(g); and 14CFR 11.89.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง39.13</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 39.13 is amended by adding the following new airworthiness directive:</textblock>
    <textblock>Jetstream Aircraft Limited:</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket 93-NM-198-AD.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicability:</textblock>
    <textblock>Model 4101 airplanes having constructor numbers 41004 through 41016 inclusive, certificated in any category.</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance:</textblock>
    <textblock>Required as indicated, unless accomplished previously.</textblock>
    <textblock>To prevent abrasion of the electrical power cables in the wiring harnesses at the wing rear spars, which could lead to a dormant failure of emergency fuel and hydraulic shutoff services, accomplish the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Within 3 months after the effective date of this AD, install new fairleads and P-clips, perform a visual inspection to detect damage of the wiring harness at the left and right wing rear spar, and verify that the currently installed P-clips are properly positioned; in accordance with Jetstream Series 4100 Service Bulletin J41-57-003, dated October 13, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) If any wiring harness is found to be damaged, prior to further flight, accomplish the requirements of either paragraph (a)(1)(i) or (a)(1)(ii) of this AD.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Replace the damaged wiring harness with a new wiring harness assembly in accordance with Jetstream Series 4100 Aircraft Maintenance Manual. Or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Repair the damaged wiring harness in accordance with a method approved by the Manager, Standardization Branch, ANM-113, FAA, Transport Airplane Directorate.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If any currently installed P-clip is found to be improperly positioned, prior to further flight, reposition the P-clip in accordance with the service bulletin.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) An alternative method of compliance or adjustment of the compliance time that provides an acceptable level of safety may be used if approved by the Manager, Standardization Branch, ANM-113. Operators shall submit their requests through an appropriate FAA Principal Maintenance Inspector, who may add comments and then send it to the Manager, Standardization Branch, ANM-113.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information concerning the existence of approved alternative methods of compliance with this AD, if any, may be obtained from the Standardization Branch, ANM-113.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Special flight permits may be issued in accordance with FAR 21.197 and 21.199 to operate the airplane to a location where the requirements of this AD can be accomplished.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Renton, Washington, on February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Darrell M. Pederson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Manager, Transport Airplane Directorate, Aircraft Certification Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3350 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
