<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00101</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under</textblock>
    <textblock>control number 1512-0520)</textblock>
    <textblock>§178.131</textblock>
    <textblock>Handgun transactions not subject to the waiting</textblock>
    <textblock>period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)(1) A licensed importer, licensed manufacturer, or</textblock>
    <textblock>licensed dealer whose sale, delivery, or transfer of a</textblock>
    <textblock>handgun is made pursuant to the alternative provisions of §178.102(b) and is not subject to the waiting period</textblock>
    <textblock>prescribed by §178.102(a) shall maintain the records</textblock>
    <textblock>required by this paragraph (a).</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If the transfer is pursuant to a written statement</textblock>
    <textblock>of the chief law enforcement officer in accordance with §178.102(b)(1), the licensee shall retain such statement and</textblock>
    <textblock>attach it to the firearms transaction record, Form 4473,</textblock>
    <textblock>executed upon delivery of the handgun.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) If the transfer is pursuant to a permit or license</textblock>
    <textblock>in accordance with §178.102(b)(2), the licensee shall</textblock>
    <textblock>retain a copy of such permit or license and attach it to</textblock>
    <textblock>the firearms transaction record, Form 4473, executed upon</textblock>
    <textblock>delivery of the handgun.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) If the transfer is pursuant to a verification</textblock>
    <textblock>of eligibility to possess a handgun (e.g., an instant</textblock>
    <textblock>record check) by a government official in accordance with §178.102(b)(3), the licensee shall attach to the firearms transaction record, Form 4473, executed upon delivery of</textblock>
    <textblock>the handgun, a statement showing the date of verification,</textblock>
    <textblock>any identifying number assigned to the transaction by</textblock>
    <textblock>the official, and the name, location, and title of the</textblock>
    <textblock>official.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) If the transfer is pursuant to a certification by</textblock>
    <textblock>ATF in accordance with §§178.102(b)(5) and 178.150, the</textblock>
    <textblock>licensee shall maintain the certification as part of the</textblock>
    <textblock>records required to be kept under this subpart and for the</textblock>
    <textblock>period prescribed for the retention of Form 5300.35 in</textblock>
    <textblock>§178.129(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The requirements of this section shall be in</textblock>
    <textblock>addition to any other recordkeeping requirements contained</textblock>
    <textblock>in this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under</textblock>
    <textblock>control number 1512-0520)</textblock>
    <textblock>§178.150</textblock>
    <textblock>[Redesignated as §178.151.]</textblock>
    <textblock>Par. 12.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 178.150 of Subpart I is redesignated</textblock>
    <textblock>as §178.151, and new §178.150 is added to</textblock>
    <textblock>read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§178.150</textblock>
    <textblock>Alternative to handgun waiting period in certain</textblock>
    <textblock>geographical locations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The provisions of §178.102(b)(5) shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable when the Director has certified that compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>with the waiting period provisions of §178.102(a) is impracticable because:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The ratio of the number of law enforcement</textblock>
    <textblock>officers of the State in which the transfer is to occur to</textblock>
    <textblock>the number of square miles of land area of the State does</textblock>
    <textblock>not exceed 0.0025;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The business premises of the licensee at which the</textblock>
    <textblock>transfer is to occur are extremely remote in relation to</textblock>
    <textblock>the chief law enforcement officer; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) There is an absence of telecommunications</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities in the geographical area in which the business</textblock>
    <textblock>premises are located.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) A licensee who desires to obtain a certification</textblock>
    <textblock>under this section shall submit a written request to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Director. Each request shall be executed under the</textblock>
    <textblock>penalties of perjury and contain information sufficient for</textblock>
    <textblock>the Director to make such certification. Such information</textblock>
    <textblock>shall include statistical data, official reports, or other</textblock>
    <textblock>statements of government agencies pertaining to the ratio</textblock>
    <textblock>of law enforcement officers to</textblock>
    <textblock>the number of square miles of land area of a State and</textblock>
    <textblock>statements of government agencies and private utility companies regarding the absence of telecommunications</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities in the geographical area in which the licensee's</textblock>
    <textblock>business premises are located.</textblock>
    <textblock>Signed: January 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Daniel R. Black,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director.</textblock>
    <textblock>Approved: January 27, 1994.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John P. Simpson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Assistant Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>(Regulatory, Tariff and Trade Enforcement).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3227 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4810-31-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
