<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00076</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00047</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Final Memorandum of Understanding Between the Nuclear Regulatory Commission and the State of Kansas</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice is to advise the public of the issuance of a Final Memorandum of Understanding (MOU) between the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) and the State of Kansas. The MOU provides the basis for mutually agreeable procedures whereby the State of Kansas may utilize the NRC Emergency Response Data System (ERDS) to receive data during an emergency at a commercial nuclear power plant in Kansas. Public comments were addressed in conjunction with the MOU with the State of Michigan published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>Vol. 57, No. 28, February 11, 1992.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>This MOU is effective January 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of all NRC documents are available for public inspection and copying for a fee in the NRC Public Document Room, 2120 L Street, NW. (Lower Level), Washington, DC.</textblock>
    <textblock>For Further Information Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>John R. Jolicoeur or Eric Weinstein, Office for Analysis and Evaluation of Operational Data, U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555. Telephone (301) 492-4155 or (301) 492-7836.</textblock>
    <textblock>This attached MOU is intended to formalize and define the manner in which the NRC will cooperate with the State of Kansas to provide data related to plant conditions during emergencies at commercial nuclear power plants in Kansas.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated at Rockville, Maryland, this 7th day of February, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </address>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Edward L. Jordan,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office for Analysis and Evaluation of Operational Data.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
