<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00054</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00037</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,288; Chevron USA, Inc., Chevron Information Technology Co, Headquartered in San Ramon, CA &amp; Other Operations in the Following States: A; CA, B; CO, C; LA, D; MS, E; NM, F; OK, G; PA, H; TX, I; UT, J; WY</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after November 19, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,267; Nicole Fashions, Inc., Larksville, PA</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,275; USA Manufacturing, Larksville, PA</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after November 17, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-28,250; Isratex, Inc., Winfield, AL</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after October 29, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,246; General Glass Industries Corp., Jeannette, PA</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after November 8, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,238; Slyter Chair, Inc., Tacoma, WA</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after November 5, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,235; Natural Casing Co., Pishtigo, WI</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after November 2, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,276; Worcester Knitting Co., Worcester, MA</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,277; Worcester Spinning &amp; Finishing, Cherry Valley, MA</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,278; Nanagansett Knitting Mills, Woonsocket, RI</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after November 16, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also, pursuant to Title V of the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act (Pub. L. 103-182) concerning transitional adjustment assistance hereinafter called (NAFTA-TAA) and in accordance with Section 250(a) Subchapter D, Chapter 2, Title II, of the Trade Act as amended, the Department of Labor presents summaries of determinations regarding eligibility to apply for NAFTA-TAA issued during the month of February, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order for an affirmative determination to be made and a certification of eligibility to apply for NAFTA-TAA the following group eligibility requirements of Section 250 of the Trade Act must be met:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) That a significant number or proportion of the workers in the workers' firm, or an appropriate subdivision thereof, (including workers in any agricultural firm or appropriate subdivision thereof) have become totally or partially separated from employment and either_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) That sales or production, or both, of such firm or subdivision have decreased absolutely,</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) That imports from Mexico or Canada of articles like or directly competitive with articles produced by such firm or subdivision have increased.</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) That the increase in imports contributed importantly to such workers' separations or threat of separation and to the decline in sales or production of such firm or subdivision; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) That there has been a shift in production by such workers' firm or subdivision to Mexico or Canada of articles like or directly competitive with articles which are produced by the firm or subdivision.</textblock>
    <textblock>Negative Determinations NAFTA-TAA</textblock>
    <textblock>NAFTA-TAA-00001; American Marketing Industries, Inc., Swingster Co., Ocean Springs, MS</textblock>
    <textblock>The investigation revealed that criterion: (1) Has not been met in conjunction with the requirements of Section 506(b)(2) of the Act. Workers at the subject firm were not separated from employment on or after December 8, 1993, the earliest date for which certification under NAFTA-TAA applies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Affirmative Determinations NAFTA-TAA</textblock>
    <textblock>NAFTA-TAA-00006; Nintendo of America, Inc., Redmond, WA</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers, engaged in the assembly of electronic games for the Mexican and Latin American markets, separated on December 8, 1993 and before September 30, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>I hereby certify that the aforementioned determinations were issued during the month of February, 1994. Copies of these determinations are available for inspection in room C-4318, U.S. Department of Labor, 200 Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20210 during normal business hours or will be mailed to persons to write to the above address.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Marvin M. Fooks,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Trade Adjustment Assistance.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3388 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4510-30-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
