<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00091</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00055</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 7, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>On February 9, 1993, the Pacific Stock Exchange, Inc. (``PSE'' or ``Exchange'') submitted to the Securities and Exchange Commission (``Commission'' or ``SEC''), pursuant to section 19(b)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (``Act'')</textblock>
    <textblock>and Rule 19b-4 thereunder,</textblock>
    <textblock>a proposed rule change to permit two Floor Officials to waive, on a case-by-case basis, the required maximum bid/ask differentials for options when the bid/ask differential in the security underlying an options contract is greater than one-half of a point. Notice of the proposed rule change appeared in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 23, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>No comments were received on the proposed rule change. On February 7, 1994, the Exchange submitted Amendment No. 1 to the proposed rule change.</textblock>
    <textblock>This order approves the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Exchange proposes to amend its rule establishing the maximum bid/ask differentials that may be created in making a market in options contracts. Rule 6.37(b)(1) currently provides, for example, that a Market Maker may bid and/or offer so as to create differences of no more than one-quarter of a point between the bid and the offer when the bid is less than $2. The current rule also provides, however, that the Exchange's Options Floor Trading Committee (``Committee'')</textblock>
    <textblock>may establish maximum spreads other than those specified. Additionally, Rule 6.37(b)(1) also currently provides that in the event the bid/ask differential in the underlying security is greater than the bid/ask differential contained in the rule, the permissible price differential for any in-the-money option series may be identical to those in the underlying security market.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Release No. 34-33586; File No. SR-PSE-93-03]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Self-Regulatory Organizations; Pacific Stock Exchange, Inc.; Order Approving Proposed Rule Change and Notice of Filing and Order Granting Accelerated Approval of Amendment No. 1 to the Proposed Rule Change Relating to Waiver of Maximum Bid/Ask Differentials in Individual Equity Options</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(1) (1982).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 240.19b-4 (1993).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See Securities Exchange Act Release No. 33351 (December 16, 1993), 58 FR 68185 (December 23, 1993).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>In Amendment No. 1, the Exchange proposes to: (1) Move the last sentence from Rule 6.37(b)(1) to Rule 6.36(b)(3); and (2) delete the references to in-the-money options series from the language originally proposed to be added to Rule 6.37(b)(3). Letter from Michael Pierson, Senior Attorney, Market Regulation, PSE, to Brad Ritter, Attorney, Office of Derivatives Regulation, Division of Market Regulation, Commission, dated February 7, 1994 (``Amendment No. 1'').</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The Committee is comprised of the Exchange's 14 Floor Officials: (1) Seven Floor brokers, and (2) seven Market Makers or Lead Market Makers. Telephone conversation between Michael Pierson, Senior Attorney, Market Regulation, PSE, and Brad Ritter, Attorney, Office of Derivatives Regulation, Division of Market Regulation, Commission, on February 2, 1994.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
