<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00078</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standards; Air Brake Systems; Air Applied, Mechanically Held Brake Systems</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Highway Traffic Safety Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>49 CFR Part 571</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93-17; Notice 2]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 2127-AE77</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA), Department of Transportation.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule amends Standard No. 121, Air Brake Systems, with respect to the requirements related to the application and holding of parking brake systems and the requirements related to the supply line pressure retention for trailer brakes. NHTSA initiated rulemaking to respond to concerns raised by International Transquip Industries (ITI) which manufactures air-applied, mechanically held parking brakes. These amendments provide regulatory relief by removing unnecessary restrictions to facilitate the use of alternative brake systems, without adversely affecting safety.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective Date:</textblock>
    <textblock>The amendments in this notice become effective March 16, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Petitions for Reconsideration:</textblock>
    <textblock>Any petitions for reconsideration of this rule must be received by NHTSA no later than March 16, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Petitions for reconsideration of this rule should refer to Docket 93-17; Notice 2 and should be submitted to: Administrator, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, 400 Seventh Street, SW., Washington, DC 20590.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Richard Carter, Office of Vehicle Safety Standards, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, 400 Seventh Street, SW., Washington, DC 20590 (202-366-5274).</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Introduction</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Notice Of Proposed Rulemaking And Comments On The Proposal</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Agency Decision</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Grade Holding Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Background Considerations</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Diaphragm Failure Modes</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Test Procedure</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Supply Line Pressure Requirements for Trailers</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Leadtime</textblock>
    <textblock>V. Rulemaking Analyses and Notices</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Executive Order 12688 (Federal Regulation) and DOT Regulatory Policies and Procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
