<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00100</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Firearms transaction record and statement of</textblock>
    <textblock>intent to obtain a handgun.</textblock>
    <textblock>Licensees shall retain each</textblock>
    <textblock>Form 4473 and Form 4473(LV) for a period of not less than</textblock>
    <textblock>20 years after the date of sale or disposition. Licensees</textblock>
    <textblock>shall retain each Form 5300.35 for a period of not less</textblock>
    <textblock>than 5 years after notice of the intent to obtain the</textblock>
    <textblock>handgun was forwarded to the chief law enforcement officer.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(Paragraph (b) approved by the Office of Management</textblock>
    <textblock>and Budget under control number 1512-0520; all other</textblock>
    <textblock>recordkeeping approved by the Office of Management and</textblock>
    <textblock>Budget under control number 1512-0129.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Par. 11.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 178.130 and 178.131 are added to</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart H to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§178.130</textblock>
    <textblock>Statement of intent to obtain a handgun after</textblock>
    <textblock>February 27, 1994, and before November 30, 1998.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)(1) Except as provided in §§178.102(b) and</textblock>
    <textblock>178.131, a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer, or</textblock>
    <textblock>licensed dealer shall not sell, deliver, or transfer a</textblock>
    <textblock>handgun unless the licensee has received from the</textblock>
    <textblock>transferee a statement of intent to obtain a handgun on</textblock>
    <textblock>Form 5300.35 in duplicate. The statement shall contain the</textblock>
    <textblock>transferee's name, address, and date of birth. The</textblock>
    <textblock>transferee must date and execute the sworn statement contained on the form showing that the transferee is not</textblock>
    <textblock>under indictment for a crime punishable by imprisonment for</textblock>
    <textblock>a term exceeding 1 year; has not been convicted in any</textblock>
    <textblock>court of such a crime; is not a fugitive from justice; is</textblock>
    <textblock>not an unlawful user of or addicted to any controlled</textblock>
    <textblock>substance; has not been adjudicated as a mental defective</textblock>
    <textblock>or been committed to a mental institution; is not an alien</textblock>
    <textblock>who is illegally or unlawfully in the United States;</textblock>
    <textblock>has not been discharged from the Armed Forces under</textblock>
    <textblock>dishonorable conditions; and is not a person who, having</textblock>
    <textblock>been a citizen of the United States, has renounced such</textblock>
    <textblock>citizenship.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) In order to facilitate the transfer of a handgun</textblock>
    <textblock>and enable the chief law enforcement officer to verify the</textblock>
    <textblock>identity of the person acquiring the handgun, Form 5300.35</textblock>
    <textblock>requests certain additional optional information. This</textblock>
    <textblock>information includes the social security number, height,</textblock>
    <textblock>weight, sex, and place of birth of the transferee. Such</textblock>
    <textblock>information may help avoid the possibility of the</textblock>
    <textblock>transferee being misidentified as a felon or other</textblock>
    <textblock>prohibited person.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Upon receipt of Form 5300.35 from the transferee,</textblock>
    <textblock>the licensee shall:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Verify the identity of the transferee by examining the identification document presented and note on</textblock>
    <textblock>Form 5300.35 the type of identification used; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Complete Form 5300.35 to show that notice of the</textblock>
    <textblock>transferee's statement of intent to obtain a handgun and a</textblock>
    <textblock>copy of the form have been provided to the chief law</textblock>
    <textblock>enforcement officer in compliance with §178.102(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The licensee shall retain the original Form</textblock>
    <textblock>5300.35 as part of the records required to be kept under</textblock>
    <textblock>this subpart. If the sale, delivery, or transfer of the</textblock>
    <textblock>handgun to the transferee is made, Form 5300.35 shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>attached to the firearms transaction record, Form 4473,</textblock>
    <textblock>executed upon delivery of the handgun as provided in</textblock>
    <textblock>§178.124. If the sale, delivery, or transfer is not made,</textblock>
    <textblock>the licensee shall retain Form 5300.35 as part of the</textblock>
    <textblock>records required to be kept under this subpart. Forms</textblock>
    <textblock>5300.35 with respect to which a sale, delivery, or transfer</textblock>
    <textblock>did not take place shall be retained in alphabetical (by</textblock>
    <textblock>name of transferee) or chronological (by date of</textblock>
    <textblock>transferee's sworn statement) order.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) The requirements of this section shall be in</textblock>
    <textblock>addition to any other recordkeeping requirements contained</textblock>
    <textblock>in this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) A licensee may obtain, upon request, an emergency</textblock>
    <textblock>supply of Forms 5300.35 from any regional director</textblock>
    <textblock>(compliance).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
