<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00010</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Cost Containment and Vulnerability</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Farmers Home Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>7 CFR Parts 1924, 1930, and 1944</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 0575-AB08</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Farmers Home Administration, USDA.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Farmers Home Administration (FmHA) amends its regulations regarding the processing of preapplications for Rural Rental Housing (RRH) assistance. This action is necessary to decrease costs associated with the program and to reduce program vulnerability. The intended effect is to improve credit quality and to make our regulations more responsive to the prudent development of RRH complexes in rural America.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Gail McCowan, Senior Loan Specialist, Rural Rental Housing Branch, Multi-Family Housing Processing Division, Farmers Home Administration, USDA, Room 5337_South Agriculture Building, Washington, DC 20250, telephone (202) 720-1608.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Classification</textblock>
    <textblock>We are issuing this final rule in conformance with Executive Order 12866, and we have determined that it is not a ``significant regulatory action.'' Based on information compiled by the Department, we have determined that this final rule:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Would have an effect on the economy of less than $100 million;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Would not adversely affect in a material way the economy, a sector of the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, or State, local or tribal governments or communities;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Would not create a serious inconsistency or otherwise interfere with an action taken or planned by another agency;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Would not alter the budgetary impact of entitlements, grants, user fees, or loan programs or rights and obligations of recipients thereof; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Would not raise novel legal or policy issues arising out of legal mandates, the President's priorities, or principles set forth in Executive Order 12866.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
