<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00024</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 8, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission's (Commission's) regulations, 18 CFR part 380 (Order No. 486, 52 FR 47897), the Office of Hydropower Licensing has reviewed the application for license for the Upper Kezar Falls Hydroelectric Project located on the Ossipee River, in York and Oxford Counties, Maine, and has prepared an Environmental Assessment (EA) for the project.</textblock>
    <textblock>On September 24, 1993, staff issued and distributed to all parties a draft EA, and requested that comments on the draft EA be filed within 30 days. All comments that were filed have been considered in the EA.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the EA, the Commission's staff has analyzed the environmental effects of the project and has concluded that approval of the project, with appropriate mitigation and enhancement measures, would not constitute a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the EA are available for review in the Public Reference Branch, room 3104 of the Commission's offices at 941 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Project No. 11124-000 Maine]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Lawrence E. and Veronica P. Smith; Availability of Final Environmental Assessment</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3331 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
