<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00073</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00044</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Renewal of Charter for Nuclear Safety Research Review Committee</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Renewal of the Nuclear Safety Research Review Committee.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Nuclear Safety Research Review Committee was established by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission as a Federal Advisory Committee in February 1988 to provide advice to the Director, Office of Nuclear Regulatory Research, on matters relating to NRC's nuclear safety research programs. The committee is composed of experts capable of providing a wide variety of technical and managerial viewpoints drawn from industrial national laboratory, university and not-for-profit research organizations.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463), and after consultation with the General Services Administration, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission has determined that there is a continuing need for the Nuclear Safety Research Review Committee and that renewal of the committee for a two year period beginning February 9, 1994 is in the public interest.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. George Sege, Office of Nuclear Regulatory Research, U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John C. Hoyle,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Advisory Committee Management Officer.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3373 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7590-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
