<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00095</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12866</textblock>
    <textblock>It has been determined that this temporary rule is not</textblock>
    <textblock>a significant regulatory action, because the economic</textblock>
    <textblock>effects flow directly from the underlying statute and not</textblock>
    <textblock>from this temporary rule. Therefore, it is found that this</textblock>
    <textblock>temporary rule is not likely to (1) Have an annual effect</textblock>
    <textblock>on the economy of $100 million or more or adversely affect</textblock>
    <textblock>in a material way the economy, a sector of the economy,</textblock>
    <textblock>productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public</textblock>
    <textblock>health or safety, of State, local, or tribal governments or</textblock>
    <textblock>communities; (2) Create a serious inconsistency or</textblock>
    <textblock>otherwise interfere with an action taken or planned by</textblock>
    <textblock>another agency; (3) Materially alter the budgetary impact</textblock>
    <textblock>of entitlements, grants, user fees, or loan programs or the</textblock>
    <textblock>rights and obligations of recipients thereof; or (4) Raise</textblock>
    <textblock>novel legal or policy issues arising out of legal mandates,</textblock>
    <textblock>the President's priorities, or the principles set forth in</textblock>
    <textblock>this Executive order.</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative Procedure Act</textblock>
    <textblock>Because this document merely implements the law and</textblock>
    <textblock>because immediate guidance is necessary to implement the</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions of the law, it is found to be impracticable</textblock>
    <textblock>to issue this Treasury decision with notice and public</textblock>
    <textblock>procedure under 5 U.S.C. ยง553(b), or subject to the</textblock>
    <textblock>effective date limitation in section 553(d).</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The provisions of the Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>relating to an initial and final regulatory flexibility</textblock>
    <textblock>analysis (5 U.S.C. 604) are not applicable to this</textblock>
    <textblock>temporary rule because the agency was not required to</textblock>
    <textblock>publish a notice of proposed rulemaking under 5 U.S.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>553 or any other law.</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulation is being issued without prior notice</textblock>
    <textblock>and public procedure pursuant to the Administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>Procedure Act (5 U.S.C. 553). For this reason, the</textblock>
    <textblock>collection of information contained in this regulation has</textblock>
    <textblock>been reviewed and, pending receipt and evaluation of public</textblock>
    <textblock>comments, approved by the Office of Management and Budget</textblock>
    <textblock>(OMB) under control number 1512-0520. The estimated</textblock>
    <textblock>average annual burden associated with the collection</textblock>
    <textblock>of information in this regulation is 2.52 hours per</textblock>
    <textblock>respondent or recordkeeper.</textblock>
    <textblock>For further information concerning this collection</textblock>
    <textblock>of information, and where to submit comments on the</textblock>
    <textblock>collection of information and the accuracy of the estimated</textblock>
    <textblock>burden, and suggestions for reducing this burden, refer to</textblock>
    <textblock>the preamble to the cross-reference notice of proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rulemaking published elsewhere in this issue of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
