<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00069</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00040</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>7. SBM Coal Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. M-94-12-C]</textblock>
    <textblock>SBM Coal Company, R.D.</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>2, Box 97A, Hegins, Pennsylvania 17938 has filed a petition to modify the application</textblock>
    <textblock>of 30 CFR 75.1200(i) (mine map) to its M &amp; R Slope (I.D. No. 36-05495) located in Northumberland County, Pennsylvania. The petitioner proposes to limit the mapping of mine workings above and below to those present within 100 feet of the vein being mined except when veins are interconnected to other veins beyond the 100 feet limit through rock tunnels. The petitioner asserts that the proposed alternate method would provide at least the same measure of protection as would the mandatory standard.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Gatliff Coal Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. M-94-13-C]</textblock>
    <textblock>Gatliff Coal Company, P.O. Box 39, Nevisdale, Kentucky 40754 has filed a petition to modify the application of 30 CFR 75.360(b)(6) (preshift examination) to its Blue Gem</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>6 Deep Mine (I.D. No. 15-12475) located in Whitley County, Kentucky. Due to adverse roof conditions in the parallel intake air course, the area cannot be traveled safely. The petitioner states that the area involved was driven off a parallel pure intake air course prior to the new ventilation regulation of November 1992, that even with extensive cribbing the intake area has developed adverse roof conditions, and that to perform preshift examinations of the room necks would be unsafe. The petitioner proposes to install methane detecting sensors at the areas of approach in the parallel intakes and an additional methane detecting sensor where the air which has coursed by these room necks, driven in excess of 20 feet deep, joins with the main mine intake. The petitioner asserts that the proposed alternate method would provide at least the same measure of protection as would the mandatory standard.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Arclar Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. M-94-14-C]</textblock>
    <textblock>Arclar Company, 29 West Raymond, P.O. Box 444, Harrisburg, Illinois 62946 has filed a petition to modify the application of 30 CFR 18.41 to its Big Ridge Mine (I.D. No. 11-02879) located in Saline County, Illinois. The petitioner proposes to use fabricated metal locking devices with a locking screw threaded through a steel bracket to lock battery plugs to machine-mounted battery receptacles on permissible, mobile, battery-powered machines instead of using padlocks; and to submit a training plan for all operators of this equipment concerning this proposed alternate method to the Agency and District Manager.</textblock>
    <textblock>10. AKZO Salt, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. M-94-05-M]</textblock>
    <textblock>AKZO Salt, Inc., P.O. Box 6920, Cleveland, Ohio 44101 has filed a petition to modify the application of 30 CFR 57.19109 to its Cleveland Mine (I.D. No. 33-01994) located in Cuyahoga</textblock>
    <textblock>County, Ohio. The petitioner proposes to install pairs of cables approximately 4 feet above and parallel to the divider timbers to enhance the function of the timbers; to cover the sides of each divider timber with ultra-high molecular weight polyethylene material to reduce abrasion to the timbers; in addition to water slicing, to inspect the shaft prior to conducting any work on the platform to ensure that there are no loose material on the sides of the shaft; to place barricades around the shaft at both the collar and mine level prior to doing work on the platform; and to provide training to all personnel working on the platform. The petitioner states that to place boards across the shaft at the mine level when personnel are required to work on the dividers</textblock>
    <textblock>would result in a diminution of safety and would expose miners to hazardous conditions. In addition, the petitioner asserts that the proposed alternate method would provide at least the same measure of protection as would the mandatory standard.</textblock>
    <textblock>Request for Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons interested in these petitions may furnish written comments. These comments must be filed with the Office of</textblock>
    <textblock>Standards, Regulations and Variances, Mine Safety and Health</textblock>
    <textblock>Administration, room 627, 4015 Wilson Boulevard, Arlington,</textblock>
    <textblock>Virginia 22203. All comments must be postmarked or received in that office on or before March 16, 1994. Copies of these petitions are available for inspection at that address.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 8, 1994</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Patricia W. Silvey,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Standards, Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>and Variances.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3389 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4510-43-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
