<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00043</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-2-00028</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463), the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) announces the following council meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>Name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Advisory Council for the Elimination of Tuberculosis (ACET).</textblock>
    <textblock>Times and dates:</textblock>
    <textblock>8:30 a.m.-5 p.m., March 15, 1994; 8:30 a.m.-12 Noon, March 16, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>Corporate Square Office Park, Corporate Square Boulevard, Building 11, room 1413, Atlanta, Georgia 30329.</textblock>
    <textblock>Status:</textblock>
    <textblock>Open to the public, limited only by the space available.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose:</textblock>
    <textblock>This council advises and makes recommendations to the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Assistant Secretary for Health, and the Director, CDC, regarding the elimination of tuberculosis. Specifically, the council makes recommendations regarding policies, strategies, objectives, and priorities; addresses the development and application of new technologies; and reviews the extent to which progress has been made toward eliminating tuberculosis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Matters to be discussed:</textblock>
    <textblock>Update on federal tuberculosis activities; update on hospital surveys; update on MDR-TB hospital outbreaks and tuberculosis guideline revision; BCG status report; model tuberculosis program; update on Prevention Effectiveness studies Unit; evaluating tuberculosis programs/program management reports; review of corrections statement; and tuberculosis screening guidelines.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agenda items are subject to change as priorities dictate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contact person for more information:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dixie E. Snider, Jr., M.D., Acting Deputy Associate Director for Science, CDC, and Executive Secretary, ACET, 1600 Clifton Road NE., Mailstop A-20, Atlanta, Georgia 30333, telephone 404/639-3812.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Advisory Council for the Elimination of Tuberculosis; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Elvin Hilyer,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Director for Policy Coordination, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3348 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-18-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
