<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00094</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Act also provides that an individual who is</textblock>
    <textblock>determined to be ineligible to purchase a handgun under the</textblock>
    <textblock>waiting period provision may request that the</textblock>
    <textblock>chief law enforcement officer who made the determination</textblock>
    <textblock>provide reasons for that determination. The officer must</textblock>
    <textblock>provide such reasons to the individual in writing within 20</textblock>
    <textblock>business days after receipt of the request.</textblock>
    <textblock>Alternatives to the Waiting Period</textblock>
    <textblock>The statute provides the following alternatives to the</textblock>
    <textblock>waiting period provision:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The transferee provides a written statement issued</textblock>
    <textblock>within the last 10 days by the chief law enforcement</textblock>
    <textblock>officer of the transferee's place of residence that the</textblock>
    <textblock>transferee requires a handgun because of a threat to the</textblock>
    <textblock>life of the transferee or any member of the transferee's</textblock>
    <textblock>household;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The transferee presents to the licensee a permit</textblock>
    <textblock>issued by the State within the past 5 years to possess a handgun and the law of the State requires verification that</textblock>
    <textblock>the transferee is not prohibited by law from possessing the</textblock>
    <textblock>handgun;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Purchases in States which require that, before</textblock>
    <textblock>any licensee transfers a handgun to an individual,</textblock>
    <textblock>an authorized government official has verified that</textblock>
    <textblock>possession of the handgun by the transferee would not</textblock>
    <textblock>violate the law (e.g., a background check);</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Purchases of handguns which are subject to the</textblock>
    <textblock>National Firearms Act and which have been approved for</textblock>
    <textblock>transfer under 27 CFR part 179 (Machine Guns, Destructive</textblock>
    <textblock>Devices, and Certain Other Firearms);</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Purchases of handguns for which the Secretary has</textblock>
    <textblock>certified that compliance with the 5-day waiting period</textblock>
    <textblock>procedure is impracticable because the purchaser resides in</textblock>
    <textblock>a rural area, the premises of the licensee are remote in</textblock>
    <textblock>relation to the chief law enforcement officer of the area,</textblock>
    <textblock>and there is an absence of telecommunications facilities in</textblock>
    <textblock>the geographical area in which the business premises are</textblock>
    <textblock>located.</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional Provisions of Public Law 103-159</textblock>
    <textblock>Titles II and III of Public Law 103-159 provide additional</textblock>
    <textblock>amendments to the GCA. These provisions, which became</textblock>
    <textblock>effective on November 30, 1993, are as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Multiple sales reports.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to furnishing</textblock>
    <textblock>reports of multiple handgun sales to ATF, licensees are required to submit such reports to the ``department of State</textblock>
    <textblock>police or State law enforcement agency of the State or</textblock>
    <textblock>local law enforcement agency of the jurisdiction in which</textblock>
    <textblock>the sale or other disposition took place.''</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Common carriers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Common or contract carriers are</textblock>
    <textblock>prohibited from requiring or causing any label or other</textblock>
    <textblock>written notice to be placed on the outside of any package,</textblock>
    <textblock>luggage, or other container indicating that such package</textblock>
    <textblock>contains a firearm. In addition, common or contract</textblock>
    <textblock>carriers who deliver firearms in interstate or foreign</textblock>
    <textblock>commerce are required to obtain written acknowledgement</textblock>
    <textblock>of receipt from the recipient of the package or other</textblock>
    <textblock>container.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Theft of firearms.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is unlawful for any person to</textblock>
    <textblock>steal from the person or premises of a Federal firearms</textblock>
    <textblock>licensee any firearm in the licensee's business inventory</textblock>
    <textblock>which has been shipped or transported in interstate or</textblock>
    <textblock>foreign commerce.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>License fees.</textblock>
    <textblock>License fees for all dealers in</textblock>
    <textblock>firearms (other than destructive devices), including</textblock>
    <textblock>pawnbrokers, have been increased to $200 for 3 years,</textblock>
    <textblock>except that the fee for renewal of a license is $90 for</textblock>
    <textblock>3 years.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
