<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00091</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Western Pacific Crustacean Fisheries</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>50 CFR Part 681</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 940237-4037; ID. 010594A]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>1994 initial quota for crustaceans; request for comments.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>NMFS announces a 1994 initial quota of 200,000 lobsters for the Northwestern Hawaiian Islands (NWHI) crustacean fishery. The quota was calculated according to the formula contained in Amendment 7 to the Fishery Management Plan for the Crustacean Fisheries of the Western Pacific Region (FMP). The final quota for the 1994 fishing year, which begins July 1, 1994, will be announced after the first month of fishing.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective July 1, 1994, through December 31, 1994, inclusive. Comments are invited until March 16, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be sent to Gary Matlock, Acting Regional Director, Southwest Region, NMFS, 501 West Ocean Boulevard, suite 4200, Long Beach, CA 90802-4213. Copies of Amendment 7 and the associated background material for determining the quota may be obtained from Kitty Simonds, Executive Director, Western Pacific Fishery Management Council, 1164 Bishop Street, suite 1405, Honolulu, HI 96813.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Svein Fougner, Fisheries Management Division, Southwest Region, NMFS, 310-980-4034; Alvin Z. Katekaru, Pacific Area Office, Southwest Region, NMFS, Honolulu, Hawaii 808-955-8831; or Kitty Simonds, address above, 808-523-1368.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The crustacean fisheries of the NWHI are managed by the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) according to the FMP, which was prepared by the Western Pacific Fishery Management Council (Council) under the authority of the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act (Magnuson Act). Regulations affecting the U.S. fishery are at 50 CFR part 681.</textblock>
    <textblock>The annual quota for the crustacean fishery is announced in two steps. First, based on previous years' fishery data, sampling during research cruises, and other available data, the Regional Director determines an initial quota, which is announced in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>by the Assistant Administrator for Fisheries, NOAA. A population model by which the quota is determined is described in Amendment 7 to the FMP. The final quota for the year is then determined based on actual commercial fisheries data collected during the first month of fishing. This actual catch and effort data, in conjunction with the previous information, provides a more reliable indicator of the status of the lobster stocks in the NWHI.</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendment 7 provides that an annual quota be set at a level permitting an average catch per unit of effort (CPUE) of 1.0 for the fleet. In 1992, the initial quota was set at 750,000 lobsters, which was subsequently reduced to 438,000 lobsters following an analysis of data obtained from the fishery. In 1993, there was no quota, and the fishery was closed for the entire year.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Regional Director has used the formula in Amendment 7 to set an initial quota for 1994 of 200,000 lobsters (spiny and slipper lobsters combined). Data collected during NMFS survey cruises indicate that recruitment to the fishery remained at about 840,000 lobsters during the 1992-93 period, and there were no removals of lobster by the fishery in 1993; therefore, there is a net addition to the stock to support a fishery in 1994. The model projects a commercial CPUE of 1.0 at the start of the fishing year with an initial quota of 200,000 lobsters. The final quota, to be announced in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>as soon as practicable after August 15, 1994, may increase or decrease substantially from the initial quota. The Southwest Region, NMFS, will monitor landings against the quota and issue timely reports of summary data. The Southwest Region also will attempt to promptly notify participants in the fishery of any changes in the fishery; however, participants are advised to contact the Southwest Region (see</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>) periodically to stay of changes in the quota and progress of the fishery toward attaining the quota. Announcement of a closure of the fishery due to reaching the quota will follow the procedures set forth in 50 CFR 681.31(c).</textblock>
    <textblock>Classification</textblock>
    <textblock>This action is authorized by 50 CFR part 681.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule is not subject to review under Executive Order 12866.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 50 CFR Part 681</textblock>
    <textblock>Fisheries, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 1801</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rolland A. Schmitten,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Administrator for Fisheries, National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3370 Filed 2-11-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
