<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940214-1-00039</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940214-1-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>•The total viable microbial count for the dialysate</textblock>
    <textblock>should not exceed 2000/ml. The supplier of the dialysate</textblock>
    <textblock>supply system recommends a method of cleaning the equipment</textblock>
    <textblock>that results in a device capable of meeting this</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement. The user is responsible for monitoring the</textblock>
    <textblock>purity of the dialysate.</textblock>
    <textblock>3.2.2␣Maximum Level of Chemical Contaminants</textblock>
    <textblock>•This section includes a table listing the maximum</textblock>
    <textblock>allowable chemical contaminant levels for the water used to</textblock>
    <textblock>prepare dialysate. The manufacturer or supplier of the</textblock>
    <textblock>water treatment device is responsible for recommending a</textblock>
    <textblock>system capable of meeting the requirements of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>The physician in charge of dialysis has the ultimate</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility for selecting the water treatment system and</textblock>
    <textblock>is also responsible for monitoring the water.</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix B, Sections B1 Through B5: Guideline for</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring Purity of Water Used for Hemodialysis</textblock>
    <textblock>•Appendix B outlines the responsibilities of users of</textblock>
    <textblock>hemodialysis systems to ensure purity of water used for</textblock>
    <textblock>hemodialysis. Sections B1 through B5 delineate committee</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendations with respect to frequency of monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>water used in dialysis to ensure that the maximum levels of</textblock>
    <textblock>contaminants specified in section 3.2.1 and 3.2.2 are not</textblock>
    <textblock>exceeded. These recommendations include:</textblock>
    <textblock>+ The bacteriology of water and dialysate should be</textblock>
    <textblock>sampled at least monthly or more frequently to define,</textblock>
    <textblock>solve, and control problems.</textblock>
    <textblock>+ The frequency of sampling for chemical contaminants</textblock>
    <textblock>varies from 3 months to 12 months depending on the method of</textblock>
    <textblock>water treatment. Because chemical contamination can vary</textblock>
    <textblock>widely from month to month, monthly testing is recommended</textblock>
    <textblock>initially to develop a data base for determining optimum</textblock>
    <textblock>frequency of testing for each facility. When chloramines</textblock>
    <textblock>are added municipally to the water supply, the water used to</textblock>
    <textblock>prepare dialysate should be checked for the presence of</textblock>
    <textblock>chloramines at least once a day.</textblock>
    <textblock>+ Maximum levels of organic chemicals, pesticides,</textblock>
    <textblock>herbicides, and radioactive material cannot be specified at</textblock>
    <textblock>present, therefore, frequency of testing for these materials</textblock>
    <textblock>cannot be established.</textblock>
    <textblock>+ Frequency of disinfection of the water treatment and</textblock>
    <textblock>disinfection system, dialysis machines, and equipment used</textblock>
    <textblock>to distribute and prepare dialysate should be determined by</textblock>
    <textblock>the results of microbiological monitoring, by any</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements to meet AAMI standards and/or guidelines, and</textblock>
    <textblock>by the manufacturer's recommendations.</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Reuse of Hemodialyzers</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1881(f)(7) of the Act requires the Secretary to</textblock>
    <textblock>establish protocols for reuse of hemodialyzers for those</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities that voluntarily elect to reuse the filters. In</textblock>
    <textblock>the process of hemodialysis, the patient's blood is cleansed</textblock>
    <textblock>of impurities by passing the blood through the filter</textblock>
    <textblock>(hemodialyzer) of a hemodialysis machine. Various</textblock>
    <textblock>techniques exist that allow these filters to be reused.</textblock>
    <textblock>Reuse involves cleaning, disinfecting, and preparing</textblock>
    <textblock>disposable hemodialysis devices for subsequent use for the</textblock>
    <textblock>same patient. Although the potential exists for adverse</textblock>
    <textblock>patient outcomes from reuse, reprocessing and reuse of</textblock>
    <textblock>dialyzers are safe when done properly.</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 2, 1987, through a</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>publication (52 FR 36926), final regulations were issued</textblock>
    <textblock>specifying the performance requirements for reuse of</textblock>
    <textblock>hemodialyzers and other dialysis supplies (§405.2150).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 405.2150 requires ESRD facilities reusing</textblock>
    <textblock>hemodialyzers to meet the voluntary guidelines and standards</textblock>
    <textblock>adopted by AAMI and issued in July 1986 as ``Recommended</textblock>
    <textblock>Practice for Reuse of Hemodialyzers''.</textblock>
    <textblock>Unlike AAMI ``standards'' which are directed to</textblock>
    <textblock>manufacturers, ``recommended practices'' are directed to</textblock>
    <textblock>health professionals and provide guidelines for the use,</textblock>
    <textblock>care, and processing of a medical device or system. The</textblock>
    <textblock>AAMI guidelines on reuse of hemodialyzers are based on the</textblock>
    <textblock>national consensus of physicians, other health care</textblock>
    <textblock>professionals, government representatives, patients, and</textblock>
    <textblock>industry. They describe the details of reprocessing</textblock>
    <textblock>dialyzers and address various areas such as personnel</textblock>
    <textblock>qualifications and training, patient considerations,</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment, reprocessing supplies, monitoring during</textblock>
    <textblock>dialysis, quality assurance, and quality control.</textblock>
    <textblock>Since the publication of the 1986 edition of the</textblock>
    <textblock>``Recommended Practice for Reuse of Hemodialyzers'' and HCFA's</textblock>
    <textblock>adoption of the recommended practice, users of the</textblock>
    <textblock>guidelines have asked numerous questions. As a result of</textblock>
    <textblock>the AAMI review of the 1986 guidelines, the Hemodialyzer</textblock>
    <textblock>Reuse Subcommittee of the AAMI Renal Disease and</textblock>
    <textblock>Detoxification Committee developed a 1993 edition. The</textblock>
    <textblock>subcommittee consists of representatives from the</textblock>
    <textblock>manufacturing, governmental (including HCFA), physician,</textblock>
    <textblock>dialysis facility, and patient consumer communities.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
