<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00159</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00102</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[ID-010-03-4210-04; IDI-28798]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Availability; Amendment of the Cascade Resource Management Plan (RMP)/Notice of Realty Action (NORA); Sale of Two Parcels and Exchange of Public Lands in Canyon, Gem and Ada Counties, Idaho</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>agency:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management_Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <summary>
    <textblock>summary:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the BLM Planning Regulations (43 CFR 1610.5-2), notice is hereby given that the BLM is proposing to amend the Cascade RMP to allow for transfer of certain public lands to Gem and Canyon Counties via sale and transfer of certain public lands in Ada County to a private party via exchange.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following described lands have been examined and through the public supported land use planning process have been determined to be suitable for disposal by direct sale pursuant to Section 203 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act (FLPMA) of 1976 (43 U.S.C. 1713) at no less than the appraised fair market value. The lands will not be offered for sale until at least 60 days after the date of publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. IDI-28798_Sale to Gem County:</textblock>
    <textblock>Boise Meridian, Idaho</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 6 N., R. 1 W.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 27; W1/2SW1/4,</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 28; E1/2SE1/4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Containing 160 acres more or less.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. IDI-29240, Sale to Canyon County:</textblock>
    <textblock>Boise Meridian, Idaho</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 2 N., R. 3 W.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 21; W1/2SW1/4NE1/4, W1/2W1/2SE1/4, S1/2SE1/4SW1/4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Containing 80 acres more or less.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following described lands have been examined and through the public supported land use planning process have been determined to be suitable for transfer by land exchange pursuant to section 206 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act (FLPMA) of 1976 (43 U.S.C. 1713).</textblock>
    <textblock>3. IDI-29143, Private Exchange to W. P. Stillwell Sr. Estate:</textblock>
    <textblock>Non-Federal lands to be acquired are described as:</textblock>
    <textblock>Boise Meridian, Idaho</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 5 N., R. 1 E., B.M., Idaho</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 14; S1/2NW1/4, NW1/4SW1/4,</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 23; S1/2S1/2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Containing 280 acres more or less.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public lands to be transferred are described as:</textblock>
    <textblock>Boise Meridian, Idaho</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 5 N., R. 1 E., B.M., Idaho</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 20; Lot 1, E1/2SE1/4,</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 21; NW1/4NW1/4, S1/2NW1/4, NW1/4SW1/4, S1/2SE1/4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Containing 357.81 acres more or less.</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative access across Stillwell's private lands would also be acquired.</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the land sales is to provide Gem County with a new sanitary landfill site and Canyon County with lands necessary to meet new standards for their existing landfill.</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the exchange is to acquire the non-Federal lands which contain important populations of</textblock>
    <textblock>Allium aaseae</textblock>
    <textblock>(Aase's onion), a C1 Candidate species to prevent possible listing of the species under the Endangered Species Act. The subject lands were previously identified for acquisition in the plan amendment designating ACECs for protection of Aase's onion and determining the management prescriptions under which the lands are to be managed. The subject lands will be added to the designated ACEC and will be managed with the same restrictions as the other public lands within the ACEC to protect the critical habitat.</textblock>
    <textblock>The value of the lands to be exchanged will be approximately equal; some of the above-described public lands may not be included and some of the private lands may not be acquired in order to equalize values and protect resource values.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>addresses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be sent to the District Manager, Bureau of Land Management, Boise District, 3948 Development Avenue, Boise, Idaho 83705.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>for further information contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>John Fend, Cascade Resource Area Manager, Bureau of Land Management, 3948 Development Avenue, Boise, Idaho 83705, (208) 384-3352 or 384-3300.</textblock>
  </further>
</doc>
