<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00068</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>M. Additional Guidance_FDA Fish and Fishery Products Hazards and Controls Guide Including Specific Guidance on Smoked Fishery Products</textblock>
    <textblock>As an adjunct to its rulemaking to require HACCP procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>in the seafood industry, FDA is drafting an extensive guidance</textblock>
    <textblock>for processors to use in understanding and implementing HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>principles for their operations. This guidance will provide</textblock>
    <textblock>information that processors and importers can use in the</textblock>
    <textblock>development of their HACCP plans. This information consists</textblock>
    <textblock>largely of an identification of hazards that can affect the</textblock>
    <textblock>safety of seafood and a review of control measures that can keep</textblock>
    <textblock>the hazards from actually occurring, or that can at least</textblock>
    <textblock>minimize the likelihood of their occurrence.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA has included selected portions of the draft HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>guidance as Appendix 1 to this proposal, so as to better inform</textblock>
    <textblock>the public about how this guidance will be structured and about</textblock>
    <textblock>the kinds of assistance that will be available to processors and</textblock>
    <textblock>importers who implement HACCP. The agency emphasizes, however,</textblock>
    <textblock>that this guidance is a work-in-progress and still being developed by FDA. Nonetheless, the agency seeks comment on the</textblock>
    <textblock>need for this guidance and the usefulness of the format the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency proposes to adopt.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, FDA is including in Appendix 1 specific</textblock>
    <textblock>guidance on time-temperature and salinity parameters and other</textblock>
    <textblock>matters for use in the HACCP plans of processors of smoked and</textblock>
    <textblock>smoke-flavored fishery products. While FDA is seeking comment on</textblock>
    <textblock>the guidance generally, it particularly seeks comment on the</textblock>
    <textblock>guidance on smoked and smoke-flavored fishery products. Material</textblock>
    <textblock>relevant to the safe processing of smoked and smoke-flavored</textblock>
    <textblock>fishery products is found in various sections of the HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>guidance because this general guidance is primarily organized by</textblock>
    <textblock>hazard rather than by commodity type. However, the agency has</textblock>
    <textblock>gathered the materials relating to smoked and smoke-flavored</textblock>
    <textblock>fishery products into a single section of the guidance to</textblock>
    <textblock>facilitate use of this guidance by this industry, and to</textblock>
    <textblock>facilitate obtaining public comment on it. As stated above, FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>seeks public comment on the appropriateness of the materials</textblock>
    <textblock>relating to smoked and smoke-flavored fishery products as</textblock>
    <textblock>guidance, on their validity as guidelines, and on whether they</textblock>
    <textblock>should be made mandatory by incorporating them into any final</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation that results from this rulemaking.</textblock>
    <textblock>While no known outbreaks of botulism attributed to smoked</textblock>
    <textblock>fish have been reported since 1963, FDA believes that the failure</textblock>
    <textblock>by manufacturers to obtain information about the composition of</textblock>
    <textblock>hot- and cold-process products represents a potential health hazard. Without analytical results from the testing for</textblock>
    <textblock>water-phase salt and sodium nitrite levels, a manufacturer cannot</textblock>
    <textblock>determine whether the fish have been adequately processed to</textblock>
    <textblock>inhibit</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>spore outgrowth and toxin production. The</textblock>
    <textblock>agency's concerns are underscored by the diversity of processing</textblock>
    <textblock>temperatures and salt levels used in the manufacture of these</textblock>
    <textblock>products, particularly the lower range temperatures and</textblock>
    <textblock>water-phase salt levels (Ref. 24).</textblock>
    <textblock>Finally, as stated above, the use of modified atmosphere and</textblock>
    <textblock>vacuum packaging with smoked and smoke-flavored fish products is</textblock>
    <textblock>also a source of concern. These types of packaging provide an</textblock>
    <textblock>anaerobic environment in which</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>spores can grow out</textblock>
    <textblock>and produce botulin, the causative agent in botulism. When</textblock>
    <textblock>consumed, the toxin attacks the central nervous system and may</textblock>
    <textblock>cause death if untreated within 3 to 6 days.</textblock>
    <textblock>For all these reasons, FDA has tentatively concluded that</textblock>
    <textblock>some type of guidance that defines the procedures for the safe</textblock>
    <textblock>processing of smoked and smoke-flavored fish is necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>Historically, fish have been smoked in order to preserve</textblock>
    <textblock>them. Today, the primary reason for smoking is to impart certain</textblock>
    <textblock>taste and texture qualities to the fish. There are essentially</textblock>
    <textblock>two types of smoked fish: (1) Those that are subjected to a</textblock>
    <textblock>``cold process'' that leaves the fish soft and moist, with a</textblock>
    <textblock>delicate smoke flavor, such as lox, and (2) those that are</textblock>
    <textblock>subjected to a ``hot process'' that produces a less moist, firmer</textblock>
    <textblock>product with heavier smoke flavor, such as smoked whitefish.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
