<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00039</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>G. Sanitation Control Procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>1. General</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require in ยง123.10 that processors and</textblock>
    <textblock>importers that engage in processing perform sanitation</textblock>
    <textblock>inspections at specified frequencies and maintain sanitation</textblock>
    <textblock>control records that document the results and frequency of those</textblock>
    <textblock>inspections. If these regulations are adopted, the sanitation</textblock>
    <textblock>control records will be subject to the recordkeeping requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>in ยง123.8, including review by FDA investigators.</textblock>
    <textblock>For seafood, sanitary practices affect most directly the</textblock>
    <textblock>safety of those products that do not receive any further cooking</textblock>
    <textblock>by the consumer. These products include raw molluscan shellfish;</textblock>
    <textblock>finfish destined to be consumed as sushi; cooked, ready-to-eat</textblock>
    <textblock>products; and certain smoked and salted products. Both finfish</textblock>
    <textblock>and shellfish are regarded as microbiologically sensitive foods</textblock>
    <textblock>based on the potential presence of pathogens, notably</textblock>
    <textblock>L.</textblock>
    <textblock>monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>(Ref. 55, pp. 31 and 32).</textblock>
    <textblock>L. monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>is a pathogenic bacterium that is</textblock>
    <textblock>widespread in the environment. Thus, the likelihood of finding</textblock>
    <textblock>it on the exterior surfaces and viscera of fish is high. Since</textblock>
    <textblock>1983, several large outbreaks of human listeriosis have been</textblock>
    <textblock>linked to contaminated foods. Although it is a relatively rare</textblock>
    <textblock>illness, the exceptionally high mortality rate among susceptible</textblock>
    <textblock>individuals makes this illness one of the leading fatal foodborne</textblock>
    <textblock>diseases in the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>Numerous seafood products have been shown to support growth</textblock>
    <textblock>of</textblock>
    <textblock>L. monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>(Refs. 56 and 57), and seafoods have been</textblock>
    <textblock>epidemiologically linked to two outbreaks and one sporadic case</textblock>
    <textblock>of listeriosis (Ref. 58). Furthermore, several cooked seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>products have been recalled from the market in North America</textblock>
    <textblock>because of contamination with</textblock>
    <textblock>L. monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>(Ref. 27). Seven</textblock>
    <textblock>of nine smoked fish processing facilities recently inspected by</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA in New York State had</textblock>
    <textblock>L. monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>in the environment or</textblock>
    <textblock>in the products (Ref. 59).</textblock>
    <textblock>Good sanitation practices are critical to the prevention of</textblock>
    <textblock>listeriosis and other microbiologically related foodborne</textblock>
    <textblock>illnesses. FDA's CGMP regulations for food in part 110 set out</textblock>
    <textblock>general principles of sanitation that should be followed in</textblock>
    <textblock>plants that manufacture, package, label, or hold human food.</textblock>
    <textblock>They address such matters as personal hygiene and cleanliness</textblock>
    <textblock>among workers who handle food, the suitability of the plant</textblock>
    <textblock>design to sanitary operations, and the cleaning of food-contact</textblock>
    <textblock>surfaces. FDA inspections of seafood processors apply the</textblock>
    <textblock>principles in part 110.</textblock>
    <textblock>Nearly half of the consumer complaints relating to seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>that FDA receives in a typical year are related to plant or food</textblock>
    <textblock>hygiene (Ref. 60). The reasons, while not entirely clear, appear</textblock>
    <textblock>to be related to factors such as the age of processing</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities, the seasonal nature of operations that affect</textblock>
    <textblock>training, and the turnover of personnel.</textblock>
    <textblock>A representative cross section of those FDA establishment</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection reports (EIR's) for domestic seafood manufacturers</textblock>
    <textblock>that revealed CGMP deficiencies for fiscal years 1988-90</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrates this point (Ref. 61). The cross section involves</textblock>
    <textblock>795 EIR's covering 561 facilities. (The number of EIR's exceeds</textblock>
    <textblock>the number of facilities because followup visits were made to</textblock>
    <textblock>check on the status of corrective actions.) The following</textblock>
    <textblock>percentages refer to EIR's with deficiencies where at least some</textblock>
    <textblock>of the deficiencies involved sanitation:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Twenty-three percent documented receiving area</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities that were not clean/orderly or in good repair.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Twenty-six percent documented facilities lacking</textblock>
    <textblock>effective insect and rodent control measures in the receiving</textblock>
    <textblock>area.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Sixteen percent documented failure to handle ice in a</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitary manner and to protect it properly.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
