<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-0-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-0-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(b) Has not carried out the other responsibilities described in this part;</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Dies;</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) No longer wishes to be representative payee;</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Is unable to manage the benefit payments; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) Fails to cooperate, within a reasonable time, in providing evidence, accounting, or other information which the Board requests.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง266.14</textblock>
    <textblock>When representative payment will be stopped.</textblock>
    <textblock>If an annuitant receiving representative payment shows the Board that he or she is mentally and physically able to manage or direct the management of benefit payments, the Board will make direct payment to the annuitant. Information which the annuitant may give to the Board to support his or her request for direct payment include the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A physician's statement regarding the annuitant's condition, or a statement by a medical officer of the institution where the annuitant is or was confined, showing that the annuitant is able to manage or direct the management of his or her funds;</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) A certified copy of a court order restoring the annuitant's rights in a case where an annuitant was adjudged legally incompetent; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Other evidence which establishes the annuitant's ability to manage or direct the management of benefits.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง266.15</textblock>
    <textblock>Transfer of accumulated benefit payments.</textblock>
    <textblock>A representative payee who has conserved or invested funds from railroad retirement payments made to him or her on behalf of an annuitant shall, upon direction of the Board, transfer any such funds (including interest or dividends earned from investment of such funds) to a successor representative payee appointed by the Board, or, at the option of the Board, shall transfer such funds, including interest, to the Board for payment to a successor payee or to the annuitant.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 21, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By Authority of the Board.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Beatrice Ezerski,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary to the Board.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1919 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7905-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
