<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00136</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Where reference is made in this Appendix to temperature-indicating devices and temperature-recording devices, the</textblock>
    <textblock>following conditions should apply:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Temperature-indicating devices</textblock>
    <textblock>. Temperature-indicating</textblock>
    <textblock>devices should be installed where they can be easily read and</textblock>
    <textblock>located to ensure that they accurately measure the warmest</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature of the refrigeration equipment and the coldest</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature of the smoking equipment, as appropriate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Temperature-indicating devices should be calibrated at the</textblock>
    <textblock>routine operating temperature of the refrigeration, cooling, or</textblock>
    <textblock>smoking equipment against a known accurate standard thermometer</textblock>
    <textblock>upon installation and at least once a year thereafter, or more</textblock>
    <textblock>frequently, if necessary, to ensure their accuracy. Records of</textblock>
    <textblock>accuracy checks for temperature-indicating devices required to be</textblock>
    <textblock>maintained under 21 CFR 123.8 should specify the date, standard</textblock>
    <textblock>used, method used, results, and person performing the test. A</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature-indicating device that has a divided fluid column or</textblock>
    <textblock>that cannot be adjusted to the standard should be immediately</textblock>
    <textblock>repaired or replaced.</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Temperature-recording devices</textblock>
    <textblock>. Temperature-recording</textblock>
    <textblock>devices should be installed where they can be easily read and the</textblock>
    <textblock>sensors for such devices should be installed to ensure that they</textblock>
    <textblock>accurately measure the warmest temperature of the refrigeration</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment and the coldest temperature of the smoking equipment,</textblock>
    <textblock>as appropriate. Computerized storage of temperature data may be</textblock>
    <textblock>used in place of recorder thermometer charts if the use of such a</textblock>
    <textblock>system has been validated and can be shown to be substantially</textblock>
    <textblock>equivalent to the use of a temperature-recording device. Each</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature-recording device should be checked for accuracy at</textblock>
    <textblock>the beginning and end of each production day and adjusted as</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to agree as nearly as possible with the reference</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature-indicating device. A record of these accuracy checks</textblock>
    <textblock>should be maintained that specifies the time, date, temperatures</textblock>
    <textblock>indicated by both devices before adjustment, corrective action</textblock>
    <textblock>taken, where applicable, and person performing the accuracy</textblock>
    <textblock>check.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Packaging</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Vacuum- or modified atmosphere-packaging should be</textblock>
    <textblock>conducted only within the facilities in which the product is</textblock>
    <textblock>produced.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Permanently legible code marks should be placed on each</textblock>
    <textblock>finished product package and shipping container. These marks</textblock>
    <textblock>should identify the plant where the product was packed and the</textblock>
    <textblock>date of packing.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Corrective Action</textblock>
    <textblock>Under 21 CFR 123.7, whenever a deviation occurs at a</textblock>
    <textblock>critical control point, the processor is required to segregate</textblock>
    <textblock>and hold the product until a review can be made to determine the</textblock>
    <textblock>effect of that deviation and take corrective action as necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>For smoked and smoke-flavored fishery products, when a deviation</textblock>
    <textblock>occurs at a brining or smoking critical control point, the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor should meet the requirements of ยง123.7 either by</textblock>
    <textblock>destroying the product; by fully reprocessing, where possible,</textblock>
    <textblock>that portion of the production involved, keeping full records of</textblock>
    <textblock>the reprocessing conditions; or by setting aside that portion of</textblock>
    <textblock>the product involved for further evaluation as to any potential</textblock>
    <textblock>public health significance. Such an evaluation should be made by</textblock>
    <textblock>a process authority and should be in accordance with procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>recognized by process authorities as being adequate to detect any</textblock>
    <textblock>unacceptable hazard to public health. Unless this evaluation</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrates that the product had been rendered safe for its</textblock>
    <textblock>intended use, the product set aside should be either fully</textblock>
    <textblock>reprocessed to correct the deficiency or destroyed. A record</textblock>
    <textblock>should be made of the evaluation procedures used and the results.</textblock>
    <textblock>Either upon completion of full reprocessing or after the</textblock>
    <textblock>determination that no significant public health hazard exists,</textblock>
    <textblock>that portion of the product involved may be shipped in normal</textblock>
    <textblock>distribution. Otherwise, the portion of the product involved</textblock>
    <textblock>should be destroyed.</textblock>
    <textblock>10. Sanitary Zones</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to the requirements of 21 CFR 123.10, sanitary</textblock>
    <textblock>zones should be established around areas in which a smoked</textblock>
    <textblock>product is handled or stored. In such areas, objects and</textblock>
    <textblock>employees that have come into contact with waste, raw product, or</textblock>
    <textblock>other insanitary objects are excluded. Packaging material,</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment, employees, and in-process materials that enter a</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitary zone should be treated in a manner that will minimize</textblock>
    <textblock>the risk of the introduction of microorganisms. Air handling</textblock>
    <textblock>systems should be designed to minimize the risk of airborne</textblock>
    <textblock>contamination into sanitary zones and to provide positive air</textblock>
    <textblock>pressure in the sanitary zone relative to the surrounding areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>11. Alternative Parameters</textblock>
    <textblock>A processor of smoked or smoke-flavored fishery products may</textblock>
    <textblock>use parameters other than those provided in Appendix C, section</textblock>
    <textblock>5.a., if those parameters will achieve the following, as</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrated by adequate scientific studies:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) For botulism, zero toxin production in the product</textblock>
    <textblock>through a time period slightly beyond the shelf life of the</textblock>
    <textblock>product, demonstrated through inoculated pack studies under</textblock>
    <textblock>normal and moderate abuse conditions, and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For listeria, no detectable</textblock>
    <textblock>Listeria monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>in</textblock>
    <textblock>the final product. A processor using alternative parameters</textblock>
    <textblock>should have on file, subject to the requirements of 21 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>123.8(d), a description, including the results of, the scientific</textblock>
    <textblock>studies.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
