<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00085</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>FDA has also evaluated the potential health benefits</textblock>
    <textblock>associated with increased consumption of seafood. Because of the</textblock>
    <textblock>negative publicity concerning water pollution and seafood safety,</textblock>
    <textblock>consumer perception of seafood safety may overestimate actual</textblock>
    <textblock>risk. In addition, contamination scares cause drastic short-term</textblock>
    <textblock>drops in consumer demand for seafood products and undoubtedly</textblock>
    <textblock>contribute to the chronic level of consumer concern about seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>safety. Thus, safety concerns about seafood are a likely factor</textblock>
    <textblock>preventing wider consumer acceptance of seafood as part of the</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. diet.</textblock>
    <textblock>If this proposal is finalized, consumer concerns about</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood safety may be reduced which may, in turn, lead to</textblock>
    <textblock>increased consumption of seafood. FDA has evaluated the</textblock>
    <textblock>possibility that consumers may switch from higher fat flesh</textblock>
    <textblock>protein, such as meat and poultry, to seafood. The resulting</textblock>
    <textblock>reduced dietary fat in the diet of the general population would</textblock>
    <textblock>result in reduced incidence of coronary heart disease and cancer.</textblock>
    <textblock>Using the same methodology employed in an earlier analysis of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Nutrition Labeling and Education Act of 1990 (Pub. L. 101-535),</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA analyzed the benefits of a 1- and 5-pound per capita increase</textblock>
    <textblock>in consumption of seafood. These were estimated to decrease</textblock>
    <textblock>deaths by 673 and 2,782, respectively, over a 10-year period.</textblock>
    <textblock>The resulting benefits are valued at $3 and $14 billion.</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Small Business Impact</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule will have a substantial impact on small</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood processors as defined by the Regulatory Flexibility Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Eighty percent of the seafood processors covered by this proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation are small, where small is defined for nonshrimp firms</textblock>
    <textblock>as less than $1 million in annual gross revenue and less than $2</textblock>
    <textblock>million for shrimp firms. The provisions of this rule, such as</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring and recordkeeping, are largely fixed costs (costs</textblock>
    <textblock>which do not vary significantly with the amount of the product</textblock>
    <textblock>produced) which will impose larger per unit costs on small rather</textblock>
    <textblock>than on large businesses. In addition, small firms may have as</textblock>
    <textblock>many critical control points as large firms because critical</textblock>
    <textblock>control points tend to be related to the complexity of the</textblock>
    <textblock>operation, not the size of the business. However, it may be that</textblock>
    <textblock>smaller firms are less complex than large firms, although the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency does not have sufficient data to determine if this is so.</textblock>
    <textblock>In some cases the increase in cost will be large enough to</textblock>
    <textblock>cause some firms to go out of business. For example, estimates</textblock>
    <textblock>of firm failure have been as low as 2 percent (96 firms) of all</textblock>
    <textblock>firms (from the Canadian experience) to 334 firms (estimated for</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance with MSSP). However, FDA does not have enough</textblock>
    <textblock>information to estimate the number of firms that will close if</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed rule becomes final.</textblock>
    <textblock>There are several factors that affect the ability of small</textblock>
    <textblock>processors to comply with the proposed regulations. First, the</textblock>
    <textblock>basic HACCP requirements proposed in subpart A of part 123</textblock>
    <textblock>deliberately include only the essentials of HACCP in order to</textblock>
    <textblock>keep fixed costs to a minimum. Second, FDA is developing</textblock>
    <textblock>considerable guidance in the form of a hazard guide and model</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP plans to enable small processors to implement an effective</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP system at the lowest possible cost. Third, FDA is also</textblock>
    <textblock>aware that academia and trade associations are available to</textblock>
    <textblock>assist processors to implement HACCP. Finally, for those small</textblock>
    <textblock>processors that have very simple operations requiring few</textblock>
    <textblock>critical control points, an inherent feature of HACCP is that it</textblock>
    <textblock>adjusts to the complexity and risks of an operation.</textblock>
    <textblock>While any closure is regrettable, the agency strongly</textblock>
    <textblock>believes that firms that are unable to identify the likely</textblock>
    <textblock>hazards associated with their products and take reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>preventive controls to prevent those hazards from occurring</textblock>
    <textblock>should not be selling food in interstate commerce. As described</textblock>
    <textblock>in the preamble, FDA is keenly interested in keeping the costs of</textblock>
    <textblock>implementing HACCP to a minimum and is issuing guidance documents</textblock>
    <textblock>and model HACCP plans to facilitate such implementation.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is specifically requesting comment in areas where costs</textblock>
    <textblock>and benefit estimates are either very uncertain or potentially</textblock>
    <textblock>large. FDA will utilize answers received on these comments along</textblock>
    <textblock>with all other comments to help formulate the final rule.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
