<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00192</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00121</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>For a more complete statement of the facts and representations supporting the Department's decision to grant this exemption, refer to the notice of proposed exemption published on December 3, 1993 at 58 FR 64012.</textblock>
  </text>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Jan D. Broady of the Department, telephone (202) 219-8881. (This is not a toll-free number.)</textblock>
    <textblock>W.J. Casey Trucking &amp; Rigging Co., Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>Employees Profit Sharing Plan and Trust (the Plan)</textblock>
    <textblock>Located in Union, New Jersey</textblock>
    <textblock>[Prohibited Transaction Exemption 94-11 ;</textblock>
    <textblock>Exemption Application No. D-9506]</textblock>
    <textblock>Exemption</textblock>
    <textblock>The restrictions of sections 406(a), 406(b)(1) and (b)(2) of the Act and the sanctions resulting from the application of section 4975 of the Code, by reason of section 4975(c)(1)(A) through (E) of the Code, shall not apply to: (1) The seven-year loan of $300,000 (the Loan) by the Plan to W. J. Casey Trucking &amp; Rigging Co., Inc. (the Employer), a party in interest with respect to the Plan; and (2) the personal guarantees of the Employer's obligations under the Loan by James P. and Nicholas J. Biondi (the Biondis), parties in interest with respect to the Plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>This exemption is conditioned upon the following requirements: (a) All terms and conditions of the Loan are at least as favorable to the Plan as those obtainable in an arm's-length transaction with an unrelated party; (b) the Loan will not exceed twenty-five percent of the Plan's assets at any time during the transaction; (c) the Loan is secured by a first lien</textblock>
    <textblock>interest on certain equipment (the Equipment), which has been appraised by a qualified, independent appraiser to ensure that the fair market value of the Equipment is at least 200 percent of the amount of the Loan; (d) the Employer's obligations under the Loan are personally guaranteed by the Biondis; (e) the fair market value of the Equipment remains not less than 200 percent of the outstanding balance of the Loan throughout the duration of the Loan; (f) an independent, qualified fiduciary determines on behalf of the Plan that the Loan is administratively feasible, in the best interests of the Plan, and protective of the Plan and its participants and beneficiaries; and (g) the independent, qualified fiduciary monitors compliance with the terms and conditions of the exemption and the Loan throughout the duration of the transaction, taking any action necessary to safeguard the Plan's interest, including foreclosure on the Equipment in the event of default.</textblock>
    <textblock>For a more complete statement of the facts and representations supporting the Department's decision to grant this exemption, refer to the notice of proposed exemption published on December 10, 1993 at 58 FR 64983.</textblock>
  </further>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Kathryn Parr of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department, telephone (202) 219-8971. (This is not a toll-free number.)</textblock>
  </further>
</doc>
