<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-0-00039</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-0-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Nothing in this action should be construed as permitting, allowing or establishing a precedent for any future request for revision to any SIP. The USEPA shall consider each request for revision to the SIP in light of specific technical, economic, and environmental factors and in relation to relevant statutory and regulatory requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>This action has been classified as a Table 2 action by the Regional Administrator under the procedures published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on January 19, 1989 (54 FR 2214-2225). On January 6, 1989, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) waived Table 2 and 3 SIP revisions (54 FR 2222) from the requirements of section 3 of Executive Order 12291 for a period of 2 years. The USEPA has submitted a request for a permanent waiver for Table 2 and 3 SIP revisions. OMB has agreed to continue the waiver until such time as it rules on USEPA's request. This request continues in effect under Executive Order 12866 which superseded Executive Order 12291 on September 30, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under section 307(b)(1) of the Clean Air Act, petitions for judicial review of this action must be filed in the United States Court of Appeals for the appropriate circuit by March 29, 1994. Filing a petition for reconsideration by the Administrator of this final rule does not affect the finality of this rule for the purposes of judicial review nor does it extend the time within which a petition for judicial review may be filed, and shall not postpone the effectiveness of such rule or action. This action may not be challenged later in proceedings to enforce its requirements. (See section 307(b)(2).)</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 40 CFR Part 52</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental protection, Air pollution control, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Sulfur oxides.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Valdas V. Adamkus,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Regional Administrator.</textblock>
    <textblock>40 CFR part 52 is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 52_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 52 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 7401-7671q.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart O_Illinois</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 52.720 is amended by adding paragraph (c)(99) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§52.720</textblock>
    <textblock>Identification of plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(99) On January 4, 1989, the State submitted revisions to its sulfur dioxide rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Incorporation by reference.</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Title 35: Environmental Protection, Subtitle B: Air Pollution, Chapter 1: Pollution Control Board, Subchapter c: Emission Standards and Limitations for Stationary Sources, Part 214 Sulfur Limitations, Subpart A: General Provisions, section 214.102 Abbreviations and Units. Amended at 12 Ill. Reg. 20778, effective December 5, 1988.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Title 35: Environmental Protection, Subtitle B: Air Pollution, Chapter 1: Pollution Control Board, Subchapter c: Emission Standards and Limitations for Stationary Sources, Part 214 Sulfur Limitations, Subpart A: General Provisions, section 214.104 Incorporations by Reference. Amended at 15 Ill. Reg. 1017, effective January 15, 1991.</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Title 35: Environmental Protection, Subtitle B: Air Pollution, Chapter 1: Pollution Control Board, Subchapter c: Emission Standards and Limitations for Stationary Sources, Part 214 Sulfur Limitations, Subpart O: Petroleum Refining, Petrochemical and Chemical Manufacturing, section 214.382 Petroleum and Petrochemical Processes. Amended at 12 Ill. Reg. 20778, effective December 5, 1988.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1859 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
