<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00040</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(4) Thirty-five percent documented lack of adequate</textblock>
    <textblock>cleaning or sanitizing of processing equipment.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Twenty-one percent documented processing equipment that</textblock>
    <textblock>was not constructed so that it could be easily cleaned and</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitized.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Eighteen percent documented processing equipment that</textblock>
    <textblock>was not made of suitable materials.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Fifteen percent documented hand sanitizers that were</textblock>
    <textblock>not kept at proper sanitizing levels.</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) Eighteen percent documented failure to have hand</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitizers available in the processing area.</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) Thirty percent documented processing areas that were</textblock>
    <textblock>not maintained in a clean and sanitary manner.</textblock>
    <textblock>(10) Forty-two percent documented processing areas with</textblock>
    <textblock>exterior openings that were not sealed/covered properly to</textblock>
    <textblock>prevent the entrance of pests or insects.</textblock>
    <textblock>(11) Sixteen percent documented waste material not being</textblock>
    <textblock>collected/covered in suitable containers or not being disposed of</textblock>
    <textblock>properly.</textblock>
    <textblock>(12) Twenty-three percent documented handling of finished</textblock>
    <textblock>product in a manner that did not preclude contamination.</textblock>
    <textblock>(13) Twenty-two percent documented employees not taking</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary precautions to avoid food contamination.</textblock>
    <textblock>During fiscal years 1991-92, FDA conducted abbreviated</textblock>
    <textblock>inspections of nearly all domestic manufacturers in its seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>establishment inventory. These inspections provide data on</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitation practices and conditions that are generally consistent</textblock>
    <textblock>with the above findings (Ref. 62). Examples of these data are:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Sixteen percent of firms had problems with the general</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitation condition of their processing areas. (This percentage</textblock>
    <textblock>is lower than for item 9 above because the universe is all firms,</textblock>
    <textblock>not just firms with deficiencies.)</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Nineteen percent of firms did not clean and sanitize</textblock>
    <textblock>their processing areas or equipment throughout the day's</textblock>
    <textblock>production. (This matches most closely with item 4 above but is</textblock>
    <textblock>lower, presumably for the reason stated in the previously</textblock>
    <textblock>numbered paragraph.)</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Twenty-eight percent of firms had employees that were</textblock>
    <textblock>not following proper sanitation practices in processing</textblock>
    <textblock>activities. (This figure does not precisely match any of the</textblock>
    <textblock>items listed above because the EIR's break employee practices</textblock>
    <textblock>down into specific categories, such as the wearing of hair nets.</textblock>
    <textblock>Some categories involve relatively minor matters, others are more</textblock>
    <textblock>significant. Findings with respect to these employee practices</textblock>
    <textblock>were not listed above for the sake of brevity.)</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Twenty percent had employees that were not following</textblock>
    <textblock>proper sanitation practices for packaging and finished product</textblock>
    <textblock>storage. (The parenthetical observations in the previously</textblock>
    <textblock>numbered paragraph apply here as well.)</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Thirty-six percent of firms either lacked hand</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitizers in their processing areas or had sanitizers that were</textblock>
    <textblock>not kept at proper sanitizing levels. (This finding is</textblock>
    <textblock>equivalent to a combination of items 7 and 8 above.</textblock>
    <textblock>Surprisingly, this finding is roughly the same as 7 and 8 added</textblock>
    <textblock>together, even though it includes all processors rather than</textblock>
    <textblock>processors with deficiencies.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Sanitation problems found by NMFS during the operation of</textblock>
    <textblock>its fee-for-service inspection program for seafood manufacturers,</textblock>
    <textblock>as described earlier, are generally consistent with FDA's</textblock>
    <textblock>findings. Entrants into the NMFS program undergo initial</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitation surveys by NMFS and are checked for sanitation</textblock>
    <textblock>practices thereafter. NMFS' data show significant sanitation</textblock>
    <textblock>deficiencies during the initial surveys (Ref. 35, p. 40). Some</textblock>
    <textblock>of the most common for 1989 include:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Sixty-four percent of plants had discrepancies relating</textblock>
    <textblock>to proper cleaning and sanitizing of product contact surfaces or</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment, containers, or utensils after use.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Fifty-one percent of plants had discrepancies relating</textblock>
    <textblock>to design, materials, or construction that prevented their being</textblock>
    <textblock>maintained in a sanitary manner.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Forty-five percent of plants had discrepancies relating</textblock>
    <textblock>to design of equipment, containers, and utensils so that they did</textblock>
    <textblock>not provide protection from contaminants and could not be readily</textblock>
    <textblock>cleaned and effectively sanitized.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Forty-three percent of plants had discrepancies</textblock>
    <textblock>relating to improper storage of equipment, litter, waste, uncut</textblock>
    <textblock>weeds, and grass.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
