<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00122</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00084</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Under the provisions of the Federal Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. chapter 35), we have submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) a request for approval for the continued use of an information collection titled: ``Worksheet for Integrated AFDC, Food Stamps and Medicaid Eligibility Quality Control Reviews.'' This information collection is jointly designed and used by the Office of Family Assistance (OFA) of the Administration for Families and Children (ACY) and Health Care Financing Administration (HCFA) both of the Department of Health and Human Services and the Food and Nutrition Service (FNS) of the Department of Agriculture.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Administration for Children and Families</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Agency Information Collection Under OMB Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <address>
    <textblock>addresses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of this information collection request may be obtained from Stephen R. Smith of the Office of Information Systems Management, ACY, by calling (202) 401-6964.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments and questions regarding the requested approval for information collection should be sent directly to: Laura Oliven, OMB Desk Officer for ACF, OMB Reports Management Branch, New Executive Office Building, room 3002, 725 17th Street NW., Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-7316.</textblock>
    <textblock>Information on Document</textblock>
    <textblock>Title: Worksheet for Integrated AFDC, Adult, Food Stamps and Medicaid Eligibility Quality Control Reviews Form ACF-4340.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB No.: 0970-0072.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description:</textblock>
    <textblock>This information collection is authorized by Sections 2, 408, 1402, and 1602 of the Social Security Act and required under regulatory authority found at 45 CFR 205.40. The Worksheet for Integrated Quality Control Reviews is a joint form developed and utilized by the Administration for Children and Families and Health Care Financing Administration both of the Department of Health and Human Services and the Food and Nutrition Service of the Department of Agriculture for quality reviews of the Aid to Families with Dependent Children (AFDC), Food Stamps and Medicaid programs. The Quality Control (QC) Reviews of the three programs are conducted by the State agencies which administer the programs for the sponsoring federal agencies. Form 4340 is used by the States to document the findings of state quality reviewers who review the correctness of a sample of eligibility decisions made by the states for the AFDC, Food Stamps and Medicaid programs. The purpose of this QC reviews are to assure that individuals are not being denied categories of Federal assistance for which they are eligible and to take necessary corrective measures to reduce the incidence of improperly authorized or denied assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>This information is utilized in determining the principal causes of incorrect actions and in developing appropriate corrective action.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>59,500</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Frequency:</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>Average Burden Hours Per Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>11.0236</textblock>
    <textblock>Total Burden Hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>655,904</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </address>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Larry Guerrero,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Director, Office of Information Systems Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1920 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4184-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
