<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00119</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The agency believes that the proposed processing</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for cold-process smoked and smoke-flavored products,</textblock>
    <textblock>air-packed and vacuum- or modified atmosphere-packaged, will</textblock>
    <textblock>produce a safe and commercially acceptable product. However,</textblock>
    <textblock>because less data and information are available for these</textblock>
    <textblock>products than for hot-process products, the agency is requesting</textblock>
    <textblock>specific comments, data, and information about these processing</textblock>
    <textblock>parameters and any alternative processing parameters that should</textblock>
    <textblock>be included in the guideline.</textblock>
    <textblock>3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cooling and storage of finished products.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rapid cooling</textblock>
    <textblock>and storage at temperatures of 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below are</textblock>
    <textblock>essential for all smoked, smoke-flavored, and salted fish</textblock>
    <textblock>products to minimize microbial growth. The exceptions are</textblock>
    <textblock>cold-process air-packaged products that contain a water-phase</textblock>
    <textblock>salt content of 2.5 percent, which should be frozen immediately</textblock>
    <textblock>after processing and remain frozen throughout distribution</textblock>
    <textblock>because of the lower water-phase salt content and lower</textblock>
    <textblock>processing temperatures that may provide an opportunity for food</textblock>
    <textblock>spoilage microorganisms to flourish during storage (see section</textblock>
    <textblock>5.a.3. of Example 6 of this appendix) and the discussion above).</textblock>
    <textblock>Outgrowth of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>spores, types A and proteolytic B,</textblock>
    <textblock>and toxin production are inhibited at temperatures of 50</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (10</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) and lower. Spore types E and nonproteolytic B are completely</textblock>
    <textblock>inhibited at temperatures of 38</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (3.3</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) and lower (Refs. 174</textblock>
    <textblock>and 185 through 188).</textblock>
    <textblock>At section 6 of Example 6 of the appendix, the agency is</textblock>
    <textblock>recommending specific time/temperature controls for processing</textblock>
    <textblock>after smoking. These proposed controls are the same as those</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed for after cooking in the cooked, ready-to-eat section of</textblock>
    <textblock>this document (Appendix A, section 6). A full discussion of the</textblock>
    <textblock>controls is provided in section VII.J.3. of this document.</textblock>
    <textblock>4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Alternative processing parameters.</textblock>
    <textblock>As this preamble</textblock>
    <textblock>indicates, FDA has tentatively concluded that the TTS processing</textblock>
    <textblock>parameters reflected in this appendix are the minimum necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>to ensure that these products are free from botulinum toxin over</textblock>
    <textblock>their shelf life. FDA has also tentatively concluded that the</textblock>
    <textblock>T-T-S parameters, coupled with good sanitation practices, will</textblock>
    <textblock>also render these products listeria free. Nonetheless, the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency does not wish to discourage the development and use of</textblock>
    <textblock>alternative procedures that are capable of achieving the same</textblock>
    <textblock>outcome.</textblock>
    <textblock>Consequently, section 11 of Example 6 of this appendix calls</textblock>
    <textblock>for the use of alternative processing parameters when the user</textblock>
    <textblock>can demonstrate the following: (1) For botulism, zero toxin</textblock>
    <textblock>production slightly beyond the expected shelf life of the</textblock>
    <textblock>product, demonstrated through inoculated pack studies under</textblock>
    <textblock>normal and moderate abuse conditions and (2) for listeria, no</textblock>
    <textblock>detectable</textblock>
    <textblock>L. monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>in the final product. The data</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrating these outcomes would have to be available to FDA to</textblock>
    <textblock>enable the agency to determine whether they have been achieved.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 6 of this appendix states that those data should be</textblock>
    <textblock>part of a processor's HACCP records. FDA asks for comment on</textblock>
    <textblock>whether a third-party scientific expert, or processing authority,</textblock>
    <textblock>should be involved in the development of the data that</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrate the effectiveness of the alternative procedure.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
