<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00113</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>ยง1240.3</textblock>
    <textblock>General definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(p)</textblock>
    <textblock>Molluscan shellfish.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any edible species of fresh or</textblock>
    <textblock>frozen oysters, clams, mussels, and scallops or edible portions</textblock>
    <textblock>thereof, except when the scallop or scallop product consists</textblock>
    <textblock>entirely of the shucked adductor muscle.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Section 1240.60 is amended by revising the section</textblock>
    <textblock>heading; by designating the existing text as paragraph (a) and</textblock>
    <textblock>adding the word ``molluscan'' before the word ``shellfish'' the two</textblock>
    <textblock>times that it appears; and by adding new paragraphs (b) and (c)</textblock>
    <textblock>to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง1240.60</textblock>
    <textblock>Molluscan shellfish.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) All unshucked raw molluscan shellfish, that is all</textblock>
    <textblock>unshucked molluscan shellfish that has not been subject to a</textblock>
    <textblock>treatment sufficient to kill pathogens of public health</textblock>
    <textblock>significance, shall bear a tag that discloses the date and place</textblock>
    <textblock>they were harvested, type and quantity of shellfish, and by whom</textblock>
    <textblock>they were harvested, including the number assigned to the</textblock>
    <textblock>harvester by the shellfish control authority. Any raw molluscan</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish that are found by FDA in interstate commerce without</textblock>
    <textblock>such a tag or label, or with a tag or label that does not bear</textblock>
    <textblock>all the required information, will be subject to seizure and</textblock>
    <textblock>destruction.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Shucked molluscan shellfish shall be subject to the</textblock>
    <textblock>same requirements as apply to molluscan shellfish that has not</textblock>
    <textblock>been shucked as provided in paragraph (b) of this section, except</textblock>
    <textblock>that, in lieu of a tag, the body of the container of shucked</textblock>
    <textblock>molluscan shellfish, shall bear a label that identifies the name,</textblock>
    <textblock>address, and certification number of the processor of the</textblock>
    <textblock>molluscan shellfish.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David A. Kessler,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna E. Shalala,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of Health and Human Services.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>The following appendix will not appear in the annual Code</textblock>
    <textblock>of Federal Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix 1_FDA Fish Fishery Products Hazard and Controls Guide Including Guidance on Smoked Fish</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is in the process of developing guidance to, among</textblock>
    <textblock>other things, assist the seafood industry develop and implement</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP systems. The guidance will be titled</textblock>
    <textblock>the ``FDA Fish and Fishery Products Hazard</textblock>
    <textblock>and Controls Guide.'' When a draft of the entire Guide is completed in the near future, FDA will publish a notice</textblock>
    <textblock>of availability in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>and invite public</textblock>
    <textblock>comment. FDA will revise the draft as warranted and then issue</textblock>
    <textblock>the first edition of the Guide.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. The Information Presented</textblock>
    <textblock>The selected portions of the draft Guide that are provided</textblock>
    <textblock>below are:</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 1.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Table of Contents.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 2.</textblock>
    <textblock>One page each from the ``Vertebrate'' and</textblock>
    <textblock>``Invertebrate Hazard and Control Lists.'' Together, these lists</textblock>
    <textblock>contain about 350 species of commercially marketed fish. Each</textblock>
    <textblock>list is in the form of a chart that directs the reader to one or</textblock>
    <textblock>more of the 10 numbered hazard and control descriptions elsewhere</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Guide for species-related hazards. For purposes of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Guide, species-related hazards are those that can occur in the</textblock>
    <textblock>environment or during harvest. Processors should find in the</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate list the species they handle, then turn to those</textblock>
    <textblock>numbered hazard and control descriptions that are relevant to</textblock>
    <textblock>that species.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 3.</textblock>
    <textblock>A sample of a species-related hazard and</textblock>
    <textblock>control description (Species-related Hazard and Control</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>(Chemical Contamination)). Each description explains a hazard</textblock>
    <textblock>and the measures available to control it, with an emphasis on</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP controls such as critical control points, critical limits,</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring procedures and frequencies, recordkeeping, and</textblock>
    <textblock>corrective actions. Some descriptions contain several control</textblock>
    <textblock>options.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
