<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00169</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00108</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Park Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Environmental Impact Statement; Natchez Trace Parkway, MS</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Park Service, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of intent to prepare an Environmental Impact Statement for the Southern Terminus of the Natchez Trace Parkway and notice of public meetings.</textblock>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Background and Description of the Proposed Action</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, Public Law 91-190, the National Park Service (NPS) is preparing an Environmental Impact Statement (EIS) to determine the final alignment and the impacts of constructing this final portion of the Natchez Trace Parkway in Adams County, Mississippi. This portion will include the southern terminus of the parkway and extend from U.S. 84/98 through the city of Natchez to the vicinity of the Mississippi River, a distance of approximately 7 miles. The EIS will evaluate potential impacts from a range of alternatives which address cultural and natural resources protection, transportation and socioeconomic concerns, visitor use, visual characteristics, and interpretation.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Natchez Trace Parkway, established in 1938, is a 445-mile long scenic road that follows the historic route of the Natchez Trace. The parkway links the cities of Natchez, Mississippi and Nashville, Tennessee. About 400 miles of the parkway have been completed. The purpose of the parkway is to provide and maintain a scenic and recreational roadway commemorating the historic Old Natchez Trace and to provide access to significant natural and cultural resources along the route.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Scoping Process/Public Involvement</textblock>
    <textblock>Scoping meetings will be held for the general public as well as particular interest and community groups during the winter of 1994. The purpose of scoping is to determine the scope of issues to be addressed and to identify the significant issues related to the project. Meetings will be conducted in the cities of Natchez and Jackson. Meeting dates, locations, and times will be announced through local media.</textblock>
  </action>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>To obtain information or provide comments other than at the meetings, please contact Dan Brown, Superintendent, Natchez Trace Parkway, Rural Route 1, NT-143, Tupelo, Mississippi 38801, telephone (601 680-4003. The responsible official for this EIS is James W. Coleman, Jr., Regional Director, Southeast Region, 75 Spring Street, SW., Atlanta, Georgia 30303.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Representatives from the EIS team will be present to receive comments and answer questions at the public meetings. The public is encouraged to attend and submit verbal and/or written comments regarding the proposed action and EIS.</textblock>
    <textblock>The draft and final EIS will be distributed to all known interested parties and appropriate agencies. Full public participation by Federal, State, and local agencies as well as other concerned organizations and private citizens is invited during this scoping process and throughout preparation of the document.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 19, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>James W. Coleman, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Regional Director, Southeast Region.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1935 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-70-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
