<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00016</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>B. Alternatives Other Than HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>Continuous visual inspection of seafood is not a viable</textblock>
    <textblock>alternative. Few hazards associated with seafood are detectable</textblock>
    <textblock>through visual inspection. Moreover, the costs of such a system</textblock>
    <textblock>would likely exceed the nearly half-billion-dollar public outlay</textblock>
    <textblock>now required to operate this kind of system for meat and poultry.</textblock>
    <textblock>Another alternative would be to direct significant</textblock>
    <textblock>additional resources toward greatly increasing the frequency of</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA's inspection of seafood, as well as increasing the agency's</textblock>
    <textblock>sampling, laboratory analysis, and related regulatory activities</textblock>
    <textblock>with respect to seafood. While thousands of samples of domestic</textblock>
    <textblock>and imported seafood products are collected each year for</textblock>
    <textblock>analysis in FDA laboratories, and these samples are</textblock>
    <textblock>scientifically designed to represent a broad range of products,</textblock>
    <textblock>they are generally perceived by the public to represent only a</textblock>
    <textblock>small fraction of the total poundage of seafood consumed in this</textblock>
    <textblock>country. Substantial new expenditures would be needed to</textblock>
    <textblock>increase laboratory analyses to nationally statistically</textblock>
    <textblock>significant levels.</textblock>
    <textblock>Even if the funds for increased inspection and increased</textblock>
    <textblock>sampling and analysis were available (which they are not), this</textblock>
    <textblock>approach alone would likely not be the best way for the agency to</textblock>
    <textblock>spend its money to protect the public health. Reliance on end-product testing involves a certain amount of inefficiency that</textblock>
    <textblock>can require very large sample sizes to overcome. NAS recently</textblock>
    <textblock>observed that ``the statistical uncertainties associated with lot</textblock>
    <textblock>sampling make this an unreliable method for ensuring safety of</textblock>
    <textblock>food products *␣*␣*'' (Ref. 7, p. 283). FDA has traditionally</textblock>
    <textblock>sought to minimize this type of inefficiency by targeting its</textblock>
    <textblock>efforts based on its experiences, but some inefficiency is</textblock>
    <textblock>unavoidable. NAS recommended the HACCP system as an alternative</textblock>
    <textblock>(Ref. 7, p. 283).</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Current Import System Is Not Well-Suited to Seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>Similar considerations apply to imports. FDA does not</textblock>
    <textblock>generally inspect processing facilities in other countries to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine whether seafood products are being prepared, packed, or</textblock>
    <textblock>held there under appropriate conditions. Such inspections are</textblock>
    <textblock>extremely costly and require an invitation from the foreign</textblock>
    <textblock>country. Traditionally, therefore, FDA's primary strategy for</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood imports has involved: (1) Reviewing all customs entries</textblock>
    <textblock>documents to determine which imported products to examine or</textblock>
    <textblock>sample; (2) conducting wharf examinations of selected products</textblock>
    <textblock>based on that review; and (3) sampling and laboratory analyses</textblock>
    <textblock>as appropriate.</textblock>
    <textblock>One concern about this process that has been voiced with</textblock>
    <textblock>some regularity in the media, Congress, and elsewhere is that FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>physically looks at less than 5 percent of all imports. This</textblock>
    <textblock>figure is somewhat misleading because it refers to seafood lots</textblock>
    <textblock>that can vary substantially in size. Also, it does not take into</textblock>
    <textblock>account such factors as the representative nature of the</textblock>
    <textblock>examinations, FDA's automatic detention program for imports that</textblock>
    <textblock>requires importers of products with a history of problems to</textblock>
    <textblock>obtain a laboratory analysis and certification prior to entry, or</textblock>
    <textblock>the fact that imports receiving further processing in the United</textblock>
    <textblock>States become subject to domestic inspection. Nonetheless, it is</textblock>
    <textblock>certainly true that most imported seafood is not physically</textblock>
    <textblock>sampled or examined by a Federal health official.</textblock>
    <textblock>The total number of customs entries for seafood each year is</textblock>
    <textblock>approaching 200,000 (Ref. 27) from about 135 countries (compared</textblock>
    <textblock>to about 33 countries for beef and poultry (Ref. 28)), and huge</textblock>
    <textblock>sums of money would be needed to enable FDA to increase its</textblock>
    <textblock>physical examination and sampling program to nationally,</textblock>
    <textblock>statistically significant levels. Still, many developing</textblock>
    <textblock>countries export seafood products to this country, and their</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory protections tend to be comparatively weak, if they</textblock>
    <textblock>exist at all. Processing conditions in such countries do not</textblock>
    <textblock>always meet U.S. standards for sanitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>While many importers are conscientious about the safety and</textblock>
    <textblock>quality of the products that they import, others have little</textblock>
    <textblock>understanding of potential hazards. The denial of entry of a</textblock>
    <textblock>violative lot may be regarded as simply a cost of doing business,</textblock>
    <textblock>which is offset in many cases by insurance purchased against just</textblock>
    <textblock>such an eventuality. Such policies are identified as ```FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>rejection' insurance'' and usually the premium is 2 to 3 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>of the value of the shipment (Ref. 29). It is reasonable to</textblock>
    <textblock>assume that this cost is being passed on to the consumer. The</textblock>
    <textblock>insurance also permits importers to buy seafood from foreign</textblock>
    <textblock>processors without first ensuring that it meets FDA requirements,</textblock>
    <textblock>i.e., that it is safe, wholesome, and properly labeled.</textblock>
    <textblock>This system leaves much to be desired. It, too, is a</textblock>
    <textblock>``snapshot''-type approach that places a significant burden on the</textblock>
    <textblock>Government to uncover problems without fostering or promoting</textblock>
    <textblock>industry responsibility. It lacks the preventive controls that</textblock>
    <textblock>the agency has tentatively concluded are the minimum necessary to</textblock>
    <textblock>ensure safety. Moreover, it has not provided full public</textblock>
    <textblock>confidence in the safety of imported seafood.</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Public Confidence</textblock>
    <textblock>Continuing public concerns about the safety of seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>provide additional evidence that the current regulatory system is</textblock>
    <textblock>not well-suited for seafood. Consumers have become increasingly</textblock>
    <textblock>concerned about the effects of pollution on seafood. Medical</textblock>
    <textblock>wastes washing up on beaches, ocean dumping of toxic wastes,</textblock>
    <textblock>chemical run-off, and multiple oil spills continually dramatize</textblock>
    <textblock>the fact that bodies of water, no matter how large, can be</textblock>
    <textblock>adversely affected by human activity.</textblock>
    <textblock>Media and other public attention on seafood safety and</textblock>
    <textblock>quality, and on the adequacy of the current regulatory program</textblock>
    <textblock>for seafood, has been substantial in recent years, and there is</textblock>
    <textblock>no reason to expect that this attention will decrease. Problems</textblock>
    <textblock>with some seafood products draw attention to, and has tended to</textblock>
    <textblock>raise concerns about, all seafood, a situation that is bad for</textblock>
    <textblock>consumers because seafood is a low fat product, and bad for an</textblock>
    <textblock>industry that can ill afford it.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
