<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00058</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Appendix A, section 6.c. advises how processors can ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>that microbiological hazards associated with final product</textblock>
    <textblock>cooling can be controlled. Following the manipulation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>product during postcooking processing, it will be necessary for</textblock>
    <textblock>the processor to cool the product to a temperature that will not</textblock>
    <textblock>support the further growth of mesophilic or psychrotropic</textblock>
    <textblock>pathogens. This result can be achieved by cooling the finished</textblock>
    <textblock>product to an internal temperature of 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) within 4</textblock>
    <textblock>hours of either placing it in the finished product container or</textblock>
    <textblock>completing pasteurization. Again, the recommendation is based on</textblock>
    <textblock>the minimum growth temperature of such psychrotropic pathogens as</textblock>
    <textblock>L. monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>and on the normal lag phase of such mesophilic</textblock>
    <textblock>pathogens as</textblock>
    <textblock>Salmonella spp</textblock>
    <textblock>. Of specific concern to the</textblock>
    <textblock>pasteurization process is the reduction of the internal</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature of the product to a level that will not support the</textblock>
    <textblock>growth of any surviving spores of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>, type E.</textblock>
    <textblock>The ability of the firm's processing procedures to</textblock>
    <textblock>consistently achieve its time/temperature parameters can be</textblock>
    <textblock>confirmed by a program of routine time and temperature monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>designed to address the particulars of the firm's processing</textblock>
    <textblock>system. Real time documentation of this monitoring should be</textblock>
    <textblock>done to facilitate management and regulatory review.</textblock>
    <textblock>Alternately, the firm's ability to consistently meet its</textblock>
    <textblock>parameters can be confirmed through scientifically conducted</textblock>
    <textblock>time/temperature studies that take into consideration the range</textblock>
    <textblock>of processing variations encountered at the firm. Examples of</textblock>
    <textblock>these processing variations include container size, the</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature of the cooling medium, and the amount of product</textblock>
    <textblock>normally placed in the cooling unit. In many instances, in-process time/temperature monitoring may be impractical and</textblock>
    <textblock>expensive for sealed finished product containers. A</textblock>
    <textblock>scientifically conducted study is especially appropriate in such</textblock>
    <textblock>situations, where it can be assured that in all plausible</textblock>
    <textblock>situations the time/temperature constraints will be met.</textblock>
    <textblock>Documentation of the conduct and results of the study is required</textblock>
    <textblock>under proposed §123.8 to facilitate management and regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>review.</textblock>
    <textblock>Temperature control during refrigerated storage is best</textblock>
    <textblock>achieved through the use of temperature indicating and recording</textblock>
    <textblock>devices and recordkeeping, as stated in Appendix A, section</textblock>
    <textblock>6.d.2. (Ref. 85). However, FDA recognizes that some processors</textblock>
    <textblock>may desire to manually monitor the temperature of the</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigeration unit, using only a temperature-indicating device</textblock>
    <textblock>and a logbook. When coupled with a high temperature alarm or a</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum-indicating thermometer, the agency feels that this</textblock>
    <textblock>practice represents an acceptable alternative.</textblock>
    <textblock>The guideline advises, in Appendix A, section 3.i., that</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP plans prepared in accordance with subpart A of part 123</textblock>
    <textblock>will normally identify distribution as a critical control point.</textblock>
    <textblock>Distribution of perishable products encompasses the same hazards</textblock>
    <textblock>as associated with refrigerated storage. For this reason, in</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix A, section 6.e., the agency is recommending a critical</textblock>
    <textblock>limit of an internal temperature maximum of 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) and is</textblock>
    <textblock>encouraging the shipper and consignee to arrange for appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>control measures.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency recognizes that distribution patterns vary</textblock>
    <textblock>considerably from single shipments to pooled and multiple</textblock>
    <textblock>delivery shipments, from iced shipments to refrigerated</textblock>
    <textblock>shipments, and from shipments on the consignee's truck to</textblock>
    <textblock>shipments on the shipper's truck to common carrier shipments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each mode presents different opportunities and impediments for</textblock>
    <textblock>control.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Temperature Monitoring Equipment</textblock>
    <textblock>Processors must monitor and control the temperature of their</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigeration units in order to ensure that microorganisms of</textblock>
    <textblock>public health concern do not increase in numbers. Likewise,</textblock>
    <textblock>processors must control the times and temperatures of their</textblock>
    <textblock>thermal processes in order to ensure that the minimum thermal</textblock>
    <textblock>process is consistently delivered to the product. The guidelines</textblock>
    <textblock>address the outfitting of cooking, pasteurization, and</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigeration equipment with temperature indicating and recording</textblock>
    <textblock>devices (Appendix A, sections 4. a.2.ii. and b.2.ii., and section</textblock>
    <textblock>6.d.2., respectively). A temperature-recording device provides a</textblock>
    <textblock>complete history of the temperature throughout the thermal</textblock>
    <textblock>process by continuously recording it on a chart. As has been</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrated for low acid canned foods, the chart itself provides</textblock>
    <textblock>an excellent HACCP record for the benefit of both processor and</textblock>
    <textblock>regulator. For this record to be meaningful, it is critical that</textblock>
    <textblock>the temperature-recording device sensor be installed so as to</textblock>
    <textblock>accurately represent the temperature of the heating or cooling</textblock>
    <textblock>medium.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
