<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00008</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Radio Broadcasting Services; Ocean Isle Beach, NC</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL COMMUNICATIONS COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>47 CFR Part 73</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[MM Docket No. 93-321, RM-8409]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission comments on a petition filed by Ocean Isle Broadcasting Company seeking the allotment of Channel 228A to Ocean Isle Beach, North Carolina, as its first local aural transmission service. Channel 228A can be allotted to Ocean Isle Beach in compliance with the Commission's minimum distance separation requirements with a site restriction of 4.3 kilometers (2.7 miles) west, at coordinates North Latitude 33-53-40 and West Longitude 78-28-26, to avoid a short spacing to vacant but applied-for Channel 229A at Wrightsville Beach, North Carolina.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be filed on or before March 17, 1994, and reply comments on or before April 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission, Washington, DC 20554. In addition to filing comments with the FCC, interested parties should serve the petitioner, or its counsel or consultant, as follows: Gary S. Smithwick, Esq., Shaun A. Maher, Esq., Smithwick &amp; Belendiuk, P.C., 1990 M Street NW., suite 510, Washington, DC 20036 (Counsel to petitioner).</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Leslie K. Shapiro, Mass Media Bureau, (202) 634-6530.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a synopsis of the Commission's Notice of Proposed Rule Making, MM Docket No. 93-321, adopted December 21, 1993, and released January 25, 1994. The full text of this Commission decision is available for inspection and copying during normal business hours in the FCC Reference Center (room 239), 1919 M Street NW., Washington, DC. The complete text of this decision may also be purchased from the Commission's copy contractor, International Transcription Services, Inc., (202) 857-3800, 2100 M Street NW., suite 140, Washington, DC 20037.</textblock>
    <textblock>Provisions of the Regulatory Flexibility Act of 1980 do not apply to this proceeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>Members of the public should note that from the time a Notice of Proposed Rule Making is issued until the matter is no longer subject to Commission consideration or court review, all</textblock>
    <textblock>ex parte</textblock>
    <textblock>contacts are prohibited in Commission proceedings, such as this one, which involve channel allotments. See 47 CFR 1.1204(b) for rules governing permissible</textblock>
    <textblock>ex parte</textblock>
    <textblock>contacts.</textblock>
    <textblock>For information regarding proper filing procedures for comments, see 47 CFR 1.415 and 1.420.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 47 CFR Part 73</textblock>
    <textblock>Radio broadcasting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John A. Karousos,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Chief, Allocations Branch, Policy and Rules Division, Mass Media Bureau.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1873 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
