<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00076</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>FDA also invites comment on the effect of using a modified</textblock>
    <textblock>approach on the regulation of imports, especially with regard to</textblock>
    <textblock>the types of products described in item (5) above.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Exempting Small Firms</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA invites comment on whether small firms should be exempt</textblock>
    <textblock>from the proposed regulation. Even if exempted, these firms</textblock>
    <textblock>would still be subject to the requirements of current food safety</textblock>
    <textblock>law and to inspection by FDA and State authorities.</textblock>
    <textblock>As stated earlier in this preamble, small operations are the</textblock>
    <textblock>norm in the seafood industry. A significant majority of</textblock>
    <textblock>processors have total revenues of under 1 million dollars. If</textblock>
    <textblock>small firms are to be exempted, FDA invites comment on the</textblock>
    <textblock>criteria that should be used for exempting them, including how a</textblock>
    <textblock>small firm should be defined for purposes of an exemption.</textblock>
    <textblock>The implementation of HACCP may be more burdensome for small</textblock>
    <textblock>firms than for large firms. Large firms tend to have quality</textblock>
    <textblock>control personnel already in place. In addition, many regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements are less burdensome for a large firm in proportion</textblock>
    <textblock>to output than they are for a small firm. On the other hand, FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>is taking steps, such as the preparation of its HACCP guidance,</textblock>
    <textblock>to minimize the cost of these regulations for small businesses.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thus, such an exemption may not be needed.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency also points out that, because many large firms</textblock>
    <textblock>already have quality control systems, an exemption for small</textblock>
    <textblock>business would appear to result in requiring HACCP for that</textblock>
    <textblock>segment of the industry (i.e., large firms) that needs it the</textblock>
    <textblock>least. Large processors, moreover, tend to process relatively</textblock>
    <textblock>low risk products, such as breaded fish and shrimp and raw fish</textblock>
    <textblock>blocks. Many high-risk processors, such as processors of</textblock>
    <textblock>cooked, ready-to-eat products, tend to be small, and processors</textblock>
    <textblock>of raw molluscan shellfish tend to be very small.</textblock>
    <textblock>Nonetheless, an exemption for small business could be</textblock>
    <textblock>limited to those small businesses that produce low risk products,</textblock>
    <textblock>and FDA invites comment on this approach. As stated earlier,</textblock>
    <textblock>however, the criteria for determining low as well as high risk</textblock>
    <textblock>are not clear, due largely to the limitations of the U.S.</textblock>
    <textblock>foodborne illness reporting system. Moreover, a case can be made</textblock>
    <textblock>that risk also relates to the margin for error in a processing</textblock>
    <textblock>operation and to the consequences of failure as well as to the</textblock>
    <textblock>actual occurrence of illness.</textblock>
    <textblock>With these points in mind, FDA invites comment on how to</textblock>
    <textblock>define ``low risk.'' FDA also invites comment on what the nature</textblock>
    <textblock>of the exemption should be. Should a firm be exempt from all or</textblock>
    <textblock>part of the HACCP requirements? As circumstances change, a</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP-based analysis of risk by a firm might reveal that the firm</textblock>
    <textblock>has become a high risk processor rather than a low risk</textblock>
    <textblock>processor. In addition, FDA invites comment on whether such an</textblock>
    <textblock>exemption should be obtained by petitioning the agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>Finally, even if an exemption were to be adopted in the</textblock>
    <textblock>final rule based on the comments received, the agency would still</textblock>
    <textblock>encourage voluntary adoption of HACCP systems by exempted firms.</textblock>
    <textblock>The advantages that HACCP is expected to provide in terms of</textblock>
    <textblock>consumer confidence, control of process, and access to</textblock>
    <textblock>international markets warrant adoption of this system.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
