<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00025</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>VII. The Proposed Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>These proposed regulations consist of a subpart of general</textblock>
    <textblock>applicability (subpart A) and one subpart that sets forth</textblock>
    <textblock>specific additional provisions for raw molluscan shellfish</textblock>
    <textblock>(subpart C). The agency is also setting forth guidelines, in the</textblock>
    <textblock>form of appendices, that will provide assistance to processors of</textblock>
    <textblock>cooked, ready-to-eat products (Appendix A), and to processors of</textblock>
    <textblock>scombrotoxin forming species (Appendix B), on how to meet various</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements in subpart A relating to the development and</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation of HACCP plans. The products addressed in the</textblock>
    <textblock>guidelines involve special considerations or special hazards for</textblock>
    <textblock>which additional guidance would be useful. Processors and</textblock>
    <textblock>importers that follow these guidelines will increase the</textblock>
    <textblock>likelihood that FDA will find their preventive controls</textblock>
    <textblock>acceptable. FDA requests comments on the need for, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>substance of, the guidelines that it has set forth. Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>should address whether it would be more appropriate for FDA to</textblock>
    <textblock>adopt the guidelines as regulations. If the comments provide a</textblock>
    <textblock>convincing basis for doing so, FDA will include some or all of</textblock>
    <textblock>the guidelines in the regulations in any final rule that results</textblock>
    <textblock>from this rulemaking.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is also including a guideline on how to ensure product</textblock>
    <textblock>integrity relating to economic adulteration (Appendix D). FDA is</textblock>
    <textblock>including this guideline because economic adulteration is a</textblock>
    <textblock>particular problem in the seafood industry.</textblock>
    <textblock>In Appendix 1 to this document, FDA is also providing</textblock>
    <textblock>samples from a package of general guidance, to be published</textblock>
    <textblock>separately, for processors to use in understanding and</textblock>
    <textblock>implementing HACCP principles in their operations. One of these</textblock>
    <textblock>samples is specific guidance on the processing of smoked and</textblock>
    <textblock>smoke-flavored fish. FDA requests comments on whether the latter</textblock>
    <textblock>guidance should remain as such, be provided as guidelines in an</textblock>
    <textblock>appendix to the regulations, or be made mandatory by</textblock>
    <textblock>incorporating them into any final rule that results from this</textblock>
    <textblock>proceeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Definitions</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is relying generally on the definitions contained</textblock>
    <textblock>in the act, in the umbrella good manufacturing practice</textblock>
    <textblock>guidelines in part 110, and in other agency regulations. The</textblock>
    <textblock>agency is using these definitions because it considers</textblock>
    <textblock>consistency in how it uses terms in its regulations to be</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary and appropriate. Thus, §123.3(o) is derived from</textblock>
    <textblock>§113.3(s), and §123.3(r) is derived from §110.3(q).</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional definitions are proposed in §123.3 that are specific</textblock>
    <textblock>to the proposed HACCP program for fish and fishery products.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
