<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00130</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Example 5</textblock>
    <textblock>Process-Related Hazard and Control No. 11</textblock>
    <textblock>Hazard No. 11 (Safety)_Pathogen Survival During Pasteurization</textblock>
    <textblock>Hazard Statement</textblock>
    <textblock>Survival of</textblock>
    <textblock>Clostridium botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>type E) or</textblock>
    <textblock>other microorganisms of public health concern, through the</textblock>
    <textblock>pasteurization process is a food safety hazard for cooked, ready-to-eat products packed in hermetically sealed containers and held</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigerated. Pasteurization is a process applied to a fish or</textblock>
    <textblock>fishery product after that fish or fishery product has been</textblock>
    <textblock>placed in a final, hermetically sealed package. The process</textblock>
    <textblock>involves the application of sufficient heat (or other processes)</textblock>
    <textblock>for a sufficient time to cause the reduction of microorganisms of</textblock>
    <textblock>public health concern to levels that, under normal conditions of</textblock>
    <textblock>storage, are unlikely to cause disease.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>type E is</textblock>
    <textblock>a pathogenic microorganism that may be found in fish and fishery</textblock>
    <textblock>products.</textblock>
    <textblock>Botulism is a severe type of food poisoning caused by the</textblock>
    <textblock>ingestion of foods containing the potent neurotoxin formed during</textblock>
    <textblock>the growth of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum. C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>type E can grow and</textblock>
    <textblock>produce toxin at temperatures as low as 3.3</textblock>
    <textblock>○C (38</textblock>
    <textblock>○F), and must,</textblock>
    <textblock>therefore, be eliminated from the hermetically sealed container</textblock>
    <textblock>during the pasteurization process. Pasteurized products that are</textblock>
    <textblock>stored, distributed, and displayed in the frozen state, and are</textblock>
    <textblock>so labeled, are not similarly at risk, and need not be subjected</textblock>
    <textblock>to the constraints of these control measures.</textblock>
    <textblock>For there to be assurance that the pasteurization step</textblock>
    <textblock>effectively eliminates the microorganisms of public health</textblock>
    <textblock>significance (e.g.,</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>type E), a minimum acceptable</textblock>
    <textblock>process should be scientifically established. This requires</textblock>
    <textblock>expert knowledge of thermal process calculations. Procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>used in establishing the minimum thermal process should be those</textblock>
    <textblock>that are generally recognized and accepted. Sometimes, thermal</textblock>
    <textblock>death time, heat penetration, and inoculated pack studies will be</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to establish the minimum process. In other instances,</textblock>
    <textblock>existing literature is sufficient to provide the processor with a</textblock>
    <textblock>minimum process.</textblock>
    <textblock>In either case, characteristics of the process and/or the</textblock>
    <textblock>product will necessarily affect the ability of the cook step to</textblock>
    <textblock>effectively eliminate the microorganisms of public health</textblock>
    <textblock>significance. Such factors should be considered in the</textblock>
    <textblock>establishment of the process. Where control of those factors is</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to consistently achieve that goal, the process</textblock>
    <textblock>authority should specify these to the processor.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is necessary that the pasteurizing equipment be designed</textblock>
    <textblock>and operated so that every unit of product receives the</textblock>
    <textblock>established minimum process. This will require that a competent</textblock>
    <textblock>process authority, who is thoroughly familiar with the dynamics</textblock>
    <textblock>of heat transfer in processing equipment, evaluate the design and</textblock>
    <textblock>operation of the type of equipment used by the processor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sometimes temperature distribution studies will be necessary to</textblock>
    <textblock>establish the adequacy of the equipment. In other instances</textblock>
    <textblock>existing literature will be sufficient to establish the adequacy</textblock>
    <textblock>of the equipment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Critical Control Point: Pasteurization Control Measures</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Make sure that the pasteurization process that is being</textblock>
    <textblock>used was designed to ensure an appropriate reduction in the</textblock>
    <textblock>numbers of viable microorganisms of public health concern. The</textblock>
    <textblock>adequacy of the pasteurization process should be established by a</textblock>
    <textblock>process authority. The pasteurization process that is being used</textblock>
    <textblock>should meet any factors of the process or of the product that are</textblock>
    <textblock>identified by the process authority as critical to achieving</textblock>
    <textblock>pathogen destruction. At a minimum, these critical factors</textblock>
    <textblock>should include pasteurizing times and temperatures.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Make sure that the pasteurization equipment being used</textblock>
    <textblock>is properly designed and operated to deliver the process</textblock>
    <textblock>established by the process authority. The engineering</textblock>
    <textblock>specifications of the equipment being used (e.g., pipe sizes,</textblock>
    <textblock>flow rates, loading pattern) should meet or exceed that of the</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment evaluated by a process authority.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Deliver the pasteurization process in a way that there</textblock>
    <textblock>is no deviation from the minimum established pasteurization</textblock>
    <textblock>critical factors.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Monitor the pasteurization temperature with a</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature recording device (i.e., temperature recorder). The</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature recorder should be installed where it can be easily</textblock>
    <textblock>read and the sensor for the device should be installed to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>that it accurately measures the coldest temperature of the</textblock>
    <textblock>pasteurizing equipment. The temperature recorder must show a</textblock>
    <textblock>continuous record of the process. Computerized storage of</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature data may be used for a temperature recorder chart if</textblock>
    <textblock>the use of such a system has been validated and can be shown to</textblock>
    <textblock>be equivalent to the use of a temperature recorder.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Check the accuracy of each temperature recorder at the</textblock>
    <textblock>beginning and end of each production day and adjust it as</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to agree as nearly as possible with a temperature</textblock>
    <textblock>indicating device (mercury-in-glass thermometer or equivalent</textblock>
    <textblock>device). The thermometer should be installed where it can be</textblock>
    <textblock>easily read and placed to ensure that it accurately measures the</textblock>
    <textblock>coldest temperature of the pasteurizing equipment.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Calibrate the thermometer at the pasteurizing</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature against an accurate standard thermometer. This</textblock>
    <textblock>should be done when the thermometer is installed and at least</textblock>
    <textblock>once a year after that, or more frequently, if necessary, to</textblock>
    <textblock>ensure its accuracy.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Monitor the length of the pasteurization cycle.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Monitor other critical factors (e.g., initial</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature, container size, product formulation) at the start of</textblock>
    <textblock>each shift or when the product changes during a shift.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
