<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00124</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Example 3</textblock>
    <textblock>Species-Related Hazards and Controls No. 1</textblock>
    <textblock>Hazard No. 1 (Safety)_Chemical Contamination Other Than Methyl</textblock>
    <textblock>Mercury</textblock>
    <textblock>Contamination of Raw Material at Receipt with Pesticides,</textblock>
    <textblock>Radioactivity, Toxic Elements, and Industrial Chemicals, Derived</textblock>
    <textblock>From the Harvest Area.</textblock>
    <textblock>Hazard Statement</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and molluscan shellfish may be harvested from waters</textblock>
    <textblock>that are exposed to varying amounts of environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>contaminants. Industrial chemicals, pesticides, and many toxic</textblock>
    <textblock>elements may accumulate in fish at levels that can cause public</textblock>
    <textblock>health problems. Concern for these contaminants primarily</textblock>
    <textblock>focuses on fish and shellfish harvested from fresh water,</textblock>
    <textblock>estuaries, and near-coastal waters rather than from the open</textblock>
    <textblock>ocean. Pesticides and herbicides used near aquaculture</textblock>
    <textblock>operations or for other purposes may contaminate fish and fishery</textblock>
    <textblock>products.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal tolerances or action levels are established for some</textblock>
    <textblock>of the most toxic and persistent contaminants that are found in</textblock>
    <textblock>fish and fishery products shipped in interstate commerce. (These</textblock>
    <textblock>contaminants and their corresponding limits are listed below.)</textblock>
    <textblock>When products exceed these limits, FDA can seize the contaminated</textblock>
    <textblock>fish and fishery products.</textblock>
    <textblock>States often use the limits for deciding whether to issue</textblock>
    <textblock>consumption advisories or to close or classify waters for</textblock>
    <textblock>harvesting. Molluscan shellfish waters are controlled by the</textblock>
    <textblock>State Shellfish Control Agency (SSCA) or the equivalent in</textblock>
    <textblock>foreign countries that have Memoranda of Understanding with the</textblock>
    <textblock>United States that permit them to export molluscan shellfish to</textblock>
    <textblock>this country. If local or regional contaminants are not covered</textblock>
    <textblock>by federal limits, contact local health departments to decide if</textblock>
    <textblock>contaminant levels in fish and fishery products are of public</textblock>
    <textblock>health concern.</textblock>
    <textblock>The control measures provided in this section are</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate for the control of methyl mercury contamination in</textblock>
    <textblock>fish, where such contamination is the result of industrial</textblock>
    <textblock>contamination in a harvest area. Recommended controls for the</textblock>
    <textblock>problem of open ocean species, such as swordfish and shark,</textblock>
    <textblock>concentrating methyl mercury from their diet and its diffuse</textblock>
    <textblock>presence in the environment are provided in the ``Mercury'' hazard</textblock>
    <textblock>section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Critical Control Point: Receiving</textblock>
    <textblock>There are five options for control at this critical control</textblock>
    <textblock>point.</textblock>
    <textblock>Option 1</textblock>
    <textblock>Where the firm receives wild caught fish, other than</textblock>
    <textblock>molluscan shellfish, directly from the fisher or from a supplier</textblock>
    <textblock>that has credible knowledge of the harvest area location (e.g., a</textblock>
    <textblock>tender or related company that pools fish from various fishers),</textblock>
    <textblock>the following applies:</textblock>
    <textblock>Control Measures</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Find out the harvest area location for each lot or batch</textblock>
    <textblock>from the fisher upon receipt.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Find out whether the harvest area is closed to fishing</textblock>
    <textblock>by foreign, Federal, State or local health authorities due to</textblock>
    <textblock>known instances of chemical contamination.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Reject fish that have been caught in a closed area.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example</textblock>
    <textblock>ABC Fish Co. has contacted the State Department of</textblock>
    <textblock>Health and learned that the Long River is closed to</textblock>
    <textblock>commercial harvest above Lookout Point, including its</textblock>
    <textblock>tributaries, due to the presence of chlordecone</textblock>
    <textblock>(Kepone</textblock>
    <textblock>TM</textblock>
    <textblock>). The species affected are croaker,</textblock>
    <textblock>bluefish, and striped bass. ABC Fish Co., which</textblock>
    <textblock>processes these species, will reject any of the listed</textblock>
    <textblock>species originating from the area.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
