<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00102</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(2) There are no cross connections between the potable</textblock>
    <textblock>water system and any nonpotable system.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) All food contact surfaces of plant equipment and</textblock>
    <textblock>utensils, including equipment used for ice production and</textblock>
    <textblock>storage, are so designed and of such material and workmanship as</textblock>
    <textblock>to be easily cleanable, and are maintained in a sanitary</textblock>
    <textblock>condition. Such surfaces shall be constructed of nontoxic</textblock>
    <textblock>materials and designed to withstand the environment of its</textblock>
    <textblock>intended use and the action of the food, cleaning compounds, and</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitizing agents.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) All utensils and surfaces of equipment that contact</textblock>
    <textblock>food during processing are cleaned and sanitized with effective</textblock>
    <textblock>cleaning and sanitizing preparations with the following</textblock>
    <textblock>frequency:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Cleaned at the end of the day's operations;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Cleaned and sanitized at least every 4 hours during</textblock>
    <textblock>the processing of cooked, ready-to-eat fishery products; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Sanitized before the beginning of the day's</textblock>
    <textblock>operations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Gloves and outer garments that contact food or food</textblock>
    <textblock>contact surfaces are made of an impermeable material and are</textblock>
    <textblock>maintained in a clean and sanitary condition.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Employees' hands, gloves, outer garments, utensils and</textblock>
    <textblock>food contact surfaces of equipment that come into contact with</textblock>
    <textblock>waste, the floor, or other insanitary objects, do not contact</textblock>
    <textblock>fish or fishery products without first being adequately cleaned</textblock>
    <textblock>and sanitized.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Where applicable, employee's hands, gloves, outer</textblock>
    <textblock>garments, utensils and food contact surfaces of equipment that</textblock>
    <textblock>come into contact with raw product shall not contact cooked</textblock>
    <textblock>product or ice used on cooked product, without first being</textblock>
    <textblock>adequately cleaned and sanitized.</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) Hand washing and hand sanitizing facilities are:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Located in all processing areas in which good sanitary</textblock>
    <textblock>practice requires employees to wash and sanitize their hands; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Equipped with hand-cleaning and effective sanitizing</textblock>
    <textblock>preparations and single service towels or suitable hand drying</textblock>
    <textblock>devices.</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) Food, food contact surfaces, and food-packaging</textblock>
    <textblock>materials shall be protected from adulteration with lubricants,</textblock>
    <textblock>fuel, pesticides, cleaning compounds, sanitizing agents, metal</textblock>
    <textblock>fragments, or other chemical or physical contaminants.</textblock>
    <textblock>(10) Toxic compounds shall be identified, held, used, and</textblock>
    <textblock>stored in a manner that protects against contamination of food,</textblock>
    <textblock>food-contact surfaces, or food-packaging materials.</textblock>
    <textblock>(11) Food, food-contact surfaces, and food-packaging</textblock>
    <textblock>materials shall be protected from contaminants that may drip,</textblock>
    <textblock>drain, or be drawn into the food.</textblock>
    <textblock>(12) Compressed gases that contact food or food contact</textblock>
    <textblock>surfaces of equipment shall be filtered or treated in a way that</textblock>
    <textblock>ensures that they will not contaminate the food with unapproved</textblock>
    <textblock>indirect food additives or other chemical, physical, or</textblock>
    <textblock>microbiological contaminants.</textblock>
    <textblock>(13) Unprotected cooked, ready-to-eat fishery products,</textblock>
    <textblock>smoked fishery products, raw molluscan shellfish, and raw fish</textblock>
    <textblock>and fishery products shall be physically separated from each</textblock>
    <textblock>other during refrigerated storage.</textblock>
    <textblock>(14) Refrigeration units that store raw materials, in-</textblock>
    <textblock>process, or finished fish or fishery products that are cooked,</textblock>
    <textblock>ready-to-eat, smoked, or made in whole or in part from scombroid</textblock>
    <textblock>toxin forming species shall be operated at a temperature of 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F</textblock>
    <textblock>(4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below.</textblock>
    <textblock>(15) Any person who, by medical examination or supervisory</textblock>
    <textblock>observation, is shown to have, or appears to have, an illness,</textblock>
    <textblock>open lesion, including boils, sores, or infected wounds, or any</textblock>
    <textblock>other source of microbial contamination by which there is a</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonable possibility that food, food-contact surfaces, or food-</textblock>
    <textblock>packaging materials will become contaminated, shall be excluded</textblock>
    <textblock>from any operations that may be expected to result in such</textblock>
    <textblock>contamination until the condition is corrected.</textblock>
    <textblock>(16) Adequate, readily accessible toilet facilities that</textblock>
    <textblock>provide for proper sewage disposal shall be available and</textblock>
    <textblock>maintained in a sanitary condition and in good repair.</textblock>
    <textblock>(17) No pests are in any area of a food plant.</textblock>
    <textblock>(18) The plant is designed to minimize the risk of</textblock>
    <textblock>contamination of the food, food-contact surfaces, and food-</textblock>
    <textblock>packaging material.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
