<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00044</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require in §123.10(a)(4)(ii) that, in</textblock>
    <textblock>those operations in which microbiological contamination can</textblock>
    <textblock>adversely affect the safety of the product (e.g., the processing</textblock>
    <textblock>of cooked, ready-to-eat products), the equipment also be washed</textblock>
    <textblock>and sanitized at least every 4 hours during processing. Washing</textblock>
    <textblock>and sanitizing with this frequency is necessary to inactivate</textblock>
    <textblock>mesophilic pathogens, such as</textblock>
    <textblock>Salmonella spp.</textblock>
    <textblock>, before they leave</textblock>
    <textblock>the lag phase of growth and enter the rapid log phase (Ref. 23).</textblock>
    <textblock>Temperatures in fish and fishery product processing plants are</textblock>
    <textblock>generally not low enough to control the growth of such</textblock>
    <textblock>microorganisms and are certainly not low enough to control the</textblock>
    <textblock>growth of such psychrotropic pathogens as</textblock>
    <textblock>L. monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>(Refs.</textblock>
    <textblock>23, 78, 79, and 80). Therefore, FDA tentatively finds that</textblock>
    <textblock>washing and sanitizing equipment every 4 hours is necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require both cleaning and sanitizing</textblock>
    <textblock>because neither step is fully effective without the other. When</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitizing occurs without benefit of cleaning, pathogenic</textblock>
    <textblock>microorganisms can be protected from the action of the sanitizer</textblock>
    <textblock>by food residue. Conversely, while cleaning can effectively</textblock>
    <textblock>remove product residue and a portion of the microorganisms,</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitizing is generally needed to remove the remaining</textblock>
    <textblock>microorganisms (Refs. 81 and 82).</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require in §123.10(c)(2) that the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor inspect the condition of the utensils and surfaces of</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment that contact food immediately after each cleaning and</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitizing. The purpose of the inspection is to ensure the</textblock>
    <textblock>adequacy of the cleaning and sanitizing operations, and to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>that the equipment is in a condition that is suitable for further</textblock>
    <textblock>operations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is also proposing in §123.10(c)(2) that the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor document the time of each cleaning and sanitizing, the</textblock>
    <textblock>concentration of the sanitizer, and the condition of the</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment. Documentation of the time of each cleaning and</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitizing will facilitate an assessment of compliance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>frequency requirement of §123.10(a)(4). Documentation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>concentration of the sanitizer will facilitate an assessment of</textblock>
    <textblock>the adequacy of the sanitizing operation. Sanitizers must be of</textblock>
    <textblock>sufficient strength to be effective, while excessive sanitizer</textblock>
    <textblock>concentrations can contaminate the product with indirect food</textblock>
    <textblock>additives (21 CFR part 178) (Ref. 82). Documentation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>condition of the equipment is necessary to ensure that it is</textblock>
    <textblock>examined after cleaning and sanitizing to make sure that these</textblock>
    <textblock>processes were done properly.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is proposing in §123.10(a)(5) to require that</textblock>
    <textblock>the processor ensure that gloves and outer garments that contact</textblock>
    <textblock>the food or food-contact surfaces are made of an impermeable</textblock>
    <textblock>material and are maintained in a clean and sanitary condition.</textblock>
    <textblock>Gloves or aprons that are made of cloth or other porous materials</textblock>
    <textblock>are difficult to clean and may serve as a reservoir for</textblock>
    <textblock>pathogenic microorganisms that can migrate to the food during</textblock>
    <textblock>processing, in much the same manner as previously described for</textblock>
    <textblock>processing equipment (Refs. 65 and 83). Gloves and aprons that</textblock>
    <textblock>are not maintained in a clean and sanitary condition can also</textblock>
    <textblock>house pathogens that can migrate to the food. Therefore, FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>tentatively finds that it is appropriate to require the measures</textblock>
    <textblock>set out in §123.10(a)(5).</textblock>
    <textblock>At §123.10(c), the agency is proposing to require that,</textblock>
    <textblock>like most of the other sanitation measures that FDA is proposing,</textblock>
    <textblock>the sanitary condition and impermeability of gloves and outer</textblock>
    <textblock>garments that may contact the food or food-contact surfaces be</textblock>
    <textblock>checked at least daily while processing operations are occurring.</textblock>
    <textblock>Such checking will ensure that employees arriving for work are</textblock>
    <textblock>equipped with gloves and outer garments that will not serve as a</textblock>
    <textblock>source of contamination to the product. It will also ensure that</textblock>
    <textblock>employees are never using personally owned gloves and garments</textblock>
    <textblock>that are made of materials that are unsuitable for the processing</textblock>
    <textblock>environment. Proposed §123.10(c) also requires that such</textblock>
    <textblock>checking be documented on a daily basis to provide a record that</textblock>
    <textblock>such checking has occurred.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under proposed §123.10(a)(6), the processor must ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>that employees' hands, gloves, outer garments, utensils, and</textblock>
    <textblock>food-contact surfaces that come into contact with insanitary</textblock>
    <textblock>objects are thoroughly cleaned and sanitized before contacting</textblock>
    <textblock>fish or fishery products. Under proposed §123.10(a)(7), the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor must also ensure that employees' hands, gloves, outer</textblock>
    <textblock>garments, utensils, and food-contact surfaces that contact raw</textblock>
    <textblock>products are thoroughly cleaned and sanitized before they contact</textblock>
    <textblock>cooked product.</textblock>
    <textblock>Employees and food-contact surfaces can serve as vectors in</textblock>
    <textblock>the transmission of filth and pathogenic microorganisms to the</textblock>
    <textblock>food. Filth and pathogenic microorganisms can be brought into</textblock>
    <textblock>the processing environment on the employees' hands from outside</textblock>
    <textblock>areas, restrooms, contaminated raw materials, waste or waste</textblock>
    <textblock>receptacles, floors, and other insanitary objects (Refs. 63, 64,</textblock>
    <textblock>73, 74, 84, and 85).</textblock>
    <textblock>Bacteria naturally present on fresh fish skin and gills and</textblock>
    <textblock>in the gastrointestinal tract reflect the microbial content of</textblock>
    <textblock>the water from which the fish were harvested. Typical</textblock>
    <textblock>microorganisms found on and in fresh fish include</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>,</textblock>
    <textblock>enteric bacteria,</textblock>
    <textblock>Vibrio parahaemolyticus</textblock>
    <textblock>, salmonella, shigella,</textblock>
    <textblock>hepatitis A, and other microorganisms that pollute harvest waters</textblock>
    <textblock>(Ref. 7). These microorganisms contaminate the environment in</textblock>
    <textblock>processing plants and cannot, using reasonable methods, be</textblock>
    <textblock>completely eliminated.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proper precautions, such as proper hand and equipment</textblock>
    <textblock>cleaning and sanitizing, must be taken to minimize opportunities</textblock>
    <textblock>for contamination of the finished product (Refs. 63, 64, 73, 74,</textblock>
    <textblock>and 84). Therefore, FDA is proposing in §123.10 (a)(6) and</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)(7) that such precautions be taken with respect to hands,</textblock>
    <textblock>gloves, garments, utensils, and food-contact surfaces.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
