<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00166</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00107</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>This is the second in a series of notices which, together with public meetings, provide the public with an opportunity to participate in the development of the United States negotiating positions for the ninth regular meeting of the Conference of the Parties to CITES (COP9). The first</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice was published on November 18, 1993 (58 FR 60873) which detailed possible changes in the criteria for listing species on the CITES appendices and requested comments from the public on aspects of these changes which should be considered by the U.S. The Service's regulations governing this public process are found in Title 50 of the Code of Federal Regulations §§23.31-23.39.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of the Ninth Regular Meeting of the Conference of the Parties</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service hereby notifies the public of the convening of the ninth meeting of the Conference of the Parties (COP9) to be held in Fort Lauderdale, Florida, U.S.A. from November 7-18, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Provisional Agenda for COP9</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service will participate in the 31st meeting of the CITES Standing Committee, and by this notice calls for a public meeting to discuss the agenda for this meeting and items of concern for COP9. A copy of the agenda for the Standing Committee meeting, scheduled for March 21-25, 1994, is available from the Office of Management Authority (see</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>, above). While it has not yet received formal notice of the provisional agenda for COP9, the Service expects the issues noted below to be on the agenda, which will likely follow the sample format outlined below. A brief discussion follows of those agenda items that may not be self-evident to the public:</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Opening ceremony by the Authorities of the United States</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Welcoming addresses</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Adoption of the Rules of Procedure</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Election of Chair and Vice-Chair of the meeting and of Chair of Committees I and II</textblock>
    <textblock>V. Adoption of the Agenda and Working Programme</textblock>
    <textblock>VI. Establishment of the Credentials Committee and Committees I and II</textblock>
    <textblock>VII. Report of the Credentials Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>VIII. Admission of observers</textblock>
    <textblock>IX. Matters related to the Standing Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Report by the Chair</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Election of new members and alternate regional members: The Standing Committee is the governing body of CITES between meetings of the COP. It is composed of representatives of North America (currently Canada), South and Central America and the Caribbean (Trinidad and Tobago), Asia (Thailand), Oceania (New Zealand), Africa (Senegal) and Europe (Sweden), along with the Depositary Government (Switzerland), the host of the last COP (Japan), and the host of the next COP (the United States). The United States will attend the next Standing Committee in its capacity as host government for the next CITES COP.</textblock>
    <textblock>X. Report of the Secretariat</textblock>
    <textblock>XI. Financing and budgeting of the Secretariat and of meetings of the Conference of the Parties</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Financial report for 1992-1993-1994</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Anticipated expenditures for 1995</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Budget for 1995-1997 and Medium Term Plan for 1995-2000</textblock>
    <textblock>4. External funding</textblock>
    <textblock>XII. Committee reports and recommendations</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Animals Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Plants Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Identification Manual Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Nomenclature Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>XIII. Interpretation and implementation of the Convention</textblock>
    <textblock>It is expected that resolutions will be submitted by one or more Parties dealing with many of these agenda items. Resolutions can only be submitted by Parties, and must be submitted to the Secretariat by June 10, 1994. With this notice, the United States begins the process of receiving input from the public on possible resolutions the United States may submit.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Report on national reports under Article VIII, paragraph 7, of the Convention:</textblock>
    <textblock>Each Party is required by the Convention to submit an annual report containing a summary of the permits it has granted, and the types and numbers of specimens of species in the CITES Appendices that it has imported and exported. The U.S. CITES Annual reports are available from the Office of Management Authority (see</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>, above).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Review of alleged infractions:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretariat prepares an Infractions Report for each meeting of the Conference of the Parties, which details instances that species listed in the Appendices are being adversely affected by trade or the Convention is not being effectively implemented, or actions by Party countries that undermine the effectiveness of the Convention. The COP8 Infractions Report highlighted those cases of the most serious infractions, in order to focus the attention of the Parties; the COP9 Infractions Report is expected to do the same. A future</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice will notify the public of the availability of the Infractions Report.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Exports of leopard hunting trophies and skins: This refers to the importation of leopard skins, including hunting trophies, under a quota system approved by the Conference of the Parties.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
