<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00020</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Meanwhile, processors and importers of scombrotoxin-forming</textblock>
    <textblock>species can exercise HACCP controls aimed at ensuring that their</textblock>
    <textblock>incoming raw materials or imported shipments have not been</textblock>
    <textblock>time/temperature abused. Because any HACCP plans for such</textblock>
    <textblock>processors or importers would be clearly inadequate if</textblock>
    <textblock>scombrotoxin were not identified as a hazard and appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>controls were not in place and systematically monitored,</textblock>
    <textblock>processors and importers should consider placing time/temperature</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements on vessel owners as a prerequisite to doing</textblock>
    <textblock>business.</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP can also be applied to control of hazards from</textblock>
    <textblock>chemical contaminants, even though the full range of possible</textblock>
    <textblock>chemical hazards is still imperfectly understood. Government and</textblock>
    <textblock>academia have important roles to play in researching the</textblock>
    <textblock>toxicities of these chemicals, in monitoring them, and in</textblock>
    <textblock>performing various forms of risk assessment. In some cases,</textblock>
    <textblock>these efforts may result in the establishment of national maximum</textblock>
    <textblock>limits. In other cases, regional advisories may be more</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate. The seafood industry has a responsibility to know</textblock>
    <textblock>whether chemical hazards are associated with the species they are</textblock>
    <textblock>handling, whether the occurrence of such hazards depends on</textblock>
    <textblock>harvest site or other factors, and whether a sampling and</textblock>
    <textblock>analysis program on their part would be appropriate. Processors</textblock>
    <textblock>and importers should monitor the origin of raw materials and</textblock>
    <textblock>imported shipments to ensure, for example, that harvest did not</textblock>
    <textblock>occur in locations subject to public health advisories.</textblock>
    <textblock>These are but a few examples of environmentally related</textblock>
    <textblock>hazards to which HACCP can be applied. HACCP controls can also</textblock>
    <textblock>ensure that hazards are not being created inside a processing</textblock>
    <textblock>facility through improper handling, cooking, or storing.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Regulatory Considerations</textblock>
    <textblock>From a regulatory standpoint, inspections of processing</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities and of importers' plans and records would become more</textblock>
    <textblock>efficient and would be likely to have a much greater impact if</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP controls were in place. A key feature of an inspection</textblock>
    <textblock>system tied to implementation of HACCP is access by Government</textblock>
    <textblock>investigators to the HACCP plan and to monitoring records kept</textblock>
    <textblock>under that plan. In contrast to the ``snapshot'' provided by</textblock>
    <textblock>current inspections, examination of HACCP records will enable an</textblock>
    <textblock>investigator to see how the processing facility or the importer</textblock>
    <textblock>operates over time. It will enable an investigator to determine</textblock>
    <textblock>whether problems have occurred, and how they were addressed. It</textblock>
    <textblock>will also enable an investigator to spot trends that could lead</textblock>
    <textblock>to problems, and thus to help prevent them from occurring.</textblock>
    <textblock>Additionally, it will enable the regulator to review the adequacy</textblock>
    <textblock>of the processor's or importer's preventive control system</textblock>
    <textblock>itself. Under such an inspection system, inadequate preventive</textblock>
    <textblock>controls would warrant remedial or regulatory action regardless</textblock>
    <textblock>of whether the processor's or importer's product is actually</textblock>
    <textblock>contaminated or unsafe.</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP is not a zero risk system, however. Problems in food</textblock>
    <textblock>production and processing will still occur. HACCP systems are</textblock>
    <textblock>designed to detect and document those problems, so that they can</textblock>
    <textblock>be corrected as quickly as possible. Thus, regulatory action</textblock>
    <textblock>would not be warranted on the basis of the mere occurrence of</textblock>
    <textblock>processing problems. It would be warranted, though, if the HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>system is not functioning properly to detect and correct the</textblock>
    <textblock>problems, or if adulterated food is allowed to enter into</textblock>
    <textblock>commerce.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
