<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00038</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing in §123.8(e) to exempt tags as defined in</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.3(t) from the recordkeeping requirements of §123.8. While</textblock>
    <textblock>the information on tags must be saved in accordance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed requirements of this section and §123.28(d), the agency</textblock>
    <textblock>has tentatively concluded that it would be burdensome for</textblock>
    <textblock>processors to be required to retain the tags themselves for</textblock>
    <textblock>extended periods of time. NSSP now provides that processors are</textblock>
    <textblock>to retain tags for 90 days.</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Training</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §123.9 requires that each processor and importer</textblock>
    <textblock>employ at least one individual who has successfully completed a</textblock>
    <textblock>training course on the application of HACCP to fish and fishery</textblock>
    <textblock>products processing. The agency has tentatively concluded that</textblock>
    <textblock>training is critical to the successful implementation of HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>systems in the seafood industry. Based on experience obtained</textblock>
    <textblock>during the FDA/NOAA HACCP pilot programs in 1991-92, the agency</textblock>
    <textblock>believes that a significant portion of the seafood industry will</textblock>
    <textblock>be unprepared to meet the requirements of a mandatory HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>program without some training. As discussed earlier, the pilot</textblock>
    <textblock>program revealed a general lack of understanding of the</textblock>
    <textblock>preventive nature of HACCP, including misunderstandings about how</textblock>
    <textblock>to establish critical limits, control measures, corrective</textblock>
    <textblock>actions, and recordkeeping procedures (Ref. 40).</textblock>
    <textblock>A similar concern that the industry did not understand the</textblock>
    <textblock>application of HACCP principles formed the basis for the training</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements in the agency's regulations for low acid canned</textblock>
    <textblock>foods. Improvements in canning operations can be attributed in</textblock>
    <textblock>significant measure to the success of the training programs that</textblock>
    <textblock>were established to implement that requirement (Ref. 54). NAS</textblock>
    <textblock>concluded that the successful application of HACCP principles to</textblock>
    <textblock>low acid canned foods was substantially the result of the</textblock>
    <textblock>training requirement in the regulations for those products (Ref.</textblock>
    <textblock>36, p. 309). The CGMP regulations for foods in part 110 also</textblock>
    <textblock>call for training in appropriate food protection principles (§</textblock>
    <textblock>110.10(c)).</textblock>
    <textblock>The often seasonal nature, remote location, and small size</textblock>
    <textblock>of many seafood processors also support the need for formalized</textblock>
    <textblock>training. All of these conditions result in difficulty</textblock>
    <textblock>recruiting highly qualified management and supervisory staff.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thus, FDA has tentatively concluded that proposed §123.9 is</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to ensure that seafood processors and importers employ</textblock>
    <textblock>at least one person who is familiar with HACCP.</textblock>
    <textblock>These regulations propose to require at §123.9 that the</textblock>
    <textblock>person or persons at each importing and processing establishment</textblock>
    <textblock>who has received training be responsible for reviewing records of</textblock>
    <textblock>critical control point monitoring, recognizing critical limit</textblock>
    <textblock>deficiencies, and assessing the need for corrective actions</textblock>
    <textblock>relative to the product in question and the HACCP plan itself.</textblock>
    <textblock>While it is the intent of the agency to provide as much guidance</textblock>
    <textblock>as possible to assist processors and importers, these activities</textblock>
    <textblock>require specialized training in the principles of HACCP, various</textblock>
    <textblock>aspects of food science, and the criteria of existing regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>and guidelines.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency anticipates that 2- or 3-day training sessions,</textblock>
    <textblock>modeled after the Better Process Control Schools currently in</textblock>
    <textblock>place for low acid canned food and acidified food</textblock>
    <textblock>manufacturers, will be provided by various public and semiprivate</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions. The uniformity of this training can be assured by</textblock>
    <textblock>a review of their contents and by periodic onsite monitoring by</textblock>
    <textblock>the agency. Thus, FDA is proposing to require that the program</textblock>
    <textblock>of instruction be approved by the agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>While 2- or 3-day courses may well become the norm, FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>invites comment on whether the training requirement could be</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfied by different gradations of training, depending on the</textblock>
    <textblock>complexity or size of the operation, or on the degree of risk</textblock>
    <textblock>posed by the product being produced, without compromising the</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes for which training is proposed to be required. For</textblock>
    <textblock>example, could training for a small business with few hazards be</textblock>
    <textblock>accomplished in a shorter time and at a lower cost through the</textblock>
    <textblock>use of a video? FDA also invites comment on whether training in</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP received before these proposed regulations become effective</textblock>
    <textblock>as final regulations should be ``grandfathered'' as fulfilling the</textblock>
    <textblock>training requirement.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
