<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00062</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>If decomposition is found in less than 2.5 percent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>lot, and the time/temperature records show that conditions on the</textblock>
    <textblock>vessel were unlikely to cause, or significantly contribute to,</textblock>
    <textblock>the formation of histamine in the fish, Appendix B, section</textblock>
    <textblock>3.a.2.iii. provides that the decomposed fish should be removed in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with the procedure outlined in Appendix B, section</textblock>
    <textblock>3.a.2.i., but that it is not necessary to subject the lot to a</textblock>
    <textblock>histamine examination. The agency has tentatively concluded that</textblock>
    <textblock>decomposition below 2.5 percent is not significant in terms of</textblock>
    <textblock>the acceptability of the entire lot. Under the best conditions,</textblock>
    <textblock>it is possible that some fish in a large lot will experience some</textblock>
    <textblock>minimal decomposition. Under these circumstances, so long as the</textblock>
    <textblock>fish with decomposition are culled from the lot, there is no</textblock>
    <textblock>reason to suspect that the lot has been subject to unusual</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions that could cause histamine or scombrotoxin to form.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is aware that the canned tuna industry uses the 2.5</textblock>
    <textblock>percent value to determine whether special handling of a lot is</textblock>
    <textblock>warranted (Ref. 119). The canned tuna industry has concluded,</textblock>
    <textblock>just as FDA tentatively concludes, that levels above 2.5 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>represent likely exposure of the fish in a lot to conditions that</textblock>
    <textblock>are out of the ordinary and potentially dangerous.</textblock>
    <textblock>For these reasons, if the processor finds decomposition in</textblock>
    <textblock>more than 2.5 percent of the fish from a lot, those fish must be</textblock>
    <textblock>removed from the lot, and a histamine examination needs to be</textblock>
    <textblock>performed on a representative sample of the remaining fish in</textblock>
    <textblock>that lot (Appendix B, section 3.a.2.iv.).</textblock>
    <textblock>It is important to recognize that where the time/temperature</textblock>
    <textblock>records are inadequate for all the fish on a vessel, or show poor</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions for all the fish from a vessel, histamine analyses</textblock>
    <textblock>should be performed on representative samples from each lot on</textblock>
    <textblock>the vessel. Although an appropriate number of fish for sampling</textblock>
    <textblock>could possibly be provided from a single lot, the results would</textblock>
    <textblock>not be representative of the vessel as a whole.</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix B, section 3.a.3. describes how fish should be</textblock>
    <textblock>disposed of depending on the results of a histamine examination.</textblock>
    <textblock>In keeping with current policy, the agency expects that any fish</textblock>
    <textblock>that is found to have histamine above a defect action level or</textblock>
    <textblock>other regulatory level or limit for histamine established by FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>will not be used for food. Moreover, the agency expects, as</textblock>
    <textblock>reflected in Appendix B, section 3.a.3.i., that a finding of</textblock>
    <textblock>histamine over such level or limit in any fish in a lot from the</textblock>
    <textblock>vessel will result in the destruction of that entire lot,</textblock>
    <textblock>regardless of the percentage of decomposition that was</textblock>
    <textblock>organoleptically detected or the conditions on the vessel as</textblock>
    <textblock>indicated by the time/temperature records. Such a histamine</textblock>
    <textblock>finding strongly indicates that neither the records from the</textblock>
    <textblock>vessel nor the decomposition test (if the results were below 2.5</textblock>
    <textblock>percent) are reliable. Histamine may be present in the absence</textblock>
    <textblock>of organoleptically detectable decomposition.</textblock>
    <textblock>Similarly, the agency expects, as reflected in</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix B, section 3.a.3.ii., that a finding of histamine below</textblock>
    <textblock>the action level, but higher than is normally found in fresh fish</textblock>
    <textblock>(Refs. 120 and 121), in any fish in a lot will result in the</textblock>
    <textblock>immediate cooking of all the fish in the lot to ensure that</textblock>
    <textblock>scombrotoxin will not form over the shelf life of the fish.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cooking stops the histamine forming process once it has started.</textblock>
    <textblock>Without this cooking, any elevated temperatures later in the</textblock>
    <textblock>distribution system or in the home can result in a rapid</textblock>
    <textblock>elevation of histamine levels to hazardous levels (Ref. 117, p.</textblock>
    <textblock>341).</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix B, section 3.b. addresses raw materials controls</textblock>
    <textblock>that can be exercised by subsequent processors, i.e., those other</textblock>
    <textblock>than the first processor to take possession of scombroid toxin</textblock>
    <textblock>forming fish and fish products from a harvester. Assuming that</textblock>
    <textblock>the first processor has met its responsibilities with regard to</textblock>
    <textblock>raw materials as explained above, and has not caused a problem</textblock>
    <textblock>through improper handling during processing, subsequent</textblock>
    <textblock>processors should determine whether decomposition occurred during</textblock>
    <textblock>transfer from the previous processor. Consequently, the</textblock>
    <textblock>guideline provides, at Appendix B, section 3.b.1., that</textblock>
    <textblock>subsequent processors that do processing other than simply</textblock>
    <textblock>storing, should subject a representative sample of fish or fish</textblock>
    <textblock>products from each lot to an organoleptic examination. Any</textblock>
    <textblock>finding of decomposition in that sample should lead to</textblock>
    <textblock>organoleptic examination of the entire lot. If decomposition is</textblock>
    <textblock>found in more than 2.5 percent of the fish in the lot, the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor should perform a histamine examination on a</textblock>
    <textblock>representative sample of fish from the lot. These gradations are</textblock>
    <textblock>consistent with the expectations reflected in the guidelines for</textblock>
    <textblock>first processors.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA has tentatively concluded these measures need not be</textblock>
    <textblock>taken by those who only store fish and fishery products. While</textblock>
    <textblock>time/temperature abuse can occur during storage, and thus</textblock>
    <textblock>scombroid toxin forming species must be ␣held ␣at ␣appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>␣temperatures (40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below), the hazard of</textblock>
    <textblock>scombrotoxin in the finished product can be controlled by those</textblock>
    <textblock>who own the product or manipulate it during processing.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
