<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00008</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Antidumping Duty Order</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 736 of the Act, the Department will direct Customs officers to assess, upon further advice by the administering authority pursuant to section 736(a)(1) of the Act, antidumping duties equal to the amount by which the foreign market value of the merchandise exceeds the United States price for all entries of certain stainless steel wire rods from France. These antidumping duties will be assessed on all unliquidated entries of certain stainless steel wire rods from France entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption on or after August 5, 1993, the date on which the Department published its preliminary determination notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 41726). On or after the date of publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, U.S. Custom officers must require, at the same time as importers would normally deposit estimated duties, the following cash deposits for the subject merchandise:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice constitutes the antidumping duty order and amended final determination with respect to certain stainless steel wire rods from France, pursuant to section 736(a) of the Act. Interested parties may contact the Central Records Unit, room B-099 of the Main Commerce Building, for copies of an updated list of antidumping duty orders currently in effect.</textblock>
    <textblock>This order is published in accordance with section 736(a) of the Act and 19 CFR 353.21.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Manufacturer/Producer/</textblock>
    <textblock>Exporter</textblock>
    <textblock>1Weighted-average margin percentage</textblock>
    <textblock>Imphy</textblock>
    <textblock>24.51</textblock>
    <textblock>Ugine-Savoie</textblock>
    <textblock>24.51</textblock>
    <textblock>All Others</textblock>
    <textblock>24.51</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Joseph A. Spetrini,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Assistant Secretary for Import Administration.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2028 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DS-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
