<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00077</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>FDA also invites comment on the effect of a small business</textblock>
    <textblock>exemption on the regulation of imports. How would HACCP be</textblock>
    <textblock>applied to imports under a tiered approach? Would it be possible</textblock>
    <textblock>to treat domestic and imported products equally under such an</textblock>
    <textblock>approach?</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Staggered Phase-in</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations include an effective date of 1 year</textblock>
    <textblock>from the publication of a final rule. FDA has explained the</textblock>
    <textblock>reasoning behind this proposed effective date and has invited</textblock>
    <textblock>comment on it elsewhere in this preamble. In addition, comments</textblock>
    <textblock>are invited on the merits of a staggered phase-in instead of a</textblock>
    <textblock>single implementation date for all affected entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>The two most obvious ways of accomplishing a staggered</textblock>
    <textblock>phase-in would be to differentiate on the basis of size or on the</textblock>
    <textblock>basis of risk. Differentiating on the basis of size would</textblock>
    <textblock>presumably allow small businesses to have a longer time or times</textblock>
    <textblock>for implementation than would be allowed for larger firms. As</textblock>
    <textblock>suggested earlier, large firms are probably much more able to</textblock>
    <textblock>implement a HACCP system than are small firms. Theoretically,</textblock>
    <textblock>the longer lead time for small firms would allow the private</textblock>
    <textblock>sector to develop an infrastructure that could help small firms</textblock>
    <textblock>implement HACCP. Such an infrastructure could include process</textblock>
    <textblock>authorities (see the preamble discussion on cooked, ready-to-eat</textblock>
    <textblock>products), testing facilities, and consulting services from trade</textblock>
    <textblock>associations, academia, and others.</textblock>
    <textblock>As an additional consideration, FDA will likely learn</textblock>
    <textblock>lessons from its experiences in implementing the regulation that</textblock>
    <textblock>it could apply to the benefit of those that would have to</textblock>
    <textblock>implement it at a later date. For example, FDA is considering</textblock>
    <textblock>whether it should make the first review of HACCP plans by agency</textblock>
    <textblock>investigators a nonregulatory evaluation to facilitate plan</textblock>
    <textblock>development by the processor (although the overall inspection of</textblock>
    <textblock>the plant would be regulatory). The agency invites comment on</textblock>
    <textblock>this approach. Presumably, the more experience the agency has,</textblock>
    <textblock>the better this evaluation will be.</textblock>
    <textblock>On the other hand, as noted above, small firms are involved</textblock>
    <textblock>in the processing of higher risk products. How does this fact</textblock>
    <textblock>bear on the possibility of longer implementation times for small</textblock>
    <textblock>firms?</textblock>
    <textblock>Differentiation solely on the basis of risk appears to be</textblock>
    <textblock>more complex than differentiation on the basis of size. If high</textblock>
    <textblock>risk products were to be phased in first, it would appear that</textblock>
    <textblock>those with the most complex plans to develop and implement would</textblock>
    <textblock>receive the shortest lead time, while those with the simplest</textblock>
    <textblock>plans would receive the longest lead time.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also, the criteria for determining risk would have to be</textblock>
    <textblock>carefully considered. FDA asks for comment on whether a</textblock>
    <textblock>staggered start should begin with raw molluscan shellfish and</textblock>
    <textblock>certain species of finfish that can accumulate scombrotoxin and</textblock>
    <textblock>ciguatoxin, or whether other criteria should apply, as discussed</textblock>
    <textblock>previously.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA invites comment on all these matters. FDA also invites</textblock>
    <textblock>comment on the effect of a phase-in approach on the regulation of</textblock>
    <textblock>imports. How could this approach be applied to imported</textblock>
    <textblock>products?</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Deleting or Modifying Aspects of This Proposal, or Taking</textblock>
    <textblock>Some Other Step, to Reduce the Burden of Implementation</textblock>
    <textblock>As has already been explained in this preamble, FDA has</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed only the basics of HACCP in order to keep the regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>burden to a minimum. Several features of HACCP included within</textblock>
    <textblock>the NACMCF's seven principles, such as flow charts and the</textblock>
    <textblock>establishment of ``HACCP teams,'' are noted in this preamble, but</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA has not proposed to require them. Nonetheless, FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>acknowledges that, theoretically, there are a number of ways in</textblock>
    <textblock>which this proposal could be scaled back even further. FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>invites comments on whether such scaling back would be desirable,</textblock>
    <textblock>and, if so, how it could be done. Possible areas for scale-back</textblock>
    <textblock>include, but are not limited to:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Requiring only negative, rather than positive records.</textblock>
    <textblock>Negative records note only deviations from critical limits and</textblock>
    <textblock>how they are corrected. If a critical control point is under</textblock>
    <textblock>control, no record is made. Admittedly, FDA has reservations</textblock>
    <textblock>about such an approach. For example, it is virtually impossible</textblock>
    <textblock>for firms or for FDA to spot trends that could lead to problems</textblock>
    <textblock>if only negative records are being kept. Nonetheless, FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>invites comment on this approach.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
