<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00229</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00146</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee Meeting on Transport Airplane and Engine Issues</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA is issuing this notice to advise the public of a meeting of the Federal Aviation Administration's Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee to discuss transport airplane and engine issues.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held on February 16, 1994 at 8 a.m. Arrange for oral presentations by February 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held at Air Transport Association of America, 1301 Pennsylvania Ave., NW., Washington, DC.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Lewis Lebakken, Office of Rulemaking, FAA, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591, telephone (202) 267-9682.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463; 5 U.S.C. App. II), notice is given of a meeting of the Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee to be held on February 16, 1994 at Air Transport Association of America, 1301 Pennsylvania Ave., NW., Washington, DC. The agenda for the meeting will include:</textblock>
    <textblock>•Opening Remarks.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Review of Action Items.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Reports of working groups.</textblock>
    <textblock>Attendance is open to the interested public, but will be limited to the space available. The public must make arrangements by February 7, 1994, to present oral statements at the meeting. The public may present written statements to the committee at any time by providing 25 copies to the Assistant Executive Director for Transport Airplane and Engine Issues or by bringing the copies to him at the meeting. In addition, sign and oral interpretation can be made available at the meeting, as well as an assistive listening device, if requested 10 calendar days before the meeting. Arrangements may be made by contacting the person listed under the heading</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 19, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Chris A. Christie,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Executive Director, Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1928 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
