<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00042</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>COMMITTEE FOR PURCHASE FROM PEOPLE WHO ARE BLIND OR SEVERELY DISABLED</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Procurement List Additions</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee for Purchase From People Who Are Blind or Severely Disabled.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Additions to the Procurement List.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This action adds to the Procurement List commodities and services to be furnished by nonprofit agencies employing persons who are blind or have other severe disabilities.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee for Purchase From People Who Are Blind or Severely Disabled, Crystal Square 3, suite 403, 1735 Jefferson Davis Highway, Arlington, Virginia 22202-3461.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Beverly Milkman, (703) 603-7740.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On November 15, November 29, and December 10, 1993, the committee for Purchase From People Who Are Blind or Severely Disabled published notices (58 FR 60181, 62646 and 64932) of proposed additions to the Procurement List.</textblock>
    <textblock>After consideration of the material presented to it concerning capability of qualified nonprofit agencies to provide the commodities and services, fair market price, and impact of the additions on the current or most recent contractors, the Committee has determined that the commodities and services listed below are suitable for procurement by the Federal Government under 41 U.S.C. 46-48c and 41 CFR 51-2.4.</textblock>
    <textblock>I certify that the following action will not have a significant impact on a substantial number of small entities. The major factors considered for this certification were:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The action will not result in any additional reporting, recordkeeping or other compliance requirements for small entities other than the small organizations that will furnish the commodities and services to the Government.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The action does not appear to have a severe economic impact on current contractors for the commodities and services.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The action will result in authorizing small entities to furnish the commodities and services to the Government.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. There are no known regulatory alternatives which would accomplish the objectives of the Javits-Wagner-O'Day Act (41 U.S.C. 46-48c) in connection with the commodities and services proposed for addition to the Procurement List. Accordingly, the following commodities and services are hereby added to the Procurement List:</textblock>
    <textblock>Commodities</textblock>
    <textblock>Sponge, Surgical</textblock>
    <textblock>6510-00-559-3219</textblock>
    <textblock>6510-00-119-9314</textblock>
    <textblock>6510-00-116-1285</textblock>
    <textblock>(Requirements for Defense Personnel Support Center only_1285)</textblock>
    <textblock>6510-00-988-3838</textblock>
    <textblock>Services</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative Services, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, Nashville District, Estes Kefauver Building &amp; Adjacent Buildings, Nashville, Tennessee</textblock>
    <textblock>Janitorial/Grounds Maintenance, Soo Area Office, Soo Locks, Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan</textblock>
    <textblock>This action does not affect current contracts awarded prior to the effective date of this addition or options exercised under those contracts.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Beverly L. Milkman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Executive Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1949 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6820-33-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
