<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The agency is proposing to define ``shucked shellfish'' in</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.3(s) as meaning molluscan shellfish that have one or both</textblock>
    <textblock>shells removed. The labeling and recordkeeping requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed in §123.28(c) apply to shucked shellfish.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is proposing to define ``tag'' in §123.3(t) as a</textblock>
    <textblock>record of harvesting information attached to a container of</textblock>
    <textblock>shellstock by the harvester or processor. Under proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§1240.60(b), the tag or bill-of-lading will identify the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor, harvester, date of harvest, and State, including the</textblock>
    <textblock>specific location of harvest. Most shellfish-producing States</textblock>
    <textblock>and countries currently require that shellfish harvested in their</textblock>
    <textblock>waters bear documentation with such information. This</textblock>
    <textblock>information is the minimum necessary to permit ready</textblock>
    <textblock>identification of site and time of harvest of the shellfish.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because raw molluscan shellfish directly reflect the quality of</textblock>
    <textblock>the harvesting area, this information is necessary to provide</textblock>
    <textblock>assurance that the shellfish were harvested from an area that was</textblock>
    <textblock>safe and open for harvesting.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Purpose and Criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 123.5(a) of the proposed regulations references the</textblock>
    <textblock>umbrella CGMP guidelines in part 110 as providing general</textblock>
    <textblock>guidance with regard to such matters as facility design,</textblock>
    <textblock>materials, personnel practices, and cleaning and sanitation</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures. Because part 110 provides guidance of general</textblock>
    <textblock>applicability to all foods, the agency intends that this guidance</textblock>
    <textblock>will continue to be valid for seafood processors when the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations at part 123 are issued in final form.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §123.5(b) makes clear that the purpose of subpart A of</textblock>
    <textblock>part 123 is to set forth requirements specific to the processing</textblock>
    <textblock>and importation of fish and fishery products.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. HACCP Plans</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Summary</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require in §123.6 that commercial</textblock>
    <textblock>processors and importers of fish and fishery products develop and</textblock>
    <textblock>implement HACCP plans in keeping with Principle 6 of the NACMCF</textblock>
    <textblock>discussed previously. Development and implementation of an HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>plan requires that processors think through the entire process</textblock>
    <textblock>flow from raw materials to finished product shipping to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>that safety hazards are controlled by design, and that they</textblock>
    <textblock>operate that process as a matter of daily routine. For</textblock>
    <textblock>importers, the thought process will begin with a decision from</textblock>
    <textblock>whom and from where to buy fishery products and follow through to</textblock>
    <textblock>arrangements for shipment to the United States, storage in the</textblock>
    <textblock>United States, and end when the product leaves the control of the</textblock>
    <textblock>importer. The plan provides the structure for the preventive</textblock>
    <textblock>controls, including the recordkeeping associated with those</textblock>
    <textblock>controls, that a processor or importer is to employ.</textblock>
    <textblock>In summary, FDA has tentatively concluded that the essential</textblock>
    <textblock>elements of this structure must include: (1) The identification</textblock>
    <textblock>of hazards to ensure that the processor or importer knows what</textblock>
    <textblock>the hazards are, so that it controls them by design rather than</textblock>
    <textblock>by chance (proposed §123.6(b)(1)); (2) the identification of</textblock>
    <textblock>critical control points to ensure that the processor or importer</textblock>
    <textblock>knows where to monitor to prevent or minimize the occurrence of</textblock>
    <textblock>the relevant hazard (proposed §123.6(b)(2)); (3) the</textblock>
    <textblock>identification of critical limits that must be met at each</textblock>
    <textblock>critical control point, so that the processor or importer has</textblock>
    <textblock>objective standards in place by which to determine whether it is</textblock>
    <textblock>controlling the relevant hazard (proposed §123.6(b)(3)); (4)</textblock>
    <textblock>the identification of procedures for how and when the processor</textblock>
    <textblock>or importer will monitor the critical control points to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>both that monitoring is done as a matter of routine, and that it</textblock>
    <textblock>is done in an appropriate manner and with sufficient frequency to</textblock>
    <textblock>establish preventive control (proposed §123.6(b)(4)); and (5) a</textblock>
    <textblock>recordkeeping system for that monitoring that will establish for</textblock>
    <textblock>the processor's or importer's benefit that it is effectively</textblock>
    <textblock>implementing a system of preventive controls, and record how</textblock>
    <textblock>those controls are operating over time (proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.6(b)(5)).</textblock>
    <textblock>The recordkeeping system is the key to HACCP. As explained</textblock>
    <textblock>above, the records will enable the processor or importer, and</textblock>
    <textblock>ultimately the regulator, to see the operations of the processor</textblock>
    <textblock>or importer through time, rather than only how they are</textblock>
    <textblock>functioning at a particular moment in time. Among other things,</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP records can reveal trends that might otherwise go</textblock>
    <textblock>undetected until significant problems occurred.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
