<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-0-00023</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-0-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>A derivation table is provided to show the sources of the revised part 266.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 20 CFR Part 266</textblock>
    <textblock>Railroad employees, Railroad retirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set out in the preamble, title 20, chapter II, Part 266, of the Code of Federal Regulations is revised as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 266_REPRESENTATIVE PAYMENT</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.1␣Introduction.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.2␣Recognition by the Board of a person to act in behalf of another.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.3␣Information considered in determining whether to make representative payments.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.4␣Information considered in selecting a representative payee.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.5␣Order of preference in selecting a representative payee.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.6␣Information to be submitted by a representative payee applicant; face-to-face interview.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.7␣Accountability of a representative payee.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.8␣Advance notice of the determination to make representative payment.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.9␣Responsibilities of a representative payee.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.10␣Use of benefit payments.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.11␣Conservation and investment of benefit payments.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.12␣Effect of matters or actions submitted or taken by legal guardian, etc.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.13␣When a new representative payee will be selected.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.14␣When representative payment will be stopped.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.15␣Transfer of accumulated benefit payments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>45 U.S.C. 231k and 231f.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 266_REPRESENTATIVE PAYMENT</textblock>
    <textblock>§266.1</textblock>
    <textblock>Introduction.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Explanation of representative payment.</textblock>
    <textblock>This part explains the principles and procedures that the Board follows in determining whether to make representative payment and in selecting a representative payee. It also explains the responsibilities that a representative payee has concerning the use of the funds which he or she receives on behalf of an annuitant. A representative payee may be either a person or an organization selected by the Board to receive benefits on behalf of an annuitant. A representative payee will be selected if the Board believes that the interest of an annuitant will be served by representative payment rather than direct payment of benefits. Generally, the Board will appoint a representative payee if it determines that the annuitant is not able to manage or direct the management of benefit payments in his or her interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Statutory authority.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 12 of the Railroad Retirement Act provides that every annuitant and claimant shall be conclusively presumed to have been competent until the date on which the Board receives a notice in writing that a legal guardian or other person legally vested with the care of the person or estate of an incompetent or a minor has been appointed: Provided, however, That despite receiving such notice, the Board may, if it finds the interests of such annuitant or claimant to be served thereby, recognize actions by, conduct transactions with, and make payments to such annuitant or claimant.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Old section</textblock>
    <textblock>1New section</textblock>
    <textblock>266.1</textblock>
    <textblock>266.2.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.2</textblock>
    <textblock>266.5.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.3</textblock>
    <textblock>266.3.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.4</textblock>
    <textblock>none.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.5</textblock>
    <textblock>266.5.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.6</textblock>
    <textblock>none.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.7</textblock>
    <textblock>266.12.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.8</textblock>
    <textblock>none.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.9</textblock>
    <textblock>266.6.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.10</textblock>
    <textblock>266.7, 266.9, 266.10, 266.11.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.10</textblock>
    <textblock>266.8.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.12</textblock>
    <textblock>266.4.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.13</textblock>
    <textblock>none.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.14</textblock>
    <textblock>none.</textblock>
    <textblock>266.15</textblock>
    <textblock>266.13.</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
