<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00079</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Description:</textblock>
    <textblock>The information requirements in this proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule are essentially monitoring and recordkeeping requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>encompassing critical control points in the production and</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection of fish and fishery products as established in the</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP plans of processors and importers. The specific</textblock>
    <textblock>information collected and the frequency of collection will depend</textblock>
    <textblock>on such factors as the species and the processing conditions. It</textblock>
    <textblock>will include observations of processing parameters such as the</textblock>
    <textblock>time and temperature of processing and storage; the condition of</textblock>
    <textblock>raw materials; the results of chemical and microbiological tests;</textblock>
    <textblock>the sanitation conditions in a processing facility; the</textblock>
    <textblock>corrective actions taken in response to processing deviations,</textblock>
    <textblock>etc. Records identifying production lot codes and date of</textblock>
    <textblock>manufacture will also be maintained. Records will be maintained</textblock>
    <textblock>by the processing facility or at an importer's place of business</textblock>
    <textblock>for 1 year after the date of preparation in the case of</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigerated products and at least 2 years for frozen products.</textblock>
    <textblock>This information will be used by FDA investigators during</textblock>
    <textblock>regularly scheduled inspections of processing plants, or at the</textblock>
    <textblock>time of entry of imports, to determine whether products were</textblock>
    <textblock>processed under sanitary conditions and processed, packaged,</textblock>
    <textblock>stored, and distributed using HACCP control techniques to avoid</textblock>
    <textblock>hazards that might cause the products to be adulterated. The</textblock>
    <textblock>information will also be used when necessary to trace and remove</textblock>
    <textblock>potentially hazardous products from the marketplace.</textblock>
    <textblock>Records of processing conditions will also provide a means</textblock>
    <textblock>for processors to monitor the quality of their products and to</textblock>
    <textblock>alert them when a deviation from the critical limits established</textblock>
    <textblock>in the HACCP plan has occurred that may create a potential public</textblock>
    <textblock>health hazard in the final product.</textblock>
    <textblock>The figures provided below reflect an FDA estimate of the</textblock>
    <textblock>annual hours of monitoring and recordkeeping based upon currently</textblock>
    <textblock>available data and assumptions about the effects of the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements in proposed part 123. The estimate is based on data</textblock>
    <textblock>used to develop cost estimates for the economic impact analysis</textblock>
    <textblock>required by Executive Order 12866 and thus is subject to the same</textblock>
    <textblock>types of uncertainties described elsewhere in this preamble. For</textblock>
    <textblock>example, the agency has anecdotal evidence that the burden on</textblock>
    <textblock>firms that are operating under a mandatory HACCP system</textblock>
    <textblock>established by the State of Alaska is more nominal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Consequently, FDA acknowledges the possibility that the estimates</textblock>
    <textblock>provided here are conservatively high, indicating recordkeeping</textblock>
    <textblock>burdens that are higher than would customarily be the case. FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>specifically invites comments on this point.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
