<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00123</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00085</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Under the provisions of the Federal Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. chapter 35), we have submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) a request for approval for the continued use of an information collection titled: ``Quality Control Negative Case Action Worksheet/Review Schedule Form ACF-6401.'' This request for clearance is made by the Office of Family Assistance (OFA) of the Administration for Children and Families (ACF).</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Agency Information Collection Under OMB Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the Information Collection request may be obtained from Stephen R. Smith, of the Office of Information Systems Management, ACF, by calling (202) 401-6964.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments and questions regarding the requested approval for information collection should be sent directly to: Laura Oliven, OMB Desk Officer for ACF, OMB Reports Management Branch, New Executive Office Building, room 3002, 725 17th Street NW., Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-7316.</textblock>
    <textblock>Information on Document</textblock>
    <textblock>Title: Quality Control Negative Case Action Worksheet/Review Schedule Form ACF-6401</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB No.: 0970-0006</textblock>
    <textblock>Description:</textblock>
    <textblock>This information collection is authorized by section 2(a)(6), section 408(b)(1) and section 1402(a) of the Social Security Act and required under regulatory authority found at 45 CFR 205.40. The purpose of this collection of information is to assure that individuals are not being denied categories of Federal assistance for which they are eligible and to take necessary corrective measures to reduce the incidence of improperly authorized or denied assistance. Specifically, categories of assistance covered by this collection of information are Aid to Families With Dependent Children (AFDC) and Medicaid in all States and jurisdictions, and Adult Assistance Programs under titles I, X, XIV, and XVI of the Social Security Act in Guam, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands.</textblock>
    <textblock>This collection of information was jointly designed and used by the Health Care Financing Administration and the Administration for Children and Families both of the Department of Health and Human Services.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Quality Control Negative Case Action system is a joint State/Federal effort to obtain data on the correctness of State actions to deny or terminate AFDC/Adult financial assistance or Medicaid eligibility. This information is utilized in determining the principal causes of incorrect actions and in developing appropriate corrective action. The Quality Control Negative Case Action system promotes proper State administration of their AFDC and adult programs by helping to assess performance in the denial or termination of benefits. Negative case action quality control therefor provides: (a) Continuous review of a statistically reliable statewide samples of negative actions; and (b) periodic compilation and analysis of findings to determine the incidence of incorrect actions. The Negative Case Action review supplements the Quality Control review of active cases and, thus, provides a balanced quality control system capable of measuring overall program performance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>20,057</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Frequency:</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>Average Burden Hours Per Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>1.00284</textblock>
    <textblock>Total Burden Hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>20,114</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 21, 1994</textblock>
  </address>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Larry Guerrero,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Director, Office of Information Systems Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1921 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4184-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
