<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00116</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>To minimize the variation in salt content of the fish, the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency is recommending in section 5.f. of Example 6 of this</textblock>
    <textblock>appendix that only fish of the same species and of similar size</textblock>
    <textblock>and similar weight be brined in the same tank (Refs. 171 and</textblock>
    <textblock>199). Because reuse of brine solutions is a possible route of</textblock>
    <textblock>microbial contamination of raw fish, the agency is providing in</textblock>
    <textblock>section 5.g. of Example 6 of this appendix that brines not be</textblock>
    <textblock>reused unless they have been processed in some way to return them</textblock>
    <textblock>to a microbiological quality equivalent to the original, unused</textblock>
    <textblock>brine made with potable water and food-grade salt. The agency is</textblock>
    <textblock>also providing in section 5.h. of Example 6 of this appendix that</textblock>
    <textblock>a processor may rinse the brined fish with fresh water to remove</textblock>
    <textblock>any unwanted excess salt on the exterior of the fish.</textblock>
    <textblock>2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Drying.</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish that are to be processed as smoked or</textblock>
    <textblock>smoke-flavored fish are dried after brining to remove excess</textblock>
    <textblock>water and prevent dripping during smoking. The drying process,</textblock>
    <textblock>usually of several hours in duration, provides another</textblock>
    <textblock>opportunity for microbial growth. Therefore, to minimize the</textblock>
    <textblock>opportunity for microbial growth by reducing those conditions</textblock>
    <textblock>that would provide a favorable environment for such growth, the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency is providing in section 5.i. of Example 6 of this appendix</textblock>
    <textblock>that the presmoking drying step should be conducted in a</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigerated room (Ref. 46).</textblock>
    <textblock>3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Smoking.</textblock>
    <textblock>Smoke deposition, like water-phase salt</textblock>
    <textblock>content, is very difficult to control. Constituents of smoke</textblock>
    <textblock>called ``inhibitory compounds'' (such as phenolic compounds) are</textblock>
    <textblock>reported to have a bactericidal effect (Ref. 177). Factors that</textblock>
    <textblock>affect the quantity of inhibitory compounds deposited on the fish</textblock>
    <textblock>surface and the degree of penetration by those compounds into the</textblock>
    <textblock>fish are the humidity in the smoking chamber, the temperature of</textblock>
    <textblock>smoking, and the air flow in the smoking chamber (Ref. 178).</textblock>
    <textblock>Decreased levels of inhibitory compounds reduce the preservative</textblock>
    <textblock>effect of the smoke and make dependence on these compounds</textblock>
    <textblock>inadvisable (Ref. 178). In general, smoked products are not</textblock>
    <textblock>shelf stable and must be either refrigerated at a temperature of</textblock>
    <textblock>40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or lower or frozen immediately after processing</textblock>
    <textblock>(Refs. 43, 45, and 178).</textblock>
    <textblock>To promote uniform deposition of smoke, heat exposure, and</textblock>
    <textblock>dehydration, and to ensure that on completion of these processes,</textblock>
    <textblock>the fish do not contain any raw or wet sections that would create</textblock>
    <textblock>an environment favorable for microbial growth and spoilage, the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency is providing in section 5.j. of Example 6 of this appendix</textblock>
    <textblock>that fish should be arranged in the smokehouse chamber or oven so</textblock>
    <textblock>that they are not overcrowded or touching each other, and that</textblock>
    <textblock>only fish of like size and weight should be included in a single</textblock>
    <textblock>batch of fish for smoking.</textblock>
    <textblock>Liquid smoke, a solution of wood smoke that, when diluted,</textblock>
    <textblock>may be used to impart a smoke flavor to fish products, is often</textblock>
    <textblock>used as an alternative to generated smoke. Liquid smoke has been</textblock>
    <textblock>reported to have similar antibacterial properties to, and some</textblock>
    <textblock>advantages over, generated smoke (Ref. 26). It is easier to</textblock>
    <textblock>apply uniformly, and the inhibitory compounds penetrate further</textblock>
    <textblock>into the fish flesh (Ref. 26). Liquid smoke, generated smoke, or</textblock>
    <textblock>a combination of liquid smoke and generated smoke needs to be</textblock>
    <textblock>applied to all surfaces of fish to be smoked. Liquid smoke may</textblock>
    <textblock>be applied to the product before, at the commencement of, or</textblock>
    <textblock>during the process, while generated smoke needs to be applied to</textblock>
    <textblock>the fish during the first half of the process and longer if</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary (Refs. 178 and 179). If a combination of liquid smoke</textblock>
    <textblock>and generated smoke is used, the method for use of liquid smoke</textblock>
    <textblock>may be followed, and the generated smoke may be applied at any</textblock>
    <textblock>stage of the process (Ref. 26). The agency is providing for the</textblock>
    <textblock>use of liquid smoke alone or in combination with generated smoke</textblock>
    <textblock>in section 3.c.2. of Example 6 of this appendix to impart smoke</textblock>
    <textblock>flavor and antibacterial properties to the products.</textblock>
    <textblock>4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Use of sodium nitrite.</textblock>
    <textblock>Use of sodium nitrite in smoked</textblock>
    <textblock>and smoke-flavored fish products is limited to the species listed</textblock>
    <textblock>in §172.175 (21 CFR 172.175) and to chubs in §172.177 (21 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>172.177). Section 172.175 permits the use of sodium nitrite as a</textblock>
    <textblock>preservative and color fixative in cured, smoked sablefish,</textblock>
    <textblock>salmon, and shad. However, it requires that the level of sodium</textblock>
    <textblock>nitrite in the final product not exceed 200 ppm. Use of sodium</textblock>
    <textblock>nitrite substantially reduces the level of salt necessary to</textblock>
    <textblock>inhibit outgrowth of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>type A and type E spores,</textblock>
    <textblock>although the levels vary because of the difference in heat</textblock>
    <textblock>resistance between the two types of spores (Ref. 179). The</textblock>
    <textblock>quantity of sodium nitrite necessary to achieve inhibition is</textblock>
    <textblock>affected by both the level of contamination and the resistance of</textblock>
    <textblock>the spores (Refs. 179 and 180). Refrigeration of the finished</textblock>
    <textblock>product at temperatures of 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below is necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>to retain the inhibitory characteristic gained through use of</textblock>
    <textblock>sodium nitrite (Ref. 179). Therefore, in accordance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions of §§172.175 and 172.177, the agency is proposing to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide for the use of sodium nitrite in the processing and</textblock>
    <textblock>packaging of smoked and smoke-flavored fish in section 5.a. and</textblock>
    <textblock>section 5.b. of Example 6 of this appendix.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
