<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00101</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>§123.8</textblock>
    <textblock>Records.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Records required by this part that involve observations</textblock>
    <textblock>or measurements during processing or related activities,</textblock>
    <textblock>including corrective actions taken in accordance with §123.7,</textblock>
    <textblock>shall include the identity of the product, product code, and date</textblock>
    <textblock>of activity that the record reflects. Processing and other</textblock>
    <textblock>information shall be entered at the time that it is observed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each record shall be signed by the operator or observer, except</textblock>
    <textblock>that corrective action records need only be signed in accordance</textblock>
    <textblock>with paragraph (b) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Records required by this part shall be reviewed,</textblock>
    <textblock>signed, and dated by an individual who has been trained in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with §123.9, before distribution of the product for</textblock>
    <textblock>completeness and compliance with the established critical limits.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The records required by this part shall be retained at</textblock>
    <textblock>the processing facility or the importer's place of business in</textblock>
    <textblock>the United States for at least 1 year after the date they were</textblock>
    <textblock>prepared in the case of refrigerated products and for at least 2</textblock>
    <textblock>years after the date they were prepared in the case of frozen or</textblock>
    <textblock>preserved products. Records that relate to the general adequacy</textblock>
    <textblock>of equipment or processes being used by a processor, including</textblock>
    <textblock>the results of scientific studies and evaluations, shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>retained at the processing facility for at least 2 years after</textblock>
    <textblock>their applicability to the product being produced at the</textblock>
    <textblock>facility. If the processing facility is closed between seasonal</textblock>
    <textblock>packs, the records may be transferred to some other reasonably</textblock>
    <textblock>accessible location during the period of closure.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) All records required by this part, including HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>plans required in §123.6 and consumer complaints that may be</textblock>
    <textblock>related to a critical limit deviation, shall be available for</textblock>
    <textblock>review and copying at reasonable times by duly authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>officers and employees.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Tags as defined in §123.3(t) are not subject to the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.9</textblock>
    <textblock>Training.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each processor and importer shall employ at least one</textblock>
    <textblock>individual who has successfully completed a prescribed course of</textblock>
    <textblock>instruction in the application of Hazard Analysis Critical</textblock>
    <textblock>Control Point (HACCP) principles to fish and fishery product</textblock>
    <textblock>processing at a program of instruction approved by the Food and</textblock>
    <textblock>Drug Administration. At a minimum, this individual shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible for developing and modifying the plan as required by</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.6, evaluating critical limit deviations and corrective</textblock>
    <textblock>actions as required by §123.7, and performing record review as</textblock>
    <textblock>required by §123.8(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.10</textblock>
    <textblock>Sanitation control procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Every processor and importer who takes physical</textblock>
    <textblock>possession of fish or fishery products and engages in the</textblock>
    <textblock>processing of such fish or fishery products, including storing</textblock>
    <textblock>such products, shall perform sanitation inspections and ensure at</textblock>
    <textblock>a minimum that, to the extent applicable to the operations</textblock>
    <textblock>conducted by the processor or importer, the following conditions</textblock>
    <textblock>apply:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Water that directly comes into contact with a product</textblock>
    <textblock>or with food contact surfaces, or is used in the manufacture of</textblock>
    <textblock>ice, is derived from a safe and sanitary source or is being</textblock>
    <textblock>treated to render it of safe and sanitary quality.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
