<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00034</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>9. Recordkeeping</textblock>
    <textblock>As explained above, a HACCP system will not work unless</textblock>
    <textblock>records are generated during the operation of the HACCP plan, and</textblock>
    <textblock>these records are maintained and are available for review (see</textblock>
    <textblock>section IV.A.6. of this document). Thus, FDA is requiring in</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed §123.6(b)(5) that the HACCP plan provide for a</textblock>
    <textblock>recordkeeping system that will document the processor's or</textblock>
    <textblock>importer's monitoring of the critical control points. Proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.6(b)(5) also requires that HACCP records contain the actual</textblock>
    <textblock>values obtained during monitoring, such as the actual</textblock>
    <textblock>temperatures and times. FDA has tentatively concluded that it is</textblock>
    <textblock>not possible for the processor to derive the full benefits of its</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP system, nor is it possible for FDA to verify the operation</textblock>
    <textblock>of the system, without actual values. Notations that</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigeration temperatures are satisfactory or unsatisfactory,</textblock>
    <textblock>without recording the actual temperatures, are vague and subject</textblock>
    <textblock>to varying interpretation and thus will not ensure that</textblock>
    <textblock>preventive controls are working. Also, it is not possible to</textblock>
    <textblock>discern trends without actual values.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, proposed §123.6(b)(5) requires that HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>records include the actual consumer complaints that may have been</textblock>
    <textblock>received by the processor or importer relating to the operation</textblock>
    <textblock>of critical control points or possible critical limit deviations.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA has tentatively concluded that it may be necessary on</textblock>
    <textblock>occasion for it to review these complaints in order to be able to</textblock>
    <textblock>validate whether the firm is taking necessary steps to review</textblock>
    <textblock>controls and correct deviations as necessary in response to</textblock>
    <textblock>consumer complaints.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is not FDA's intent to gain unlimited access to</textblock>
    <textblock>industry's consumer complaint files through this proposal or to</textblock>
    <textblock>engage in ``fishing expeditions'' through consumer complaint files.</textblock>
    <textblock>Only those consumer complaints relating to the operation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP critical control points need be included as HACCP records.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA's interest is solely in verifying that the HACCP system is</textblock>
    <textblock>working as it should. The agency understands the sensitivities</textblock>
    <textblock>associated with consumer complaint records and invites comments</textblock>
    <textblock>on this aspect of the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>10. Nonsafety Hazards</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §123.6(c) encourages, but does not require,</textblock>
    <textblock>processors and importers to include in their plans controls for</textblock>
    <textblock>hazards other than hazards to health. Examples listed in</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.6(c)(1)(i) and (ii) are decomposition not associated with</textblock>
    <textblock>human illness and economic adulteration. FDA is not requiring</textblock>
    <textblock>processors and importers to include nonsafety hazards in their</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP plans for reasons stated previously. However, the agency</textblock>
    <textblock>is encouraging processors and importers to apply HACCP principles</textblock>
    <textblock>to these nonsafety hazards, and to control them in the same</textblock>
    <textblock>manner that processors and importers control safety hazards (see</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed §123.6(c)(2)), because they are common problems in the</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood industry. FDA has included a guideline on economic</textblock>
    <textblock>adulteration with these proposed regulations (see Appendix D).</textblock>
    <textblock>Despite the fact that these proposed regulations do not</textblock>
    <textblock>require HACCP controls for nonsafety hazards, such hazards as</textblock>
    <textblock>economic adulteration, decomposition not normally associated with</textblock>
    <textblock>human illness, general unfitness for food, and misbranding,</textblock>
    <textblock>constitute violations of the act and are subject to regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>action by FDA (see sections 402(a)(3) and 403 of the act (21</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S.C. 343). Inspections by FDA investigators will continue</textblock>
    <textblock>to consider and enforce these provisions of the act.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
