<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00024</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>At the same time, the United States is the world's largest</textblock>
    <textblock>exporter of fishery products. In 1991, the United States</textblock>
    <textblock>exported more than $3 billion worth of seafood, making a</textblock>
    <textblock>significant positive contribution to this country's balance of</textblock>
    <textblock>payments as well as to the many coastal State economies in which</textblock>
    <textblock>these products are produced (Refs. 42 and 43). Our largest</textblock>
    <textblock>market is Japan, followed by the European Community (EC) and</textblock>
    <textblock>Canada. Both Canada and the EC have implemented or are in the</textblock>
    <textblock>process of implementing mandatory HACCP-based seafood inspection</textblock>
    <textblock>systems (Refs. 32 and 44).</textblock>
    <textblock>Given the significance of both international and domestic</textblock>
    <textblock>trade, ongoing efforts to harmonize or make equivalent country</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection systems and requirements takes on great significance.</textblock>
    <textblock>The current multilateral round of trade negotiations under the</textblock>
    <textblock>General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT) has resulted in</textblock>
    <textblock>further focus on this area. The draft text on sanitary and</textblock>
    <textblock>phytosanitary measures acknowledges the desire of the contracting</textblock>
    <textblock>parties, including the United States, to support ``the use of</textblock>
    <textblock>harmonized sanitary and phytosanitary measures between</textblock>
    <textblock>contracting parties, on the basis of international standards,</textblock>
    <textblock>guidelines, and recommendations developed by the relevant</textblock>
    <textblock>international organizations including the Codex Alimentarious</textblock>
    <textblock>Commission *␣*␣*'' (Ref. 45, p. L.35). This move toward</textblock>
    <textblock>harmonization, coupled with the current recommendations of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Codex Committee on Food Hygiene encouraging the international use</textblock>
    <textblock>of the HACCP system (Ref. 46), clearly argue for the adoption of</textblock>
    <textblock>this approach in the United States for seafood. Failure by the</textblock>
    <textblock>United States to adopt a mandatory, HACCP-based inspection system</textblock>
    <textblock>may ultimately undermine its export success, with considerable</textblock>
    <textblock>economic consequences. For example, in addition to the EC,</textblock>
    <textblock>Canada, Iceland, Australia, and many other fishing nations have</textblock>
    <textblock>moved to a mandatory HACCP approach that could affect United</textblock>
    <textblock>States competitiveness in the major seafood markets.</textblock>
    <textblock>The EC is the United States' second largest export market,</textblock>
    <textblock>purchasing $441 million worth of U.S. products in 1991. On July</textblock>
    <textblock>22, 1991, EC Council Directive 91/493 was issued to set out the</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions for the production and placing on the EC market fish</textblock>
    <textblock>and fishery products (Ref. 44). This Directive requires, as of</textblock>
    <textblock>January 1, 1993, that both member States and third countries:</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣*␣* take all necessary measures so that, at</textblock>
    <textblock>all stages of the production of fishery</textblock>
    <textblock>products *␣*␣* persons responsible must carry</textblock>
    <textblock>out their own checks based on the following</textblock>
    <textblock>principles:</textblock>
    <textblock>_Identification of critical control</textblock>
    <textblock>points in their establishments on the basis</textblock>
    <textblock>of the manufacturing processes used;</textblock>
    <textblock>_establishment and implementation of</textblock>
    <textblock>methods for monitoring and checking such</textblock>
    <textblock>critical control points; *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>_keeping a written record *␣*␣* with</textblock>
    <textblock>a view to submitting them to the competent</textblock>
    <textblock>authority *␣*␣*.</textblock>
    <textblock>While the directive provides some flexibility in terms of</textblock>
    <textblock>equivalence, it is clear that the EC is looking for a mandatory</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP system along the lines proposed in this regulation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Maintaining and expanding this export market is likely to be</textblock>
    <textblock>facilitated if this proposal is adopted.</textblock>
    <textblock>Similarly, ongoing discussions with Canada under the terms</textblock>
    <textblock>of section 708 of the U.S./Canada Free Trade Agreement (FTA) to</textblock>
    <textblock>harmonize or make equivalent the two nations' respective</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection systems and standards have made it clear that this</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed HACCP regulation will significantly facilitate the</textblock>
    <textblock>process (Ref. 47). Canada has recently completed implementation</textblock>
    <textblock>of a mandatory, HACCP-based seafood inspection program. Because</textblock>
    <textblock>Canada is the United States' third largest export market and</textblock>
    <textblock>largest supplier of imported seafood, adoption of an equivalent</textblock>
    <textblock>system would not only achieve the objectives of the FTA but</textblock>
    <textblock>potentially would save resources currently devoted to monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>shipments between our two countries. Similar potential benefits</textblock>
    <textblock>could be expected under the proposed North American FTA,</textblock>
    <textblock>particularly at this formative stage in that process. Thus,</textblock>
    <textblock>facilitation of international trade is a fourth factor supporting</textblock>
    <textblock>the appropriateness, and thus providing a rational basis, for</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA's proposed course of action.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
