<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00148</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00093</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(b) A summary of the project (PHSIS), not to exceed one page,</textblock>
    <textblock>which provides:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A description of the population to be served.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A summary of the services to be provided.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) A description of the coordination planned with the</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate State and local health agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12372</textblock>
    <textblock>The HIV Demonstration Program for Children, Adolescents, and</textblock>
    <textblock>Families has been determined to be a program which is subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>the provisions of Executive Order 12372 concerning</textblock>
    <textblock>intergovernmental review of Federal programs by appropriate health</textblock>
    <textblock>planning agencies, as implemented by 45 CFR part 100. Executive</textblock>
    <textblock>Order 12372 allows States the option of setting up a system for</textblock>
    <textblock>reviewing applications from within their States for assistance</textblock>
    <textblock>under certain Federal programs. The application packages to be</textblock>
    <textblock>made available under this notice (Form PHS 5161-1 with revised face</textblock>
    <textblock>sheet HHS Form 424 and with Program Narrative and Checklist</textblock>
    <textblock>approved under OMB 0937-0189) will contain a listing of States</textblock>
    <textblock>which have chosen to set up such a review system and will provide a</textblock>
    <textblock>single point of contact (SPOC) in the States for review.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicants (other than federally-recognized Indian tribal</textblock>
    <textblock>governments) should contact their State SPOCs as early as possible</textblock>
    <textblock>to alert them to the prospective applications and receive any</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary instructions on the State process. For proposed projects</textblock>
    <textblock>serving more than one State, the applicant is advised to contact</textblock>
    <textblock>the SPOC of each affected State. The due date for State process</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendations is 60 days after the application deadline for new</textblock>
    <textblock>and competing awards. The granting agency does not guarantee to</textblock>
    <textblock>``accommodate or explain'' State process recommendations it receives</textblock>
    <textblock>after that date. (See part 148, Intergovernmental Review of PHS</textblock>
    <textblock>Programs under Executive Order 12372 and 45 CFR part 100 for a</textblock>
    <textblock>description of the review process and requirements.)</textblock>
    <textblock>(The OMB Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance number for the HIV</textblock>
    <textblock>Demonstration Program for Children, Adolescents, and Families is</textblock>
    <textblock>93.153.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 16, 1993</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John H. Kelso,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1886 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-15-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
