<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00140</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00089</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12372 Review</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications are subject to Intergovernmental Review of Federal Programs as governed by Executive Order (E.O.) 12372. E.O. 12372 sets up a system for State and local government review of proposed Federal assistance applications. Potential applicants should have already contacted their State Single Point of Contact (SPOC) to alert them to the prospective applications and to receive instructions on the State process. For proposed projects that serve more than one State, the applicant should contact the SPOC for each State served. If SPOCs have any State process recommendations on applications submitted to CDC, they should forward them, no later than February 25, 1994, to Clara M. Jenkins, Grants Management Officer, Grants Management Branch, Procurement and Grants Office, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), 255 East Paces Ferry Road, NE., room 320, Mail Stop E-15, Atlanta, GA 30305. The CDC does not guarantee to accommodate or explain State process recommendations it receives after February 25, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Health System Reporting Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>This program is not subject to the Public Health System Reporting Requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Number</textblock>
    <textblock>The Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Number is 93.939, HIV Prevention Activities_Non-Governmental Organization Based.</textblock>
    <textblock>Where To Obtain Additional Information</textblock>
    <textblock>If you are interested in obtaining additional information regarding these projects, please refer to Announcement 305A and contact Sharron Orum or Van Malone, Grants Management Specialists, Grants Management Branch, Procurement and Grants Office, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), 255 East Paces Ferry Road, NE., room 320, Mail Stop E-15, Atlanta, GA 30305, telephone (404) 842-6575.</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of ``Healthy People 2000'' (Full Report, Stock No. 017-001-00474-0) or ``Healthy People 2000'' (Summary Report, Stock No. 017-001-00473-1)</textblock>
    <textblock>referenced in the</textblock>
    <textblock>SUMMARY</textblock>
    <textblock>may be obtained through the Superintendent of Documents, Government Printing Office, Washington, DC 20402-9325, telephone (202) 783-3238.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Robert L. Foster,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Associate Director for Management</textblock>
    <textblock>and Operations, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1880 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-18-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
