<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00151</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00096</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Mortgagee Review Board Administrative Actions</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of the Assistant Secretary for Housing_Federal Housing Commissioner</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. N-94-3708; FR-3641-N-01]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the Assistant Secretary for Housing_Federal Housing Commissioner, HUD.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In compliance with section 202(c) of the National Housing Act, notice is hereby given of the cause and description of administrative actions taken by HUD's Mortgagee Review Board against HUD-approved mortgagees.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>William Heyman, Director, Office of Lender Activities and Land Sales Registration, 451 Seventh Street, SW., Washington, DC 20410, telephone (202) 708-1824. The Telecommunications Device for the Deaf (TDD) number is (202) 708-4594. (These are not toll-free numbers).</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 202(c)(5) of the National Housing Act (added by Section 142 of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Reform Act of 1989 (Pub.L. 101-235, approved December 15, 1989) requires that HUD ``publish in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>a description of and the cause for administrative action against a HUD-approved mortgagee'' by the Department's Mortgagee Review Board. In compliance with the requirements of section 202(c)(5), notice is hereby given of administrative actions that have been taken by the Mortgagee Review Board from October 1, 1993 through December 31, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Certified Mortgage Bankers, Inc., Coral Gables, Florida</textblock>
    <textblock>Action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Settlement Agreement that includes indemnification to the Department for claim losses in connection with three improperly originated loans, and payment of a civil money penalty in the amount of $500 for reporting violations under the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act (HMDA).</textblock>
    <textblock>Cause:</textblock>
    <textblock>A HUD monitoring review that cited the company for violations of HUD-FHA program requirements that included: failure to comply with HUD-FHA reporting requirements under the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act (HMDA); failure to verify mortgagors' source of funds used for downpayment and/or closing costs; failure to properly verify a mortgagor's employment, income and property occupancy; and failure to maintain an adequate Quality Control Plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Pioneer Mortgage, Inc., Haddon Heights, New Jersey</textblock>
    <textblock>Action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Settlement Agreement that includes indemnification to the Department for claim losses in connection with three improperly originated loans, and corrective action to assure compliance with HUD-FHA requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cause:</textblock>
    <textblock>A HUD monitoring review that disclosed violations of HUD-FHA program requirements including: failure to implement a Quality Control Plan in compliance with HUD-FHA requirements; failure to verify a mortgagor's source of funds used for downpayment and closing costs; and failure to adequately verify mortgagors' income.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
