<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00037</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Similarly, FDA is also proposing to require in ยง123.8(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>that the processor retain any records relating to the general</textblock>
    <textblock>adequacy of the equipment or processes being used by the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor, including the results of scientific studies and</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluations to determine adequacy, for 1 year beyond the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicability of these records to refrigerated products being</textblock>
    <textblock>produced by the processor, and for 2 years beyond the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicability of the records to frozen or preserved products</textblock>
    <textblock>being produced by the processor. The processor may need to</textblock>
    <textblock>obtain a written scientific evaluation of a process, such as a</textblock>
    <textblock>cooking, pasteurization, or cooling process, to ensure that the</textblock>
    <textblock>process it is using is adequate to destroy pathogens or to</textblock>
    <textblock>prevent their growth. Such an evaluation may also be necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>to ensure the adequacy of the cooking, pasteurizing, or</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigerating equipment that the processor is using. (See the</textblock>
    <textblock>preamble discussion on cooked, ready-to-eat fishery products.)</textblock>
    <textblock>As with processing records, these records should be retained for</textblock>
    <textblock>a period of time that reflects the period that the products to</textblock>
    <textblock>which they relate can be expected to be in commercial</textblock>
    <textblock>distribution.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA recognizes that some processing plants may be closed on</textblock>
    <textblock>a seasonal basis. Given the nature of the HACCP system, however,</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA may choose to inspect at least the records of a plant even if</textblock>
    <textblock>the plant is not in operation. Therefore, FDA is providing in</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed ยง123.8(c) that if a processing facility is closed</textblock>
    <textblock>between seasonal packs, the records may be transferred to some</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonably accessible location during the period of closure.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require in ยง123.8(d) that HACCP plans</textblock>
    <textblock>and records be available for review and copying by authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>agency employees at reasonable times. As already discussed, the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency's access to HACCP records is essential to ensure that the</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP system is working, and that the safety of seafood is being</textblock>
    <textblock>ensured by design. FDA's authority to require maintenance of</textblock>
    <textblock>these records, and to provide for agency access to them, is fully</textblock>
    <textblock>supported by the holding in</textblock>
    <textblock>National Confectioners Association</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Califano,</textblock>
    <textblock>569 F.2d 694-95 (D.C. Cir. 1978). In this case, the</textblock>
    <textblock>court recognized FDA's authority to impose recordkeeping</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements on firms that process foods when such requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>effectuate the goals of the act. See also</textblock>
    <textblock>Toilet Goods</textblock>
    <textblock>Association</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Gardner,</textblock>
    <textblock>387 U.S. 158, 163-164 (1967). The</textblock>
    <textblock>importance of the records in ensuring that fish and fishery</textblock>
    <textblock>products will not be rendered injurious to health has been fully</textblock>
    <textblock>discussed. FDA access to these records will expedite the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency's efforts to ensure that the fish and fishery products in</textblock>
    <textblock>interstate commerce are not adulterated and to identify any such</textblock>
    <textblock>products that are.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is aware that there is substantial public interest in</textblock>
    <textblock>the extent to which industry-generated HACCP records could or</textblock>
    <textblock>should be publicly available. As FDA understands it, the</textblock>
    <textblock>argument in favor of availability is that where an inspection</textblock>
    <textblock>system to protect the public health relies heavily on records,</textblock>
    <textblock>those records should be public to the maximum extent possible.</textblock>
    <textblock>The arguments in favor of protection of records, on the other</textblock>
    <textblock>hand, are based on concerns about advantages to competitors from</textblock>
    <textblock>disclosure and on the risk that the records will be otherwise</textblock>
    <textblock>misused if they become public. FDA invites comment on the</textblock>
    <textblock>general question of public disclosure of HACCP records and on the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency's preliminary analysis of their availability, as follows.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA has longstanding explicit statutory access to certain</textblock>
    <textblock>industry records during inspections involving infant formula,</textblock>
    <textblock>drugs, and devices and has access by regulation to certain</textblock>
    <textblock>processing records during inspections of low acid canned food</textblock>
    <textblock>processors. The agency has the right to copy and take possession</textblock>
    <textblock>of these records but does not routinely do so. FDA typically</textblock>
    <textblock>copies and takes possession of records only when they may be</textblock>
    <textblock>needed for regulatory purposes. As a preliminary matter, FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>expects to continue that practice with regard to seafood HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>records.</textblock>
    <textblock>The public availability of those HACCP records that FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>would possess as a result of copying during an inspection would</textblock>
    <textblock>be governed by section 301(j) of the act and by the Freedom of</textblock>
    <textblock>Information Act (FOIA) and regulations issued pursuant to it by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS) and FDA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 301(j) of the act expressly prohibits FDA from disclosing</textblock>
    <textblock>trade secret information obtained during the course of an</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection. The FOIA regulations also say that FDA will not</textblock>
    <textblock>divulge either trade secret or commercial confidential</textblock>
    <textblock>information. As a preliminary matter, HACCP plans and monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>records appear to fall within these two categories of protected</textblock>
    <textblock>records. As a consequence, FDA may well have little discretion</textblock>
    <textblock>in this area. Moreover, under DHHS' FOIA regulations, processors</textblock>
    <textblock>may be entitled to challenge in court a pending disclosure of</textblock>
    <textblock>records on the grounds that the records to be disclosed are</textblock>
    <textblock>commercial confidential or trade secret.</textblock>
    <textblock>As an additional matter, there are significant legal and</textblock>
    <textblock>practical questions as to whether FDA has the authority to</textblock>
    <textblock>require disclosure of industry records that are not in FDA's</textblock>
    <textblock>possession. As discussed elsewhere in this document, FDA does</textblock>
    <textblock>not contemplate the submission of HACCP plans or other records to</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA under these proposed regulations. The preapproval of HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>plans by FDA (and thus the submission of HACCP plans to FDA) is</textblock>
    <textblock>simply not practical. The agency has tentatively concluded that</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP plans and monitoring records will be reviewed on site by</textblock>
    <textblock>agency investigators as part of FDA's normal inspection regime.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
