<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00098</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00064</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>EPA announces the next steps in the development of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Leadership Program (ELP). After reviewing many</textblock>
    <textblock>possible options, the Agency has decided to proceed with pilot</textblock>
    <textblock>projects to test the feasibility of a voluntary program to</textblock>
    <textblock>recognize industrial facilities. The pilots will explore ways to</textblock>
    <textblock>encourage facilities to develop innovative audit and compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>programs and to reduce the risk of non-compliance through pollution</textblock>
    <textblock>prevention practices.</textblock>
    <textblock>The wide variety of public comments on the original ELP</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal (published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on January 15, 1993)</textblock>
    <textblock>clearly indicated an interest in a program to recognize and</textblock>
    <textblock>encourage ``environmental excellence.'' While no true consensus</textblock>
    <textblock>emerged on the best structure or goals for the program, several</textblock>
    <textblock>themes were common to the majority of the comments:</textblock>
    <textblock>•EPA should encourage companies and facilities of all</textblock>
    <textblock>sizes and from all industries to participate in the</textblock>
    <textblock>program.</textblock>
    <textblock>•EPA should focus its program on individual facilities</textblock>
    <textblock>rather than on entire corporations.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Any EPA-developed statement of environmental principles</textblock>
    <textblock>would duplicate existing private-sector efforts and would</textblock>
    <textblock>be difficult to enforce.</textblock>
    <textblock>In response to these comments, EPA has decided to continue</textblock>
    <textblock>developing a voluntary, facility-based program. The Agency will</textblock>
    <textblock>develop pilot projects with specific industries and states to</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluate the many unresolved issues raised during the comment</textblock>
    <textblock>period. These include a possible multiple-tier structure to</textblock>
    <textblock>encourage broad participation, determining the role of compliance,</textblock>
    <textblock>self-reporting of violations, public accountability, the role of</textblock>
    <textblock>incentives in encouraging companies to exceed minimum requirements,</textblock>
    <textblock>and how pollution prevention practices can help facilities reduce</textblock>
    <textblock>or avoid the risk of non-compliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA Deputy Administrator Bob Sussman and Steve Herman, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Assistant Administrator for the Office of Enforcement and</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance Assurance (OECA) have been asked to coordinate this</textblock>
    <textblock>effort. The Agency will provide more information on the process</textblock>
    <textblock>for selecting pilot participants and on the development of test</textblock>
    <textblock>projects in the early spring of 1994. The Office of Compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>within OECA will be responsible for this process. Please call Mike</textblock>
    <textblock>Schiavo at (202) 260-2824 for more information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also in response to the comments, the Agency has concluded</textblock>
    <textblock>that it will not issue its own guidelines for corporate</textblock>
    <textblock>environmental principles, but rather work cooperatively with the</textblock>
    <textblock>many other organizations that have developed corporate and</textblock>
    <textblock>industry-wide codes of environmental conduct. The Office of</textblock>
    <textblock>Pollution Prevention and Toxics will take responsibility for</textblock>
    <textblock>representing the Agency in this area, and for ensuring the</textblock>
    <textblock>involvement of other EPA offices where appropriate. Please call</textblock>
    <textblock>David Kling at (202) 260-3557 for more information. EPA thanks all</textblock>
    <textblock>of those who have expressed an interest in the ELP concept and</textblock>
    <textblock>looks forward to making this program an exciting and effective</textblock>
    <textblock>approach to pollution prevention and compliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4831-1]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Environmental Leadership Program: Update</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Carol M. Browner,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1953 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
