<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00114</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00076</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The companies listed in this notice have filed an application under  225.23(a)(1) of the Board's Regulation Y (12 CFR 225.23(a)(1)) for the Board's approval under section 4(c)(8) of the Bank Holding Company Act (12 U.S.C. 1843(c)(8)) and  225.21(a) of Regulation Y (12 CFR 225.21(a)) to commence or to engage</textblock>
    <textblock>de novo</textblock>
    <textblock>, either directly or through a subsidiary, in a nonbanking activity that is listed in  225.25 of Regulation Y as closely related to banking and permissible for bank holding companies. Unless otherwise noted, such activities will be conducted throughout the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each application is available for immediate inspection at the Federal Reserve Bank indicated. Once the application has been accepted for processing, it will also be available for inspection at the offices of the Board of Governors. Interested persons may express their views in writing on the question whether consummation of the proposal can ``reasonably be expected to produce benefits to the public, such as greater convenience, increased competition, or gains in efficiency, that outweigh possible adverse effects, such as undue concentration of resources, decreased or unfair competition, conflicts of interests, or unsound banking practices.'' Any request for a hearing on this question must be accompanied by a statement of the reasons a written presentation would not suffice in lieu of a hearing, identifying specifically any questions of fact that are in dispute, summarizing the evidence that would be presented at a hearing, and indicating how the party commenting would be aggrieved by approval of the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Unless otherwise noted, comments regarding the applications must be received at the Reserve Bank indicated or the offices of the Board of Governors not later than February 17, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta</textblock>
    <textblock>(Zane R. Kelley, Vice President) 104 Marietta Street, N.W., Atlanta, Georgia 30303:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. First Rainsville Bancshares, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Rainsville, Alabama; to engage</textblock>
    <textblock>de novo</textblock>
    <textblock>in making, acquiring, or servicing loans or other extensions of credit, through its finance company, First Finance Corporation, Rainsville, Alabama, pursuant to  225.25(b)(1) of the Board's Regulation Y.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis</textblock>
    <textblock>(James M. Lyon, Vice President) 250 Marquette Avenue, Minneapolis, Minnesota 55480:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. First Bank System, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Minneapolis, Minnesota; to engage</textblock>
    <textblock>de novo</textblock>
    <textblock>in data processing and data transmission services pursuant to  225.25(b)(7) of the Board's Regulation Y. These activities will be conducted in the States of Arizona, Texas, Florida, Kansas, Missouri, and Utah.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this application must be received by February 11, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, January 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>First Rainsville Bancshares, Inc., et al.; Notice of Applications to Engage de novo in Permissible Nonbanking Activities</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jennifer J. Johnson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Secretary of the Board.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1938 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6210-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
