<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00074</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00040</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463, 92-463, 86 Stat. 770), notice is hereby given of the following meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>Name:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Coal Council.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date and time:</textblock>
    <textblock>Thursday, February 17, 1994, 10:30-11:30 a.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>Stouffer Concourse Hotel, St. Louis, 9801 Natural Bridge Road, Berkely, MO 63134.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Margie D. Biggerstaff, U.S. Department of Energy, Office of Fossil Energy (FE-5), Washington, DC 20585, telephone: 202/586-3867.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose of the council:</textblock>
    <textblock>To provide advice, information, and recommendations to the Secretary of Energy on matters relating to coal and coal industry issues.</textblock>
    <textblock>Tentative agenda:</textblock>
    <textblock>_Call to order by William R. Wahl, Chairman of the National Coal Council.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Remarks by Chairman Wahl.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Report of the Coal Policy Committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Discussion and approval of the Council report ``Clean Coal Technology for Sustainable Development.''</textblock>
    <textblock>_Discussion of any other business properly brought before the Council.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Public comment_10-minute rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Adjournment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public participation:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting is open to the public. The Chairman of the Council is empowered to conduct the meeting in a fashion that will facilitate the orderly conduct of business. Any member of the public who wishes to file a written statement with the Council will be permitted to do so, either before or after the meeting. Members of the public who wish to make oral statements pertaining to agenda items should contact Margie D. Biggerstaff at the address or telephone number listed above. Requests must be received at least five days prior to the meeting and reasonable provisions will be made to include the presentation on the agenda.</textblock>
    <textblock>Transcript:</textblock>
    <textblock>Available for public review and copying at the Public Reading Room, room 1E-190, Forrestal Building, 1000 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC, between 9 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through Friday, except Federal holidays.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued at Washington, DC, on January 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Coal Council; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Marcia Morris,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Advisory Committee Management Officer.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1956 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
