<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00080</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00046</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 24, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 14, 1994, CNG Transmission Corporation (CNG), tendered for filing proposed changes in its FERC Gas Tariff, Second Revised Volume No. 1:</textblock>
    <textblock>First Revised Sheet No. 345</textblock>
    <textblock>CNG requests the Commission to allow this tariff sheet to become effective on January 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>CNG states that it is filing this sheet as required by the Commission's order dated December 30, 1993, in this proceeding. CNG further states that the effect of this filing is to update CNG's tariff provision describing its calculation of load factors for assessment of the research, development, and demonstration (RD&amp;D) program costs of the Gas Research Institute (GRI), in accordance with the methodology of the ``Stipulation and Agreement Concerning Post-1993 GRI Funding Mechanism'' (GRI Settlement), as approved by the Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>CNG states that copies of the filing were served upon CNG's jurisdictional customers and interested state commissions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to protest said filing should file a protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with 385.211 of the Commission's Rules and Regulations. All such protests should be filed on or before January 31, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection in the public reference room.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. TM94-3-22-001]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>CNG Transmission Corp.; Proposed Changes in FERC Gas Tariff</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1805 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
