<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00049</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require at §123.10(b) that processors</textblock>
    <textblock>maintain sanitation control records that document the occurrence</textblock>
    <textblock>and findings of the inspections required by §123.10(a) as well</textblock>
    <textblock>as the frequency required by §123.10(c). FDA is also proposing</textblock>
    <textblock>to require that the problems found during these inspections be</textblock>
    <textblock>corrected, and the corrections recorded in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed §123.10(d). Such corrections are essential to the</textblock>
    <textblock>proper working of the HACCP system. The records that are</textblock>
    <textblock>produced are subject to the recordkeeping requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed §123.8, including being subject to inspection by FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>investigators. FDA has tentatively concluded that HACCP-type</textblock>
    <textblock>preventive controls, including recordkeeping, will ensure that</textblock>
    <textblock>the hazards caused by insanitation are controlled by design.</textblock>
    <textblock>Recordkeeping is the key to an HACCP-type system. The agency's</textblock>
    <textblock>access to these records is essential to ensuring that the system</textblock>
    <textblock>is working.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to these proposed requirements, FDA is</textblock>
    <textblock>encouraging processors in §123.10(e) to have a written standard</textblock>
    <textblock>operating procedure for sanitation. The details of many</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitation procedures can differ from plant to plant depending</textblock>
    <textblock>upon the type of operation and other conditions. For example,</textblock>
    <textblock>how a piece of equipment should be cleaned can differ from plant</textblock>
    <textblock>to plant. In one plant, it may be necessary to disassemble all</textblock>
    <textblock>or part of the equipment in order to clean it. In other plants,</textblock>
    <textblock>breaking down the equipment may not be necessary. Likewise,</textblock>
    <textblock>different cleaning compounds may be needed from one plant to</textblock>
    <textblock>another in order to solve specialized problems such as buildups</textblock>
    <textblock>of mineral deposits. FDA is therefore encouraging each processor</textblock>
    <textblock>to study its own plant and develop a procedure that is tailored</textblock>
    <textblock>to that processor's needs and circumstances.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Evisceration of Raw Fish</textblock>
    <textblock>In 1988, following botulism outbreaks traced to consumption</textblock>
    <textblock>of kapchunka, FDA published compliance policy guide (CPG) 7108.17</textblock>
    <textblock>for salt-cured, air-dried, uneviscerated fish (53 FR 44949</textblock>
    <textblock>November 7, 1988). In this CPG, FDA stated that the processing</textblock>
    <textblock>and sale of smoked and salted uneviscerated fish products pose a</textblock>
    <textblock>potential health hazard, and that it would consider such products</textblock>
    <textblock>to be adulterated under section 402(a)(4) of the act in that they</textblock>
    <textblock>have been prepared, packed, or held under insanitary conditions</textblock>
    <textblock>whereby they may have been rendered injurious to health (Ref.</textblock>
    <textblock>175). FDA issued this CPG in an effort to prevent further</textblock>
    <textblock>outbreaks, as well as other potential health hazards, related to</textblock>
    <textblock>the consumption of ungutted fish products. The agency recognized</textblock>
    <textblock>only two exceptions: (1) Small species, such as anchovies and</textblock>
    <textblock>herring pieces (sprats), provided that they are processed by a</textblock>
    <textblock>method that will ensure a water-phase salt content of at least</textblock>
    <textblock>10 percent, a water activity below 0.85, or a pH of 4.6 or less;</textblock>
    <textblock>and (2) fish that are fully cooked before further processing.</textblock>
    <textblock>As previously noted,</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>, as well as other</textblock>
    <textblock>microorganisms, are naturally present in the intestinal tract of</textblock>
    <textblock>both fresh-water fish and marine fish. Therefore, it is</textblock>
    <textblock>essential not only to remove the viscera but to do so in a manner</textblock>
    <textblock>that does not contaminate the fish flesh with viscera contents.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is the viscera that can contain the majority of the hazardous</textblock>
    <textblock>microorganisms (e.g.,</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>L. monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>) that</textblock>
    <textblock>pose the potential health hazard (Refs. 165 through 167). After</textblock>
    <textblock>the viscera is removed, it must be discarded immediately to a</textblock>
    <textblock>segregated area, using a method that minimizes the potential for</textblock>
    <textblock>contamination or cross-contamination of utensils, equipment, raw</textblock>
    <textblock>materials, and other processed products.</textblock>
    <textblock>Uneviscerated fish that have been smoked, smoke-flavored, or</textblock>
    <textblock>salted, and that are intended to be filleted after processing,</textblock>
    <textblock>pose the same potential health hazard as those products sold as</textblock>
    <textblock>uneviscerated whole fish. The potential health hazard is created</textblock>
    <textblock>when the viscera is removed after processing. As the fish are</textblock>
    <textblock>being filleted, the viscera may be cut, and its contents may</textblock>
    <textblock>spill out, contaminating the processed fish. As a result, the</textblock>
    <textblock>opportunity arises for</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>spore outgrowth and toxin</textblock>
    <textblock>production as well as for growth of other food spoilage</textblock>
    <textblock>microorganisms in these types of products.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, the agency is proposing to require in §123.10(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>that, subject to the same limitations that were set forth in the</textblock>
    <textblock>CPG: (1) All fish for smoking or salting be eviscerated prior</textblock>
    <textblock>to processing, and (2) the process of evisceration must be</textblock>
    <textblock>performed in an area that is segregated and separate from other</textblock>
    <textblock>processing operations.</textblock>
    <textblock>H. Imported Seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>As stated earlier, imports make up over half of the seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>consumed in this country, in sharp contrast to meat and poultry,</textblock>
    <textblock>which are primarily domestically produced. Many of the hazards</textblock>
    <textblock>that can affect imported seafood are likely to occur before it</textblock>
    <textblock>enters the United States. These hazards include those that can</textblock>
    <textblock>be acquired from the environment before harvest and those that</textblock>
    <textblock>are process-induced. Detection of these hazards is the focus of</textblock>
    <textblock>the current regulatory system, and thus FDA tries to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>safety by testing imported product.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, product testing places a substantial burden on the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency. The system currently is overburdened because of limits</textblock>
    <textblock>on the number of government personnel available to collect and</textblock>
    <textblock>analyze samples of imported product. In addition, FDA is</textblock>
    <textblock>concerned because this system does not promote industry</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility and accountability the way an HACCP-based problem</textblock>
    <textblock>prevention system would. Given when most problems with imported</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood occur, these problems can be more efficiently controlled</textblock>
    <textblock>if the seafood is subject to HACCP controls before it is offered</textblock>
    <textblock>for import into this country than if the product is simply tested</textblock>
    <textblock>at the time that it is offered for sale. Therefore, FDA has</textblock>
    <textblock>tentatively concluded that these HACCP regulations should cover</textblock>
    <textblock>imported products in the same manner, to the extent possible,</textblock>
    <textblock>that they cover domestic products.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
