<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00128</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Example</textblock>
    <textblock>ABC Fish Co. receives shucked oysters from other</textblock>
    <textblock>processors. The firm examines the labels of the</textblock>
    <textblock>containers in each lot to learn the name, address, and</textblock>
    <textblock>certification number of the last processor. This</textblock>
    <textblock>information is compared to the current ICSSL to confirm</textblock>
    <textblock>that the product is from a certified processor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Containers from uncertified processors and inadequately</textblock>
    <textblock>labeled containers are rejected. The firm contacts the</textblock>
    <textblock>State Department of Health to confirm certification for</textblock>
    <textblock>unlisted processors.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency</textblock>
    <textblock>1. For finding the certification number: each lot or batch.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. For finding out if the processor is certified: each lot</textblock>
    <textblock>or batch.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. For rejecting uncertified molluscan shellfish: each</textblock>
    <textblock>batch that does not meet the critical limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>Critical Limits</textblock>
    <textblock>Zero tolerance for molluscan shellfish (i.e., accept no</textblock>
    <textblock>molluscan shellfish) from an uncertified processor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Zero tolerance for molluscan shellfish (i.e., accept no</textblock>
    <textblock>molluscan shellfish) packed in containers that do not list the</textblock>
    <textblock>name, address, and certification number of the last processor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Records</textblock>
    <textblock>Record for each lot or batch that shows the date of receipt,</textblock>
    <textblock>type and quantity of shellfish, and name and certification number</textblock>
    <textblock>of the last processor.</textblock>
    <textblock>Corrective Actions</textblock>
    <textblock>Destroy or recall product that does not meet the critical</textblock>
    <textblock>limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any critical limit deviation should cause a timely</textblock>
    <textblock>assessment by management to: Learn whether the process or HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>plan needs changing to reduce the risk of recurrence of the</textblock>
    <textblock>deviation, and take appropriate followup action.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
