<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00071</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00037</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Floodplain Statement of Findings for Proposed Installation of Bedrock and Unconsolidated Monitoring Wells at the K-25 Site, Oak Ridge, TN</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Energy (DOE).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Floodplain statement of findings.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a Floodplain Statement of Findings for proposed installation of bedrock and unconsolidated monitoring wells on the Oak Ridge K-25 Site. DOE proposes to drill four monitoring wells in the Poplar Creek Floodplain, located in Roane County, Tennessee. DOE prepared a Floodplain Assessment describing the effects, alternatives, and measures designed to avoid or minimize potential harm to or within the affected floodplain. DOE will endeavor to allow 15 days of public review after publication of the Statement of Findings before implementing the proposed action.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information on the proposed action (including maps of potentially disturbed floodplain areas) is available from: Mr. Robert C. Sleeman, Director, Environmental Restoration Division, Oak Ridge Operations Office, U.S. Department of Energy, Post Office Box 2001, Oak Ridge, Tennessee 37831-8541, (615) 576-0715, (615) 576-6074 (Fax).</textblock>
    <textblock>FURTHER INFORMATION ON GENERAL DOE FLOODPLAIN/WETLANDS ENVIRONMENTAL REVIEW REQUIREMENTS IS AVAILABLE FROM:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Carol M. Borgstrom, Director, Office of NEPA Oversight (EH-25), U.S. Department of Energy, 1000 Independence Avenue SW., Washington, DC 20585, (202) 586-4600 or (800) 472-2756.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a Floodplain Statement of Findings for the Proposed Installation of Bedrock and Unconsolidated Monitoring Wells on the Oak Ridge K-25 Site, prepared in accordance with 10 CFR part 1022. A Notice of Floodplain Involvement was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on October 4, 1993, and a floodplain assessment was prepared.</textblock>
    <textblock>To facilitate future remedial actions at the K-25 Site under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (CERCLA), DOE is proposing to drill four borings. Two borings would be into bedrock to depths ranging from approximately 30 to 150 feet, and the two other borings would be in the unconsolidated sediments overlying the bedrock to depths from approximately 15 to 50 feet. Two locations would be involved, with one bedrock and one unconsolidated monitoring well at each location. Each borehole would be converted to a monitoring well for the purpose of collecting hydrologic and water quality data. The wells are proposed to be located in the floodplain because the sites were selected to intersect and monitor subsurface flow paths near Poplar Creek.</textblock>
    <textblock>Alternatives to the proposed action included (1) No action, and (2) alternate sites. The no action alternative would result in DOE being unable to accurately measure possible contaminant releases to the local environment. Alternate sites away from Poplar Creek (outside of the floodplain) could not adequately monitor subsurface flow paths. The proposed action is necessary to enable DOE to pursue future remedial actions and meet the requirements of CERCLA. The assessment reveals that the installation of monitoring wells at the K-25 site would have no adverse impact on the 100-year floodplain of Poplar Creek, nor alter the existing normal channel cross section or storage capacity of Poplar Creek. No measures are needed to minimize potential harm to or within the affected floodplain. The proposed action would conform to applicable State or local floodplain protection standards. DOE will endeavor to allow 15 days of public review after publication of the Statement of Findings prior to implementing the proposed action.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>James J. Fiore,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Eastern Area Programs, Office of Environmental Restoration.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1955 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
