<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00100</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(s)</textblock>
    <textblock>Shucked shellfish</textblock>
    <textblock>means molluscan shellfish that have</textblock>
    <textblock>one or both shells removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(t)</textblock>
    <textblock>Tag</textblock>
    <textblock>means a record of harvesting information attached</textblock>
    <textblock>to a container of shellstock by the harvester or processor.</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.5</textblock>
    <textblock>Current good manufacturing practice (sanitation).</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The criteria in part 110 of this chapter apply in</textblock>
    <textblock>determining whether the facilities, methods, practices, and</textblock>
    <textblock>controls used to process fish and fishery products are safe, and</textblock>
    <textblock>whether these products have been processed under sanitary</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The purpose of subpart A of this part is to set forth</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements specific to the processing of fish and fishery</textblock>
    <textblock>products.</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.6</textblock>
    <textblock>Hazard Analysis Critical Control Point (HACCP) plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Every processor and importer shall have and implement a</textblock>
    <textblock>written HACCP plan that is specific to:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Each location where fish and fishery products are</textblock>
    <textblock>processed by that processor; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Each kind of fish and fishery product processed by the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor. The plan may group kinds of fish and fishery products</textblock>
    <textblock>together if the hazards, critical control points, critical</textblock>
    <textblock>limits, and procedures required to be identified in paragraph (b)</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section are identical for all fish and fishery products</textblock>
    <textblock>so grouped.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The HACCP plan shall:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Identify the safety hazards that are reasonably likely</textblock>
    <textblock>to occur and that thus must be controlled for each fish and</textblock>
    <textblock>fishery product, including, as appropriate:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Natural toxins;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Microbiological contamination;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Chemical contamination;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Pesticides;</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) Drug residues;</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) Decomposition;</textblock>
    <textblock>(vii) Parasites;</textblock>
    <textblock>(viii) Unapproved direct and indirect food and color</textblock>
    <textblock>additives; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ix) Physical hazards;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Identify the critical control points for each of the</textblock>
    <textblock>identified hazards;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Identify the critical limits that must be met at each</textblock>
    <textblock>of the critical control points;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Identify the procedures, and frequency thereof,</textblock>
    <textblock>including the use of consumer complaints received by the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor or importer, that will be used to control and monitor</textblock>
    <textblock>each of the critical control points to ensure compliance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>critical limits. Such procedures shall include the calibration</textblock>
    <textblock>of process control instruments and validation of software for</textblock>
    <textblock>computer control systems as appropriate;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Provide for a recordkeeping system that will document</textblock>
    <textblock>the monitoring of the critical control points. The records shall</textblock>
    <textblock>contain the actual values obtained during monitoring. The</textblock>
    <textblock>records shall also include consumer complaints that relate to the</textblock>
    <textblock>operation of critical control points or possible critical limit</textblock>
    <textblock>deviations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) In addition, the HACCP plan should:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Identify other consumer hazards not related to the</textblock>
    <textblock>safety of the product, including, but not necessarily limited to:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Decomposition not associated with human illness; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Economic adulteration.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Provide for control of these hazards in the manner</textblock>
    <textblock>described by paragraphs (b)(2) through (b)(5) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Failure of a processor or importer to have and</textblock>
    <textblock>implement an HACCP plan that complies with this section or to</textblock>
    <textblock>operate in accordance with the requirements of this part, shall</textblock>
    <textblock>render the products of that processor or importer adulterated</textblock>
    <textblock>under section 402(a)(4) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic</textblock>
    <textblock>Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.7</textblock>
    <textblock>Corrective actions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Any critical limit deviation shall require:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Segregation and holding of the affected product, at</textblock>
    <textblock>least until the requirements of paragraphs (a)(2) and (a)(3) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section are met;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Immediate review by an individual or individuals who</textblock>
    <textblock>have been trained in accordance with §123.9, to determine the</textblock>
    <textblock>acceptability of the lot in question for distribution, based on a</textblock>
    <textblock>judgment as to whether the deviation may have rendered the</textblock>
    <textblock>product in that lot injurious to health or otherwise adulterated;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Corrective action, when necessary, with respect to the</textblock>
    <textblock>affected product and the critical control point at which the</textblock>
    <textblock>deviation occurred;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Timely assessment by an individual or individuals who</textblock>
    <textblock>have been trained in accordance with §123.9, to determine</textblock>
    <textblock>whether the process or Hazard Analysis Critical Control Point</textblock>
    <textblock>(HACCP) plan needs to be modified to reduce the risk of</textblock>
    <textblock>recurrence of the deviation; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Modification when necessary as it applies to the</textblock>
    <textblock>process or HACCP plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) When a processor or importer receives a consumer</textblock>
    <textblock>complaint that may be related to the performance of a critical</textblock>
    <textblock>control point or that may reflect a critical limit deviation, it</textblock>
    <textblock>shall determine whether corrective action as described by</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (a) of this section is appropriate and, if so, it shall</textblock>
    <textblock>take such action.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) All actions required by paragraphs (a) and (b) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section shall be documented in records that are subject to the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of §123.8.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
