<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00052</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>To assist themselves in the implementation of their</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish laws, the States have formed the ISSC. The ISSC is an</textblock>
    <textblock>organization of State officials, representatives of Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies, and representatives of the shellfish industry. It</textblock>
    <textblock>provides guidance to the States and provides a forum for them to</textblock>
    <textblock>discuss their problems in attempting to ensure the sanitary</textblock>
    <textblock>control of shellfish handling and production (Ref. 97, p. 3).</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA evaluates State and international shellfish sanitation</textblock>
    <textblock>programs (Ref. 98, part I, p. 2). When it finds that the program</textblock>
    <textblock>is consistent with the NSSP, FDA accepts the State's or country's</textblock>
    <textblock>shipper certifications. FDA publishes the ``Interstate Certified</textblock>
    <textblock>Shellfish Shippers List'' monthly, in which it lists the</textblock>
    <textblock>approximately 2,000 shellfish dealers that have been certified by</textblock>
    <textblock>participating States.</textblock>
    <textblock>While FDA continues to believe in the cooperative</textblock>
    <textblock>partnership that it has established with the States, there is</textblock>
    <textblock>evidence that this system is not protecting the public health as</textblock>
    <textblock>well as it might (Refs. 7, p. 331; 99, p. iii; and 100).</textblock>
    <textblock>Problems can originate anywhere. As explained in the discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>above of the term ``lot of molluscan shellfish,'' the water from</textblock>
    <textblock>which shellfish are harvested plays a significant role in</textblock>
    <textblock>determining their safety. If they are harvested from</textblock>
    <textblock>unclassified or polluted waters, shellfish can be a vector of</textblock>
    <textblock>communicable disease. Problems can also occur as a result of</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions under which the shellfish are held on the harvest</textblock>
    <textblock>vessel, in the processing plant, or by subsequent handlers or</textblock>
    <textblock>repackers of shucked products.</textblock>
    <textblock>Given the current situation, FDA has tentatively determined</textblock>
    <textblock>that it is necessary for it to take steps to strengthen and</textblock>
    <textblock>provide additional support for the existing cooperative program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thus, FDA is proposing two measures.</textblock>
    <textblock>First, FDA is proposing to add ยง1240.60(b), which will</textblock>
    <textblock>require that all shellfish offered for transport or transported</textblock>
    <textblock>in interstate commerce bear a tag that lists the date, place,</textblock>
    <textblock>type, and quantity of shellfish, and by whom it was harvested,</textblock>
    <textblock>including the harvester's identification number. FDA is</textblock>
    <textblock>proposing this requirement because it has determined that a tag</textblock>
    <textblock>is the only means by which the agency can ensure that it will be</textblock>
    <textblock>possible to determine whether the shellfish have been taken from</textblock>
    <textblock>safe water. FDA is proposing to require that the place where the</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish were harvested be listed because it will enable a</textblock>
    <textblock>processor who receives the shellfish, or a regulatory official</textblock>
    <textblock>who inspects them, to determine whether they were taken from safe</textblock>
    <textblock>water.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require that the date when the shellfish</textblock>
    <textblock>were harvested be listed because, as discussed above, the</textblock>
    <textblock>shifting conditions in shellfish harvesting waters make shellfish</textblock>
    <textblock>safety virtually a day-to-day proposition. Therefore, when the</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish are harvested becomes a critical factor.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing that the type of shellfish e.g., oysters,</textblock>
    <textblock>clams, mussels, or scallops, and quantity be shown on the tag or</textblock>
    <textblock>bill of lading to ensure that the tag is applied only to the</textblock>
    <textblock>product to which it was initially affixed. Information on type</textblock>
    <textblock>and quantity of shellfish describes that product. FDA is</textblock>
    <textblock>proposing to require that the person by whom the shellfish were</textblock>
    <textblock>harvested be listed because that person has the most direct</textblock>
    <textblock>knowledge of where and when the shellfish were harvested and</textblock>
    <textblock>should be readily identifiable in case there are problems with</textblock>
    <textblock>the shellfish, so that quick action can be taken to meet the</textblock>
    <textblock>effect of any problem.</textblock>
    <textblock>Finally, FDA is proposing that the harvester identification</textblock>
    <textblock>number issued by the shellfish control authority be included to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide a means to confirm the harvester's identity and to obtain</textblock>
    <textblock>the harvester's local address in case of an illness investigation</textblock>
    <textblock>or followup to tagging and labeling discrepancies.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing this tagging requirement under section 361</textblock>
    <textblock>of the PHS Act. Under this section, the Surgeon General and, by</textblock>
    <textblock>delegation, FDA, is authorized to make and enforce such</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations as in FDA's judgment are necessary to prevent the</textblock>
    <textblock>introduction, transmission, or spread of communicable disease.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA tentatively finds that requiring a tag is a measure necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>to prevent the spread of communicable diseases because the tag</textblock>
    <textblock>will readily permit identification of those raw shellfish that</textblock>
    <textblock>were harvested from properly classified waters, and thus that</textblock>
    <textblock>will not be vectors of communicable disease in interstate</textblock>
    <textblock>commerce, and those that were not harvested from properly</textblock>
    <textblock>classified waters and thus that may be vectors of disease.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the PHS Act, FDA is also authorized to provide for</textblock>
    <textblock>such measures which in its judgment may be necessary to enforce</textblock>
    <textblock>the regulations that it adopts to prevent the spread of</textblock>
    <textblock>communicable diseases (section 361(a) of the PHS Act).</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, FDA is proposing to provide in ยง1240.60(b) for the</textblock>
    <textblock>seizure and destruction of any shellfish that are not properly</textblock>
    <textblock>tagged. Without the assurances provided by the tag, the</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish may bear a microorganism that may render them injurious</textblock>
    <textblock>to health. Thus, they are unfit for consumption and must be</textblock>
    <textblock>removed from the food supply.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
