<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00046</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The agency is proposing to require single-service towels or</textblock>
    <textblock>suitable hand drying devices to ensure that microbiological</textblock>
    <textblock>contamination does not occur though the repeated use of the same</textblock>
    <textblock>towel by several individuals. A hot-air blower is an example of</textblock>
    <textblock>a suitable hand drying device because contamination from</textblock>
    <textblock>individual to individual is eliminated.</textblock>
    <textblock>In §123.10(c)(3), the agency is proposing to require that</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection and documentation of the location of hand washing</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities be performed at sufficient frequency to ensure that</textblock>
    <textblock>there is compliance with §123.10(a)(8)(i). Generally, this</textblock>
    <textblock>procedure will be necessary only after construction or any</textblock>
    <textblock>significant building or process modification.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require in §123.10(c) that the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor inspect, and document that it has inspected, the hand</textblock>
    <textblock>washing and hand sanitizing facilities to ensure that they are</textblock>
    <textblock>properly equipped no less than once per day. This procedure will</textblock>
    <textblock>ensure that cleaning and sanitizing preparations, as well as</textblock>
    <textblock>towels or hand drying devices, are present whenever needed by</textblock>
    <textblock>employees.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require at §123.10 (a)(9) and (a)(10)</textblock>
    <textblock>that the processor protect the food, food-contact surfaces, and</textblock>
    <textblock>food packaging materials against adulteration by chemical and</textblock>
    <textblock>physical contaminants. Such protection is necessary to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>that the food produced by the processor is safe. The use of</textblock>
    <textblock>toxic compounds (e.g., pesticides, cleaning and sanitizing</textblock>
    <textblock>agents, and lubricants) is frequently necessary in the processing</textblock>
    <textblock>environment. For example, lubricants and fuel are necessary to</textblock>
    <textblock>operate equipment. Improper use of these compounds is a frequent</textblock>
    <textblock>cause of product adulteration throughout the food industry (Ref.</textblock>
    <textblock>74). Thus, it is necessary to ensure that food, food-contact</textblock>
    <textblock>surfaces, and food packaging materials are not contaminated by</textblock>
    <textblock>these toxic compounds. Food and food packaging material should</textblock>
    <textblock>be protected or removed from areas where pesticides are used, and</textblock>
    <textblock>caustic cleaning compounds should be thoroughly removed from</textblock>
    <textblock>food-contact surfaces before processing begins. Finally, as an</textblock>
    <textblock>additional protection, FDA is proposing to require in</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.10(a)(10) that toxic compounds be labeled, held, and used</textblock>
    <textblock>in a manner that minimizes the risk of contamination of the</textblock>
    <textblock>product.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require in §123.10(c) that the</textblock>
    <textblock>processing plant be inspected daily to ensure that the food is</textblock>
    <textblock>protected from toxic compounds, and that this inspection be</textblock>
    <textblock>documented. This check should normally be performed before the</textblock>
    <textblock>start of operations, at a time when the equipment can be</textblock>
    <textblock>effectively inspected, and in time to prevent adulteration of the</textblock>
    <textblock>product. Because processing conditions vary on a day-to-day</textblock>
    <textblock>basis, FDA has tentatively concluded that daily inspection is</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require at §123.10(a)(11) that the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor ensure that products are not exposed to contaminants</textblock>
    <textblock>that may drip, drain, or be drawn into the food. An example of</textblock>
    <textblock>such a contaminant is condensate, which may form on the ceilings</textblock>
    <textblock>and equipment in a processing plant. If the condensate forms on</textblock>
    <textblock>an insanitary surface and then falls on the product, it may carry</textblock>
    <textblock>with it filth and microbiological contaminants from that surface</textblock>
    <textblock>to the food (Ref. 65, pp. 24 and 25).</textblock>
    <textblock>In §123.10(c), the agency is proposing to require that the</textblock>
    <textblock>processing plant be inspected daily to ensure that the potential</textblock>
    <textblock>for such contamination is minimized, and that this inspection be</textblock>
    <textblock>documented. This check should normally be performed during the</textblock>
    <textblock>actual operations, at a time when condensate or other such</textblock>
    <textblock>contaminating conditions are likely to be present. As explained</textblock>
    <textblock>above, the agency has tentatively concluded that daily variations</textblock>
    <textblock>in processing and climatic conditions necessitate daily</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection.</textblock>
    <textblock>In §123.10(a)(12), the agency is proposing to require that</textblock>
    <textblock>the processor ensure that compressed gases that contact food or</textblock>
    <textblock>food-contact surfaces of equipment are filtered or treated in</textblock>
    <textblock>such a way that the food is not contaminated with unapproved</textblock>
    <textblock>indirect food additives or other chemical, physical, or</textblock>
    <textblock>microbiological contaminants. Compressed gases can be</textblock>
    <textblock>contaminated with oil from the compressor, filth and</textblock>
    <textblock>microbiological contaminants from the air intake, and rust or</textblock>
    <textblock>other physical contaminants from the compression, storage, and</textblock>
    <textblock>distribution equipment. Filtration at the air intake and after</textblock>
    <textblock>compression, storage, and distribution is an effective means of</textblock>
    <textblock>reducing the risk of such contaminants entering the food (Ref.</textblock>
    <textblock>89).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
