<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00069</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The processing of these fish basically involves: (1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Cleaning and gutting followed by (2) immersion in a brine</textblock>
    <textblock>solution or dry salt in order to salt them, (3) drying in a cool</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature to avoid bacterial growth, (4) smoking in a smoking</textblock>
    <textblock>chamber at a temperature and for a time necessary to achieve the</textblock>
    <textblock>desired ``cold process'' or ``hot process'' effect, and (5)</textblock>
    <textblock>packaging and cooling. The taste and texture qualities</textblock>
    <textblock>attributable to ``cold process'' smoked fish require much lower</textblock>
    <textblock>temperatures during the smoking phase of the process than those</textblock>
    <textblock>attributable to ``hot process.'' Salted fish may not be smoked at</textblock>
    <textblock>all.</textblock>
    <textblock>As with virtually all fish, the species used to make smoked</textblock>
    <textblock>fish are exposed during their lives to</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>, a spore-</textblock>
    <textblock>forming bacterium that is ubiquitous in the marine and freshwater</textblock>
    <textblock>environment. Type E is the predominant type of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>found in fish, other aquatic animals, water, and sediment,</textblock>
    <textblock>although other types such as A, proteolytic and nonproteolytic B,</textblock>
    <textblock>C, D, and F also have been found in fish (Refs. 148 through 152).</textblock>
    <textblock>The concentration of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>spores that may be expected in</textblock>
    <textblock>and on a naturally contaminated fish is unknown, although it is reported to vary from one spore per 16 g of fish to one spore per</textblock>
    <textblock>200 g (Refs. 153 and 180).</textblock>
    <textblock>Under certain conditions,</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>can produce a toxin</textblock>
    <textblock>that causes botulism, a disease that attacks the central nervous</textblock>
    <textblock>system of humans and can cause death within 3 to 6 days of</textblock>
    <textblock>ingestion if not properly treated (Ref. 193).</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum's</textblock>
    <textblock>ability to form spores means that in a dormant state, it can</textblock>
    <textblock>survive environments that are otherwise hostile to it.</textblock>
    <textblock>C.</textblock>
    <textblock>botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>is ``anaerobic,'' meaning that air constitutes a hostile</textblock>
    <textblock>environment. When conditions become favorable, that is, when no</textblock>
    <textblock>air is present, the spores experience ``outgrowth'' during which</textblock>
    <textblock>toxin can be produced. In fish,</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>spores are found in</textblock>
    <textblock>the intestines and can also adhere to the surface of fish.</textblock>
    <textblock>For these reasons,</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>can be found in the</textblock>
    <textblock>environment of most any fish processor and cannot be totally</textblock>
    <textblock>eliminated using reasonable means. Moreover, even though a fish</textblock>
    <textblock>might be cleaned, gutted, and air packaged, some risk will still</textblock>
    <textblock>exist because</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>spores can find their way into muscle</textblock>
    <textblock>tissue during processing. Muscle tissue below the surface of the</textblock>
    <textblock>fish can provide an anaerobic environment where outgrowth and</textblock>
    <textblock>toxin production can occur if time and temperature permit.</textblock>
    <textblock>Although the processing procedures in Appendix 1 are based</textblock>
    <textblock>on studies of the time-temperature and salinity conditions</textblock>
    <textblock>required to prevent the outgrowth of botulinum spores, these</textblock>
    <textblock>practices are also effective in the elimination of risk from</textblock>
    <textblock>other pathogenic bacteria such as</textblock>
    <textblock>L. monocytogenes. L.</textblock>
    <textblock>monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>is a pathogenic bacterium that is widespread in the</textblock>
    <textblock>environment and that is commonly isolated from surface waters and</textblock>
    <textblock>other environmental samples. Thus the likelihood of finding this</textblock>
    <textblock>pathogen on the exterior surfaces and viscera of fish is high.</textblock>
    <textblock>Since 1983, several large outbreaks of human listeriosis have</textblock>
    <textblock>been linked to the consumption of contaminated foods (Refs. 130,</textblock>
    <textblock>131, and 132), thereby demonstrating the etiologic importance of</textblock>
    <textblock>foodborne transmission of this disease in humans.</textblock>
    <textblock>Although listeriosis is a relatively rare illness</textblock>
    <textblock>(approximately 2,000 reported cases per year in the United</textblock>
    <textblock>States), the exceptionally high mortality rate, as high as 34</textblock>
    <textblock>percent, makes this illness one of the leading fatal foodborne</textblock>
    <textblock>diseases in the United States. The highest incidence of</textblock>
    <textblock>listeriosis generally occurs in neonates, the elderly, pregnant</textblock>
    <textblock>women, and individuals suffering from compromised immune systems.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, there are instances in which apparently healthy</textblock>
    <textblock>individuals have contracted listeriosis (Refs. 130 and 133).</textblock>
    <textblock>The incidence of</textblock>
    <textblock>Listeria</textblock>
    <textblock>species (including</textblock>
    <textblock>L.</textblock>
    <textblock>monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>) in frozen raw and cooked seafood products is</textblock>
    <textblock>reportedly as high as 61 percent (Ref. 136). Indeed, numerous</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood products have been shown to support growth of</textblock>
    <textblock>L.</textblock>
    <textblock>monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>(Refs. 137 and 138).</textblock>
    <textblock>L. monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>is capable</textblock>
    <textblock>of prolific growth on smoked salmon stored at 4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C, even when</textblock>
    <textblock>test inocula as low as 6 organisms per gram (g) are applied to</textblock>
    <textblock>the surface of fish samples (Ref. 139). Seafoods other than</textblock>
    <textblock>smoked or smoke-flavored fish have been epidemiologically linked</textblock>
    <textblock>to two outbreaks and one sporadic case of listeriosis (Ref. 140).</textblock>
    <textblock>Furthermore, several cooked seafood products have been recalled</textblock>
    <textblock>from the market in North America because of contamination with</textblock>
    <textblock>L.</textblock>
    <textblock>monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>, but these crises did not involve smoked or smoke-</textblock>
    <textblock>flavored fish products.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
