<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00135</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>e. For dry salting, the fish should be returned to a</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigerated area of 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or lower immediately after</textblock>
    <textblock>the application of the salt.</textblock>
    <textblock>f. Different species of fish and fish of dissimilar size</textblock>
    <textblock>and weight should not be mixed in the same brining tank.</textblock>
    <textblock>g. Brines should not be reused unless they are subject to a</textblock>
    <textblock>process that effectively returns them to a microbiological</textblock>
    <textblock>condition equivalent to the original, unused brine made with</textblock>
    <textblock>potable water and food-grade salt.</textblock>
    <textblock>h. Fish may be rinsed with potable water after brining.</textblock>
    <textblock>i. Drying of a product to be cold-smoked should be carried</textblock>
    <textblock>out in a refrigerated area at 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below.</textblock>
    <textblock>j. Smoking operation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Fish should be arranged without overcrowding and</textblock>
    <textblock>without touching each other within the smokehouse oven or chamber</textblock>
    <textblock>to permit uniform smoke absorption, heat exposure, and</textblock>
    <textblock>dehydration. Fish smoked in the same smoke chamber load should</textblock>
    <textblock>be of relatively uniform size and weight.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Liquid smoke, generated smoke, or a combination of</textblock>
    <textblock>liquid smoke and generated smoke needs to be applied to all</textblock>
    <textblock>surfaces of the product. Liquid smoke may be applied to the</textblock>
    <textblock>product before, at the beginning, or during the process. If only</textblock>
    <textblock>generated smoke is to be used, it needs to be applied to the fish</textblock>
    <textblock>during the first half of the process. If a combination of liquid</textblock>
    <textblock>smoke and generated smoke is used, the generated smoke may be</textblock>
    <textblock>applied at any stage of the process.</textblock>
    <textblock>k. Each smoking chamber should be equipped with a</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature recording device to indicate the temperature of the</textblock>
    <textblock>air and of the fish within the smoking chamber. Additionally,</textblock>
    <textblock>each chamber should be equipped with a temperature indicating</textblock>
    <textblock>device to indicate the temperature of the air within the smoking</textblock>
    <textblock>chamber.</textblock>
    <textblock>l. During hot-smoking or cold-smoking, a temperature</textblock>
    <textblock>recording device should be used to monitor both the internal</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature of the fish and the ambient temperature of the</textblock>
    <textblock>smoking chamber. The internal temperature readings should be</textblock>
    <textblock>obtained by inserting probes from the temperature recording</textblock>
    <textblock>device into the thickest flesh portion of three or more of the</textblock>
    <textblock>largest fish in the smoking chamber. The temperature from the</textblock>
    <textblock>slowest heating fish should be considered the processing</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Post-Smoking</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Cooling after smoking.</textblock>
    <textblock>After smoking, the product needs</textblock>
    <textblock>to be rapidly cooled to minimize recontamination. Continuous</textblock>
    <textblock>cooling from 140</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (60</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) to achieve an internal temperature of</textblock>
    <textblock>70</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (21.1</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below within 2 hours and an internal</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature of 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below within an additional 4</textblock>
    <textblock>hours, unless processing after smoking as described in section</textblock>
    <textblock>6.b. of this Appendix, occurs during either of these time</textblock>
    <textblock>periods, will effectively minimize recontamination. Other</textblock>
    <textblock>time/temperature parameters may also be effective. Processors</textblock>
    <textblock>should ensure that the cooling parameters are met by either:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring and recording internal product</textblock>
    <textblock>temperatures at least every 2 hours; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Studies.</textblock>
    <textblock>i. Conducting or obtaining a study that establishes that</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate cooling temperatures are always met under prescribed</textblock>
    <textblock>processing conditions. The study should establish the limits of</textblock>
    <textblock>significant variables that could affect the rate of cooling.</textblock>
    <textblock>These variables may include product size, ambient air</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature, and amount of product in the cooler. An adequate</textblock>
    <textblock>study should consist of at least three processing runs under the prescribed processing</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions; and</textblock>
    <textblock>ii. Monitoring and recording the prescribed processing</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions as identified by the study in section 6.a.2.i. of this</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix at least every 2 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Processing after smoking.</textblock>
    <textblock>Products that will receive</textblock>
    <textblock>processing after smoking should not be exposed to ambient</textblock>
    <textblock>temperatures of 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or higher for longer than a</textblock>
    <textblock>cumulative total of 4 hours after smoking. If they are exposed</textblock>
    <textblock>to such temperatures for more than 4 hours, unacceptable</textblock>
    <textblock>recontamination is the likely result. Processors are required to</textblock>
    <textblock>regularly monitor and record the length of time that the product</textblock>
    <textblock>is exposed to temperatures above 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) under 21 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>123.8. FDA recommends that such monitoring and recording be done</textblock>
    <textblock>at least every 2 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>c.</textblock>
    <textblock>Final product cooling.</textblock>
    <textblock>To avoid microbiological hazards</textblock>
    <textblock>for perishable finished products, the internal temperature of the</textblock>
    <textblock>finished product should be 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below within 4 hours</textblock>
    <textblock>of placement in a finished product container. Processors should</textblock>
    <textblock>either conduct:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitor and record internal product</textblock>
    <textblock>temperatures at least every 2 hours; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Studies.</textblock>
    <textblock>i. Conduct or obtain a study that establishes that the</textblock>
    <textblock>internal temperature of the finished product will always be 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F</textblock>
    <textblock>(4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below within 4 hours of placement in a finished</textblock>
    <textblock>product container under prescribed processing conditions. The</textblock>
    <textblock>study should establish the limits of significant variables that</textblock>
    <textblock>could affect the rate of cooling. These variables may include</textblock>
    <textblock>product size, ambient air temperature, and amount of product in</textblock>
    <textblock>the cooler. An adequate study should consist of at least three</textblock>
    <textblock>processing runs under the prescribed processing conditions; and</textblock>
    <textblock>ii. Monitoring and recording the prescribed processing</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions as identified by the study in section 6.c.2.i. of this</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix at least every 2 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Refrigerated storage.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) In-process products.</textblock>
    <textblock>Refrigeration units that are</textblock>
    <textblock>being used to store in-process products or finished products must</textblock>
    <textblock>operate at a temperature of 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below in accordance</textblock>
    <textblock>with 21 CFR 123.10(a)(14).</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Temperature devices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Units should be equipped with</textblock>
    <textblock>both a temperature-indicating device and a temperature-recording</textblock>
    <textblock>device. In lieu of a temperature-recording device, a processor</textblock>
    <textblock>may equip a refrigeration unit with a high temperature alarm or a</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum-indicating thermometer and maintain a temperature log</textblock>
    <textblock>that notes temperature with such frequency as is necessary to</textblock>
    <textblock>achieve control.</textblock>
    <textblock>e.</textblock>
    <textblock>Distribution.</textblock>
    <textblock>All perishable finished products should</textblock>
    <textblock>be distributed in a manner that ensures that the internal</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature is maintained at 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Temperature Monitoring Equipment</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
