<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00004</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>District</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>7_The State of Arizona, the remainder of the State of California, including San Luis Obispo, Kern, and San Bernardino counties, and the State of New Mexico.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board has recommended that the new districts become effective for the three-year term of office which begins on January 1, 1995. If adopted, this proposal would affect the eligibility of three current Board members and could necessitate Board member nomination meetings for Districts 4, 5, 6, and 7 in spring 1994. In the normal cycle of nominating approximately one-third of the Board members each year, spring 1994 nomination meetings were already planned for Districts 2 and 3.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, if this proposal is adopted, it will be necessary to make a conforming change to §1210.401. Section 1210.401 currently states that the districts are defined in §1210.320 of the Plan. Since, this rule would define new district boundaries in a new §1210.501, this rule would also change §1210.401(b) to reflect this new section number.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 7 CFR Part 1210</textblock>
    <textblock>Advertising, Agricultural practice and procedure, Agricultural research, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Watermelons.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set forth in the preamble, part 1210, chapter XI of title 7 is proposed to be amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 1210_WATERMELON RESEARCH AND PROMOTION PLAN</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for 7 CFR Part 1210 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>7 U.S.C. 4901-4916.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. In §1210.401(b), the words ``1210.320'' in the last sentence are revised to read ``1210.501''.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. A new §1210.501 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§1210.501</textblock>
    <textblock>Realignment of districts.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to §1210.320(c) of the Plan, the districts shall be as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>District</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>1_South Florida, including all areas south of State Highway 50.</textblock>
    <textblock>District</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>2_North Florida, including all areas north of State Highway 50.</textblock>
    <textblock>District</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>3_The States of Alabama, Georgia, and Mississippi.</textblock>
    <textblock>District</textblock>
    <textblock>#4</textblock>
    <textblock>_The States of Connecticut, Delaware, Indiana, Kentucky, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, Michigan,</textblock>
    <textblock>New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, North Carolina, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, South Carolina, Tennessee, Vermont, Virginia, and West Virginia.</textblock>
    <textblock>District</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>5_The States of California_north of San Luis Obispo, Kern, and San Bernardino counties, Colorado, Idaho, Illinois, Iowa, Kansas, Minnesota, Missouri, Montana, Nebraska, Nevada, North Dakota, Oklahoma, Oregon, South Dakota, Utah, Washington, Wisconsin, and Wyoming.</textblock>
    <textblock>District</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>6_The States of Arkansas, Louisiana, and Texas.</textblock>
    <textblock>District</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>7_The State of Arizona, the remainder of the State of California, including San Luis Obispo, Kern, and San Bernardino counties, and the State of New Mexico.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 20, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lon Hatamiya,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1905 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
