<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00160</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00102</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>PLANNING PROTESTS</textblock>
    <textblock>: Any party that participated in the plan amendment and is adversely affected by the amendment may protest this action only as it affects issues submitted for the record during the planning process. The protest shall be in writing and filed with the Director (760), Bureau of Land Management, 1800 ``C'' Street, NW., Washington, DC 20240, within 30 days of publication of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>SALE AND LAND EXCHANGE COMMENTS:</textblock>
    <textblock>For a period of 45 days from the publication of this notice, interested parties may submit comments regarding the sales or land exchange to the District Manager, Bureau of Land Management, 3948 Development Ave., Boise, ID 83705. Objections will be reviewed by the State Director who may sustain, vacate, or modify this realty action. In the absence of any planning protests or objections regarding the land exchange, this realty action will become the final determination of the Department of Interior and the planning amendment will be in effect.</textblock>
  </text>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Upon publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, any lands described above which are not already segregated will be segregated from appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining laws, except the sale and exchange provisions of FLPMA. The segregative effect will end upon issuance of patent or 270 days for sales and 2 years for exchanges from the date of publication, whichever occurs first.</textblock>
    <textblock>Lands to be transferred from the United States will be subject to the following reservations, terms, and conditions:</textblock>
    <textblock>EXCEPTING AND RESERVING TO THE UNITED STATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. A right-of-way thereon for ditches and canals constructed by the authority of the United States, Act of August 30, 1890 (43 U.S.C. 945). Sales IDI-29240 and IDI-28798:</textblock>
    <textblock>2. All oil, gas, and geothermal resources thereon together with the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the minerals.</textblock>
    <textblock>SUBJECT TO:</textblock>
    <textblock>Sale IDI-29240 to Canyon County shall also include:</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Those rights for a communication site, access road and powerline granted to Radio Paging Service, its successors or assigns by Right-of-Way IDI-23106, under the Act of October 21, 1976 (90 Stat. 2776; 43 U.S.C. 1761). Private Exchange IDI-29145:</textblock>
    <textblock>4. The following rights-of-way of record: IDI-20004 granted to Merle and Jean Long for a road and IDI-20976 granted to U.S. West Communications for a buried telephone line, both under the Act of October 21, 1976 (90 Stat. 2776; 43 U.S.C. 1761); and IDI-20038 asserted by the Ada County Highway District under Revised Statute 2477 (43 U.S.C. 932).</textblock>
    <textblock>Continued use of the land by valid right-of-way holders or their successors or assigns is proper subject to the terms and condition of the grant. Administrative responsibility previously held by the United States will be assumed by the patentee.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 20, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Barry C. Cushing,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>District Manager.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1686 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-GG-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
