<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00019</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>7. Establish Procedures to Verify That the HACCP System Is</textblock>
    <textblock>Working</textblock>
    <textblock>This process involves: (1) Verifying that the critical</textblock>
    <textblock>limits are adequate to control the hazards; (2) ensuring that the</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP plan is working properly, e.g., that it is being followed,</textblock>
    <textblock>and that appropriate decisions are being made about corrective</textblock>
    <textblock>actions; and (3) ensuring that there is documented, periodic</textblock>
    <textblock>revalidation of the plan to make sure that it is still relevant</textblock>
    <textblock>to raw materials as well as to conditions and processes in the</textblock>
    <textblock>plant. Government regulatory activities also help ensure that</textblock>
    <textblock>the HACCP system is working.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Specific Applications to Seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>As NAS has pointed out, most health risks associated with</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood originate in the environment (Ref. 7, p. 1). Many of</textblock>
    <textblock>these risks are the subject of research by FDA, the National</textblock>
    <textblock>Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) of the Department</textblock>
    <textblock>of Commerce, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and</textblock>
    <textblock>others. This research is designed both to produce information</textblock>
    <textblock>that will provide a better understanding of the toxins, bacteria,</textblock>
    <textblock>chemical contaminants, and other phenomena and to provide a basis</textblock>
    <textblock>for developing more advanced types of controls for them. Within</textblock>
    <textblock>the limits of existing scientific knowledge, however, the</textblock>
    <textblock>industry can and should use HACCP to control the source and</textblock>
    <textblock>condition of raw materials based on an understanding of the</textblock>
    <textblock>likely hazards that need to be prevented.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Pillsbury team that first applied HACCP to food</textblock>
    <textblock>production began with a systematic review of raw materials to</textblock>
    <textblock>ensure that they were not bringing hazards into the plant. As</textblock>
    <textblock>Bauman pointed out:</textblock>
    <textblock>This required the development of a</textblock>
    <textblock>familiarity with the raw materials that was</textblock>
    <textblock>not a normal process in food product</textblock>
    <textblock>development *␣*␣*. The areas of concern</textblock>
    <textblock>ranged from the potential presence of</textblock>
    <textblock>pathogens, heavy metals, toxins, physical</textblock>
    <textblock>hazards and chemicals, to the type of</textblock>
    <textblock>treatments the ingredients might have</textblock>
    <textblock>received such as pesticide applications or a</textblock>
    <textblock>pasteurization step. (Ref. 33, pp. 2 and 3.)</textblock>
    <textblock>While all these areas that were of concern to Pillsbury are not</textblock>
    <textblock>germane to all seafoods, they certainly cover the range of</textblock>
    <textblock>hazards to which seafoods are susceptible.</textblock>
    <textblock>Of the three most frequently reported seafood-related</textblock>
    <textblock>illnesses, two are environmentally related: ciguatera in warm</textblock>
    <textblock>water reef fish, as described previously, and water-borne viruses</textblock>
    <textblock>in molluscan shellfish consumed raw and partially cooked. While</textblock>
    <textblock>a rapid test to detect ciguatoxin in fish continues to be the</textblock>
    <textblock>target of research at FDA and elsewhere, processors and importers</textblock>
    <textblock>can exercise control by ensuring that they are obtaining fish</textblock>
    <textblock>from responsible sources that are not harvesting from waters</textblock>
    <textblock>where ciguatoxin is being found.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ciguatera has been associated with recreational fishing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Processors and importers should address through HACCP any safety</textblock>
    <textblock>considerations that might exist with the commercial sale of</textblock>
    <textblock>recreational catch generally, depending upon species and locale.</textblock>
    <textblock>For viruses from molluscan shellfish to be controlled, HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>measures must be in place to ensure that molluscan shellfish</textblock>
    <textblock>harvested from polluted waters are not entering commerce. Other</textblock>
    <textblock>key safety controls relate to proper refrigeration to keep</textblock>
    <textblock>potentially harmful microbes from reaching dangerous levels.</textblock>
    <textblock>The third seafood-related illness, scombroid poisoning, is</textblock>
    <textblock>caused by a toxin created as part of the process of decomposition</textblock>
    <textblock>after a fish has died. The formation of scombrotoxin can be</textblock>
    <textblock>triggered by time/temperature abuse anywhere in the commercial</textblock>
    <textblock>system and beyond, including as early as on the harvesting vessel</textblock>
    <textblock>if good handling controls are not followed.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is considering whether to develop good handling practice</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements (not necessarily HACCP) specific to fishing vessels</textblock>
    <textblock>and invites comment on this matter. FDA has traditionally</textblock>
    <textblock>refrained from directly regulating fishing vessels, largely</textblock>
    <textblock>because of the huge number of such vessels in the U.S. fleet,</textblock>
    <textblock>even though it has authority to do so. FDA invites comment on</textblock>
    <textblock>whether those boats that harvest scombrotoxin-forming species, or</textblock>
    <textblock>any other specific component of the fleet, should be subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>mandatory HACCP controls.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
