<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00089</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(2) FDA also specifically requests comments on the number</textblock>
    <textblock>of cases of illness included in the baseline estimate (33,035)</textblock>
    <textblock>that may be due to factors outside the processors' control, such</textblock>
    <textblock>as those due to recreational harvests (that are not eventually</textblock>
    <textblock>sent to processors), those due to restaurants and supermarkets,</textblock>
    <textblock>and those due to consumer mishandling.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) As mentioned above, FDA has also estimated potential</textblock>
    <textblock>benefits associated with increased seafood consumption. These</textblock>
    <textblock>benefits will only be realized if the price increase resulting</textblock>
    <textblock>from this rule does not offset the effect of increased demand for</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood which will result from reduced consumer anxiety. FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>requests specific comment on the likelihood that seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>consumption will be increased as a result of this rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) FDA has identified but not quantified benefits to</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood exporters as well as reduced public anxiety associated</textblock>
    <textblock>with the safety of seafood. FDA requests comments on these</textblock>
    <textblock>benefits (including how to quantify them) as well as other</textblock>
    <textblock>potential benefits such as how HACCP will help firms gain better</textblock>
    <textblock>control over their operations, better sanitation and greater</textblock>
    <textblock>efficiencies such as reduced product waste.</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Tribal Governments</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is aware that some tribal governments are involved in</textblock>
    <textblock>the processing of seafood for interstate commerce. The agency</textblock>
    <textblock>expects that the proposed regulations will apply to them in such</textblock>
    <textblock>cases. Executive Order 12875 of October 26, 1993, requires,</textblock>
    <textblock>among other things, consultation with tribal governments before</textblock>
    <textblock>the formal promulgation of regulations containing unfunded</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal mandates. While FDA does not believe that the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations would impose an unfunded Federal mandate, the agency</textblock>
    <textblock>wishes to foster consultation on matters that might significantly</textblock>
    <textblock>affect tribal communities. Consequently, FDA specifically</textblock>
    <textblock>requests comment on the economic effect of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations on tribal governments.</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Availability of PRIA/RFA</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA acknowledges considerable uncertainty in both cost and</textblock>
    <textblock>benefit estimates of the proposed regulations and requests</textblock>
    <textblock>comment on all aspects of the PRIA and the RFA. The full</textblock>
    <textblock>PRIA/RIA is available at the Dockets Management Branch (address</textblock>
    <textblock>above).</textblock>
    <textblock>XI. Environmental Impact</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency has carefully considered the potential</textblock>
    <textblock>environmental effects of this action. FDA has concluded that the</textblock>
    <textblock>action will not have a significant impact on the human</textblock>
    <textblock>environment, and that an environmental impact statement is not</textblock>
    <textblock>required. The agency's finding of no significant impact and the</textblock>
    <textblock>evidence supporting that finding, contained in an environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>assessment, may be seen in the Dockets Management Branch (address</textblock>
    <textblock>above) between 9 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through Friday.</textblock>
    <textblock>XII. Request for Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons may, on or before April 28, 1994, submit</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Dockets Management Branch (address above) written comments</textblock>
    <textblock>regarding this proposal. Two copies of any comments are to be</textblock>
    <textblock>submitted, except that individuals may submit one copy. Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>are to be identified with the docket number found in brackets in</textblock>
    <textblock>the heading of this document. Received comments may be seen in</textblock>
    <textblock>the office above between 9 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through</textblock>
    <textblock>Friday.</textblock>
    <textblock>XIII. References</textblock>
    <textblock>The following references have been placed on display in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Dockets Management Branch (address above) and may be seen by</textblock>
    <textblock>interested persons between 9 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through</textblock>
    <textblock>Friday.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
