<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00033</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>6. Critical Control Points</textblock>
    <textblock>Consistent with the HACCP principles identified by NACMCF,</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require in §123.6(b)(2) that critical</textblock>
    <textblock>control points be identified for each of the hazards that the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor or importer has identified. Hazards may be caused by</textblock>
    <textblock>improper processing or by events outside the processor's or</textblock>
    <textblock>importer's direct control. To control the latter type of hazard,</textblock>
    <textblock>that is, environmental hazards and hazards that may be caused by</textblock>
    <textblock>poor handling prior to receipt of fish or fishery products by the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor or importer, the point of receipt by the processor or</textblock>
    <textblock>importer represents a critical control point. As indicated</textblock>
    <textblock>previously in this preamble, the processor or importer may need</textblock>
    <textblock>to ensure that it obtains imported shipments or raw materials</textblock>
    <textblock>only from harvesters, transporters, and others who can</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrate that they also have exercised appropriate controls.</textblock>
    <textblock>The hazards that may be caused by both improper processing and</textblock>
    <textblock>events outside the plant are controlled by the critical limits,</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring, control procedures, and recordkeeping that are done</textblock>
    <textblock>as part of HACCP.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Critical Limits</textblock>
    <textblock>In §123.6(b)(3), consistent with NACMCF principles, FDA is</textblock>
    <textblock>proposing that processors and importers identify critical limits</textblock>
    <textblock>in the plan that must be met at each critical control point.</textblock>
    <textblock>Critical limits must be met to ensure that the relevant hazard is</textblock>
    <textblock>avoided. Thus, some critical limits can be set to reflect</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory levels established by FDA in the form of action</textblock>
    <textblock>levels, regulatory limits, and tolerances for such contaminants</textblock>
    <textblock>as pesticides, histamine, and other contaminants. FDA intends to</textblock>
    <textblock>compile all such levels in the guidance document described</textblock>
    <textblock>earlier.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other critical limits can be set in consultation with</textblock>
    <textblock>outside experts, in keeping with the longstanding practice for</textblock>
    <textblock>low acid canned foods. For example, as explained later in this</textblock>
    <textblock>preamble with respect to cooked, ready-to-eat products, there</textblock>
    <textblock>exist a range of possible cooking time-temperature combinations</textblock>
    <textblock>that will deactivate pathogens during the cooking step, depending</textblock>
    <textblock>on the type of equipment being used by the processor and the size</textblock>
    <textblock>and species of fish being cooked. The existence of a range of</textblock>
    <textblock>effective cooking time-temperature combinations convinced FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>not to establish specific cooking time-temperatures for industry</textblock>
    <textblock>in the regulations for low acid canned foods. Rather, FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>decided to rely on outside experts and on research within the</textblock>
    <textblock>scientific community to establish cooking times and temperatures</textblock>
    <textblock>for these products. FDA is not proposing specific cooking time-temperature requirements for most seafood products (although FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>is providing guidance on time, temperature, and salinity</textblock>
    <textblock>parameters for smoked and smoke-flavored fish, as is fully</textblock>
    <textblock>explained in Appendix 1 to this document) for the same reason.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Monitoring and Control Procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §123.6(b)(4) requires that the processor or</textblock>
    <textblock>importer identify in the HACCP plan the procedures that it will</textblock>
    <textblock>use to control and monitor each critical control point.</textblock>
    <textblock>Monitoring steps are necessary to ensure that the critical</textblock>
    <textblock>control point is in fact under control and to produce an accurate</textblock>
    <textblock>record of what has occurred at the critical control point (Ref.</textblock>
    <textblock>34, p. 197). Among the procedures that are to be used under</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed §123.6(b)(4) is monitoring of the consumer complaints</textblock>
    <textblock>received by the processor. While the goal of an HACCP system is</textblock>
    <textblock>to prevent all likely hazards from occurring, no system is</textblock>
    <textblock>foolproof. Consumer complaints may be the first alert that a</textblock>
    <textblock>processor has that deviations are occurring that are not being</textblock>
    <textblock>prevented or uncovered by the processor's HACCP controls. FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>has tentatively concluded, therefore, that each HACCP system</textblock>
    <textblock>should take advantage of consumer complaints as they relate to</textblock>
    <textblock>the operation of critical control points.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §123.6(b)(4) also requires that procedures for</textblock>
    <textblock>controlling and monitoring critical control points must include</textblock>
    <textblock>calibration of process control instruments and validation of</textblock>
    <textblock>software for computer control systems, as appropriate. For a</textblock>
    <textblock>processor's preventive controls to work, the instruments and</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment that it relies upon in monitoring critical control</textblock>
    <textblock>points, such as thermometers, temperature-recording devices, and</textblock>
    <textblock>computer software, must be accurate and reliable. FDA has</textblock>
    <textblock>tentatively concluded that the best way to ensure such accuracy</textblock>
    <textblock>and reliability is to require that the processor's monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures include steps necessary to verify the reliability of</textblock>
    <textblock>these instruments and devices.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
