<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00118</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00080</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The notificants listed below have applied under the Change in Bank Control Act (12 U.S.C. 1817(j)) and  225.41 of the Board's Regulation Y (12 CFR 225.41) to acquire a bank or bank holding company. The factors that are considered in acting on the notices are set forth in paragraph 7 of the Act (12 U.S.C. 1817(j)(7)).</textblock>
    <textblock>The notices are available for immediate inspection at the Federal Reserve Bank indicated. Once the notices have been accepted for processing, they will also be available for inspection at the offices of the Board of Governors. Interested persons may express their views in writing to the Reserve Bank indicated for that notice or to the offices of the Board of Governors. Comments must be received not later than February 17, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City</textblock>
    <textblock>(John E. Yorke, Senior Vice President) 925 Grand Avenue, Kansas City, Missouri 64198:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Wiley William Smith</textblock>
    <textblock>, Sapulpa, Oklahoma; to acquire an additional 3.8 percent for a total of 16.03 percent; and Edward A. Carson, Sapulpa, Oklahoma, to acquire an additional 0.13 percent for a total of 16.03 percent of the voting shares of Security National Bancshares of Sapulpa, Inc., Sapulpa, Oklahoma, and thereby indirectly acquire Security National Bank of Sapulpa, Sapulpa, Oklahoma.</textblock>
    <textblock>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, January 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Wiley William Smith, et al.; Change in Bank Control Notices; Acquisitions of Shares of Banks or Bank Holding Companies</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jennifer J. Johnson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Secretary of the Board.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1941 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6210-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
