<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00170</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00109</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Jimmy Carter National Historic Site Advisory Commission; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Park Service, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of advisory commission meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given in accordance with the Federal Advisory Commission Act that a meeting of the Jimmy Carter National Historic Site Advisory Commission will be held at 8:30 a.m. to 4 p.m., at the following location and date.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>April 12, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Carter Presidential Center, One Copenhill, Atlanta, Georgia 30307, (404) 331-3900.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Fred Boyles, Superintendent, Jimmy Carter National Historic Site, Route 1 Box 800, Andersonville, Georgia 31711, (912) 924-0343.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the Jimmy Carter National Historic Site Advisory Commission is to advise the Secretary of the Interior or his designee on achieving balanced and accurate interpretation of the Jimmy Carter National Historic Site.</textblock>
    <textblock>The members of the Advisory Commission are as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Steven Hochman</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. James Sterling Young</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Donald B. Schewe</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Henry King Stanford</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Barbara Fields</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, National Park Service, Ex-Officio member</textblock>
    <textblock>The matters to be discussed at this meeting include the status of park development and planning activities. This meeting will be open to the public. However, facilities and space for accommodating members of the public are limited. Any member of the public may file with the commission a written statement concerning the matters to be discussed. Written statements may also be submitted to the Superintendent at the address above. Minutes of the meeting will be available at Park Headquarters for public inspection approximately 4 weeks after the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>C.W. Ogle,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Director, Southeast Region.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1934 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-70-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
