<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00120</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00082</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>GENERAL SERVICES ADMINISTRATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Border Station, Highgate Springs, VT; Environmental Impact Statement</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>General Services Administration.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of intent to prepare an Environmental Impact Statement.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The General Services Administration (GSA) is issuing this notice to advise the public that an Environmental Impact Statement (EIS) will be prepared and considered for the construction of a new Border Station in Highgate Springs, Vermont.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ralph A. Scalise, Senior Planner, General Services Administration, Public Buildings Service, 10 Causeway Street, Boston, MA 02222, (617) 565-5821.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The GSA will prepare an Environmental Impact Statement for the construction of a Border Station in Highgate Springs, Vermont. The proposed Border Station will contain approximately 37,800 occupiable square feet of space and house 75 employees. The operations of the U.S. Immigration and Naturalization Service and U.S. Customs Service at the existing Border Station in Highgate Springs are severely hindered due to the functional obsolescence of the existing facilities. The proposed project is being undertaken to accommodate the expansion requirements of the U.S. Customs Service, Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS), and the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA).</textblock>
    <textblock>The EIS will evaluate alternatives, including the no-action alternative. The EIS will evaluate impacts on the affected environment for the following resource areas: subsurface and geological conditions, landforms, vegetation and wildlife, natural hazards, air quality/meteorological conditions, population/fiscal conditions, land use and zoning, traffic and transportation, utilities, cultural resources, and hazardous wastes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Scoping Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>To ensure that the full range of issues relating to the proposed project are addressed and all potential significant issues are identified, comments and suggestions are being solicited. To facilitate the receipt of comments, a public scoping meeting will be held on March 8, 1994, from 3 p.m. to 5 p.m. and from 7 p.m. to 9 p.m. at the Town Hall in Highgate Center, Vermont. The Highgate Center Town Hall is located on Route 78 (exit 21 on Route 89).</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments may be mailed to the informational contact person no later than March 23, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in New York, NY on January 13, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Karen R. Adler,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Regional Administrator, General Services Administration, Region 2.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1844 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6820-23-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
