<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00011</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>4. Seafood industry representatives have urged the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Government to institute a mandatory, HACCP-type</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection system for their products.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. A nationally mandated HACCP-type system of controls</textblock>
    <textblock>appears to be a prerequisite for continued access to world</textblock>
    <textblock>markets.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Safety</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Background</textblock>
    <textblock>Ensuring the safety of seafood presents special challenges</textblock>
    <textblock>to both the industry that produces it and to Government agencies</textblock>
    <textblock>charged with protecting the public health. Seafood is unique in</textblock>
    <textblock>many respects. While often thought of as homogeneous in nature,</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood is actually a variety of products encompassing literally</textblock>
    <textblock>hundreds of species that have little in common other than an</textblock>
    <textblock>aquatic origin. Collectively, seafoods have perhaps the most</textblock>
    <textblock>diverse and complex microbiology of any food commodity (Ref. 3,</textblock>
    <textblock>p. xi).</textblock>
    <textblock>The range of habitats for edible species is also</textblock>
    <textblock>extraordinary and diverse ranging from cold to warm water, bottom</textblock>
    <textblock>dwelling to surface feeding, deep sea to near shore, and fresh</textblock>
    <textblock>water to saltwater. Fish are exposed to the bacteria and viruses</textblock>
    <textblock>that naturally occur in their environment as well as to those</textblock>
    <textblock>that enter the water through pollution. Chemicals, some of which</textblock>
    <textblock>are toxic to humans, can accumulate in fish as well. Fish can</textblock>
    <textblock>also accumulate natural toxins and parasites that are specific to</textblock>
    <textblock>marine animals. As a consequence, fish are subject to a wide</textblock>
    <textblock>range of hazards before harvest.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. The Safety Data</textblock>
    <textblock>The question of how safe is the seafood in the marketplace</textblock>
    <textblock>has been the subject of public debate in recent years. This</textblock>
    <textblock>debate has occurred partly because precise data on the numbers</textblock>
    <textblock>and causes of foodborne illnesses in the United States do not</textblock>
    <textblock>exist. Foodborne illnesses tend to be significantly</textblock>
    <textblock>underreported to public health authorities. Data on foodborne</textblock>
    <textblock>illnesses that are meaningful from an epidemiological standpoint</textblock>
    <textblock>are difficult and expensive to develop.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDCP) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Public Health Service (PHS) compiles data in its Foodborne</textblock>
    <textblock>Disease Surveillance System that are reported from State and</textblock>
    <textblock>local health authorities. All foodborne illnesses are</textblock>
    <textblock>underreported to this system (Ref. 4).</textblock>
    <textblock>Nonetheless, CDCP data are the best available and can at</textblock>
    <textblock>least be used to identify trends and emerging concerns about</textblock>
    <textblock>various diseases (Ref. 5, p. 219). The data suggest that most</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood-related illnesses result from certain natural toxins in</textblock>
    <textblock>finfish and from viruses in molluscan shellfish consumed raw or</textblock>
    <textblock>partially cooked (Ref. 4). The wide range of other hazards that</textblock>
    <textblock>can affect seafood undoubtedly result in illnesses, but the</textblock>
    <textblock>available data indicate that such illnesses are not as common.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thus, according to the CDCP data, the actual occurrence of</textblock>
    <textblock>problems tends to be limited relative to the range of hazards</textblock>
    <textblock>that could cause problems and tends to be associated with a</textblock>
    <textblock>minority of commercially available species.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the CDCP system, seafood accounted for 4.8 percent of</textblock>
    <textblock>reported cases of foodborne illness for the period 1973 to 1987</textblock>
    <textblock>(Ref. 4). However, as CDCP has pointed out, variations in rates</textblock>
    <textblock>of underreporting among different foods and varying etiologies</textblock>
    <textblock>make it impossible to compare safety among different foods based</textblock>
    <textblock>solely on CDCP data (Ref. 4). This is certainly true for</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood. Some seafood-related illnesses tend to be overreported</textblock>
    <textblock>to CDCP's system relative to other foodborne diseases, due</textblock>
    <textblock>largely to their distinctive characteristics, while others are</textblock>
    <textblock>probably underreported relative to other causes because they are</textblock>
    <textblock>less distinctive and more difficult to diagnose (Ref. 4).</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA has attempted to determine the relative safety of</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood through risk assessment. The results of this effort</textblock>
    <textblock>indicate that the risk of illness associated with molluscan</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish consumed raw or partially cooked is greater than for</textblock>
    <textblock>any cooked flesh food. However, seafood overall is as safe or</textblock>
    <textblock>safer than other flesh foods in terms of frequency of illness</textblock>
    <textblock>(Refs. 5, p. 25; and 6).</textblock>
    <textblock>The conclusions of the National Academy of Sciences' (NAS)</textblock>
    <textblock>Institute of Medicine, in its 1991 report entitled ``Seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>Safety,'' are consistent with the CDCP data and the FDA risk</textblock>
    <textblock>assessment. According to NAS, ``Most seafoods available to the</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. public are wholesome and unlikely to cause illness in the</textblock>
    <textblock>consumer'' (Ref. 7, p. 1). Moreover, in reviewing the CDCP data,</textblock>
    <textblock>the report noted that the 23 percent increase in seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>consumption in the United States in the 10-year period ending</textblock>
    <textblock>1989 was not accompanied by a concomitant increase in reported</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood-borne illnesses (Ref. 7, p. 27). Nevertheless, as NAS</textblock>
    <textblock>pointed out, ``there are areas of risk'' (Ref. 7, p. 1). The</textblock>
    <textblock>report addressed at some length virtually every possible risk</textblock>
    <textblock>that could affect seafood and made numerous recommendations</textblock>
    <textblock>relating to existing and proposed control measures. NAS</textblock>
    <textblock>recommended that improvements be made in the present system of</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory control (Ref. 7, p. 1) and repeatedly recommended</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP controls wherever appropriate. ``Inspection and testing</textblock>
    <textblock>should focus on actual problems (as in HACCP systems),'' NAS</textblock>
    <textblock>concluded (Ref. 7, p. 16).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
