<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00086</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>1. Costs</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA specifically requests comments on:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The expected cost to retrofit plants as necessary for</textblock>
    <textblock>the proper operation of HACCP controls (e.g., enhance</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigerator capacity, water supply changes, etc.).</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The cost of taking corrective actions to respond to</textblock>
    <textblock>critical limit deviations on an annual basis. FDA has estimated</textblock>
    <textblock>an average of $1,000 per firm to take such actions as discarding</textblock>
    <textblock>product, buying new equipment, and changing the processing</textblock>
    <textblock>practice.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The cost of training employees. FDA has estimated that</textblock>
    <textblock>there will be a cost per plant of $900 to train an employee to</textblock>
    <textblock>manage HACCP. This will include the cost of training, travel</textblock>
    <textblock>expenses, and loss of several days of productivity for that</textblock>
    <textblock>employee. Not all of these costs may be borne by manufacturers,</textblock>
    <textblock>however, because some training may be sponsored by academia,</textblock>
    <textblock>trade associations, and others.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The cost of ensuring that cooking and pasteurizing</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment and processes are achieving the desired safety results</textblock>
    <textblock>(i.e., destroying microbiological pathogens). This ensurance may</textblock>
    <textblock>be obtained by having equipment and processes that are equivalent</textblock>
    <textblock>to those found effective by a processing authority. FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>estimated that this would cost $1,000 per plant in the first year</textblock>
    <textblock>and, on average, half that amount in the following years as</textblock>
    <textblock>processors change their processes and equipment. This cost may be offset, however, by reliance on literature that contains the</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary information from a processing authority.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) The cost of temperature indicators and thermometers for</textblock>
    <textblock>plants who do not now have this equipment. FDA estimated that</textblock>
    <textblock>the cost would be $1,000 per plant, initially, with replacement</textblock>
    <textblock>as necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) The cost of creating a HACCP plan from the guidance</textblock>
    <textblock>provided by FDA. FDA estimated that it will take processors with</textblock>
    <textblock>simpler processes 24 hours of managerial time to adapt the</textblock>
    <textblock>guidance into a HACCP plan. FDA estimated that it will take</textblock>
    <textblock>processors with more complex processes 72 hours of managerial</textblock>
    <textblock>time to adapt the guidance into a HACCP plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) FDA requests comment on the recordkeeping burden</textblock>
    <textblock>associated with the proposed sanitation requirements in §123.10</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) and (c). If possible, such estimates should be provided in</textblock>
    <textblock>terms of hours spent and translated into dollars if staff</textblock>
    <textblock>compensation rates are known.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, FDA was unable to provide cost estimates of the</textblock>
    <textblock>following provisions and requests specific comments on these</textblock>
    <textblock>areas:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Section 123.10(a)(7), prevention of cross-contamination</textblock>
    <textblock>by the separation of food-contact surfaces;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Section 123.10(a)(14), storage at 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F or below;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Appendix A.6., cooling after cooking;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Appendix B., scombroid toxin forming species;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Appendix 1., specifically, the guidance on smoked and</textblock>
    <textblock>smoke-flavored fishery products;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Increased short-term recall potential, if any, due to</textblock>
    <textblock>heightened industry awareness;</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Increasing time spent escorting Federal inspectors,</textblock>
    <textblock>particularly in the initial phases;</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) The cost of restricting catch in certain areas and</textblock>
    <textblock>seasons if processors find it necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Benefits</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) FDA is reprinting two tables from the PRIA and requests</textblock>
    <textblock>comments on both the baseline number of illnesses due to seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>and the likelihood that HACCP for processors will reduce those</textblock>
    <textblock>illnesses. The baseline number of illnesses reflects an estimate</textblock>
    <textblock>of all cases (from any source, including recreational harvest,</textblock>
    <textblock>retail, and consumer mishandling). FDA considers the estimates</textblock>
    <textblock>in both tables as preliminary estimates.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
