<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00117</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>5.</textblock>
    <textblock>Vacuum- and modified atmosphere-packaging.</textblock>
    <textblock>Vacuum</textblock>
    <textblock>packaging and other types of modified atmosphere-packaging (those in which the air in the package or container is</textblock>
    <textblock>replaced by one or more gases, in various concentrations, before</textblock>
    <textblock>the package is sealed) extend the shelf life of foods markedly.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, the anaerobic environment created in these types of</textblock>
    <textblock>packaging favors the outgrowth of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>spores and</textblock>
    <textblock>subsequent toxin production, and it inhibits growth of aerobic</textblock>
    <textblock>microorganisms that might otherwise serve as organoleptic</textblock>
    <textblock>indicators of spoilage (Refs. 180 and 182). Consequently, use of</textblock>
    <textblock>vacuum- or modified atmosphere-packaging demands strict adherence</textblock>
    <textblock>to temperature-controlled storage and distribution to reduce the</textblock>
    <textblock>opportunity for spore outgrowth and toxin production and to</textblock>
    <textblock>reduce the potential growth of other microorganisms of public</textblock>
    <textblock>health significance (such as</textblock>
    <textblock>L. monocytogenes</textblock>
    <textblock>).</textblock>
    <textblock>Two methods of reducing the potential public health hazard</textblock>
    <textblock>of vacuum or modified atmosphere packaged smoked, smoke-flavored,</textblock>
    <textblock>and salted fish products are: (1) To store and distribute the</textblock>
    <textblock>products frozen or, alternatively, (2) to use in-package heat</textblock>
    <textblock>processing followed by refrigeration. At freezer temperatures,</textblock>
    <textblock>outgrowth of spores of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>types B, E, and F is retarded</textblock>
    <textblock>(Refs. 171, 173, and 180). Type A does not grow below 50</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (10</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) (Refs. 179 and 180). Storage and distribution in the frozen</textblock>
    <textblock>state reduces the possibility that temperature abuse will occur.</textblock>
    <textblock>In-package heat processing, sometimes referred to as ``heat</textblock>
    <textblock>pasteurization,'' at temperatures in the range of 185</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (85</textblock>
    <textblock>○C)</textblock>
    <textblock>for 85 minutes to 198</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (92</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) for 55 minutes, inhibits</textblock>
    <textblock>outgrowth and toxin production by type E spores (Ref. 185).</textblock>
    <textblock>Longer exposure to processing temperatures is required for more</textblock>
    <textblock>heat resistant spores, such as types B and A (Ref. 185). In a</textblock>
    <textblock>study examining this method of packaging, samples of hot-process</textblock>
    <textblock>salmon steaks were injected with spores of nonproteolytic strains</textblock>
    <textblock>of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>types B and E (Ref. 185). The steaks were vacuum</textblock>
    <textblock>packaged, heat pasteurized, then incubated using different</textblock>
    <textblock>time-temperature combinations. The results of this research</textblock>
    <textblock>showed that closely controlled in-package heat processing extends</textblock>
    <textblock>the shelf life of the product, inactivates nonproteolytic</textblock>
    <textblock>C</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>types B, E, and F and other vegetative pathogens, and</textblock>
    <textblock>maintains product quality attributes. However, this process is</textblock>
    <textblock>more suitable for pieces, fillets, and steaks than for whole</textblock>
    <textblock>eviscerated fish because this process causes the flesh to</textblock>
    <textblock>separate from the backbone (Ref. 185).</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Specific Processing Conditions</textblock>
    <textblock>The various processing techniques used to produce smoked and</textblock>
    <textblock>smoke-flavored fish are affected by the interrelationship of the</textblock>
    <textblock>smoking, the method of smoke application, the time-temperature</textblock>
    <textblock>combinations used, and the water-phase salt content. A critical</textblock>
    <textblock>factor in determining alternative processing methods is the type</textblock>
    <textblock>of packaging utilized, specifically whether the product is</textblock>
    <textblock>air-packaged or vacuum-packaged. The following discussion sets</textblock>
    <textblock>out the various processing procedures that the agency has</textblock>
    <textblock>tentatively concluded will ensure the safety of hot-process</textblock>
    <textblock>smoked and smoke-flavored fish, and cold-process smoked and</textblock>
    <textblock>smoke-flavored fish.</textblock>
    <textblock>1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Hot-process smoked and smoke-flavored fish.</textblock>
    <textblock>a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Air-packaged.</textblock>
    <textblock>Research data and industry practice show that a</textblock>
    <textblock>lower minimum water-phase salt content (3.5 percent or lower), in</textblock>
    <textblock>combination with lower processing temperatures (lower than 180</textblock>
    <textblock>○F</textblock>
    <textblock>(82</textblock>
    <textblock>○C)) than cited in the 1970 final rule for hot-process</textblock>
    <textblock>products are effective in inhibiting spore outgrowth and toxin</textblock>
    <textblock>production when the products are not vacuum-packaged and are held</textblock>
    <textblock>at refrigerated temperatures (40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or lower) (Refs. 24,</textblock>
    <textblock>163, and 177). Research studies from the National Marine</textblock>
    <textblock>Fisheries Service and testimony presented at a public hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>held by the New York State Department of Agriculture and Markets</textblock>
    <textblock>on May 3, 1989, to establish a CGMP for the manufacture of smoked</textblock>
    <textblock>and smoke-flavored fish products, show that</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>type E</textblock>
    <textblock>is inhibited in air-packaged smoked fish products when the</textblock>
    <textblock>water-phase salt content is at least 3.0 percent, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>processing internal temperature of the product is maintained at a</textblock>
    <textblock>minimum of 145</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (63</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) for at least 30 minutes (Ref. 180). In</textblock>
    <textblock>light of these findings, FDA is setting forth these processing</textblock>
    <textblock>parameters in Example 6 of this appendix to provide guidance on</textblock>
    <textblock>the safe manufacturing of these products.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is setting forth the following minimum T-T-S</textblock>
    <textblock>parameters for air-packed, hot-process smoked and smoke-flavored</textblock>
    <textblock>fish in section 5.a.1. of Example 6 of this appendix: Heating at</textblock>
    <textblock>an internal temperature of 145</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (63</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) for 30 minutes with a</textblock>
    <textblock>water-phase salt content of 3.0 percent in the finished product.</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Vacuum-packaged/modified atmosphere.</textblock>
    <textblock>For</textblock>
    <textblock>vacuum-packaged products, National Marine Fisheries Service</textblock>
    <textblock>research shows that processing temperatures in the range of 145</textblock>
    <textblock>to 175</textblock>
    <textblock>○ F (63 to 80</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) for hot-process smoked fish will inhibit</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>type E when the water-phase salt content is greater</textblock>
    <textblock>than 3.5 percent (Refs. 26, 173, and 180). Based on this</textblock>
    <textblock>evidence, New York's CGMP included a procedure for processing</textblock>
    <textblock>vacuum-packaged smoked fish that specifies heating the fish to an</textblock>
    <textblock>internal temperature of 145</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (63</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) for 30 minutes, with a</textblock>
    <textblock>water-phase salt content of 3.5 percent (Ref. 25).</textblock>
    <textblock>The use of sodium nitrite in combination with sodium</textblock>
    <textblock>chloride significantly inhibits the outgrowth and toxin</textblock>
    <textblock>production of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>type E. Research data show that when</textblock>
    <textblock>the water-phase salt content and sodium nitrite content are at</textblock>
    <textblock>least 3.1 percent and 100 ppm, respectively, and the internal</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature of the fish is not less than 145</textblock>
    <textblock>○F, the inhibitory</textblock>
    <textblock>effect on</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>growth and toxin production greatly</textblock>
    <textblock>increases (Refs. 173 and 179). At higher processing</textblock>
    <textblock>temperatures, e.g., 180</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (82</textblock>
    <textblock>○C), a water-phase salt content of</textblock>
    <textblock>3.0 percent or more inhibits toxin formation by</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>type</textblock>
    <textblock>E (Ref. 163).</textblock>
    <textblock>Based on this information, the agency is setting forth the</textblock>
    <textblock>following T-T-S parameters for vacuum-packaged hot-process smoked</textblock>
    <textblock>and smoke-flavored fish in section 5.a.2. of Example 6 of this</textblock>
    <textblock>appendix: (1) Heating at an internal temperature of at least</textblock>
    <textblock>145</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (63</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) for 30 minutes with a minimum water-phase salt</textblock>
    <textblock>content of 3.5 percent in the finished product, or (2) heating</textblock>
    <textblock>at an internal temperature of at least 145</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (63</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) for 30</textblock>
    <textblock>minutes, with a minimum water-phase salt content of 3.0 percent,</textblock>
    <textblock>and a sodium nitrite content of 100 to 200 ppm (as permitted by</textblock>
    <textblock>the food additive regulations in §172.175) in the finished</textblock>
    <textblock>product, or (3) as described in §172.177 for smoked chub</textblock>
    <textblock>containing sodium nitrite.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
