<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00065</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The agency believes that economic adulteration occurs with</textblock>
    <textblock>sufficient frequency in various seafood products to result in</textblock>
    <textblock>substantial losses to the consumer. Evidence of such economic</textblock>
    <textblock>adulteration usually comes to light indirectly, as a result of</textblock>
    <textblock>investigations that are carried out for other purposes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Fourteen and one-half percent of the samples of seafoods</textblock>
    <textblock>reported in 1986 as having adverse findings by eight FDA district</textblock>
    <textblock>offices were so listed because of product misrepresentation (Ref.</textblock>
    <textblock>123).</textblock>
    <textblock>Similarly, FDA found that in fiscal years 1991 and 1992,</textblock>
    <textblock>14.8 and 11.7 percent, respectively, of all consumer complaints</textblock>
    <textblock>involved complaints of economic problems (Ref. 60).</textblock>
    <textblock>Imported seafood products also are subject to significant</textblock>
    <textblock>levels of economic misrepresentation. In 1992, approximately 13</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of all detentions of imported seafood involved some form</textblock>
    <textblock>of misbranding, such as false or misleading labeling, short fill,</textblock>
    <textblock>short weight, standard of identity, and omitted labeling (Ref.</textblock>
    <textblock>124).</textblock>
    <textblock>Specific data on species substitution are available from The</textblock>
    <textblock>National Seafood Inspection Laboratory (NSIL) of NMFS, Department</textblock>
    <textblock>of Commerce. Data gathered for the 3-year period of 1990-1992 by</textblock>
    <textblock>the laboratory in conducting species verification tests requested</textblock>
    <textblock>by industry show that 59 percent of the samples labeled as cod,</textblock>
    <textblock>57 percent of the product labeled as haddock, 56 percent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>product labeled as flounder or sole, and 51 percent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>product labeled as red snapper were not the species claimed on</textblock>
    <textblock>the label. While these data cannot be regarded as representative</textblock>
    <textblock>of industry-wide misbranding practices because the testing was</textblock>
    <textblock>not random, the results indicate a remarkably high incidence of</textblock>
    <textblock>species substitution. Moreover, these findings are consistent</textblock>
    <textblock>with other surveys (Ref. 35, p. 45).</textblock>
    <textblock>For example, a survey conducted in Florida to determine the</textblock>
    <textblock>extent of retail species substitution in the case of red snapper</textblock>
    <textblock>found that 64 percent of the fish fillets labeled for retail sale</textblock>
    <textblock>as red snapper were misbranded (Ref. 125). The prevalence of</textblock>
    <textblock>misbranding just this one desirable species is underscored by the</textblock>
    <textblock>observation: ``If all of the red snapper sold in the United</textblock>
    <textblock>States were genuine, the seas would long since have been swept</textblock>
    <textblock>absolutely clean of this species'' (Ref. 126, p. 41).</textblock>
    <textblock>While most States' regulations follow FDA nomenclature</textblock>
    <textblock>policy and regulations, misbranding practices are exacerbated by</textblock>
    <textblock>the failure of some States to require these common names for some</textblock>
    <textblock>species sold within the State. Red snapper again provides a case</textblock>
    <textblock>study in the extent of variation in acceptable nomenclature</textblock>
    <textblock>allowed for a species. Although not permitted when sold in</textblock>
    <textblock>interstate commerce, California regulations allow 12 species of</textblock>
    <textblock>rockfish to be labeled as ``Pacific red snapper'' within the State.</textblock>
    <textblock>Similarly, Oregon and Washington regulations also allow rockfish</textblock>
    <textblock>to be called ``snapper'' (Ref. 126, p. 305). Moreover, an even</textblock>
    <textblock>greater variety of imported species may be misrepresented as ``red</textblock>
    <textblock>snapper.''</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
