<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00115</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>To minimize microbial growth, fresh fish should be</textblock>
    <textblock>maintained at refrigerated temperatures close to 38</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (3.3</textblock>
    <textblock>○C)</textblock>
    <textblock>(Refs. 173 and 175). Although certain strains of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>are capable of growth at temperatures as low as 38</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (3.3</textblock>
    <textblock>○C),</textblock>
    <textblock>favorable growth media are necessary for a significant growth</textblock>
    <textblock>rate to occur at this temperature. For example, it has been</textblock>
    <textblock>shown that</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>Type E requires 31 to 35 days before</textblock>
    <textblock>outgrowth and toxin production occurs in a beef stew media held</textblock>
    <textblock>at 38</textblock>
    <textblock>○F. However, outgrowth and toxin production in a cooked</textblock>
    <textblock>meat medium held at 41</textblock>
    <textblock>○F does not occur until after 56 days,</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrating that less favorable growth media can significantly</textblock>
    <textblock>lower the rate of growth. Even in those cases where</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>does grow and produce toxin, the laboratory conditions are</textblock>
    <textblock>generally more ideally suited to growth than those found in</textblock>
    <textblock>nonexperimental situations where less favorable growth</textblock>
    <textblock>environments prevail. Thus, while the growth of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>is</textblock>
    <textblock>not completely inhibited at 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C), under the less than</textblock>
    <textblock>ideal conditions for its growth that are generally encountered in</textblock>
    <textblock>the processing of smoked fish, FDA has tentatively concluded that</textblock>
    <textblock>maintaining fresh fish at a maximum temperature of 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F, only 2</textblock>
    <textblock>degrees above the temperature of complete growth inhibition,</textblock>
    <textblock>before and during processing will provide adequate protection</textblock>
    <textblock>against</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>outgrowth. Moreover, 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) is</textblock>
    <textblock>consistent with the maximum temperature FDA has proposed in</textblock>
    <textblock>various guidelines, such as the Unicode (now called the Food</textblock>
    <textblock>Code) (53 FR 16472, May 9, 1988). Therefore, under proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.10(a)(14), all raw fish that is to be smoked must be</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigerated until needed for processing (Ref. 175).</textblock>
    <textblock>Similarly, fish that are initially frozen need to remain in</textblock>
    <textblock>the frozen state until needed for processing (Refs. 161 and 25).</textblock>
    <textblock>When frozen fish are needed for processing, the thawing procedure</textblock>
    <textblock>must be carried out in a way that minimizes the opportunity for</textblock>
    <textblock>microbial growth (Refs. 161 and 171). The method used to thaw</textblock>
    <textblock>the fish must provide an environment that will inhibit the growth</textblock>
    <textblock>of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>and other microorganisms that pose a potential</textblock>
    <textblock>health hazard (Refs. 171 and 172). Thus, the fish should be</textblock>
    <textblock>thawed in a way that ensures that the internal temperature at the</textblock>
    <textblock>core of the fish does not exceed 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) (Refs. 171 and</textblock>
    <textblock>172). Therefore, section 4.a. of Example 6 of this appendix, the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency suggests that this procedure be used in the thawing</textblock>
    <textblock>process.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Manufacturing Operations</textblock>
    <textblock>Reduction of the potential health hazard from</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>spore outgrowth and toxin production in smoked and smoke-flavored</textblock>
    <textblock>fish relies on the interrelationship of processing time,</textblock>
    <textblock>processing temperature, water-phase salt concentration in the</textblock>
    <textblock>loin muscle, and smoke (or constituents of smoke) deposition,</textblock>
    <textblock>combined with refrigerated storage (40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or lower) (see</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed §123.10(a)(14)) (Ref. 173). At one time, smoking and</textblock>
    <textblock>associated brining may have been an effective preservation</textblock>
    <textblock>method. With the changes in processing techniques that have</textblock>
    <textblock>occurred since the advent of refrigeration and in response to</textblock>
    <textblock>consumers' demands for products with certain organoleptic</textblock>
    <textblock>qualities, however, smoked fish products, either hot- or</textblock>
    <textblock>cold-process, have become perishable products that must be</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigerated and cannot be considered preserved foods (Ref. 173).</textblock>
    <textblock>The changes that have occurred, both in processing techniques and</textblock>
    <textblock>in organoleptic qualities, have resulted in products that are</textblock>
    <textblock>more moist and contain less salt. As a result, the two critical</textblock>
    <textblock>processing factors that affect the overall preservation and</textblock>
    <textblock>safety of the product have been altered. The processing</textblock>
    <textblock>time-temperature parameters have been decreased, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>water-phase salt content has been reduced (Ref. 173). Therefore,</textblock>
    <textblock>these products need to be maintained at refrigerated temperatures</textblock>
    <textblock>(40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or lower) or frozen immediately after processing</textblock>
    <textblock>to ensure the overall quality of these products (Ref. 173).</textblock>
    <textblock>1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Brining/dry salting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Salt, as a preservative in smoked</textblock>
    <textblock>and smoke-flavored fish, is somewhat limited in its effectiveness</textblock>
    <textblock>because of the variability in salt uptake by fish flesh, even</textblock>
    <textblock>among fish in the same brining tank. Ventral muscle, which is</textblock>
    <textblock>thin, absorbs high levels of salt, while the thicker dorsal</textblock>
    <textblock>muscles absorb less salt, limiting the effectiveness of salt as a</textblock>
    <textblock>deterrent against spore outgrowth in that part of the fish.</textblock>
    <textblock>Equilibration techniques, such as two-stage brining, reduce</textblock>
    <textblock>variation in salt content within a fish and increase the</textblock>
    <textblock>preservative effect (Ref. 176).</textblock>
    <textblock>It is possible that salt-tolerant microorganisms of public</textblock>
    <textblock>health concern (such as strains of</textblock>
    <textblock>Staphylococcus</textblock>
    <textblock>) may grow</textblock>
    <textblock>during brining or after the dry salting process. Therefore, FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>is providing in section 5.c. and 5.e. in example 6 of this</textblock>
    <textblock>appendix that the brining and dry salting of fish be carried out</textblock>
    <textblock>at refrigerated temperatures, i.e., 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or lower.</textblock>
    <textblock>Doing so will ensure that the environment in which brining is</textblock>
    <textblock>done, and in which fish are held after dry-salting, will inhibit</textblock>
    <textblock>the growth of salt-tolerant microorganisms that can cause a</textblock>
    <textblock>potential health hazard (Ref. 173).</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA recognizes that when fish are initially added to the</textblock>
    <textblock>brine, the temperature of the brine may increase. It is</textblock>
    <textblock>essential to this process that the brine be returned to</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigerated temperatures 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or lower to reduce the</textblock>
    <textblock>opportunity of microbial growth and to ensure the overall quality</textblock>
    <textblock>of the product during the brining process (Refs. 175 and 182).</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, the agency is suggesting in section 5.d. of Example 6</textblock>
    <textblock>of this appendix that the temperature of the brine not exceed 60</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (16</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) at the start of brining.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
