<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-0-00035</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Dandruff, Seborrheic Dermatitis, and Psoriasis Drug Products for Over-the-Counter Human Use; Amendment to the Monograph</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>21 CFR Part 358</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 82N-0214]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 0905-AA06</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration, HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is issuing a final rule amending the final monograph for over-the-counter (OTC) dandruff, seborrheic dermatitis, and psoriasis drug products to include 0.6 percent micronized selenium sulfide for the control of dandruff. This final rule is part of the ongoing review of OTC drug products conducted by FDA.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 30, 1995.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>William E. Gilbertson, Center for Drug Evaluation and Research (HFD-810), Food and Drug Administration, 5600 Fishers Lane, Rockville, MD 20857, 301-594-5000.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>In the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of December 4, 1991 (56 FR 63554), FDA issued a final monograph for OTC dandruff, seborrheic dermatitis, and psoriasis drug products in subpart H of part 358 (21 CFR part 358, subpart H). The monograph lists selenium sulfide 1 percent in §358.710(a)(5) as an active ingredient that is used for the control of dandruff. The selenium sulfide included in the monograph is not micronized (reduced to a fine particle size).</textblock>
    <textblock>In the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of April 5, 1993 (58 FR 17554), the agency published a notice of proposed rulemaking to amend the final monograph for OTC dandruff, seborrheic dermatitis, and psoriasis drug products to include 0.6 percent micronized selenium sulfide in §358.710(a) as an active ingredient for the control of dandruff. The agency also proposed to add the following definition for micronized selenium sulfide in §358.703(e): ``Selenium sulfide that has been finely ground and that has a median particle size of approximately 5 micrometers (μm), with not more than 0.1 percent of the particles greater than 15 μm and not more than 0.1 percent of the particles less than 0.5 μm.'' Interested persons were invited to submit written comments and comments on the agency's economic impact determination by June 4, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>No comments were received in response to the proposed amendment. As discussed in the proposal (58 FR 17554 at 17556), the agency advised that any final rule resulting from this proposed rule would be effective 12 months after its date of publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. Therefore, on or after January 30, 1995, any OTC drug product that is not in compliance with this amendment to the final rule may not be initially introduced or initially delivered for introduction into interstate commerce unless it is the subject of an approved application or abbreviated application. Further, any OTC drug product subject to the rule that is repackaged or relabeled after the effective date of the rule must be in compliance with the rule regardless of the date that the product was initially introduced or initially delivered for introduction into interstate commerce. Manufacturers are encouraged to comply voluntarily with the rule at the earliest possible date.</textblock>
    <textblock>No comments were received in response to the agency's request for specific comment on the economic impact of this rulemaking (58 FR 17554 at 17557). The agency has examined the economic consequences of this final rule in conjunction with other rules resulting from the OTC drug review. In a notice published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of February 8, 1983 (48 FR 5806), the agency announced the availability of an assessment of these economic impacts. The assessment determined that the combined impacts of all the rules resulting from the OTC drug review do not constitute a major rule according to the criteria established by Executive Order 12866. The agency therefore concludes that no one of these rules, including this amendment of the final monograph for OTC dandruff, seborrheic dermatitis, and psoriasis drug products, is a major rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>The economic assessment also concluded that the overall OTC drug review was not likely to have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities as defined in the Regulatory Flexibility Act (Pub. L. 96-354). That assessment included a discretionary regulatory flexibility analysis in the event that an individual rule might impose an unusual or disproportionate impact on small entities. However, this particular rulemaking for OTC dandruff, seborrheic dermatitis, and psoriasis drug products is not expected to pose such an impact on small businesses. This final rule will not remove any existing products from the market or require any reformulation or relabeling of existing products. The final rule will increase the scope of active ingredients available to industry for this class of OTC drug products. This final rule would allow OTC drug products containing 0.6 percent micronized selenium sulfide and labeled for the control of dandruff to be marketed without having to obtain an approved application, as is currently required. This will be beneficial to small manufacturers. Therefore, the agency certifies that this final rule will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency has determined under 21 CFR 25.24(c)(6) that this action is of a type that does not individually or cumulatively have a significant effect on the human environment. Therefore, neither an environmental assessment nor an environmental impact statement is required.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 21 CFR Part 358</textblock>
    <textblock>Labeling, Over-the-counter drugs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and under authority delegated to the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, 21 CFR part 358 is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 358_MISCELLANEOUS EXTERNAL DRUG PRODUCTS FOR OVER-THE-COUNTER HUMAN USE</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for 21 CFR part 358 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Secs. 201, 501, 502, 503, 505, 510, 701 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. 321, 351, 352, 353, 355, 360, 371).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 358.703 is amended by adding paragraph (e) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§358.703</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Selenium sulfide, micronized. Selenium sulfide that has been finely ground and that has a median particle size of approximately 5 micrometers (μm), with not more than 0.1 percent of the particles greater than 15 μm and not more than 0.1 percent of the particles less than 0.5 μm.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Section 358.710 is amended by redesignating paragraph (a)(6) as paragraph (a)(7) and by adding new paragraph (a)(6) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§358.710</textblock>
    <textblock>Active ingredients for the control of dandruff, seborrheic dermatitis, or psoriasis.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) * ␣ * ␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Selenium sulfide, micronized, 0.6 percent.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: August 26, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Michael R. Taylor,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Commissioner for Policy.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1789 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
