<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00085</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00051</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 24, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 14, 1994, Mojave Pipeline Company (Mojave) tendered for filing as part of its FERC Gas Tariff, First Revised Volume No. 1, its Substitute First Revised Sheet Nos. 11 and 126.</textblock>
    <textblock>This sheet is being revised in order to implement revisions to Mojave's implementation of its new GRI rates as required by the Commission in an order dated December 30, 1993. As ordered by the Commission, the revised tariff sheets will have an effective date of January 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Mojave states that copies of this filing were served upon all of Mojave's jurisdictional transportation customers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to protest said filing should file a protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with 385.211 of the Commission's Rules and Regulations. All such protests should be filed on or before January 31, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection in the public reference room.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. TM94-1-92-001]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Mojave Pipeline Co.; Tariff Filing</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1800 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
