<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00060</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Decomposition can also occur before the fish are removed from</textblock>
    <textblock>the harvest water if the fish dies in capture nets or on long</textblock>
    <textblock>lines. In such an event, the degree of decomposition will</textblock>
    <textblock>reflect the sea temperature, time in the water, and particular</textblock>
    <textblock>species (Ref. 118). It is not uncommon to encounter water</textblock>
    <textblock>temperatures of 80</textblock>
    <textblock>○F to 90</textblock>
    <textblock>○F in tropical waters, which can</textblock>
    <textblock>produce rapid decomposition.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thus, rapid cooling of fish when they are captured is very</textblock>
    <textblock>important to prevent initiation of the process by which histamine</textblock>
    <textblock>is produced. Fish subjected to 68</textblock>
    <textblock>○F for periods as short as one</textblock>
    <textblock>day, a practice which can happen in warm climates on fishing</textblock>
    <textblock>vessels, will yield high levels of histamine, even if the fish</textblock>
    <textblock>are later stored at refrigerated temperatures (Ref. 117).</textblock>
    <textblock>For these reasons, the guideline advises that processors of</textblock>
    <textblock>fish and fishery products from scombroid toxin forming species</textblock>
    <textblock>must ensure that their raw materials are essentially free of</textblock>
    <textblock>decomposition and histamine as a result of time/temperature abuse</textblock>
    <textblock>that occurred before the processor received them. The guideline</textblock>
    <textblock>provides for three interrelated controls for the processor to</textblock>
    <textblock>apply with regard to raw materials. For the first processor that</textblock>
    <textblock>takes ownership after harvest, these are: (1) Time/temperature</textblock>
    <textblock>records from the harvesting vessel (Appendix B, section 3.a.1.);</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) organoleptic examination of the fish from the harvesting</textblock>
    <textblock>vessel for decomposition (Appendix B, section 3.a.2.); and (3)</textblock>
    <textblock>histamine analysis, if warranted by the time/temperature history</textblock>
    <textblock>of the fish as revealed by the time/temperature record from the</textblock>
    <textblock>vessel or by the results of the organoleptic examination</textblock>
    <textblock>(Appendix B, section 3.a.3.), or both. Time/temperature records</textblock>
    <textblock>from the vessel indicate whether entire lots from the vessel may</textblock>
    <textblock>be suspect, and thus in need of a histamine examination, because</textblock>
    <textblock>of unusual events on the vessel. Such records would not normally</textblock>
    <textblock>reveal, however, whether there are individual fish in the lot</textblock>
    <textblock>that may have decomposition. An organoleptic examination for</textblock>
    <textblock>decomposition serves to screen individual fish. It also serves</textblock>
    <textblock>as a way to verify the time/temperature records from the vessel</textblock>
    <textblock>with regard to an entire lot. If organoleptic examination</textblock>
    <textblock>reveals an unusually high number of fish with decomposition, the</textblock>
    <textblock>entire lot should be considered suspect and subjected to</textblock>
    <textblock>histamine analysis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix B, section 3.a.1. provides for how the first</textblock>
    <textblock>processor can take measures to determine whether the fish were</textblock>
    <textblock>properly harvested and handled on board the harvesting vessel.</textblock>
    <textblock>Certification of the mode of capture, including information on</textblock>
    <textblock>the time between physical capture and bringing the fish on board,</textblock>
    <textblock>handling techniques, and the use of temperature logs onboard the</textblock>
    <textblock>vessel that record that time/temperature history of the fish (for</textblock>
    <textblock>example, catch date and time, means and rate of cooling, storage</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature, and refrigerated brine or seawater temperature)</textblock>
    <textblock>provide documentation to the processor and to regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>authorities that the fish were properly handled. Such records on</textblock>
    <textblock>the handling of the fish should be part of an HACCP system and</textblock>
    <textblock>can be used in the specific HACCP plans of processors.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
