<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00155</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00098</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Notice To Cancel Intent To Amend the Dillon Management Framework Plan; Butte District Office; Montana</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[MT-930-4320-01]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice to cancel intent to amend the Dillon MFP.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Butte District issued a</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice on November 29, 1993, announcing a Notice of Intent to Amend the Dillon Management Framework Plan (MFP). The Butte District is canceling the intent to amend the Dillon MFP. The decision to use only aerial shooting of predators in this area will continue to be in effect until it is reviewed on an ecosystem management basis during the preparation of the Dillon Resource Management Plan (RMP) scheduled to begin October 1996.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Sandy Brooks, Project Lead, Montana State Office, P.O. Box 36800, Billings, Montana 59107; or contact by phone at (406) 255-2929.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>In the Dillon MFP, it was decided that selective aerial predator control be the only means by which predatory animals, other than wolves be removed from the BLM land between the town of Lima and Bloody Dick Creek. The rationale was that the most positive indication of gray wolf occupancy recorded at that time had been documented in the Lemhi Pass area. Since then, however, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service has better defined occupied wolf habitat in Montana. The area between Lima and Blood Dick Creek is not considered occupied wolf habitat at this time. The proposed Dillon MFP Amendment would have allowed for Integrated Pest Management in the described area, where predator control was limited to aerial shooting of predators. However, due to the preparation of an RMP in the Dillon Resource Area beginning in 1997, the Butte District has decided to cancel their intent to amend the Dillon MFP and review the decision on an ecosystem-wide basis as part of the Dillon RMP.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 20, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Robert H. Lawton,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>State Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1845 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-DN-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
