<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00043</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Additionally, where food-contact surfaces are constructed of</textblock>
    <textblock>toxic materials (e.g., lead shucking blocks), the product may be</textblock>
    <textblock>directly contaminated with the toxic material (Ref. 74).</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, FDA tentatively concludes that it is necessary to</textblock>
    <textblock>require that processors take affirmative steps to minimize the</textblock>
    <textblock>possibility that any risks will be created by the utensils and</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment they use.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proper construction of the equipment should be ensured at</textblock>
    <textblock>the time it is received, and whenever it is modified or repaired.</textblock>
    <textblock>The frequency of subsequent inspections necessary to ensure that</textblock>
    <textblock>the sanitary condition of the equipment has not declined with</textblock>
    <textblock>time will depend on the frequency of its use, the materials and</textblock>
    <textblock>construction methods, and the nature of its use. In</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง123.10(c)(3) the agency is proposing to require that such</textblock>
    <textblock>controls be performed and documented with such frequency as is</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to ensure control.</textblock>
    <textblock>In ยง123.10(a)(4), the agency is proposing to require that</textblock>
    <textblock>the processor ensure that food-contact surfaces are regularly</textblock>
    <textblock>cleaned and sanitized with cleaning and sanitizing preparations</textblock>
    <textblock>that are suitable for this purpose. Surfaces that are not</textblock>
    <textblock>adequately cleaned and sanitized can be a source of filth to</textblock>
    <textblock>subsequent products produced on the equipment, an attractant for</textblock>
    <textblock>vermin, and a reservoir for pathogenic microorganisms.</textblock>
    <textblock>Infrequent cleaning of equipment can result in the formation of</textblock>
    <textblock>biofilms, microscopic films in which microorganisms can be</textblock>
    <textblock>entrapped, shielded from the action of sanitizers, and physically</textblock>
    <textblock>bound to the food-contact surface of the equipment.</textblock>
    <textblock>An effective cleaning compound is one that will lower the</textblock>
    <textblock>surface tension of water so that spills can be lifted and flushed</textblock>
    <textblock>away. Ordinary soap is generally ineffective for equipment</textblock>
    <textblock>washing because of its limited ability to solubilize fats, oils,</textblock>
    <textblock>and proteins. Mildly alkaline detergents are generally suitable</textblock>
    <textblock>for cleaning seafood processing plants, but high alkaline</textblock>
    <textblock>detergents are often necessary for heavy buildups of fats and</textblock>
    <textblock>proteins. Mineral deposits will frequently require the use of</textblock>
    <textblock>acid cleaners.</textblock>
    <textblock>An effective sanitizing agent is one that has a good</textblock>
    <textblock>bacteriocidal effect on the types of pathogens normally present</textblock>
    <textblock>in the plant environment and is safe, stable, and convenient for</textblock>
    <textblock>use. Examples include hypochlorites, iodophors, and quaternary</textblock>
    <textblock>ammonium compounds (Refs. 73, 74, 75, 76, and 77).</textblock>
    <textblock>To eliminate the product residue that accumulates on</textblock>
    <textblock>product contact surfaces during production, FDA is proposing in</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง123.10(a)(4)(i) to require that utensils and surfaces of</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment that contact food during processing be thoroughly</textblock>
    <textblock>washed at the end of the day's operations. FDA is also proposing</textblock>
    <textblock>in ยง123.10(a)(4)(iii) that sanitizing be performed on the same</textblock>
    <textblock>utensils and equipment immediately before the beginning of</textblock>
    <textblock>production, so that any recontamination that occurs between</textblock>
    <textblock>cleaning and production can be eliminated.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
