<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00057</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00032</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>12.</textblock>
    <textblock>Enforcement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons failing to pay established fees will be subject to enforcement action in accordance with 36 CFR 327.23, Recreation Use Fees.</textblock>
    <textblock>13.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accounting.</textblock>
    <textblock>All income derived from fee collection will be deposited into Special Receipt Account 965007 and reported in accordance with ER 37-2-10 and ER 1130-2-414.</textblock>
    <textblock>14.</textblock>
    <textblock>Credit Vouchers and Refunds.</textblock>
    <textblock>No credit vouchers or refunds will be given for day user fees.</textblock>
    <textblock>15.</textblock>
    <textblock>Golden Age and Golden Access Passports.</textblock>
    <textblock>Golden Age and Golden Access Passport discounts will apply to day user fees. The Passport will entitle the holder and all accompanying passengers in a single, private, non-commercial vehicle to a 50 percent discount of the daily or annual day user fee. Passport discounts will not apply to commercial vehicles, transporting visitors for hire. Golden Eagle Passports do not apply to user fees. The schedule of day user fees and Golden Age and Access Passport discounts is contained in Appendix C.</textblock>
    <textblock>16.</textblock>
    <textblock>Specialized Facility Reservations and Special Events.</textblock>
    <textblock>The charging of a day user fee at a recreation area does not preclude the charging of a fee for the reservation of a specialized facility or for a special event within the area. Neither does the charging of a fee for the reservation of a specialized facility or special event preclude the collecting of the established day user fee for the recreation area. Resource managers should consider local situations when determining fee applicability.</textblock>
    <textblock>17.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Information.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the interest of informing the public of the fee collection program, public information activities will be conducted to disseminate information regarding this program at least two months before the collection of fees begins at newly designated user fee areas. District commanders will notify congressional delegations, as appropriate, of the fee collection program in their congressional districts. Public information meetings, convened to discuss the new program for a project or group of projects, as well as the philosophy and rational for the new fee program, are strongly encouraged. Various additional coordination activities should also occur with any other interested parties.</textblock>
    <textblock>18.</textblock>
    <textblock>Controlling Paperwork Burden on the Public.</textblock>
    <textblock>The guidance in 5 CFR Part 1320 establishes the framework for the paperwork control process. Generally, this CFR provides that an agency shall not engage in a collection of information (from the public) without obtaining Office of Management and Budget approval. There are no procedures contained in this regulation that should be interpreted to require the public provide information other than general data.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Commander.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John R. Brown,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Colonel, Corps of Engineers, Executive Director of Civil Works.</textblock>
    <textblock>5 Appendices</textblock>
    <textblock>App A_Pertinent</textblock>
    <textblock>Legislative Language</textblock>
    <textblock>App B_Summary of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Corps User Fee Program</textblock>
    <textblock>App C_Day User Fee Schedule</textblock>
    <textblock>App D_Annual Day Use Pass</textblock>
    <textblock>App E_Cash Register Specifications</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1839 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3710-92-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
