<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00236</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00152</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Information Collection Under OMB Review: Application and Enrollment Certification for Individualized Tutorial Assistance, VA Form 22-1990t</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Veterans Affairs.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Veterans Affairs has submitted to OMB the following proposal for the collection of information under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. Chapter 35). This document lists the following information: (1) The title of the information collection, and the Department form number(s), if applicable; (2) a description of the need and its use; (3) who will be required or asked to respond; (4) an estimate of the total annual reporting hours, and recordkeeping burden, if applicable; (5) the estimated average burden hours per respondent; (6) the frequency of response; and (7) an estimated number of respondents.</textblock>
  </action>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the proposed information collection and supporting documents may be obtained from Janet G. Byers, Veterans Benefits Administration (20A5), Department of Veterans Affairs, 810 Vermont Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20420 (202) 233-3021.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments and questions about the items on the list should be directed to VA's OMB Desk Officer, Joseph Lackey, NEOB, room 3002, Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-7316. Do not send requests for benefits to this address.</textblock>
  </address>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on the information collection should be directed to the OMB Desk Officer on or before February 28, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 11, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By direction of the Secretary:</textblock>
  </date>
  <signer>
    <textblock>B. Michael Berger,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Records Management Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Application and Enrollment Certification for Individual Tutorial Assistance, VA Form 22-1990t</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The form is used by students who are receiving VA educational assistance and who require tutoring to overcome a deficiency in one or more courses. The information is used by VA to determine if the veteran or eligible person is entitled to the benefit.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Individuals or households_State or local governments_Businesses or other for-profit_Non-profit institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>4. 2,333 hours</textblock>
    <textblock>5. 35 minutes</textblock>
    <textblock>6. On occasion</textblock>
    <textblock>7. 2,000 respondents</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1825 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8320-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
