<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00061</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The harvester's goal should be to bring the fish to an</textblock>
    <textblock>internal temperature of 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below as soon as</textblock>
    <textblock>possible after the fish dies to minimize the risk of histamine</textblock>
    <textblock>production. Cooling fish below 59</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (15</textblock>
    <textblock>○C), and preferably</textblock>
    <textblock>below 50</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (10</textblock>
    <textblock>○C), greatly reduces the growth of populations of</textblock>
    <textblock>the bacteria that are most likely to cause histamine formation</textblock>
    <textblock>(Ref. 7, p. 95). Once bacterial growth has begun, temperature at</textblock>
    <textblock>or below 41</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (5</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) halts bacterial growth, although enzymatic</textblock>
    <textblock>histamine formation may slowly continue (Ref. 7, p. 95).</textblock>
    <textblock>Consequently, in proposed Appendix B, section 3.a.1., the agency</textblock>
    <textblock>is recommending a slightly lower flesh temperature of 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below. This temperature is consistent with</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendations of safe temperatures in other sections of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulation. Nonetheless, FDA specifically invites</textblock>
    <textblock>comments on the appropriateness of this temperature.</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix B, section 3.a.1. recommends that the</textblock>
    <textblock>time/temperature history from the vessel be on a lot-by-lot basis</textblock>
    <textblock>and defines a lot as a discrete storage compartment on the vessel</textblock>
    <textblock>in keeping with industry practice. A lot typically reflects a</textblock>
    <textblock>day's catch. Because a boat's catch can be subject to varying</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions and treatment from day-to-day, the time/temperature</textblock>
    <textblock>records should be specific to each lot.</textblock>
    <textblock>If the time/temperature records suggest that, for a</textblock>
    <textblock>particular lot, the conditions on the vessel were likely to</textblock>
    <textblock>cause, or significantly contribute to, the formation of histamine</textblock>
    <textblock>in the fish, or if no adequate time/temperature records exist for</textblock>
    <textblock>that lot, the guideline provides that a representative sample of</textblock>
    <textblock>fish from the lot be analyzed for histamine Appendix B, section</textblock>
    <textblock>3.a.2.ii.B.). The samples should be collected on a statistically</textblock>
    <textblock>valid sample schedule because variations in time/temperature</textblock>
    <textblock>abuse are likely at various points in a ship's hold.</textblock>
    <textblock>The second control, organoleptic examination by the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor for decomposition, should be performed regardless of</textblock>
    <textblock>what the time/temperature records show (Appendix B, section</textblock>
    <textblock>3.a.2.). First, decomposition is a form of adulteration under</textblock>
    <textblock>403(a)(3) of the act. Second, as indicated earlier, an</textblock>
    <textblock>organoleptic examination provides a screening mechanism for</textblock>
    <textblock>individual fish. It is possible for the conditions on the vessel</textblock>
    <textblock>to be good but for some fish to develop decomposition anyway.</textblock>
    <textblock>Third, also as stated earlier, an examination for decomposition</textblock>
    <textblock>provides a way to verify the time/temperature records.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA recognizes that an organoleptic examination of each fish</textblock>
    <textblock>can be highly impractical. Consequently, the guideline calls for</textblock>
    <textblock>an examination of a representative number of fish to achieve a 95</textblock>
    <textblock>percent certainty that the total number of fish in the lot that</textblock>
    <textblock>exhibit decomposition does not exceed 2.5 percent. (The</textblock>
    <textblock>significance of 2.5 percent is addressed in the preamble</textblock>
    <textblock>discussion of Appendix B, section 3. a.2.iii. and a.2.iv.) Using</textblock>
    <textblock>this approach, the number of fish examined will be reasonably</textblock>
    <textblock>close to the total number of fish, so that the goal of screening</textblock>
    <textblock>individual fish is preserved to the maximum extent practicable.</textblock>
    <textblock>Additionally, FDA expects that this representative sample will be</textblock>
    <textblock>large enough so as to provide a sufficient verification of the</textblock>
    <textblock>time/temperature records for the entire lot.</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix B, section 3.a.2.i. provides that no fish flesh</textblock>
    <textblock>that exhibits any organoleptically detectable decomposition</textblock>
    <textblock>should be used for food. Aside from the clear violation of</textblock>
    <textblock>402(a)(3) of the act presented by such decomposition, the public</textblock>
    <textblock>health risk presented by decomposition in scombrotoxin forming</textblock>
    <textblock>species is unacceptable. While the existence of decomposition</textblock>
    <textblock>does not mean that scombrotoxin is present, it does mean that a</textblock>
    <textblock>process has begun that can lead to the presence of scombrotoxin</textblock>
    <textblock>over the shelf life of the fish or fishery product.</textblock>
    <textblock>In some instances, e.g., large fish such as tuna, isolated</textblock>
    <textblock>parts of the fish will exhibit decomposition but other parts will</textblock>
    <textblock>be free of decomposition. FDA recognizes that it is possible to</textblock>
    <textblock>remove those parts of a fish that have decomposition and salvage</textblock>
    <textblock>the remainder. Appendix B, section 3.a.2.i. provides for such</textblock>
    <textblock>reconditioning so long as a histamine examination is performed on</textblock>
    <textblock>the flesh that is free of decomposition. FDA believes that a</textblock>
    <textblock>histamine test is prudent under such circumstances to verify that</textblock>
    <textblock>scombrotoxin forming processes are not at work in that flesh.</textblock>
    <textblock>The guideline also provides for how the processor should use</textblock>
    <textblock>organoleptic examination and time/temperature records in tandem</textblock>
    <textblock>to determine whether fish or fishery products from scombroid</textblock>
    <textblock>forming species are fit for further processing or should first be</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to a histamine examination. If no decomposition is</textblock>
    <textblock>found, and the time/temperature records show that conditions on</textblock>
    <textblock>the vessel were unlikely to cause, or significantly contribute</textblock>
    <textblock>to, the formation of histamine in the fish, all the fish from</textblock>
    <textblock>that lot may be further processed or directly entered into</textblock>
    <textblock>commerce (Appendix B, section 3.a.2.ii.). If, as stated earlier,</textblock>
    <textblock>the time/temperature records are inadequate or indicate</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions that could cause histamine, the processor should</textblock>
    <textblock>always conduct a histamine analysis on a representative sample</textblock>
    <textblock>regardless of the decomposition findings.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
