<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00049</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00027</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of the Secretary of the Army</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Availability of the Draft Environmental Impact Statement for Closure and Disposal of Sacramento Army Depot, California</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Army, DOD.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Availability.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with Public Law 101-510, the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990, the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission recommended the closure of Sacramento Army Depot and transfer of depot missions to other installations/agencies. Maintenance missions would be competed to determine location of transfer. In accordance with the Act, the Secretary of Defense must implement all recommendations for closure or realignment. Subject document focuses on the environmental and socioeconomic impacts and mitigations associated with the disposal and reuse of Sacramento Army Depot.</textblock>
    <textblock>No long-term adverse ecological or environmental health effects are expected due to this action. The increase in population anticipated by the reuse and disposal activities is expected to have a net positive impact on the local economy. The preferred alternative, prepared with the cooperation of the local community, is not expected to significantly impact environmental resources.</textblock>
    <textblock>A scoping meeting was held in Sacramento, California, on 28 January 1993. Public notices requesting input and comments from the public were issued in the regional area surrounding Sacramento Army Depot.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written public comments and suggestions received within 45 days of this Notice of Availability will be addressed in the Final Environmental Impact Statement.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the Draft Environmental Impact Statement can be obtained by writing to the United States Army Corps of Engineers, Sacramento District, ATTN: CESPK-ED-M (ISS), 1325 J Street, Sacramento, California 95814-2922.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Wandell Carlton (916) 557-7424.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lewis D. Walker,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Assistant Secretary of the Army, (Environment, Safety and Occupational Health) OASA (IL&amp;E).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1862 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3710-08-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
