<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00146</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00093</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The MCHB places special emphasis on improving service delivery to</textblock>
    <textblock>women and children from culturally identifiable populations who</textblock>
    <textblock>have been disproportionately affected by barriers to accessible</textblock>
    <textblock>care. This means that projects are expected to serve and</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriately involve in project activities members of</textblock>
    <textblock>ethnoculturally distinct groups, unless there are compelling</textblock>
    <textblock>programmatic or other justifications for not doing so. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau's intent is to ensure that project interventions and</textblock>
    <textblock>outcomes are of benefit to culturally distinct populations and to</textblock>
    <textblock>insure that the broadest possible representation of culturally</textblock>
    <textblock>distinct and historically under-represented groups is supported</textblock>
    <textblock>through programs and projects sponsored by the MCHB.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department will review applications for funds under the above</textblock>
    <textblock>mentioned categories as competing applications and, with particular</textblock>
    <textblock>attention to inclusion of women and persons from culturally</textblock>
    <textblock>distinct populations, will fund those which, in the Department's</textblock>
    <textblock>view, best meet the statutory purposes of the HIV Demonstration</textblock>
    <textblock>Program for Children, Adolescents, and Families and address</textblock>
    <textblock>achievement of the Healthy People 2000 objectives related to HIV</textblock>
    <textblock>infection.</textblock>
    <textblock>Review Criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications for grant categories will be reviewed and rated by</textblock>
    <textblock>objective review panels using the review criteria specified below,</textblock>
    <textblock>as appropriate. Please note that there are different criteria for</textblock>
    <textblock>Category (1) and Category (2) applicants.</textblock>
    <textblock>•For Category (1) HIV Demonstration Projects:</textblock>
    <textblock>_Adequacy of documentation of the impact of HIV/AIDS on</textblock>
    <textblock>children, youth, women, and families in the service area including:</textblock>
    <textblock>identification of HIV risk factors, description of trends in the</textblock>
    <textblock>HIV epidemic, and determination and documentation of unmet service</textblock>
    <textblock>needs.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Ability to demonstrate an organized comprehensive system</textblock>
    <textblock>of family-centered, community-based, coordinated care, including</textblock>
    <textblock>the following features: (1) Collaboration/coordination with</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate community agencies and providers, particularly State</textblock>
    <textblock>Title V agencies, other Ryan White programs, and Healthy Start</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies (2) linkages to primary care, and (3) appropriate referral</textblock>
    <textblock>mechanisms.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Adequacy of efforts to develop linkages with clinical</textblock>
    <textblock>trials and activities undertaken to facilitate access of the target</textblock>
    <textblock>population to trials, or identification of proposed activities to</textblock>
    <textblock>overcome barriers.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Clarity of delineation of goals and objectives for the</textblock>
    <textblock>grant period and appropriateness of the timeline for proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>activities. Consistency of the plan with the goals of Title IV and</textblock>
    <textblock>the extent to which the plan addresses the needs identified in the</textblock>
    <textblock>needs assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Adequacy of the strategy and proposed steps to utilize</textblock>
    <textblock>and report data and evaluation for program planning and management,</textblock>
    <textblock>as well as for measuring the efficacy and effectiveness of the</textblock>
    <textblock>program.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Organizational structure, staffing, and oversight</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to implement the proposed goals and objectives.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Adequacy of the proposed budget; budget justification</textblock>
    <textblock>based on project methodology and required resources.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Evidence of ability to obtain funding from other public</textblock>
    <textblock>and private funding sources or indication of problems in accessing</textblock>
    <textblock>such funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>_For competing renewal applicants only, demonstration of</textblock>
    <textblock>an organized, comprehensive system of care and progress in meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>the goals of the current project period will be assessed.</textblock>
    <textblock>•For Category (2) Comprehensive Care Initial Development</textblock>
    <textblock>Grants:</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
