<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00032</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Processors and importers should identify in their written</textblock>
    <textblock>plans only those safety hazards that are reasonably likely to</textblock>
    <textblock>occur, rather than every conceivable hazard no matter how</textblock>
    <textblock>theoretical or remote. This view is in keeping with NACMCF's</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendation that firms conduct a hazard analysis and then give</textblock>
    <textblock>no further consideration to hazards that are unlikely to occur</textblock>
    <textblock>(Ref. 34, p. 189). FDA has tentatively concluded that processors</textblock>
    <textblock>and importers should not be required to establish controls and</textblock>
    <textblock>regularly monitor for hazards that are highly unlikely to occur</textblock>
    <textblock>in the absence of those controls. If, for example, chemical</textblock>
    <textblock>contaminants have never been found, or have only been found in</textblock>
    <textblock>amounts significantly below levels of public health concern in a</textblock>
    <textblock>species from a particular location, processors and importers need</textblock>
    <textblock>not identify chemical contaminants as a hazard that must be</textblock>
    <textblock>controlled for that fish.</textblock>
    <textblock>As indicated earlier in this preamble, FDA intends to issue</textblock>
    <textblock>a guidance document that will cover possible environmental and</textblock>
    <textblock>processing hazards for fish and fishery products as well as types</textblock>
    <textblock>of controls that can be applied to those hazards. The agency</textblock>
    <textblock>anticipates that it will update that guidance periodically as new</textblock>
    <textblock>controls (or new hazards) are identified or established.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA cannot reasonably expect processors and importers to</textblock>
    <textblock>exercise controls for hazards that are beyond the scope of</textblock>
    <textblock>current scientific knowledge. The agency does expect processors</textblock>
    <textblock>and importers to demonstrate that they are taking precautions</textblock>
    <textblock>that are reasonable in light of available information, and that</textblock>
    <textblock>they are adopting new controls as those controls are developed</textblock>
    <textblock>and accepted.</textblock>
    <textblock>For example, the controls for</textblock>
    <textblock>Vibrio</textblock>
    <textblock>bacteria in raw</textblock>
    <textblock>molluscan shellfish, which can cause serious illness and death in</textblock>
    <textblock>certain at-risk populations, are the subject of continuing</textblock>
    <textblock>research at FDA and elsewhere. Short of a complete ban on</textblock>
    <textblock>harvesting, there is no known control that would prevent the</textblock>
    <textblock>presence of</textblock>
    <textblock>Vibrios</textblock>
    <textblock>in molluscan shellfish. Moreover, the</textblock>
    <textblock>infectious dose, that is, the number of</textblock>
    <textblock>Vibrios</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to</textblock>
    <textblock>cause illness, is unknown. Because these bacteria occur</textblock>
    <textblock>naturally in the environment and are ubiquitous, controls that</textblock>
    <textblock>are employed to prevent sewage-related viruses from entering</textblock>
    <textblock>molluscan shellfish are not relevant to</textblock>
    <textblock>Vibrios.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is known,</textblock>
    <textblock>however, that proper temperature controls from the time of</textblock>
    <textblock>harvest onward can at least limit the growth of these bacteria</textblock>
    <textblock>(Ref. 49). FDA believes that such controls are reasonable and</textblock>
    <textblock>should be applied now. (In fact, temperature controls have long</textblock>
    <textblock>been a feature of the National Shellfish Sanitation Program</textblock>
    <textblock>(NSSP).)</textblock>
    <textblock>Of the hazards listed in proposed §123.6(b), pesticides and</textblock>
    <textblock>drug residues (proposed §123.6(b)(1)(iv) and (b)(1)(v)) are</textblock>
    <textblock>forms of chemical contaminants (proposed §123.6(b)(1)(iii)) but</textblock>
    <textblock>are listed separately because they can be of special concern in</textblock>
    <textblock>aquaculture-raised species. These fish generally have a greater</textblock>
    <textblock>likelihood of being exposed to agricultural run-off than wild</textblock>
    <textblock>ocean stocks (Ref. 50, pp. 11 and 12). Aquaculture-raised fish</textblock>
    <textblock>are known to be fed drugs for various purposes. Drug residues in</textblock>
    <textblock>edible tissues can be a public health concern.</textblock>
    <textblock>Decomposition, listed in proposed §123.6(b)(1)(vi), is a</textblock>
    <textblock>known hazard in those species that can generate scombrotoxin when</textblock>
    <textblock>they decompose; otherwise, it is regarded as a quality problem.</textblock>
    <textblock>Parasites (proposed §123.6(b)(1)(vii)) are not a hazard if</textblock>
    <textblock>killed during cooking but can be a hazard in finfish consumed</textblock>
    <textblock>raw, unless that fish is commercially frozen. Unapproved direct</textblock>
    <textblock>and indirect food and color additives (proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.6(b)(1)(viii)) are a potential hazard with most any food.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
