<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00144</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00093</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Children, Adolescents, and Families</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Health Resources and Services Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Ryan White Title IV_HIV Demonstration Program for</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), PHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability of funds.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Maternal and Child Health Bureau (MCHB), HRSA,</textblock>
    <textblock>announces that fiscal year (FY) 1994 funds are available for grants</textblock>
    <textblock>for demonstration projects to provide services for children,</textblock>
    <textblock>adolescents, women and families infected with or affected by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV). Projects will be funded to</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrate strategies and innovative models of family-centered,</textblock>
    <textblock>community-based coordinated care and research for children, youth,</textblock>
    <textblock>women of childbearing age, and families infected and affected by</textblock>
    <textblock>HIV infection, AIDS or other related conditions, or those at risk</textblock>
    <textblock>for developing infection. Funds were appropriated for this purpose</textblock>
    <textblock>under Section 2671, Title IV, of the Ryan White Comprehensive AIDS</textblock>
    <textblock>Resource Emergency (CARE) Act of 1990, Public Law 101-381, which</textblock>
    <textblock>amended Title XXVI of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S. Code</textblock>
    <textblock>300ff-11</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>).</textblock>
    <textblock>The PHS is committed to achieving the health promotion and disease</textblock>
    <textblock>prevention objectives of Healthy People 2000, a PHS national</textblock>
    <textblock>activity for setting priority areas. Title IV directly addresses</textblock>
    <textblock>the Healthy People 2000 objectives related to the priority area of</textblock>
    <textblock>HIV infection. Potential applicants may obtain a copy of Healthy</textblock>
    <textblock>People 2000 (Full Report; Stock Number 017-001-0474-0) or Healthy</textblock>
    <textblock>People 2000 (Summary Report: Stock No. 017-001-00473-1) through</textblock>
    <textblock>the Superintendent of Documents, Government Printing Office,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20402-9325 (telephone 202 783-3238).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Grant applications for HIV Demonstration Program for</textblock>
    <textblock>Children, Adolescents, and Families (PHS form</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>5161-1, approved</textblock>
    <textblock>under OMB</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>0937-0189) must be obtained from and submitted to:</textblock>
    <textblock>Chief, Grants Management Branch, Office of Program Support,</textblock>
    <textblock>Maternal and Child Health Bureau, Health Resources and Services</textblock>
    <textblock>Administration, room 18-12, Parklawn Building, 5600 Fishers Lane,</textblock>
    <textblock>Rockville, Maryland 20857, (301) 443-1440.</textblock>
  </address>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The application deadline date is April 8, 1994. Competing</textblock>
    <textblock>applications will be considered to be on time if they are either:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Received on or before the deadline date, or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) postmarked on or before the deadline date and received in</textblock>
    <textblock>time for orderly processing. (Applicants should request a legibly</textblock>
    <textblock>dated receipt from a commercial carrier or U.S. Postal Service</textblock>
    <textblock>postmark or obtain a legibly dated receipt from a commercial</textblock>
    <textblock>carrier or U.S. Postal Service. Private metered postmarks shall</textblock>
    <textblock>not be acceptable as proof of timely mailing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Late applications not accepted for processing or those sent to an</textblock>
    <textblock>address other than specified in the</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>section will be</textblock>
    <textblock>returned to the applicant.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicants will be notified of grant awards in July 1994. The</textblock>
    <textblock>starting dates for projects will be specified in the program</textblock>
    <textblock>guidance.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional information regarding</textblock>
    <textblock>technical and program issues may be obtained from: Beth Roy,</textblock>
    <textblock>Division of Services for Children with Special Health Needs,</textblock>
    <textblock>Maternal and Child Health Bureau, Health Resources and Services</textblock>
    <textblock>Administration, room 18A-19, Parklawn Building, 5600 Fishers Lane,</textblock>
    <textblock>Rockville, Maryland 20857, Telephone (301) 443-9051. Requests for</textblock>
    <textblock>information concerning business management issues should be</textblock>
    <textblock>directed to: John Gallicchio, Grants Management Officer (GMO),</textblock>
    <textblock>Maternal and Child Health Bureau, at the address specified in the</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>section.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Program Background and Objectives</textblock>
    <textblock>The Pediatric AIDS Demonstration Program was initiated in 1988.</textblock>
    <textblock>The program grew from 13 projects funded at $4.4 million to a total</textblock>
    <textblock>of 44 projects funded at $20.8 in 1993. Since 1988, the program</textblock>
    <textblock>has evolved from a primary focus on the coordination of services</textblock>
    <textblock>for the management and care of infected children and their families</textblock>
    <textblock>to also address the broader prevention and care needs of youth and</textblock>
    <textblock>women affected by the HIV infection, AIDS or related conditions.</textblock>
    <textblock>In FY 1994, Congress funded the Pediatric AIDS Demonstration</textblock>
    <textblock>Program under Title IV of the Ryan White Comprehensive AIDS</textblock>
    <textblock>Resources Emergency (CARE) Act (Title IV). The program will be</textblock>
    <textblock>permanently authorized in section 2671 of the Public Health Service</textblock>
    <textblock>Act. Title IV authorizes demonstration grants to organizations to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide comprehensive services and enhance access to clinical</textblock>
    <textblock>research trials for children, youth, women, and families with or</textblock>
    <textblock>affected by HIV infection. As a result of this transfer to Title</textblock>
    <textblock>IV, the focus of the program is further expanded to develop</textblock>
    <textblock>innovative models that link systems of comprehensive</textblock>
    <textblock>primary/community-based medical and social services for the</textblock>
    <textblock>affected population with NIH and other clinical research trials.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the funding is to improve and expand the system of</textblock>
    <textblock>comprehensive care services for children, youth, women, and</textblock>
    <textblock>families who are infected with or affected by HIV and AIDS and to</textblock>
    <textblock>link comprehensive care systems with clinical research. Funds</textblock>
    <textblock>authorized and appropriated under Title IV will be used to</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrate and test potentially replicable models of service</textblock>
    <textblock>delivery and clinical research to respond to the unique and</textblock>
    <textblock>challenging problems of access to a comprehensive care system faced</textblock>
    <textblock>by HIV and AIDS affected children, youth, women, and families.</textblock>
    <textblock>While children, youth, and women represent the most rapidly growing</textblock>
    <textblock>population groups affected by HIV and AIDS, they also represent the</textblock>
    <textblock>groups facing the greatest barriers in accessing care and research.</textblock>
    <textblock>These groups disproportionately are minorities and living in</textblock>
    <textblock>poverty. Children, youth, and women have a complex array of</textblock>
    <textblock>economic and social problems that increase their need for</textblock>
    <textblock>comprehensive services and increase the cost and intensity of care.</textblock>
    <textblock>Furthermore, since they comprise the most recent and fastest</textblock>
    <textblock>growing population groups impacted by HIV and AIDS, the care</textblock>
    <textblock>infrastructure and provider capacity are often not developed and</textblock>
    <textblock>require targeted resources and efforts to develop an appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>system of care.</textblock>
    <textblock>Given these unmet needs, activities under the demonstration grants</textblock>
    <textblock>should address the following goals:</textblock>
    <textblock>_Foster the development of comprehensive care</textblock>
    <textblock>infrastructures, including primary care, that increase access to</textblock>
    <textblock>culturally-competent, family-centered, community-based, coordinated</textblock>
    <textblock>care.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Emphasize prevention within the comprehensive care</textblock>
    <textblock>system in order to reduce the spread of the HIV infection to</textblock>
    <textblock>vulnerable populations.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
