<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00047</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require in §123.10(c)(3) that the</textblock>
    <textblock>filtration and other equipment used to protect the food from such</textblock>
    <textblock>contaminants be inspected, and the inspection documented, with</textblock>
    <textblock>such frequency as is necessary to ensure control. Normally, this</textblock>
    <textblock>frequency will be directed by the manufacturer of the filtration</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment. FDA is not proposing to require daily inspection</textblock>
    <textblock>because the filter and related equipment do not normally need</textblock>
    <textblock>cleaning or replacement on a daily basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require in §123.10(a)(13) that the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor take action to ensure that unprotected cooked, ready-to-eat fishery products, smoked fishery products, raw molluscan</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish, and raw fish and fishery products are physically</textblock>
    <textblock>separated from each other during refrigerated storage. Cooked,</textblock>
    <textblock>ready-to-eat products are products that will not normally receive</textblock>
    <textblock>a cooking by the consumer adequate enough to kill pathogens.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, any microbiological recontamination of the product</textblock>
    <textblock>after cooking can subject the consumer to health risks. Raw</textblock>
    <textblock>molluscan shellfish may contain pathogens that can cause severe</textblock>
    <textblock>illness to certain at-risk individuals, e.g., those who are</textblock>
    <textblock>immunocompromised. These individuals might know to avoid eating</textblock>
    <textblock>raw molluscan shellfish but would not expect the same health risk</textblock>
    <textblock>from cooked, ready-to-eat products. Similarly, raw fish and</textblock>
    <textblock>fishery products may contain filth and pathogenic microorganisms</textblock>
    <textblock>not normally associated with raw molluscan shellfish or cooked,</textblock>
    <textblock>ready-to-eat products (Refs. 63 and 84).</textblock>
    <textblock>In §123.10(c), the agency is proposing to require that</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigerated storage areas be inspected at least daily to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>that the three types of products are physically separated from</textblock>
    <textblock>each other. This check should normally be performed during</textblock>
    <textblock>actual operations, at a time when commingling of these products</textblock>
    <textblock>is likely to take place. The agency has tentatively concluded</textblock>
    <textblock>that daily inspection is necessary because products are normally</textblock>
    <textblock>moved in and out of refrigerated storage areas on a regular</textblock>
    <textblock>basis, creating an ongoing threat that problems will occur.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require in §123.10(a)(14) that</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigerated storage units operate at 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below</textblock>
    <textblock>when storing raw materials, in-process or finished cooked, ready-to-eat fishery products, smoked fishery products, and fish and</textblock>
    <textblock>fishery products made in whole or in part of scombroid toxin</textblock>
    <textblock>forming species. The purpose of this requirement is to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>that processors control microbiological hazards associated with</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigerated storage for these products (Refs. 85 and 86).</textblock>
    <textblock>Cooked, ready-to-eat products as defined in proposed §123.3(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>and smoked fishery products (see Appendix 1) are not shelf-stable</textblock>
    <textblock>and must be kept refrigerated to retard the growth of</textblock>
    <textblock>microorganisms. As stated above, these products will not</textblock>
    <textblock>normally be cooked by the consumer at a sufficient temperature to</textblock>
    <textblock>destroy any pathogens that may be present. Scombroid toxin</textblock>
    <textblock>forming species are addressed in considerable detail later in</textblock>
    <textblock>this document. These species can form a toxin harmful to humans</textblock>
    <textblock>if subjected to time/temperature abuse after capture.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proper refrigeration is essential for fish and fishery</textblock>
    <textblock>products that include these species. Maintaining product</textblock>
    <textblock>temperatures during storage in a range that will minimize the</textblock>
    <textblock>growth of mesophilic and psychrotropic pathogens is necessary to</textblock>
    <textblock>ensure product safety throughout the shelf life of these products</textblock>
    <textblock>(Ref. 85). It is uniformly more convenient to control</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigeration unit temperatures than to control and monitor the</textblock>
    <textblock>internal temperatures of the various products under refrigerated</textblock>
    <textblock>storage, particularly when these products are in sealed</textblock>
    <textblock>containers. For these reasons, FDA is proposing that</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigeration units be operated at or below 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C). FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>tentatively finds that this temperature is appropriate because it</textblock>
    <textblock>is adequate to minimize the growth of pathogens (Refs. 85 and</textblock>
    <textblock>86.) The agency also strongly recommends this temperature or</textblock>
    <textblock>lower for all fish and fishery products that need refrigeration,</textblock>
    <textblock>regardless of whether safety is an issue. The agency is also</textblock>
    <textblock>especially interested in obtaining comment on the appropriateness</textblock>
    <textblock>of this temperature.</textblock>
    <textblock>In §123.10(c)(4) the agency is proposing to require that</textblock>
    <textblock>the processor use instruments that monitor the temperature of</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigeration units on a continuous basis. The measurements from</textblock>
    <textblock>those instruments must be checked and documented with such</textblock>
    <textblock>frequency as is necessary to ensure control.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
