<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00242</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00158</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>UNITED STATES POSTAL SERVICE BOARD OF GOVERNORS</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board of Governors of the United States Postal Service, pursuant to its Bylaws (39 C.F.R. Section 7.5) and the Government in the Sunshine Act (5 U.S.C. Section 552b), hereby gives notice that it intends to hold a meeting at 10:00 a.m. on Monday, February 7, 1994, and at 9:00 a.m. on Tuesday, February 8, 1994, in Sacramento, California. The February 7 meeting, at which the Board will discuss preparations for the rate case filing (See 59 FR 1590, January 11, 1994) is closed to the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>The February 8 meeting is open to the public and will be held at the Red Lion Hotel, 2001 Point West Way, in the Oak section of the Redwood Ballroom. The Board expects to discuss the matters stated in the agenda which is set forth below. Requests for information about the meeting should be addressed to the Secretary for the Board, David F. Harris, at (202) 268-4800.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agenda</textblock>
    <textblock>Monday Session</textblock>
    <textblock>February 7-10:00 a.m. (</textblock>
    <textblock>Closed</textblock>
    <textblock>)</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Consideration of Rate Case Filing. (Messrs. Riley, Porras, Heselton, Foucheaux and Mses. Elcano and Sonnenberg)</textblock>
    <textblock>Tuesday Session</textblock>
    <textblock>February 8-9:00 a.m. (</textblock>
    <textblock>Open</textblock>
    <textblock>)</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Minutes of the Previous Meeting, January 3-4, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Remarks of the Postmaster General/Chief Executive Officer. (Marvin Runyon)</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Appointment of Board Committee Members. (Sam Winters, Chairman of the Board)</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Quarterly Report on Service Performance. (Ann McK. Robinson, Vice President, Consumer Advocate)</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Quarterly Report on Financial Performance. (Michael J. Riley, Chief Financial Officer and Senior Vice President, Finance)</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Report on the Sacramento, California, District. (Arthur I. Montoya, District Manager, Customer Service and Sales, and Kathie Hawley, Plant Manager, Sacramento, P&amp;DC)</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Capital Investment. (Peter A. Jacobson, Senior Vice President, Processing and Distribution)</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Truck Tractors and Spotters</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Tentative Agenda for the March 7-8, 1994, meeting in Washington, D.C.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David F. Harris,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2101 Filed 1-26-94; 3:19 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7710-12-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
