<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00036</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>There is a strong view in the HACCP literature (see e.g.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Ref. 51), which is reflected in one of NACMCF's seven principles</textblock>
    <textblock>listed above, that processors should actually have a plan</textblock>
    <textblock>describing how they will handle deviations, and that this plan</textblock>
    <textblock>should be part of the overall HACCP plan. FDA believes that</textblock>
    <textblock>there is merit in this view and encourages processors and</textblock>
    <textblock>importers to think through how they will handle deviations that</textblock>
    <textblock>may occur. The agency has tentatively concluded, however, that</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed requirements in §123.7 represent the minimum</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements necessary to ensure that processors and importers</textblock>
    <textblock>respond effectively to deviations that could affect safety, and</textblock>
    <textblock>that given these provisions, it is not necessary to require that</textblock>
    <textblock>a specific plan be formulated and adopted. FDA requests comments</textblock>
    <textblock>on this tentative conclusion.</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Records</textblock>
    <textblock>As discussed above, maintenance of appropriate records is</textblock>
    <textblock>fundamental to the success of an HACCP system (see section</textblock>
    <textblock>IV.A.6. of this document). In recognition of this fact, FDA is</textblock>
    <textblock>proposing to require in §123.8 that HACCP records contain</textblock>
    <textblock>certain necessary information; that processors review records of</textblock>
    <textblock>monitoring and related activities before distributing the</textblock>
    <textblock>products to which the records pertain; that processors and</textblock>
    <textblock>importers retain records for specific periods of time; and that</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA investigators be given access to HACCP records.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing in §123.8(a) that records involving</textblock>
    <textblock>observations or measurements during processing, corrective</textblock>
    <textblock>actions, and related activities, contain the identity of the</textblock>
    <textblock>product, product code, and date that the record was made. The</textblock>
    <textblock>purpose of this provision is to ensure that both the processor or</textblock>
    <textblock>importer and the regulator can readily link a record to a product</textblock>
    <textblock>and to the timeframe in which the product was manufactured. The</textblock>
    <textblock>linkage of the record to product is especially important when</textblock>
    <textblock>there has been a deviation at a critical control point. The</textblock>
    <textblock>agency has tentatively concluded that including the identity of</textblock>
    <textblock>the product, product code, and date of the activity that the</textblock>
    <textblock>record reflects provide the minimum necessary information to</textblock>
    <textblock>enable the processor or the importer and, ultimately, the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulator to determine what product may have been affected and to</textblock>
    <textblock>take appropriate action, such as withholding the product from</textblock>
    <textblock>distribution or recalling it from distribution. Dates also help</textblock>
    <textblock>discern trends over time. Even when no deviation has occurred,</textblock>
    <textblock>the information will enable both the processor and the regulator</textblock>
    <textblock>to identify factors that may help prevent problems in the future.</textblock>
    <textblock>In §123.8(a), FDA is also proposing to require that</textblock>
    <textblock>information be recorded at the time that it is observed, and that</textblock>
    <textblock>each record be signed by the operator or observer. It is</textblock>
    <textblock>important that information relating to observations be recorded</textblock>
    <textblock>immediately to ensure accuracy. The record should be signed by</textblock>
    <textblock>the individual who made the observation to ensure responsibility</textblock>
    <textblock>and accountability. Also, if there is a question about the</textblock>
    <textblock>record, a signature ensures that the source of the record will be</textblock>
    <textblock>known.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to require in §123.8(b) that records</textblock>
    <textblock>receive a second review by an individual trained in accordance</textblock>
    <textblock>with §123.9, for verification purposes, before the product is</textblock>
    <textblock>distributed into commerce. The purpose of this review is to</textblock>
    <textblock>ensure that the processor or importer verifies that employees are</textblock>
    <textblock>recording data in HACCP records, and that deviations from</textblock>
    <textblock>critical limits are being caught before products that may have</textblock>
    <textblock>been affected can enter commerce. The agency is proposing to</textblock>
    <textblock>require that this records verification be performed by a trained</textblock>
    <textblock>individual to ensure that the records are reviewed by a person</textblock>
    <textblock>who understands the HACCP system, understands the significance of</textblock>
    <textblock>a processing deviation, and knows how to respond if a deviation</textblock>
    <textblock>occurs.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing in §123.8(c) to require that HACCP records</textblock>
    <textblock>be retained for at least 1 year after they are prepared for</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigerated products and for at least 2 years after they are</textblock>
    <textblock>prepared for frozen or preserved (i.e., shelf-stable) products.</textblock>
    <textblock>These timeframes are based on the length of time that these</textblock>
    <textblock>products can be expected to be in commercial distribution (Ref.</textblock>
    <textblock>52; Ref. 53, pp. 72-73) plus a reasonable time thereafter to</textblock>
    <textblock>ensure that the records are there when the FDA inspector performs</textblock>
    <textblock>the next inspection. They are the same timeframes as now</textblock>
    <textblock>provided for in the Manual of Operations of the NSSP for the</textblock>
    <textblock>retention of records for raw molluscan shellfish.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
