<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00042</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Private sources of water, particularly surface waters or</textblock>
    <textblock>water from shallow wells, may be subject to microbiological,</textblock>
    <textblock>chemical, or radiological contamination attributable to the</textblock>
    <textblock>source itself or to surface contamination at the well head or</textblock>
    <textblock>intake. Private sources are also frequently untreated or</textblock>
    <textblock>minimally treated (Refs. 69, p. 15; and 70). Where the processor</textblock>
    <textblock>uses a private source of water, it will need to take steps to</textblock>
    <textblock>ensure that the water is of a safe and sanitary quality. These</textblock>
    <textblock>steps may include retaining a copy of the initial local health</textblock>
    <textblock>authority well design approval and copies of the local health</textblock>
    <textblock>authority fecal coliform test results; obtaining and maintaining</textblock>
    <textblock>copies of private coliform test results; performing and recording</textblock>
    <textblock>periodic inspections of the sanitary condition of the well head</textblock>
    <textblock>or source intake; and performing and monitoring appropriate water</textblock>
    <textblock>treatment procedures, including filtration, sedimentation, and</textblock>
    <textblock>chlorination.</textblock>
    <textblock>The type and frequency of controls exercised by the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor should be based upon the type of source water and its</textblock>
    <textblock>historic safety and sanitary quality. Consequently, the agency</textblock>
    <textblock>is proposing to require, in ยง123.10(c)(3), that such controls be</textblock>
    <textblock>performed and documented at such frequency as necessary to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>control. In ยง123.10(a)(2), as a means of ensuring that potable</textblock>
    <textblock>water does not become contaminated, the agency is proposing to</textblock>
    <textblock>require that the processor ensure that there are no cross</textblock>
    <textblock>connections between the potable water system and any nonpotable</textblock>
    <textblock>systems. Nonpotable systems include waste water and sewage.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cross connections, which include situations that allow for back</textblock>
    <textblock>siphonage into a potable system from a nonpotable system under</textblock>
    <textblock>negative pressure conditions, can result in the chemical or</textblock>
    <textblock>microbiological contamination of the potable water system (Refs.</textblock>
    <textblock>64; 65, pp. 50 and 51; 68, 71, and 72). For example, if a hose</textblock>
    <textblock>from a potable water system is left in a thawing tank with water</textblock>
    <textblock>and frozen fish, and if negative pressure occurs that draws water</textblock>
    <textblock>from the tank back through the hose to the potable water system,</textblock>
    <textblock>both the potable water line and the water source itself, i.e.,</textblock>
    <textblock>the municipal or private water system, can become contaminated.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cross connections can best be controlled by performing</textblock>
    <textblock>periodic inspections of the potable and nonpotable systems.</textblock>
    <textblock>These inspections should be performed at least every time that</textblock>
    <textblock>there is a change in the plumbing of the systems and with</textblock>
    <textblock>sufficient additional frequency to ensure that unintentional</textblock>
    <textblock>cross connections do not develop. Consequently, in</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง123.10(c)(3), the agency is proposing to require that such</textblock>
    <textblock>inspections be performed and documented at such frequency as</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to ensure control.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing in ยง123.10(a)(3) to require that the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor ensure that all food-contact surfaces are designed,</textblock>
    <textblock>constructed, and maintained in a manner that minimizes the</textblock>
    <textblock>potential for chemical and microbiological contamination of the</textblock>
    <textblock>product. Utensils and equipment can be vehicles for microbial</textblock>
    <textblock>contamination of both the raw and finished products. Utensils,</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment, and other food-contact surfaces that are made of</textblock>
    <textblock>corrosive material or wood, or that contain breaks, pits, cuts,</textblock>
    <textblock>or grooves, may harbor pathogenic microorganisms that can migrate</textblock>
    <textblock>to the product and contaminate it. These kinds of surfaces are</textblock>
    <textblock>difficult to clean, with the pores and crevices shielding the</textblock>
    <textblock>microorganisms from the action of cleaning and sanitizing agents</textblock>
    <textblock>(Refs. 65, pp. 20, 36-48; 72, pp. 166 and 167; and 73).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
