<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00050</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Accordingly, FDA is proposing to make importers subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>the general provisions of subpart A. Thus, FDA is proposing in</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.11(a) to require that products that are offered for import</textblock>
    <textblock>be produced under the same HACCP and sanitation controls that it</textblock>
    <textblock>is proposing to apply to domestically produced seafood. FDA is</textblock>
    <textblock>proposing to require that importers adopt an HACCP plan that</textblock>
    <textblock>includes the criteria for how they will decide to purchase and</textblock>
    <textblock>then handle seafood while it is under their control. They must</textblock>
    <textblock>also establish ways to determine that these requirements are</textblock>
    <textblock>being met.</textblock>
    <textblock>More specifically, the plan must include hazard analysis,</textblock>
    <textblock>critical control points, and critical limits for each type of</textblock>
    <textblock>product imported as well as a copy of each supplier's HACCP plan</textblock>
    <textblock>for those products, as required in §123.11(b). Under proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.11(b), these plans must be available on file at the</textblock>
    <textblock>importer's U.S. place of business. As stated above, the agency</textblock>
    <textblock>is developing a hazard analysis book to assist importers, as well</textblock>
    <textblock>as processors, in designing their individual plans.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because of the proposed requirement of §123.11(b) that</textblock>
    <textblock>importers must have on file an HACCP plan from each of their</textblock>
    <textblock>foreign suppliers, foreign processors who wish to offer their</textblock>
    <textblock>products for import into the United States after the</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation of this regulation will have to operate under</textblock>
    <textblock>valid HACCP plans and sanitation control procedures and furnish</textblock>
    <textblock>copies of those plans to the U.S. importers. The foreign</textblock>
    <textblock>processors should maintain appropriate monitoring records, as dictated by the principles of HACCP already discussed. These</textblock>
    <textblock>records should be kept at the foreign processors' places of</textblock>
    <textblock>business.</textblock>
    <textblock>Importers will be required under proposed §123.11(c) to</textblock>
    <textblock>take affirmative steps to monitor that their suppliers are in</textblock>
    <textblock>fact operating under their HACCP plans. Thus, under this</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal, the importer will need to take such steps as: (1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Obtaining records from the foreign processors' facilities; (2)</textblock>
    <textblock>obtaining certification from foreign governments that the</textblock>
    <textblock>suppliers are operating under valid HACCP plans or obtain</textblock>
    <textblock>certification lot by lot; (3) visiting the facilities to inspect</textblock>
    <textblock>them on a regular basis; or (4) taking some similar type of</textblock>
    <textblock>action, e.g., end product testing.</textblock>
    <textblock>For example, importers of swordfish may specify to their</textblock>
    <textblock>suppliers that the mercury level in the swordfish that they</textblock>
    <textblock>purchase cannot exceed FDA's action level of 1 part per million</textblock>
    <textblock>methyl mercury. The importers may decide to require certificates</textblock>
    <textblock>of analysis for methyl mercury on a regular basis from their</textblock>
    <textblock>suppliers as a means of ensuring that the swordfish that they</textblock>
    <textblock>offer for import into the United States is not adulterated.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 123.11(d) provides an option for those importing</textblock>
    <textblock>from a country that has an active memorandum of understanding</textblock>
    <textblock>(MOU) or similar agreement with FDA. If the MOU is current, and</textblock>
    <textblock>if there is equivalency between the inspection system of the</textblock>
    <textblock>foreign country and the U.S. system, the importer will be able to</textblock>
    <textblock>rely on the MOU in lieu of the actions required under</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.11(c). An active MOU must accurately reflect the current</textblock>
    <textblock>situation between the signing parties and be functioning and</textblock>
    <textblock>enforceable in its entirety. It is the importer's responsibility</textblock>
    <textblock>to determine whether the MOU is in fact active, and whether it</textblock>
    <textblock>covers the products that the importer intends to receive from</textblock>
    <textblock>that country.</textblock>
    <textblock>Finally, the agency strongly encourages importers (as</textblock>
    <textblock>reflected in proposed §123.11(e)) to require their suppliers to</textblock>
    <textblock>obtain HACCP training such as is required in §123.9.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §123.12 provides that there must be evidence that</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood offered for import has been produced in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>part 123, subpart A. As stated previously, FDA is including this</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement to ensure that there is equivalent treatment of</textblock>
    <textblock>imported and domestic products. FDA can ensure that domestic</textblock>
    <textblock>product is being produced in accordance with the HACCP plan and</textblock>
    <textblock>the sanitation controls in §123.10 through direct observation</textblock>
    <textblock>and review of records. Similar inspection of foreign processors</textblock>
    <textblock>would be prohibitively expensive. However, FDA tentatively finds</textblock>
    <textblock>that mere reliance on the existence of an HACCP plan is not</textblock>
    <textblock>enough, and that additional evidence of compliance must be</textblock>
    <textblock>provided. FDA tentatively finds that this evidence can be</textblock>
    <textblock>provided by the means listed in proposed §123.12(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>One of the ways that the agency contemplates obtaining this</textblock>
    <textblock>evidence would be by inspecting, at the importers' U.S. place of</textblock>
    <textblock>business, the importers' and foreign suppliers' HACCP plans,</textblock>
    <textblock>sanitation procedures, and records associated with the importers'</textblock>
    <textblock>plans. If these records demonstrate that the foreign processor and the importer are operating in accordance with adequate HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>plans, agency will have assurance that the food is not</textblock>
    <textblock>adulterated under section 402(a)(4) of the act.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA also intends to pursue MOU's with countries that</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrate that their inspection systems are and continue to be</textblock>
    <textblock>substantially equivalent to those in the United States (proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.12(a)(2)). The existence of an active MOU between FDA and</textblock>
    <textblock>the country of origin covering the seafood products being offered</textblock>
    <textblock>for import will provide assurance that these products covered by</textblock>
    <textblock>the MOU are being produced under appropriate conditions.</textblock>
    <textblock>If there is no MOU, the agency will take into consideration,</textblock>
    <textblock>for purposes of verifying the compliance of imported seafood,</textblock>
    <textblock>knowledge that a foreign country has an advanced seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection system that provides for plans that are HACCP based,</textblock>
    <textblock>as provided in proposed §123.12(a)(3). The existence of such a</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory system and its enforcement will provide assurance</textblock>
    <textblock>about the conditions under which products exported from that</textblock>
    <textblock>country are being produced.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §123.12(a)(4) provides that inspection of foreign</textblock>
    <textblock>processors by the agency or other organization designated by FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>may also be used to establish compliance with these regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Finally, the agency intends to use other measures as it</textblock>
    <textblock>finds appropriate to make determinations about the acceptability</textblock>
    <textblock>of the product being offered for import, including but not</textblock>
    <textblock>limited to end product testing, as in proposed §123.12(a)(5).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
