<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00080</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Description of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Businesses.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency has submitted a copy of this proposed rule to OMB</textblock>
    <textblock>for its review of this information collection. Interested</textblock>
    <textblock>persons are requested to send comments regarding this burden</textblock>
    <textblock>estimate or any other aspect of this collection of information,</textblock>
    <textblock>including suggestions for reducing this burden to FDA's Dockets</textblock>
    <textblock>Management Branch (address above), and to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, OMB rm. 3208, New Executive</textblock>
    <textblock>Office Bldg., Washington, DC 20503, Attn: Desk Officer for FDA.</textblock>
    <textblock>X. Economic Impact</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA has examined the impacts of the proposed rule under</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12866 and the Regulatory Flexibility Act (Pub. L.</textblock>
    <textblock>96-354). Executive Order 12866 compels agencies to use</textblock>
    <textblock>cost-benefit analysis as a component of decisionmaking. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act requires regulatory relief for small</textblock>
    <textblock>businesses where feasible. FDA finds that this proposed rule</textblock>
    <textblock>constitutes a major rule under both Executive Order 12866 and the</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act. A summary of the preliminary</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory impact analysis (PRIA), which may be obtained from</textblock>
    <textblock>Dockets Management Branch (address above), is presented below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12866 requires Federal agencies to justify</textblock>
    <textblock>the need for regulations by demonstrating that the problem that</textblock>
    <textblock>the regulation is designed to remedy cannot be adequately</textblock>
    <textblock>addressed by measures other than Federal regulation. In its</textblock>
    <textblock>review of such alternatives, FDA finds that the current system</textblock>
    <textblock>(periodic inspection plus sampling of a small proportion of</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood), coupled with the uncertainty in estimating the</textblock>
    <textblock>illnesses related to seafood, has not adequately ensured</textblock>
    <textblock>consumers that a minimum level of safety has been established.</textblock>
    <textblock>Although the tort system is not able to provide remedies for</textblock>
    <textblock>unsafe seafood, the price system provides some differentiation</textblock>
    <textblock>between products based on brands and retail reputation. However,</textblock>
    <textblock>the price system works in conjunction with current Federal regulation which signals consumers as to a minimum level of seafood safety. As is argued in the preamble, countless public arguments and attempts at legislation imply that the minimum levels that some consumers believe they are getting (those that</textblock>
    <textblock>do not search for higher levels) is probably higher than the</textblock>
    <textblock>actual levels of seafood safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>The tort system fails because consumers are often unable to</textblock>
    <textblock>trace either the source of their foodborne illness to seafood,</textblock>
    <textblock>and even where that is possible, it is often difficult to trace</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood to a specific company.</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Regulatory Options</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA has evaluated multiple options to address the compelling</textblock>
    <textblock>public interest in further ensuring seafood safety. These</textblock>
    <textblock>options include: (1) Maintaining the existing approach_``snapshot'' inspections and sampling; (2) significantly</textblock>
    <textblock>increasing the frequency of both snapshot inspections and</textblock>
    <textblock>sampling under the existing approach; (3) beginning a voluntary</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP program in addition to the existing approach; (4)</textblock>
    <textblock>beginning mandatory HACCP for high risk products only, in</textblock>
    <textblock>addition to the existing approach; (5) beginning mandatory HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>for all seafood (the proposed approach); (6) beginning a more</textblock>
    <textblock>comprehensive mandatory HACCP program than that proposed, similar</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Model Seafood Surveillance Project (MSSP), which would</textblock>
    <textblock>include all CGMP's, quality factors, and economic fraud as</textblock>
    <textblock>critical control points; and (7) beginning a mandatory water-to-table HACCP program which would include all vessels, carriers,</textblock>
    <textblock>and retail food operators.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Estimated Annual Reporting and Recordkeeping Burden</textblock>
    <textblock>1Number of respondents</textblock>
    <textblock>1Average annual burden per respondent (hours)</textblock>
    <textblock>1Total burden all respondents (hours)</textblock>
    <textblock>4,349</textblock>
    <textblock>650</textblock>
    <textblock>2,826,850</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
