<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00120</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>5.</textblock>
    <textblock>Use of vacuum- and modified atmosphere-packaging.</textblock>
    <textblock>As</textblock>
    <textblock>explained above, vacuum- or modified atmosphere-packaged smoked,</textblock>
    <textblock>smoke-flavored, and salted fish products represent an increased</textblock>
    <textblock>public health hazard over conventionally packaged products</textblock>
    <textblock>because these types of packaging provide the ideal environment</textblock>
    <textblock>for spore outgrowth and toxin production. Based on the</textblock>
    <textblock>discussion above, the agency states in section 3 of Example 6 of</textblock>
    <textblock>this appendix that these types of packaging should be used only</textblock>
    <textblock>when: (1) As provided in section 5.a.2. of Example 6 of this</textblock>
    <textblock>appendix the product is a hot-process smoked or smoke-flavored</textblock>
    <textblock>product, is vacuum-packed or modified atmosphere-packed, and</textblock>
    <textblock>contains at least 3.5 percent water-phase salt in the finished</textblock>
    <textblock>product, or 3.0 percent salt and 100 to 200 ppm of sodium nitrite</textblock>
    <textblock>in the finished product (section 4.a.1. of Example 6 of this</textblock>
    <textblock>appendix); (2) as provided in section 5.a.4. of Example 6 of</textblock>
    <textblock>this appendix, the product is a cold-process smoked or</textblock>
    <textblock>smoke-flavored product, is vacuum-packed or modified atmosphere-</textblock>
    <textblock>packed, and contains at least 3.5 percent water-phase salt in the</textblock>
    <textblock>finished product or 3.0 percent salt and 100 to 200 ppm of sodium</textblock>
    <textblock>nitrite.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is providing in Appendix C, section 8.a. that all</textblock>
    <textblock>vacuum- or modified atmosphere-packaging should be conducted</textblock>
    <textblock>within the processing plant where the product is manufactured</textblock>
    <textblock>(Ref. 180). FDA considers this limitation appropriate to prevent</textblock>
    <textblock>any postprocessing contamination of the product from bacterial</textblock>
    <textblock>pathogens and to ensure that the fish will be packaged</textblock>
    <textblock>immediately after processing to protect its overall quality.</textblock>
    <textblock>6.</textblock>
    <textblock>Process monitoring.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 7 of Example 6 of this</textblock>
    <textblock>appendix, the agency is recommending specifications for</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature indicating and recording devices where they are</textblock>
    <textblock>recommended elsewhere in this appendix. These proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>specifications are the same as those proposed in Appendix A for</textblock>
    <textblock>cooked, ready-to-eat fishery products (Appendix A, section 7). A</textblock>
    <textblock>full discussion of these controls is provided in section VII.J.4.</textblock>
    <textblock>of the preamble to this document. Temperature indicating and</textblock>
    <textblock>recording devices are specifically recommended in section 5.j.</textblock>
    <textblock>and 5.k. of Example 6 of this appendix for the control of the</textblock>
    <textblock>smoking temperature.</textblock>
    <textblock>At section 5.b. of Example 6 of this appendix, the agency is</textblock>
    <textblock>recommending specific controls to ensure that the appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>water-phase salt and sodium nitrate levels are achieved. The</textblock>
    <textblock>significance of these attributes has already been discussed in</textblock>
    <textblock>this document. In section 5.b. of Example 6 of this appendix,</textblock>
    <textblock>the agency recommends that a processor perform or obtain a study</textblock>
    <textblock>that shows that under certain processing conditions the desired</textblock>
    <textblock>water phase salt or sodium nitrite level will reliably be</textblock>
    <textblock>achieved. The processor should monitor those processing</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions identified by the study as having an impact on the</textblock>
    <textblock>ability of the product to achieve the desired level. The study</textblock>
    <textblock>should provide critical limits for each of the relevant</textblock>
    <textblock>processing conditions (e.g. maximum fish size, minimum soak time,</textblock>
    <textblock>minimum salt to product ratio).</textblock>
    <textblock>Because of the existence of numerous variables that affect</textblock>
    <textblock>the ability of fish to uniformly take up salt and sodium nitrite,</textblock>
    <textblock>it may be appropriate for a processor to perform periodic</textblock>
    <textblock>finished product water phase salt or sodium nitrite analyses as a</textblock>
    <textblock>verification step. The purpose of such analyses would be to</textblock>
    <textblock>identify any variables that have an impact on salt or nitrite</textblock>
    <textblock>absorption that were not identified by the study.</textblock>
    <textblock>7.</textblock>
    <textblock>Corrective actions.</textblock>
    <textblock>At section 9 of Example 6 of this</textblock>
    <textblock>appendix, the agency is recommending corrective action</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures. These proposed procedures are the same as those</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed in the cooked, ready-to-eat section of this document</textblock>
    <textblock>(Appendix A, section 8). A full discussion of the procedures is</textblock>
    <textblock>provided in section VII.J.5 of the preamble to this document.</textblock>
    <textblock>8.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sanitary zones.</textblock>
    <textblock>At section 10 of Example 6 of this</textblock>
    <textblock>appendix, the agency is recommending the institution of sanitary</textblock>
    <textblock>zones. This proposed control procedure is the same as that</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed in the cooked, ready-to-eat section of this document</textblock>
    <textblock>(Appendix A, section 9). A full discussion of the control</textblock>
    <textblock>procedure is provided in section VII.J.6 of the preamble to this</textblock>
    <textblock>document.</textblock>
    <textblock>To further ensure the safety of the product during</textblock>
    <textblock>distribution and storage, FDA is considering adopting specific</textblock>
    <textblock>package labeling requirements for smoked and smoke-flavored fish</textblock>
    <textblock>products to reduce the opportunity of temperature abuse of the</textblock>
    <textblock>finished product. The agency requests comments on whether it</textblock>
    <textblock>should require that the label of all shipping containers and</textblock>
    <textblock>retail packages state that the product is perishable, and, more</textblock>
    <textblock>specifically, that the product must be kept refrigerated. FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>tentatively finds that such labeling is extremely important to</textblock>
    <textblock>ensuring the safe handling of these products, and, therefore, it</textblock>
    <textblock>considers it likely that it will require this labeling in the</textblock>
    <textblock>final rule. The agency requests comment on whether it should do</textblock>
    <textblock>so. The agency also requests comment on whether, if it decides</textblock>
    <textblock>to require such a label statement, the statement should specify a</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature at which the product should be refrigerated (e.g. 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (4.4</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or below). The agency is also considering requiring</textblock>
    <textblock>that the label of all frozen smoked products state that the</textblock>
    <textblock>product must remain frozen, that if the product needs to be</textblock>
    <textblock>thawed, it must be thawed at refrigerated temperatures, and that</textblock>
    <textblock>the product must not be refrozen.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA has authority to adopt these labeling requirements under</textblock>
    <textblock>sections 201(n), 403(a), and 701(a) of the act because these</textblock>
    <textblock>sections require the inclusion of facts on the food label that</textblock>
    <textblock>are material with respect to consequences that may result from</textblock>
    <textblock>use of the product under conditions of use prescribed in the</textblock>
    <textblock>label or that are otherwise customary or usual. The agency</textblock>
    <textblock>requests comments on whether it is necessary to do so.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
