<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00092</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00058</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 24, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 14, 1994, Trunkline Gas Company (Trunkline) tendered for filing as part of its FERC Gas Tariff, First Revised Volume No. 1, the following revised tariff sheets:</textblock>
    <textblock>Sub First Revised Sheet No. 216</textblock>
    <textblock>Sub First Revised Sheet No. 217</textblock>
    <textblock>Trunkline proposes that these revised tariff sheets become effective January 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Trunkline states that Ordering Paragraph (A) of the Commission's ``Order Accepting Tariff Sheets Subject to Conditions'' (Order), issued in the above-referenced proceeding on December 30, 1993, required Trunkline to make certain modifications to the tariff sheets previously submitted. As required by the Order, Section 20 (Gas Research Institute (GRI) Surcharge Provision) of the General Terms and Conditions has been modified to define the method of calculating load factors for new customers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Trunkline states that it has served a copy of the filing on its jurisdictional customers, interested state commissions and parties to the proceeding in the above-referenced docket number.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to protest said filing should file a protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rule 211 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure 18 CFR 385.211. All such protests should be filed on or before January 31, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. TM94-3-30-001]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Trunkline Gas Co.; Proposed Changes in FERC Gas Tariff</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1806 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
