<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00095</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00061</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4831-2]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Public Water Supply Supervision Program Revision for the State of Florida</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the State of Florida is revising its approved State Public Water Supply Supervision Primacy Program. Florida has adopted drinking water regulations for Lead and Copper, and Phase II (IOCs/SOCs). EPA has determined that these sets of State program revisions are no less stringent than the corresponding Federal regulations. Therefore, EPA has tentatively decided to approve these State program revisions in accordance with the conditions set forth in the December 22, 1993 letter from the Florida Department of Environmental Protection to the USEPA, Region IV.</textblock>
    <textblock>All interested parties may request a public hearing. A request for a public hearing must be submitted by March 17, 1994 to the Regional Administrator at the address shown below. Frivolous or insubstantial requests for a hearing may be denied by the Regional Administrator. However, if a substantial request for a public hearing is made by March 17, 1994, a public hearing will be held. If no timely and appropriate request for a hearing is received and the Regional Administrator does not elect to hold a hearing on his own motion, this determination shall become final and effective on March 17, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any request for a public hearing shall include the following information:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The name, address, and telephone number of the individual organization, or other entity requesting a hearing;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A brief statement of the requesting person's interest in the Regional Administrator's determination and a brief statement of the information that the requesting person intends to submit at such hearing; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The signature of the individual making the request, or, if the request is made on behalf of an organization or other entity, the signature of a responsible official of the organization or other entity.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>All documents relating to this determination are available for inspection between the hours of 8 a.m. and 4:30 p.m., Monday through Friday, at the following offices:</textblock>
    <textblock>Florida Department of Environmental Protection, Twin Towers Office Building, 2600 Blair Stone Road, Tallahassee, Florida 32399-2400.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency, Region IV, 345 Courtland Street, NE., Atlanta, Georgia 30365.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Philip H. Vorsatz, EPA Region IV Drinking Water Section at the Atlanta address given above or telephone (404) 347-2913.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>(Section 1413 of the Safe Drinking Water Act, as amended (1986), and 40 CFR 142.10 of the National Primary Drinking Water Regulations).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Patrick M. Tobin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Administrator, EPA, Region IV.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1964 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
