<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00056</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00032</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(a) A cash register may be used in the fee collection process to issue receipts to users. Visitors will be instructed to display the cash register receipt on the left side of the vehicle dashboard. Specifications for cash registers are included in Appendix E.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The Automated User Permit System (AUPS) may be used to collect day user fees.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Self-deposit vault system.</textblock>
    <textblock>Where and when appropriate, the self-deposit vault system may be used to reduce the cost of collection.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A registration point will be provided which has:</textblock>
    <textblock>_A deposit vault similar to the one shown in ER 1130-2-404, Appendix C.</textblock>
    <textblock>_A sign instructing the user on the self-deposit system, stating the fee for the area and indicating a 50 percent reduction of fees for bearers of Golden Age or Golden Access Passports. It should also provide instructions for displaying the permit stub.</textblock>
    <textblock>_ENG Form 4839A, Self-Deposit Day User Permit. This is a sealable envelope with detachable stub that will be used to pay fees. The user will be instructed to retain the stub as a receipt for display on the left side of the vehicle dashboard. These forms are available at the USACE Publication Depot.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Revenues will be collected from the deposit vault on a regular basis by authorized Corps or contractor personnel. Personnel will check to insure area users have appropriate permits.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Other methods.</textblock>
    <textblock>Fees may be collected by authorized Corps and contractor employees at project offices, visitor centers or on visits through a fee area. These collections may be made using a cash register, AUPS or ENG Form 4457.</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Types of payment.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order of preference, types of acceptable payment are in (1) U.S. currency, (2) traveler's checks or (3) personal checks for the amount of purchase only.</textblock>
    <textblock>c.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contractor collection.</textblock>
    <textblock>Whenever contractor employees are utilized for fee collection, the requirements in ER 1130-2-404 and ER 37-2-10 will apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>11.</textblock>
    <textblock>Remittance.</textblock>
    <textblock>All user fee funds will be remitted in accordance with ER 37-2-10.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
