<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00147</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00093</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>_Adequacy of the description of the impact of HIV/AIDS on</textblock>
    <textblock>children, youth, women, and families in the service area including:</textblock>
    <textblock>identification of HIV risk factors, and description of trends in</textblock>
    <textblock>the HIV epidemic.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Adequacy of the planned approach to conducting a needs</textblock>
    <textblock>assessment to identify existing resources to serve the target</textblock>
    <textblock>population and to determine and document unmet service needs.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Evidence of knowledge and understanding of HIV service</textblock>
    <textblock>delivery and experience in providing services to the population to</textblock>
    <textblock>be served.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Evidence of understanding of methods for developing</textblock>
    <textblock>comprehensive care linkages with clinical trials in order to</textblock>
    <textblock>increase access to trials for the target population.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Evidence of the potential to collaborate with</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate State/community agencies and providers in planning and</textblock>
    <textblock>developing an organized, comprehensive system of family-centered,</textblock>
    <textblock>community-based, coordinated care.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Clear delineation of goals and objectives with a</textblock>
    <textblock>timeline for accomplishment of proposed activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Clarity and appropriateness of budget based on project</textblock>
    <textblock>methodology and required resources.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Adequacy of the proposed data and evaluation plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>Eligible Applicants</textblock>
    <textblock>Grants may be awarded to public or nonprofit private entities that</textblock>
    <textblock>provide or arrange for primary health care. Eligible entities may</textblock>
    <textblock>include, but are not limited to, State or local health departments,</textblock>
    <textblock>university medical centers, public or nonprofit private hospitals,</textblock>
    <textblock>community health centers (as defined in section 330(a) of the Act),</textblock>
    <textblock>hemophilia treatment centers, drug abuse treatment agencies, tribal</textblock>
    <textblock>health programs, school based clinics and institutions of higher</textblock>
    <textblock>education. All currently funded pediatric AIDS demonstration</textblock>
    <textblock>grantees are eligible for grant funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Allowable Costs</textblock>
    <textblock>The MCHB may support reasonable and necessary costs of HIV</textblock>
    <textblock>Demonstration Project grants within the scope of approved projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>Allowable costs may include salaries, equipment and supplies,</textblock>
    <textblock>travel, contractual, consultants, and others, as well as indirect</textblock>
    <textblock>costs. The MCHB adheres to administrative standards reflected in</textblock>
    <textblock>the Code of Federal Regulation 45 CFR part 92 and 45 CFR part 74.</textblock>
    <textblock>All other sources of funding to support this project must be</textblock>
    <textblock>accurately reflected in the applicant's budget.</textblock>
    <textblock>Reporting Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>A successful applicant under this notice will submit reports in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with the provisions of the general regulations which</textblock>
    <textblock>apply under 45 CFR part 74, subpart J, Monitoring and Reporting of</textblock>
    <textblock>Program Performance, with the exception of State and local</textblock>
    <textblock>governments to which 45 CFR part 92, subpart C reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements will apply. Financial reporting will be required in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with 45 CFR part 74, subpart H, with the exception of</textblock>
    <textblock>State and local governments, to which 45 CFR 92.20 will apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Health System Reporting Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>This program is subject to the Public Health System Reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>Requirements (approved under OMB No. 0937-0195). Under these</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements, the community-based nongovernmental applicant must</textblock>
    <textblock>prepare and submit a Public Health System Impact Statement (PHSIS).</textblock>
    <textblock>The PHSIS is intended to provide information to State and local</textblock>
    <textblock>health officials to keep them apprised of proposed health services</textblock>
    <textblock>grant applications submitted by community-based nongovernmental</textblock>
    <textblock>organizations within their jurisdictions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Community-based nongovernmental applicants are required to submit</textblock>
    <textblock>the following information to the head of the appropriate State and</textblock>
    <textblock>local health agencies in the area(s) to be impacted no later than</textblock>
    <textblock>the Federal application receipt due date:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A copy of the face page of the application (SF 5161).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
