<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00028</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Consistent with the regulations at part 113, the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of ``processor'' also includes persons engaged in the</textblock>
    <textblock>production of foods that are to be used in market or consumer</textblock>
    <textblock>tests. FDA has tentatively concluded that HACCP controls are</textblock>
    <textblock>needed for such products because the hazards associated with them</textblock>
    <textblock>are no different from those that can affect other commercial</textblock>
    <textblock>products.</textblock>
    <textblock>There are, however, certain handlers of seafood that are not</textblock>
    <textblock>included in the coverage of the proposed definition. Fishing</textblock>
    <textblock>vessels that essentially only harvest are not covered by the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed HACCP regulations. As explained earlier, FDA has</textblock>
    <textblock>traditionally refrained from directly regulating fishing vessels.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency anticipates that the regulations being proposed here</textblock>
    <textblock>would affect vessels indirectly through processor and importer</textblock>
    <textblock>controls over raw materials and imported shipments, e.g.,</textblock>
    <textblock>preventive controls such as the purchasing of raw materials only</textblock>
    <textblock>from fishing vessels that engage in proper sanitation and</textblock>
    <textblock>time/temperature practices and that harvest only from approved</textblock>
    <textblock>areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>Transportation companies that carry, but do not otherwise</textblock>
    <textblock>process, fish and fishery products are also outside the scope of</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed definition, although the agency expects that</textblock>
    <textblock>transporters will be affected indirectly in the same manner as</textblock>
    <textblock>fishing vessels (see also ยง110.93). FDA invites comment on this</textblock>
    <textblock>aspect of the coverage of the proposed regulations. Proper</textblock>
    <textblock>refrigeration during transport is important for the safety of</textblock>
    <textblock>scombroid species products and of cooked, ready-to-eat products.</textblock>
    <textblock>Time and temperature conditions during shipment can also affect</textblock>
    <textblock>decomposition related to other factors bearing on seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>quality. These proposed regulations will affect transportation</textblock>
    <textblock>companies indirectly through the preventive controls the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor or importer will need to impose to ensure that the raw</textblock>
    <textblock>materials or imported shipments that it receives are free of</textblock>
    <textblock>relevant hazards and have been appropriately handled. FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>invites public discussion on whether this approach is adequate,</textblock>
    <textblock>and, if not, whether HACCP requirements should be applied</textblock>
    <textblock>directly to transportation companies. This issue is complex,</textblock>
    <textblock>especially because it is not unusual for transporters to deliver</textblock>
    <textblock>a variety of food products, including seafood, to several</textblock>
    <textblock>consignees during a single shipment.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency has also tentatively decided to exclude retail</textblock>
    <textblock>establishments from the definition of ``processor.'' As with</textblock>
    <textblock>fishing vessels, FDA has traditionally exercised enforcement</textblock>
    <textblock>discretion with regard to retail establishments. The number of</textblock>
    <textblock>retail establishments in this country_literally in the hundreds</textblock>
    <textblock>of thousands_would totally overwhelm any rational Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>inspection system. FDA has traditionally provided training and</textblock>
    <textblock>other forms of technical assistance to States and local</textblock>
    <textblock>governments to inspect retail food establishments through the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency's retail Federal/State cooperative program. A major part</textblock>
    <textblock>of that cooperative program involves the development of model</textblock>
    <textblock>codes, some of which have been widely adopted by State and local</textblock>
    <textblock>governments. FDA is now consolidating those model codes into a</textblock>
    <textblock>single, updated food code for the retail sector. Appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>HACCP-based controls are included to address seafood hazards at</textblock>
    <textblock>retail. Consequently, FDA will continue to operate through the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal/State cooperative mechanism and has not included a retail</textblock>
    <textblock>component in proposed part 123. FDA requests comments on this</textblock>
    <textblock>tentative approach.</textblock>
    <textblock>States are strongly encouraged, however, to consider how the</textblock>
    <textblock>principles in these regulations could be applied to seafood at</textblock>
    <textblock>retail and to shift to HACCP-type inspection systems as</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate. Because of the high perishability of fresh seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>and the sometimes lengthy and complex distribution chain, these</textblock>
    <textblock>products can have relatively short shelf lives by the time they</textblock>
    <textblock>reach fresh fish counters and restaurants. In addition, seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>can be subject at retail both to cross-contamination because of</textblock>
    <textblock>poor handling practices and to species substitution.</textblock>
    <textblock>Improper handling of seafood and other problems at retail</textblock>
    <textblock>have been documented in recent years. NAS has concluded that a</textblock>
    <textblock>significant number of reported acute health problems were likely</textblock>
    <textblock>linked to handling and preparation practices in food service</textblock>
    <textblock>establishments (Ref. 7, p. 27). The February, 1992 edition of</textblock>
    <textblock>Consumer Reports magazine reported on a number of such problems</textblock>
    <textblock>with regard to seafood that were observed in retail</textblock>
    <textblock>establishments. A number of studies have found lack of adequate</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature controls in retail facilities (Ref. 48, p. 75).</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is proposing to define ``shellfish control</textblock>
    <textblock>authority'' in ยง123.3(p) as the government entity responsible for</textblock>
    <textblock>implementing a comprehensive shellfish sanitation program. The</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish control authority, among other things, is responsible</textblock>
    <textblock>for classifying shellfish growing waters, performing inspections</textblock>
    <textblock>of shellfish processors, and issuing certification numbers to</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish processors. FDA relies on recognized governmental</textblock>
    <textblock>public health and food control agencies, both domestic and</textblock>
    <textblock>foreign, to carry out these functions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is proposing to define ``shellstock'' in ยง123.3(q)</textblock>
    <textblock>as meaning raw, in-shell molluscan shellfish. This specific</textblock>
    <textblock>product form designation is needed because the applicability of</textblock>
    <textblock>the tagging, labeling, and recordkeeping requirements proposed in</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง123.28(b) and (c) is determined by whether the product is</textblock>
    <textblock>shellstock or shucked product, respectively.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
