<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00118</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The agency points out that these processing parameters for</textblock>
    <textblock>vacuum-packaged hot-process smoked and smoke-flavored fish are</textblock>
    <textblock>minimums. Unless the comments on Example 6 of this appendix</textblock>
    <textblock>convince the agency otherwise, fish that have been processed at a</textblock>
    <textblock>lower temperature or with a lower water-phase salt level could</textblock>
    <textblock>provide the basis for regulatory action on the grounds that the</textblock>
    <textblock>product has been processed under conditions whereby it may have</textblock>
    <textblock>been reduced injurious to health and thus could represent a</textblock>
    <textblock>hazard for consumers.</textblock>
    <textblock>2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cold-process smoked and smoke-flavored fish.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cold-process smoked and smoke-flavored fish, by virtue of the</textblock>
    <textblock>temperatures used in processing, are not cooked because they are</textblock>
    <textblock>processed at temperatures lower than those that coagulate</textblock>
    <textblock>protein, i.e., 100</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (38</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) or lower. Because these</textblock>
    <textblock>temperatures are not high enough to inactivate</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>spores, and because they provide a favorable environment for</textblock>
    <textblock>other food spoilage microorganisms, other inhibitive factors,</textblock>
    <textblock>such as higher salt content and sodium nitrite (where permitted</textblock>
    <textblock>by food additive regulations in §172.175) need to be used.</textblock>
    <textblock>The time and temperature relationship in the processing of</textblock>
    <textblock>cold-smoked and smoke-flavored fish is a critical factor in</textblock>
    <textblock>yielding a microbiologically safe and high quality finished</textblock>
    <textblock>product (Ref. 182). Modern establishments that cold-smoked fish</textblock>
    <textblock>generally process between 40</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (5</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) and 100</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (38</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) for 18</textblock>
    <textblock>to 24 hours (Refs. 171 and 182). Based on the research data that</textblock>
    <textblock>are available and the requirements in the New York CGMP, the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency is proposing the following requirements for air-packaged</textblock>
    <textblock>and vacuum-packaged/modified atmosphere cold-process smoked and</textblock>
    <textblock>smoke-flavored fish (Refs. 25, 180, and 184).</textblock>
    <textblock>a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Air-packaged products.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is providing in</textblock>
    <textblock>section 5.a.3. of Example 6 of this appendix that air-packed,</textblock>
    <textblock>cold-process smoked and smoke-flavored fish should have a minimum</textblock>
    <textblock>water-phase salt content of: (1) 3.5 percent, or (2) 3.0</textblock>
    <textblock>percent and contain 100 to 200 ppm of sodium nitrite in the</textblock>
    <textblock>finished product, or (3) 2.5 percent in the finished product if</textblock>
    <textblock>the product is frozen immediately after processing and cooling</textblock>
    <textblock>and is kept frozen throughout holding and distribution. The</textblock>
    <textblock>agency is providing that the finished product that contains a</textblock>
    <textblock>water-phase salt content of 2.5 percent should be frozen</textblock>
    <textblock>immediately and kept frozen to ensure the microbiological safety</textblock>
    <textblock>of the product, as well as to maintain the shelf-life of the</textblock>
    <textblock>finished product.</textblock>
    <textblock>As stated above, because these products are not cooked and</textblock>
    <textblock>contain a low water-phase salt content, these products may</textblock>
    <textblock>present a potential public health hazard because they provide an</textblock>
    <textblock>ideal environment for the outgrowth of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>spores and</textblock>
    <textblock>toxin production. Therefore, based on the discussion above, the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency is suggesting that air-packaged cold-process smoked and</textblock>
    <textblock>smoke-flavored fish be processed under one of the following sets</textblock>
    <textblock>of conditions: (1) A maximum 20-hour drying and smoking period</textblock>
    <textblock>with the temperature in the smoking chamber not exceeding 90</textblock>
    <textblock>○F</textblock>
    <textblock>(32</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) (section 5.a.3.i. of Example 6 of this appendix), or (2)</textblock>
    <textblock>a maximum 24-hour drying and smoking period with the temperature</textblock>
    <textblock>in the smoking chamber not exceeding 50</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (10</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) (section</textblock>
    <textblock>5.a.3.ii. of Example 6 of this appendix) except that sablefish</textblock>
    <textblock>needs to be heated to a temperature not to exceed 120</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (49</textblock>
    <textblock>○C)</textblock>
    <textblock>for a period not to exceed 6 hours (section 5.a.3.iii. of example</textblock>
    <textblock>6 of this appendix) (Refs. 25, 180, and 184).</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Vacuum-/modified atmosphere-packaged products.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is</textblock>
    <textblock>providing in section 5.a.4. of Example 6 of this appendix that</textblock>
    <textblock>cold-process smoked and smoke-flavored fish to be vacuum- or</textblock>
    <textblock>modified atmosphere-packaged should have a minimum water-phase</textblock>
    <textblock>salt content of: (1) 3.0 percent and contain 100 to 200 ppm of</textblock>
    <textblock>sodium nitrite in the finished product, or (2) 3.5 percent in</textblock>
    <textblock>the finished product when no sodium nitrite is used. The agency</textblock>
    <textblock>is also providing that vacuum-/modified atmosphere-packaged</textblock>
    <textblock>cold-process smoked and smoke-flavored fish should be processed</textblock>
    <textblock>under one of the following sets of conditions: (1) A maximum</textblock>
    <textblock>20-hour drying and smoking period with the temperature in the</textblock>
    <textblock>smoking chamber not exceeding 90</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (32</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) (section 5.a.3.i. of</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 6 of this appendix), or (2) a maximum 24-hour drying and</textblock>
    <textblock>smoking period with the temperature in the smoking chamber not</textblock>
    <textblock>exceeding 50</textblock>
    <textblock>○F (10</textblock>
    <textblock>○C) (section 5.a.3.ii. of Example 6 of this</textblock>
    <textblock>appendix) (Refs. 25, 180, and 184).</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency again points out that these processing parameters</textblock>
    <textblock>for vacuum-/modified atmosphere-packaged cold-process smoked and</textblock>
    <textblock>smoke-flavored fish are minimums. Failure to adhere to these</textblock>
    <textblock>parameters could provide the basis for regulatory action because</textblock>
    <textblock>the product that results may be injurious to health and thus</textblock>
    <textblock>could represent a hazard to consumers.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
