<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00132</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Records of process evaluation by the process authority,</textblock>
    <textblock>where deviations from critical limits occurred.</textblock>
    <textblock>Corrective Actions</textblock>
    <textblock>When there has been a failure to maintain appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>temperature, time, or other critical factors of the process or of</textblock>
    <textblock>the product, within the critical limits, the affected product</textblock>
    <textblock>should be:</textblock>
    <textblock>•destroyed;</textblock>
    <textblock>•reprocessed to eliminate the hazard, keeping full</textblock>
    <textblock>records of the processing conditions; or,</textblock>
    <textblock>•segregated and held until an evaluation can be made</textblock>
    <textblock>to determine the effect of a deviation. The evaluation</textblock>
    <textblock>should be made by a process authority following</textblock>
    <textblock>recognized procedures. Unless the evaluation shows</textblock>
    <textblock>that the product has received adequate pasteurization,</textblock>
    <textblock>the product should be destroyed or reprocessed to</textblock>
    <textblock>eliminate the hazard.</textblock>
    <textblock>Indicating or recording thermometers that cannot be adjusted</textblock>
    <textblock>to within the critical limits should be repaired or replaced. A</textblock>
    <textblock>thermometer that has a divided fluid column should be immediately</textblock>
    <textblock>repaired or replaced.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any critical limit deviation should cause a timely</textblock>
    <textblock>assessment by management to: Learn whether the process or HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>plan needs changing to reduce the risk of recurrence of the</textblock>
    <textblock>deviation, and take appropriate followup action.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 6</textblock>
    <textblock>General Guidance for Smoked and Smoke-Flavored Fishery Products</textblock>
    <textblock>1. General guidance for smoked and smoke-flavored fishery products</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Definitions</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Critical control points</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Thawing</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Brining and smoking</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Post-smoking</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Temperature monitoring equipment</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Packaging</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Corrective actions</textblock>
    <textblock>10. Sanitary zones</textblock>
    <textblock>11. Alternative parameters</textblock>
    <textblock>1. General guidance for smoked and smoke-flavored fishery products</textblock>
    <textblock>This section provides consolidated guidance on how to meet</textblock>
    <textblock>the requirements of subpart A of 21 CFR part 123, for the</textblock>
    <textblock>processing of smoked and smoke-flavored fishery products. This</textblock>
    <textblock>guidance involves processing procedures for the control of the</textblock>
    <textblock>microbiological hazards to which these products are particularly</textblock>
    <textblock>susceptible. The guidance does not apply to finnan haddie,</textblock>
    <textblock>smoked cod fillets, smoked scotch kippers, or other smoked fish</textblock>
    <textblock>that are cooked before being consumed, because these products</textblock>
    <textblock>will be heated to destroy any potential toxins or pathogens. The</textblock>
    <textblock>guidance also does not apply to smoked fishery products that are</textblock>
    <textblock>packaged in hermetically sealed containers, processed to destroy</textblock>
    <textblock>spores of nonproteolytic</textblock>
    <textblock>C. botulinum</textblock>
    <textblock>types B, E, and F, and</textblock>
    <textblock>stored and distributed refrigerated, in the same container.</textblock>
    <textblock>These products are covered by Appendix A relating to Cooked,</textblock>
    <textblock>Ready-to-Eat fishery products. In addition, the guidance does</textblock>
    <textblock>not cover environmental or other hazards that might occur before</textblock>
    <textblock>the processor takes possession of its product or raw materials.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Guidance on these hazards may be found in a separate guidance</textblock>
    <textblock>document for all fish and fishery products issued by FDA.)</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Definitions</textblock>
    <textblock>a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cold-process smoked or cold-process smoked-flavored fish</textblock>
    <textblock>means the finished food prepared by subjecting forms of smoked</textblock>
    <textblock>fish and smoke-flavored fish to heat for a period of time that</textblock>
    <textblock>does not coagulate the protein.</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Hot-process smoked or hot-process smoke-flavored fish</textblock>
    <textblock>means the finished food prepared by subjecting forms of smoked</textblock>
    <textblock>fish and smoke-flavored fish to sufficient heat for a sufficient</textblock>
    <textblock>period of time to coagulate protein throughout the fish.</textblock>
    <textblock>c.</textblock>
    <textblock>Liquid smoke</textblock>
    <textblock>means an aqueous solution of wood smoke</textblock>
    <textblock>which, when suitably diluted, may be used to impart a smoke</textblock>
    <textblock>flavor to fish products.</textblock>
    <textblock>d.</textblock>
    <textblock>Loin muscle</textblock>
    <textblock>means the longitudinal quarter of the great</textblock>
    <textblock>lateral muscle of the fish that is free from skin, scales,</textblock>
    <textblock>visible blood clots, bones, gills, and from the nonstriated part</textblock>
    <textblock>of such muscle, which part is known anatomically as ``the median</textblock>
    <textblock>superficial muscle.''</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
