<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00050</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-2-00028</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Garnishment of Federal Civilian Employees Wages for Commercial Pay for Debt</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Defense Finance and Accounting Service, Office of the Secretary, Department of Defense</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Defense Finance and Accounting Service (DFAS) is giving notice that all requests for payments pursuant to court-ordered garnishments as authorized under Section 9 of Public Law No. 103-94, Hatch Act Reform Amendments of 1993, for all Department of Defense Civilian Employees, except those noted below, shall be submitted to the Defense Finance and Accounting Service_Cleveland Center, Office of General Counsel, Code L, 1240 East 9th Street, P.O. Box 998002, Cleveland OH 44199-8002.</textblock>
    <textblock>For Requests that apply to employees of the Army and Air Force Exchange Service or civilian employees of the Defense Contract Audit Agency (DCAA) and the Defense Logistics Agency (DLA) who are employed outside the United States, see 5 CFR part 581, appendix A.</textblock>
    <textblock>For requests that apply to civilian employees of the Army Corps of Engineers, the National Security Agency, the Defense Intelligence Agency, and non-appropriated fund civilian employees of the Air Force, contact the following offices:</textblock>
    <textblock>Army Corps of Engineers</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, Omaha District, Central Payroll Office, Attn: Garnishments, P.O. Box 1439 DTS, Omaha, NE 68101-1439.</textblock>
    <textblock>National Security Agency</textblock>
    <textblock>General Counsel, National Security Agency/Central Security Service, 9800 Savage Rd., Ft. G. Meade, MD 20755-6000.</textblock>
    <textblock>Defense Intelligence Agency</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of General Counsel, Defense Intelligence Agency, Pentagon, 2E238, Washington, DC 20340-1029.</textblock>
    <textblock>Air Force Non-Appropriated Fund Employees</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of General Counsel, Air Force Services Agency, 10100 Reunion Place, suite 503, San Antonio, TX 78216-4138.</textblock>
    <textblock>For civilian employees of the Army, Navy, and Marine Corps who are employed outside the United States, contact the following offices:</textblock>
    <textblock>Army Civilian Employees Europe</textblock>
    <textblock>266th Theater Finance Command, ATTN: AEUCF-CPF, APO New York 09007-0137.</textblock>
    <textblock>Army NAF Civilian Employees in Japan</textblock>
    <textblock>Commander, US Army Finance &amp; Accounting Office, Japan; Unit 45005, ATTN: APAJ-RM-FA-E-CP, APO AP 96343-0087.</textblock>
    <textblock>Army Civilian Employees in Korea</textblock>
    <textblock>175th Finance &amp; Accounting Office, Korea, Unit 15300, ATTN: EAFC-FO (Civilian Pay), APO AP 96205-0073.</textblock>
    <textblock>Army Civilian Employees in Panama</textblock>
    <textblock>DCSRM Finance &amp; Accounting Office, Unit 7153, ATTN: SORM-FAP-C, APO AA 34004-5000.</textblock>
    <textblock>Navy and Marine Corps Civilian Employees Overseas</textblock>
    <textblock>Director of the Office of Civilian Personnel Management; Office of the General Counsel, Navy Department, 800 N. Quincy St., Arlington, VA 22203-1998.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>This action will be effective February 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments regarding this notice should be sent to Deputy Director Resource Management, Defense Finance and Accounting Service, 1931 Jefferson Davis Highway, Crystal Mall 3, room 416, Arlington, VA 22240-5291.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Rod Winn at (216) 522-5956 or DSN 580-5956.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Congress has authorized the garnishment of Federal civilian employees' wages for commercial debts pursuant to Section 9 of Public Law 103-94, Hatch Act Reform Amendments of 1993. The applications and orders and legal issues related thereto will be reviewed by the appropriate addressee Office of General Counsel.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Patricia L. Toppings,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Alternate OSD Federal Register Liaison Officer, Department of Defense.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1817 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 5000-04-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
