<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00066</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Many in the seafood industry believe that economic abuse is</textblock>
    <textblock>one its most significant problems. A survey conducted by the</textblock>
    <textblock>National Fisheries Institute found that the Institute's</textblock>
    <textblock>membership supported mandatory inspection as a means of</textblock>
    <textblock>overcoming practices that pose a threat to the reputation of</textblock>
    <textblock>processors and packers adhering to scrupulous practices in the</textblock>
    <textblock>representation of their products (Ref. 127). General agreement</textblock>
    <textblock>was found to exist among processors, distributors, and importers,</textblock>
    <textblock>as well as retailers and restaurateurs, that abusive economic</textblock>
    <textblock>practices are widespread, including overglazing and overbreading</textblock>
    <textblock>of fishery products, inaccurate net weight measurement, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>substitution of inferior species for more valuable fish.</textblock>
    <textblock>In a similar industry study by the Southeastern Fisheries</textblock>
    <textblock>Association, members ranked problems with economic fraud (such as</textblock>
    <textblock>species identification, overglazing, and the use of phosphates)</textblock>
    <textblock>above all other seafood industry problems, except vessel handling</textblock>
    <textblock>practices (Ref. 128).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Recommended Adoption of HACCP-Based Methods</textblock>
    <textblock>Although the agency recognizes that HACCP was developed</textblock>
    <textblock>primarily to address safety, FDA believes that the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement in ยง123.6, for seafood processors to adopt HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>methods to ensure the safety of seafoods provides an opportunity</textblock>
    <textblock>for processors to develop and apply effective control point</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures that they can use to ensure that seafoods comply with</textblock>
    <textblock>the provisions of sections 402(b) and 403 of the act, The Fair</textblock>
    <textblock>Packaging and Labeling Act, the seafood standards of identity</textblock>
    <textblock>promulgated in 21 CFR, and applicable compliance policy guides</textblock>
    <textblock>issued by the agency (Compliance Policy Guides 7108.01, 7108.03,</textblock>
    <textblock>7108.04, 7108.12, 7108.13, 7108.14, 7108.21, and 7108.23).</textblock>
    <textblock>Consequently, the agency is proposing in Appendix D to establish</textblock>
    <textblock>a guideline for HACCP-based procedures to avoid economic</textblock>
    <textblock>adulteration and misbranding of seafoods. Following this</textblock>
    <textblock>guideline will enable processors to develop procedures and</textblock>
    <textblock>records that will establish that they are not engaged in any</textblock>
    <textblock>practices that would render their products economically</textblock>
    <textblock>adulterated. Clearly, however, guidelines cannot prevent</textblock>
    <textblock>economic fraud.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following guideline for product integrity lists critical</textblock>
    <textblock>control points covering raw material receipt, processing, and</textblock>
    <textblock>labels and labeling that processors and importers can incorporate</textblock>
    <textblock>in their HACCP plans. The agency believes that proper control</textblock>
    <textblock>begins with verification of the raw materials received by a</textblock>
    <textblock>processor. Therefore, in Appendix D, section 2.a., the agency is</textblock>
    <textblock>suggesting that, as part of their HACCP plan, processors and</textblock>
    <textblock>importers should include critical control points beginning with</textblock>
    <textblock>the receipt of raw materials. Ensuring that raw materials meet</textblock>
    <textblock>critical limits (e.g., correct species identification, net</textblock>
    <textblock>weight, additive identification) at the point they enter a</textblock>
    <textblock>processor's or importer's control is crucial.</textblock>
    <textblock>There are a number of ways to ensure that species are</textblock>
    <textblock>properly identified. Physical examination, as indicated in</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix D, section 2.a.1. is the typical method of determining</textblock>
    <textblock>the identity of a species. The agency believes that most seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>processors and importers are knowledgeable about the species that</textblock>
    <textblock>they handle and would have personnel available at the point of</textblock>
    <textblock>receipt who could monitor the incoming shipments for species</textblock>
    <textblock>substitution. Expert consultation is another option for</textblock>
    <textblock>correctly identifying species.</textblock>
    <textblock>Processors or importers can also check the identity of</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood by employing laboratory services, as provided for in</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix D, section 2.a.2. Protein chromatography is a</textblock>
    <textblock>laboratory method that can accurately establish the species of</textblock>
    <textblock>fish and fishery products (Ref. 50). Another option, Appendix D,</textblock>
    <textblock>section 2.a.3., is to receive raw materials certified by</textblock>
    <textblock>suppliers under either limited or general and continuing</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranties (section 303(c)(2) of the act (21 U.S.C. 333(c)(2))</textblock>
    <textblock>and 21 CFR 7.12 and 7.13).</textblock>
    <textblock>In Appendix D, section 2.b., the agency points out that</textblock>
    <textblock>processors must ensure that the labels, labeling, and invoices of</textblock>
    <textblock>their finished products accurately list weight, count, size, and</textblock>
    <textblock>product identity, as well as the content of valuable constituents</textblock>
    <textblock>(i.e., that ingredient that the consumer identifies as providing</textblock>
    <textblock>the reason to purchase the product, for example, the shrimp in</textblock>
    <textblock>breaded shrimp). The content of the valuable constituents must</textblock>
    <textblock>be maintained as required by FDA's standards of identity</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations (21 CFR part 161, including: oysters, Pacific</textblock>
    <textblock>salmon, canned wet packed shrimp in transparent or nontransparent</textblock>
    <textblock>containers, frozen raw breaded shrimp, frozen raw lightly breaded</textblock>
    <textblock>shrimp, and canned tuna) or in accordance with FDA's compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>policy guides.</textblock>
    <textblock>More specifically, as in Appendix D, section 2.b.1., the</textblock>
    <textblock>species must be correctly identified by its common or usual name</textblock>
    <textblock>and be so represented on the label and labeling. To assist</textblock>
    <textblock>processors and consumers, FDA has developed both printed and</textblock>
    <textblock>database versions of the ``FDA Fish List'' to provide such</textblock>
    <textblock>guidance. Also specific requirements for such labeling are</textblock>
    <textblock>listed in Standards of Identity and the Common or Usual Name</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations (21 CFR, parts 161 and 102).</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix D, sections 2.b.2. through b.5. are based on</textblock>
    <textblock>section 402(b) of the act. Under Appendix D, section 2.b.2., the</textblock>
    <textblock>processor needs to ensure that valuable constituents of the</textblock>
    <textblock>product are not omitted or abstracted. For example, breaded</textblock>
    <textblock>shrimp must contain the required weight ratio of shrimp to</textblock>
    <textblock>breading. Similarly, shrimp must be of the size and/or weight</textblock>
    <textblock>specified on the label or labeling.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
