<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00127</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>3. Find out whether the harvest area is closed (i.e.</textblock>
    <textblock>classified as prohibited) to fishing by a SSCA or equivalent due</textblock>
    <textblock>to chemical contamination.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Reject molluscan shellfish harvested from a closed</textblock>
    <textblock>(i.e., classified as prohibited) area, or delivered by an</textblock>
    <textblock>unlicensed harvester or uncertified dealer, or those not properly</textblock>
    <textblock>tagged.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example</textblock>
    <textblock>The ABC Fish Co. distributes clams, muscles, and</textblock>
    <textblock>oysters to restaurants. The shellfish are received</textblock>
    <textblock>from other processors. The firm examines the labels of</textblock>
    <textblock>the containers in each lot to learn the name, address,</textblock>
    <textblock>and certification number of the last processor. This</textblock>
    <textblock>information is compared to the ICSSL to confirm that</textblock>
    <textblock>the product is from a certified processor. Containers</textblock>
    <textblock>from uncertified processors and inadequately labeled</textblock>
    <textblock>containers are rejected. Contact the State Department</textblock>
    <textblock>of Health to confirm certification for unlisted</textblock>
    <textblock>processors.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency</textblock>
    <textblock>1. For finding out the location: each lot or batch.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. For checking licenses and certification: each lot or</textblock>
    <textblock>batch.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. For finding out whether the harvest area is closed:</textblock>
    <textblock>before accepting shellfish from a new area and as often after</textblock>
    <textblock>that as necessary to ensure accuracy.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. For rejecting molluscan shellfish: each lot or batch</textblock>
    <textblock>that does not meet the critical limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>Critical Limits</textblock>
    <textblock>Zero tolerance for molluscan shellfish (i.e., accept no</textblock>
    <textblock>molluscan shellfish) harvested from areas closed (i.e. classified</textblock>
    <textblock>as prohibited) by a SSCA or equivalent due to chemical</textblock>
    <textblock>contamination.</textblock>
    <textblock>Zero tolerance for molluscan shellfish (i.e., accept no</textblock>
    <textblock>molluscan shellfish) delivered by a harvester that is unlicensed</textblock>
    <textblock>or a processor that is not certified by a SSCA or equivalent.</textblock>
    <textblock>Zero tolerance for molluscan shellfish (i.e., accept no</textblock>
    <textblock>molluscan shellfish) that do not bear a tag on each container</textblock>
    <textblock>that contains the following information, at a minimum:</textblock>
    <textblock>harvester's name, address, the harvester number assigned by the</textblock>
    <textblock>SSCA or equivalent; date of harvest; location of harvest by state</textblock>
    <textblock>and site; type and quantity of shellfish. Bulk shipments should</textblock>
    <textblock>be identified by a bill-of-lading that contains the same</textblock>
    <textblock>information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Records</textblock>
    <textblock>A record for each lot or batch that shows the information</textblock>
    <textblock>from the harvester tag or bill of lading, including: name of</textblock>
    <textblock>harvester, address, identification number, the date of harvest,</textblock>
    <textblock>location of harvest by state and site, quantity and type of</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish.</textblock>
    <textblock>Corrective Actions</textblock>
    <textblock>Destroy or recall product which fails to meet the critical</textblock>
    <textblock>limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any critical limit deviation should cause a timely</textblock>
    <textblock>assessment by management to: learn whether the process or HACCP</textblock>
    <textblock>plan needs changing to reduce the risk of recurrence of the</textblock>
    <textblock>deviation, and take appropriate followup action.</textblock>
    <textblock>Option 5</textblock>
    <textblock>Where the firm receives shucked molluscan shellfish, the</textblock>
    <textblock>following applies:</textblock>
    <textblock>Control Measures</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Find out the name, address, and certification number of</textblock>
    <textblock>the last processor from the containers of shucked molluscan</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish in each lot or batch.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Compare the dealer's certification number to those</textblock>
    <textblock>listed in the most current edition of the ``Interstate Certified</textblock>
    <textblock>Shellfish Shippers List'' (ICSSL), which is published monthly. If</textblock>
    <textblock>the dealer is not listed, check for certification with the SSCA</textblock>
    <textblock>or equivalent.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Reject molluscan shellfish not from a dealer certified</textblock>
    <textblock>by a SSCA or equivalent, packed in containers not bearing the</textblock>
    <textblock>name, address, and certification number of the last processor.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
