<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00027</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940128-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The agency is proposing in §123.3(g) to define ``harvester''</textblock>
    <textblock>as a person who commercially takes molluscan shellfish from their</textblock>
    <textblock>growing waters, by any means. Harvester is defined because,</textblock>
    <textblock>under this proposal, this person has responsibility for tagging</textblock>
    <textblock>the product as to where it was harvested and when. Harvesters</textblock>
    <textblock>are expected to have an identification number issued by a</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish control authority. Harvesting is generally illegal</textblock>
    <textblock>without such a number.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is proposing to define the term ``importer'' in</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.3(h) as the owner of the imported goods or his</textblock>
    <textblock>representative in the United States. This is the person who is</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible for ensuring goods being entered are in compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>with all laws affecting the importation. Importers may not</textblock>
    <textblock>always directly handle the imported food, but they are</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible for the safety and wholesomeness of products they</textblock>
    <textblock>offer for entry into the United States and therefore are subject</textblock>
    <textblock>to part 123.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency recognizes that the term ``importer'' is often used</textblock>
    <textblock>to describe not only the owner of the goods or his representative</textblock>
    <textblock>in the United States (that is, the importer of record) but also</textblock>
    <textblock>includes freight forwarders, food brokers, food jobbers,</textblock>
    <textblock>carriers, and steamship representatives. These other agents</textblock>
    <textblock>often represent the importer for legal and financial purposes</textblock>
    <textblock>that are not necessarily related to the safety of the product.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, the agency has tentatively concluded that it is</textblock>
    <textblock>inappropriate to focus the HACCP requirements that bear on</textblock>
    <textblock>imports on these persons if they do not have authority to make</textblock>
    <textblock>decisions affecting the product's safety or wholesomeness.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to define a ``lot of molluscan shellfish'' in</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.3(i) as no more than one day's harvest from a single,</textblock>
    <textblock>defined growing area, by one or more harvesters. This definition</textblock>
    <textblock>establishes the quantity of shellfish that represents a single</textblock>
    <textblock>lot for tagging or labeling purposes. Lot distinctions are</textblock>
    <textblock>needed to differentiate shellfish harvested from different</textblock>
    <textblock>growing areas or at different times. The time limit of one day</textblock>
    <textblock>is imposed because the safety of a harvesting area can change</textblock>
    <textblock>daily as the result of rainfall, tides, winds, and other events</textblock>
    <textblock>that can bring contaminants into the area. The ultimate safety</textblock>
    <textblock>of raw molluscan shellfish is contingent on the water quality of</textblock>
    <textblock>the harvesting area. To ensure product safety, shellfish</textblock>
    <textblock>harvesting areas that are subject to appropriate state control</textblock>
    <textblock>are closed to harvesting within 24 hours of a finding of adverse</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions. The lot definition, coupled with the harvest date on</textblock>
    <textblock>the harvesting tag, provides evidence that the shellfish were</textblock>
    <textblock>harvested when the area was safe and open for harvesting.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is proposing in §123.3(j) that ``molluscan</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish'' means any edible species, or edible portion of fresh</textblock>
    <textblock>or frozen oysters, clams, mussels, and scallops, except were the</textblock>
    <textblock>scallop product consists entirely of the shucked adductor mussel.</textblock>
    <textblock>The distinction between molluscan shellfish and crustacean</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish, which include crabs, shrimp, and lobsters, is made</textblock>
    <textblock>because molluscan shellfish are commonly eaten whole and raw,</textblock>
    <textblock>while crustacean shellfish are not. The safety of molluscan</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish therefore reflects the quality of the waters from which</textblock>
    <textblock>they are harvested and requires special public health controls.</textblock>
    <textblock>Furthermore, the agency is proposing to amend the definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>``shellfish'' in §1240.3(p) (21 CFR 1240.3(p)) to make it</textblock>
    <textblock>consistent with the proposed definition in §123.3(j).</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is proposing to amend the term ``shellfish'' in</textblock>
    <textblock>§1240.3(p) to read ``molluscan shellfish'' to make the terms</textblock>
    <textblock>consistent between parts 123 and 1240. Because the term</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish in its common usage, i.e., an edible mollusk or</textblock>
    <textblock>crustacean, includes crabs and lobsters, the agency believes that</textblock>
    <textblock>it is necessary to be more specific and accurate in its</textblock>
    <textblock>definition and consequent application of the requirements in its</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations. The proposed requirements for tagging do not apply</textblock>
    <textblock>to crabs and lobsters or to scallops when the final product is</textblock>
    <textblock>the shucked adductor muscle only. The agency is proposing to</textblock>
    <textblock>expand the definition in §1240.3(p) to include scallops to make</textblock>
    <textblock>it consistent with the definitions in proposed part 123 and with</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements under NSSP.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency is proposing to define ``potable water'' in</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.3(k) as water that meets EPA's primary drinking water</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations as set forth in 40 CFR part 141. Those regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>provide limits for certain microbiological, chemical, physical,</textblock>
    <textblock>and radiological contaminants that can render water unsafe for</textblock>
    <textblock>human consumption.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed definition is slightly different from the</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of ``potable water'' in §§1240.3(k) and 1250.3(j) (21</textblock>
    <textblock>CFR 1250.3(j). That definition also references the regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>of EPA in 40 CFR part 141 but further includes FDA sanitation</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements in 21 CFR parts 1240 and 1250. Those sanitation</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements apply to interstate travel conveyances that must</textblock>
    <textblock>take on water at watering points. Such requirements are not</textblock>
    <textblock>relevant to these proposed regulations and thus were not included</textblock>
    <textblock>in the proposed definition.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is proposing to define ``processing'' and ``processor'' in</textblock>
    <textblock>§123.3(m) and (n) broadly to ensure the safety of seafood</textblock>
    <textblock>through the application of HACCP principles throughout the</textblock>
    <textblock>seafood industry. The definition of ``processor'' is intended to</textblock>
    <textblock>include all seafood processors that handle products in interstate</textblock>
    <textblock>commerce, such as shuckers and other processors of raw molluscan</textblock>
    <textblock>shellfish, factory ships, packers, repackers, wholesalers, and warehouses. Those who process low acid canned foods are also</textblock>
    <textblock>included, even though they are subject to the HACCP controls of</textblock>
    <textblock>part 113. Those controls are targeted toward a limited number of</textblock>
    <textblock>safety hazards. These proposed regulations require that</textblock>
    <textblock>processors apply HACCP controls to all likely safety hazards.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
