<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00095</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Electric power, Electric utilities, Loan programs_energy, Rural areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set out in the preamble, REA amends chapter XVII, title 7 of the Code of Federal Regulations as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 1710_GENERAL AND PRE-LOAN POLICIES AND PROCEDURES COMMON TO INSURED AND GUARANTEED ELECTRIC LOANS</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 1710 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>7 U.S.C. 901-950(b); Pub. L. 99-591, 100 Stat. 3341; Delegation of Authority by the Secretary of Agriculture, 7 CFR 2.23; Delegation of Authority by the Under Secretary for Small Community and Rural Development, 7 CFR 2.72.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 1710.2(a) is amended by adding new definitions in alphabetical order to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§1710.2</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions and rules of construction.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>Demand side management</textblock>
    <textblock>(DSM) means the deliberate planning and/or implementation of activities to influence consumer use of electricity provided by a distribution borrower to produce beneficial modifications to the system load profile. Beneficial modifications to the system load profile ordinarily improve load factor or otherwise help in utilizing electric system resources to best advantage consistent with acceptable standards of service and lowest system cost. Load profile modifications are characterized as peak clipping, valley filling, load shifting, strategic conservation, strategic load growth, and flexible load profile. (See, for example, publications of the Electric Power Research Institute (EPRI), 3412 Hillview Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, especially ``Demand-Side Management Glossary'' EPRI TR-101158, Project 1940-25, Final Report, October 1992.) DSM includes energy conservation programs. It does not include sources of electrical energy such as renewable energy systems, fuel cells, or traditionally fueled generation, such as fossil or nuclear fueled generators.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>DSM activities</textblock>
    <textblock>means activities of the type referred to in §1710.354(f).</textblock>
    <textblock>DSM plan</textblock>
    <textblock>means a plan that describes the implementation at the distribution level of the DSM activities identified in the integrated resource plan as having positive net benefits. See §1710.357.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Integrated Resources Plan (IRP)</textblock>
    <textblock>means a plan resulting from the planning and selection process for new energy resources that evaluates the benefits and costs of the full range of alternatives, including new generating capacity, power purchases, DSM programs, system operating efficiency, and renewable energy systems.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Off-grid renewable energy system</textblock>
    <textblock>means an energy source which is not electrically attached to the grid. Off-grid systems are operated as an island and will have no direct impact on a utility system's physical operations. An off-grid system need not meet electric utility power quality standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>On-grid renewable energy system</textblock>
    <textblock>means an energy source electrically attached to an existing grid. It can be attached on either side of a consumer's meter. On-grid systems are operated as part of the overall utility system and have a direct impact on a utility system's operations. An on-grid system must meet electric utility power quality and safety standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Renewable energy system</textblock>
    <textblock>means a source of energy (kWh) used to meet borrower electric load that is fueled by any of the following technologies: Hydropower, geothermal, biomass, municipal waste, solar thermal, photovoltaic, wind, fuel cells not fueled by fossil fuels. See, for example, ``Renewable Resources in U.S. Electricity Supply,'' February 1993, Publication number DOE/EIA 0561, published by the Department of Energy, Energy Information Administration, Forrestal Building, EI-231, Washington, DC 20585.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>§1710.118</textblock>
    <textblock>[Removed and Reserved]</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Section 1710.118 is removed and reserved.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Subpart H heading is revised and the text of subpart H is added to part 1710 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart H_Demand Side Management and Renewable Energy Systems</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.350␣Purpose.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.351␣General policy; renewable energy systems.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.352␣General policy; energy resource conservation programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.353␣General policy; demand side management.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.354␣Eligible DSM activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.355␣DSM loan applications.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.356␣Integrated resource plans.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.357␣DSM plans.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.358␣Requirements for a DSM plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.359␣DSM effects.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.360␣Submittal of alternate documentation.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.361␣Type and term of loans.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.362␣Loan approval.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.363␣Advance and documentation of use of loan funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>1710.364␣Loan limits.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart H_Demand Side Management and Renewable Energy Systems</textblock>
    <textblock>§1710.350</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
