<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00062</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00041</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Notice of Lodging of Consent Decree Pursuant to the Resource Conservation Act and the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with Departmental policy, 28 CFR 50.7, notice is hereby given that a proposed consent decree in United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Pacific Corp.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Civil Action No. 91-771-AS was lodged on December 17, 1993, with the United States District Court for the District of Oregon. The Consent Decree settles all claims with the two defendants, Environmental Pacific Corporation (EPC) and Richard Hill.</textblock>
    <textblock>The original complaint in this action was brought against EPC pursuant to Section 3008(h) of the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act (RCRA), 42 U.S.C. 6928(h), seeking an order that EPC perform corrective action at its facility in Amity, Oregon to clean up hazardous constituents that had been released into the environment. EPC operated a hazardous waste treatment, storage or disposal facility in Amity, where EPC handled primarily spent batteries, electroplating wastewater treatment sludge, and other allegedly recyclable materials containing plastics and metals.</textblock>
    <textblock>In an amended complaint, the United States added claims against EPC and Richard Hill, the President of EPC while the company was in operation, pursuant to 40 CFR 268.50 for improper storage of F006 electroplating wastes and mercury, which are wastes restricted from land disposal under RCRA. The amended complaint also included a claim against Richard Hill under section 104(e) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act, as amended (CERCLA), 42 U.S.C. 9604(e), for failure to timely respond to information requests that EPA had sent to Mr. Hill.</textblock>
    <textblock>As set forth in the consent decree, Settling Defendants shall pay $113,055.30 towards past response costs incurred during a removal action performed by EPA pursuant to its authority under section 104 of CERCLA, 42 U.S.C. 9604, at the EPC facility. Settling Defendants shall also pay $60,163.00 which will be used for performing sampling and analysis and groundwater monitoring outside of the boundaries of the EPC facility.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Justice will receive, for a period of thirty (30) days from the date of this publication, comments relating to the proposed consent decree. Comments should be addressed to the Assistant Attorney General for the Environment and Natural Resources Division, Department of Justice, Washington, DC 20530, and should refer to</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Pacific Corp.,</textblock>
    <textblock>DOJ Ref. #90-7-1-608.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed consent decree may be examined at the Office of the United States Attorney, 312 U.S. Courthouse, 620 SW Main Street, Portland, Oregon 97205; the Region 10 Office of EPA, 7th Floor Records Center, 1200 Sixth Avenue, Seattle, WA 98101; and at the Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., 4th Floor, Washington, DC 20005, (202) 624-0892. A copy of the proposed consent decree may be obtained in person or by mail from the Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., 4th Floor, Washington, DC 20005. In requesting a copy please refer to the referenced case and enclose a check in the amount of $6.75 (25 cents per page reproduction costs), payable to the Consent Decree Library.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle/>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John C. Cruden,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Environmental Enforcement Section, Environment and Natural Resources Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-83 Filed 1-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
