<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00033</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00024</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93E-0353]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Determination of Regulatory Review Period for Purposes of Patent Extension; Betaseron</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration, HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has determined the regulatory review period for Betaseron</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>and is publishing this notice of that determination as required by law. FDA has made the determination because of the submission of an application to the Commissioner of Patents and Trademarks, Department of Commerce, for the extension of a patent which claims that human biologic product.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments and petitions should be directed to the Dockets Management Branch (HFA-305), Food and Drug Administration, rm. 1-23, 12420 Parklawn Dr., Rockville, MD 20857.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Brian J. Malkin, Office of Health Affairs (HFY-20), Food and Drug Administration, 5600 Fishers Lane, Rockville, MD 20857, 301-443-1382.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Drug Price Competition and Patent Term Restoration Act of 1984 (Pub. L. 98-417) and the Generic Animal Drug and Patent Term Restoration Act (Pub. L. 100-670) generally provide that a patent may be extended for a period of up to 5 years so long as the patented item (human drug product, animal drug product, medical device, food additive, or color additive) was subject to regulatory review by FDA before the item was marketed. Under these acts, a product's regulatory review period forms the basis for determining the amount of extension an applicant may receive.</textblock>
    <textblock>A regulatory review period consists of two periods of time: a testing phase and an approval phase. For human drug products, the testing phase begins when the exemption to permit the clinical investigations of the drug becomes effective and runs until the approval phase begins. The approval phase starts with the initial submission of an application to market the human drug product and continues until FDA grants permission to market the drug product. Although only a portion of a regulatory review period may count toward the actual amount of extension that the Commissioner of Patents and Trademarks may award (for example, half the testing phase must be subtracted as well as any time that may have occurred before the patent was issued), FDA's determination of the length of a regulatory review period for a human drug product will include all of the testing phase and approval phase as specified in 35 U.S.C. 156(g)(1)(B).</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA recently approved for marketing the human biologic product Betaseron</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>(Interferon</textblock>
    <textblock>beta</textblock>
    <textblock>-1b). Betaseron</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>is indicated for use in ambulatory patients with relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis to reduce the frequency of clinical exacerbations. Subsequent to this approval, the Patent and Trademark Office received a patent term restoration application for Betaseron</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>(U.S. Patent No. 4,588,585) from the Cetus Oncology Corp., and the Patent and Trademark Office requested FDA's assistance in determining the patent's eligibility for patent term restoration. In a letter dated October 26, 1993, FDA advised the Patent and Trademark Office that this human biologic product had undergone a regulatory review period and that the approval of Betaseron</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>represented the first permitted commercial marketing or use of the product. Shortly thereafter, the Patent and Trademark Office requested that FDA determine the product's regulatory review period.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA has determined that the applicable regulatory review period for Betaseron</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>is 3,720 days. Of this time, 3,319 days occurred during the testing phase of the regulatory review period, while 401 days occurred during the approval phase. These periods of time were derived from the following dates:</textblock>
    <textblock>1.</textblock>
    <textblock>The date an exemption under section 505(i) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act became effective</textblock>
    <textblock>: May 19, 1983. The applicant claims April 4, 1986, as the date the investigational new drug application (IND) became effective. However, FDA records indicate that the IND effective date was May 19, 1983, which was 30 days after FDA receipt of the IND.</textblock>
    <textblock>2.</textblock>
    <textblock>The date the application was initially submitted with respect to the human drug product under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act</textblock>
    <textblock>: June 18, 1992. The applicant claims June 16, 1992, as the date the product license application (PLA) for Betaseron</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>(PLA 92-0495) was initially submitted. However, FDA records indicate that PLA 92-0495 was initially submitted on June 18, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>3.</textblock>
    <textblock>The date the application was approved</textblock>
    <textblock>: July 23, 1993. FDA has verified the applicant's claim that PLA 92-0495 was approved on July 23, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>This determination of the regulatory review period establishes the maximum potential length of a patent extension. However, the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office applies several statutory limitations in its calculations of the actual period for patent extension. In its application for patent extension, this applicant seeks 1,500 days of patent term extension.</textblock>
    <textblock>Anyone with knowledge that any of the dates as published is incorrect may, on or before March 7, 1994, submit to the Dockets Management Branch (address above) written comments and ask for a redetermination. Furthermore, any interested person may petition FDA, on or before July 5, 1994, for a determination regarding whether the applicant for extension acted with due diligence during the regulatory review period. To meet its burden, the petition must contain sufficient facts to merit an FDA investigation. (See H. Rept. 857, part 1, 98th Cong., 2d sess., pp. 41-42, 1984.) Petitions should be in the format specified in 21 CFR 10.30.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments and petitions should be submitted to the Dockets Management Branch (address above) in three copies (except that individuals may submit single copies) and identified with the docket number found in brackets in the heading of this document. Comments and petitions may be seen in the Dockets Management Branch between 9 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through Friday.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 17, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Allen B. Duncan,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Associate Commissioner for Health Affairs.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-36 Filed 1-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
