<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00037</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00028</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>MEDWATCH Conference on Drug and Device-induced Disease: Developing a Blueprint for the Future; Notice of Public Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration, HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is announcing the Commissioner's MED</textblock>
    <textblock>WATCH</textblock>
    <textblock>Conference on Drug and Device-Induced Disease: Developing a Blueprint for the Future. The conference is co-sponsored by FDA and the American Medical Association (AMA) in cooperation with the following organizations: American Association of Colleges of Nursing, American Association of Colleges of Pharmacy, American Association of Dental Schools, American Dental Association, American Hospital Association, American Nursing Association, American Society of Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics, American Society of Hospital Pharmacists, Association of American Medical Colleges, and the Council on Education in Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The conference will be held on January 21, 1994, from 8:30 a.m. to 5 p.m., and January 22, 1994, from 8:30 a.m. to 12:30 p.m.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The conference will be held at the Stouffer Mayflower Hotel, 1127 Connecticut Ave. NW., Washington, DC 20036. Registration is required.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mary Pat Couig, Office of Health Affairs (HFY-40), Food and Drug Administration, 5600 Fishers Lane, Rockville, MD 20857, 301-443-5470. For registration call the American Medical Association at 1-800-621-8335.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Drug and device-induced diseases are serious health problems. It is estimated that 2 to 10 percent of all hospitalizations are a result of serious adverse events. The purpose of this conference is to develop recommendations on ways to heighten health professionals' awareness of the extent and spectrum of drug and device-induced disease and to break down barriers to the discovery and reporting of important adverse events to FDA and manufacturers by: (1) Strengthening undergraduate curricula, (2) enhancing postgraduate training, and (3) building user-friendly reporting mechanisms for health professionals.</textblock>
    <textblock>David A. Kessler, Commissioner of Food and Drugs, and James S. Todd, Executive Vice President of the AMA, will be the keynote speakers.</textblock>
    <textblock>The conference should be of interest to the following groups: Practicing health professionals, health professional organizations, health professions educators (undergraduate and graduate), health professionals of State health departments, regulatory and safety surveillance professionals, and hospital personnel (e.g, risk managers/quality assurance personnel and members of Pharmacy and Therapeutics Committees).</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a participatory conference. Recommendations from the breakout sessions will be presented on the second day of the conference and their implementation discussed at the final panel discussion.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 23, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David A. Kessler,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-39 Filed 1-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
