<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00074</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary revises part 685 of title 34 of the Code of Federal Regulations to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 685_STANDARDS, CRITERIA, AND PROCEDURES FOR THE DIRECT LOANS PROGRAM</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart A_Purpose and Scope</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.100␣The Federal Direct Student Loan Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.101␣Participation in the Direct Loan Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.102␣Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.103␣Applicability of subparts.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart B_Borrower Provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>685.200␣Borrower eligibility.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.201␣Obtaining a loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.202␣Charges for which Direct Loan Program borrowers are responsible.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.203␣Loan limits.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.204␣Deferment.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.205␣Forbearance.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.206␣Borrower responsibilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart C_Requirements, Standards and Payments for Direct Loan Program Schools</textblock>
    <textblock>685.300␣Agreements between an eligible school and the Secretary for participation in the Direct Loan Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.301␣Certification by a Direct Loan Program school for a loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.302␣Correspondence school schedule requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.303␣Disbursing borrowers' loan proceeds and counseling borrowers.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.304␣Determining the date of a student's withdrawal.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.305␣Payment of a refund to the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.306␣Withdrawal procedure for schools participating in the Direct Loan Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.307␣Remedial actions.</textblock>
    <textblock>685.308␣Administrative and fiscal control and fund accounting requirements for schools participating in the Direct Loan Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix A␣New Loan Maximums as of July 1, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>20 U.S.C. 1087a</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart A_Purpose and Scope</textblock>
    <textblock>§685.100</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Direct Student Loan Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Under the Federal Direct Student Loan Program (Direct Loan Program), the Secretary makes loans to enable a student or parent to pay the costs of the student's attendance at postsecondary schools. This part governs the Federal Direct Stafford Loan Program, the Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan Program, and the Federal Direct PLUS Program for the academic year beginning July 1, 1994. The Secretary makes loans under the following program components:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Federal Direct Stafford Loan Program, which provides loans to undergraduate, graduate, and professional students. The Secretary subsidizes the interest while the borrower is in an in-school, grace, or deferment period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan Program, which provides loans to undergraduate, graduate and professional students. The borrower is responsible for the interest that accrues during any period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Federal Direct PLUS Program, which provides loans to parents of dependent students. The borrower is responsible for the interest that accrues during any period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The Secretary makes a Federal Direct Stafford Loan, a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan, or a Federal Direct PLUS loan only to a student or a parent of a student enrolled in a school that has been selected by the Secretary to participate in the Direct Loan Program.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
