<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00038</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In 1989, the CDFG estimated that the winter-run chinook salmon run size was only 547 fish. This unexpectedly small return represented nearly a 75 percent decline from the consistent, but low, run size of 2,000 to 3,000 fish that had occurred since 1982. As a result of this unexpected decline, NMFS issued an emergency interim rule listing the winter-run chinook salmon as threatened under the ESA on August 4, 1989 (54 FR 32085). During the period the emergency interim rule was in effect, NMFS published a proposed rule to list winter-run chinook salmon as threatened under the formal listing procedures of the ESA on March 20, 1990 (55 FR 10260). To avoid a hiatus in protection of the species until the formal listing process was completed, NMFS published a second emergency interim rule listing winter-run chinook salmon as threatened on April 2, 1990 (55 FR 12191). On November 5, 1990, NMFS completed the formal listing process and published a final rule (55 FR 46515) listing the species as threatened under the ESA.</textblock>
    <textblock>On June 5, 1991, the American Fisheries Society petitioned NMFS to reclassify winter-run chinook salmon as an endangered species. At the time the petition was submitted, the best preliminary data available indicated that the 1991 run would consist of a return of only 88 to 200 adults from the progeny of the 1988 run of 2,085 fish. The final run size estimate made by the CDFG for 1991 was 191 fish (Table 1). NMFS reviewed the petition and determined that it contained substantial information indicating that the petitioned action might be warranted. On November 7, 1991, NMFS announced (56 FR 58986) its intention to review the status of the species to determine whether reclassification was appropriate. After conducting a status review, NMFS published a proposed rule (57 FR 27416) on June 19, 1992, to reclassify winter-run chinook salmon as endangered.</textblock>
    <textblock>NMFS published a subsequent Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice (58 FR 31688) on June 4, 1993, delaying the issuance of a final determination on the reclassification for up to six months pursuant to section 4(b)(6)(B) of the ESA. On September 10, 1993, NMFS published another</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice that provided information on the 1993 run size estimate (341 fish) and reopened the public comment period on the proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>This determination does not change any of the prohibitions against taking Sacramento River winter-run chinook salmon. Section 9 of the ESA prohibits taking endangered species. The regulations issued when this species was listed as threatened in November 1990 also prohibit taking.</textblock>
    <textblock>In a separate rulemaking, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (FWS), which is responsible for the List of Endangered and Threatened Wildlife, will revise the list to reflect the reclassification of this species from threatened to endangered.</textblock>
    <textblock>Current Status</textblock>
    <textblock>Conservation measures were implemented by the Bureau of Reclamation (Bureau) beginning in 1986-1987 in an effort to improve adult passage conditions for winter-run chinook salmon at Red Bluff Diversion Dam and to provide suitable spawning and egg incubation conditions for the species in the upper Sacramento River below Keswick Dam. Despite the implementation of measures in 1986-1987 and 1987-1988, the winter-run chinook salmon run size declined to 441 fish in 1990 and to 191 fish in 1991. The estimated 1991 run size of 191 fish was primarily the result of surviving progeny from the 1988 spawning population of 2,085 fish. Thus, the 1991 spawning escapement represented nearly a 90 percent decline in a single generation, and suggested that the 1988 year class was nearly a total failure (57 FR 27416).</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table</textblock>
    <textblock>1._</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Estimated Run Size at Red Bluff Diversion Dam</textblock>
    <textblock>1Year</textblock>
    <textblock>1Number of Fish</textblock>
    <textblock>1967</textblock>
    <textblock>57,306</textblock>
    <textblock>1968</textblock>
    <textblock>84,414</textblock>
    <textblock>1969</textblock>
    <textblock>117,808</textblock>
    <textblock>1970</textblock>
    <textblock>40,409</textblock>
    <textblock>1971</textblock>
    <textblock>53,089</textblock>
    <textblock>1972</textblock>
    <textblock>37,133</textblock>
    <textblock>1973</textblock>
    <textblock>24,079</textblock>
    <textblock>1974</textblock>
    <textblock>21,897</textblock>
    <textblock>1975</textblock>
    <textblock>23,430</textblock>
    <textblock>1976</textblock>
    <textblock>35,096</textblock>
    <textblock>1977</textblock>
    <textblock>17,214</textblock>
    <textblock>1978</textblock>
    <textblock>24,862</textblock>
    <textblock>1979</textblock>
    <textblock>2,364</textblock>
    <textblock>1980</textblock>
    <textblock>1,156</textblock>
    <textblock>1981</textblock>
    <textblock>20,041</textblock>
    <textblock>1982</textblock>
    <textblock>1,242</textblock>
    <textblock>1983</textblock>
    <textblock>1,831</textblock>
    <textblock>1984</textblock>
    <textblock>2,663</textblock>
    <textblock>1985</textblock>
    <textblock>3,962</textblock>
    <textblock>1986</textblock>
    <textblock>2,422</textblock>
    <textblock>1987</textblock>
    <textblock>2,236</textblock>
    <textblock>1988</textblock>
    <textblock>2,085</textblock>
    <textblock>1989</textblock>
    <textblock>547</textblock>
    <textblock>1990</textblock>
    <textblock>441</textblock>
    <textblock>1991</textblock>
    <textblock>191</textblock>
    <textblock>1992</textblock>
    <textblock>1,180</textblock>
    <textblock>1993</textblock>
    <textblock>341</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
