<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-1-00030</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-1-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Abandoned Mine Reclamation Grant Procedures</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>30 CFR Parts 870, 886, 887, and 888</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1029-AB72</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office and Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule; extension of public comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement (OSM) of the United States Department of the Interior extends until March 8, 1994, the public comment period on the proposed rule published in the November 8, 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 59334). The extension will provide interested persons more time in which to comment.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written Comments:</textblock>
    <textblock>OSM will accept written comments on the proposed rule until 5 p.m. Eastern time on March 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written Comments:</textblock>
    <textblock>Hand deliver to the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement, Administrative Record, room 660, 800 North Capitol St., Washington, DC; or mail to the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement, Administrative Record, room 660 NC, 1951 Constitution Avenue NW., Washington, DC 20240.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Norman J. Hess, Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement, U.S. Department of the Interior, 1951 Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20240; Telephone: 202-208-2949.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>OSM published a proposed rule on November 8, 1993 (58 FR 59334), that would revise the Abandoned Mine Lands (AML) regulations in 30 CFR chapter VII, subchapter R to ensure that they will be consistent with agency practice and all past amendments to Title IV of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act. The specific changes proposed to the AML rules are set forth in the November 8, 1993,</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>The comment period for the proposed rule was scheduled to close on January 7, 1994. However, an extension of the comment period was requested in order to provide more time in which to comment on the proposed rule. Therefore, OSM is extending the comment period. Comments will now be accepted until 5 p.m. local time on March 8, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 29, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Brent Wahlquist,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Director, Reclamation and Regulatory Policy.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-68 Filed 1-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-05-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
