<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00028</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Coastal Migratory Pelagic Resources of the Gulf of Mexico and South Atlantic</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>50 CFR Part 642</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 930791-3191; I.D. UP30]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Trip limit reduction.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>NMFS reduces the commercial trip limit in the Florida west coast zone to 50 king mackerel per day in or from the exclusive economic zone (EEZ). This trip limit reduction is necessary to protect the overfished Gulf king mackerel resource.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The 50-fish commercial trip limit is effective 12:01 p.m., local time, December 29, 1993, and remains in effect through June 30, 1994, unless the commercial fishery for king mackerel in the Florida west coast zone is closed before June 30 by publication of a notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mark F. Godcharles, 813-893-3161.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The fishery for coastal migratory pelagic fish (king mackerel, Spanish mackerel, cero, cobia, little tunny, dolphin, and, in the Gulf of Mexico only, bluefish) is managed under the Fishery Management Plan for the Coastal Migratory Pelagic Resources of the Gulf of Mexico and South Atlantic (FMP). The FMP was prepared by the Gulf of Mexico and South Atlantic Fishery Management Councils (Councils) and is implemented by regulations at 50 CFR part 642, under the authority of the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Catch limits recommended by the Councils and implemented by NMFS for the Gulf of Mexico migratory group of king mackerel for the current fishing year (July 1, 1993, through June 30, 1994, 58 FR 58509, November 2, 1993) set the commercial quota of king mackerel in the Florida west coast zone at 865,000 pounds (392,361 kg). In accordance with 50 CFR 642.31(a)(2), from the date that 75 percent of the zone's commercial quota has been harvested until a closure of the Florida west coast zone has been effected, king mackerel in or from the EEZ may be possessed aboard or landed from a permitted vessel in amounts not exceeding 50 per day. Such 50-fish trip limit remains in effect through June 30, 1994, the end of the fishing year, unless 100 percent of the commercial quota is reached before June 30, in which case the commercial fishery for king mackerel in the Florida west coast zone is closed by publication of a notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>NMFS has determined that 75 percent of the commercial quota for Gulf group king mackerel from the Florida west coast zone was reached on December 28, 1993. Accordingly, a 50-fish trip limit applies to king mackerel in or from the EEZ in the Florida west coast zone effective 12:01 p.m., local time, December 29, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Florida west coast zone extends from the Alabama/Florida boundary (87</textblock>
    <textblock>○31</textblock>
    <textblock>’06</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’W. longitude) to: (1) the Dade/Monroe County, Florida boundary (25</textblock>
    <textblock>○20.4</textblock>
    <textblock>’N. latitude) from November 1 through March 31; and (2) the Monroe/Collier County, Florida boundary (25</textblock>
    <textblock>○48</textblock>
    <textblock>’N. latitude) from April 1 through October 31.</textblock>
    <textblock>Classification</textblock>
    <textblock>This action is required by 50 CFR 642.31(a)(2) and (b).</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 1801</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 50 CFR Part 642</textblock>
    <textblock>Fisheries, Fishing, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 29, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David S. Crestin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Office of Fisheries Conservation and Management, National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 93-32097 Filed 12-29-93; 3:44 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
