<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00090</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(2) Unless it expects to submit its next student status confirmation report to the Secretary within the next 60 days, notify the Secretary within 30 days_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) If it discovers that a Federal Direct Stafford, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford, or Federal Direct PLUS loan has been made to or on behalf of a student who enrolled at that school, but who has ceased to be enrolled on at least a half-time basis;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) If it discovers that a Federal Direct Stafford, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford or Federal Direct PLUS loan has been made to or on behalf of a student who has been accepted for enrollment at that school, but who failed to enroll on at least a half-time basis for the period for which the loan was intended; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) If it discovers that a Federal Direct Stafford, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford, or Federal Direct PLUS loan has been made to or on behalf of a full-time student who has ceased to be enrolled on a full-time basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Record retention requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Unless otherwise directed by the Secretary, the school or its successors_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Shall keep all records required under the regulations in this part for five years following the last day of the borrower's attendance at the school;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Shall keep for five years after completion, copies of reports and other forms used by the school relating to the Federal Direct Stafford, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford, or Federal Direct PLUS programs;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Shall keep all records involved in any loan, claim, or expenditure questioned by a Federal audit until resolution of any audit questions;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Shall provide, in the event of the school's closure, termination, suspension, or change in ownership resulting in a change of control as described in 34 CFR part 600, for the retention of the records and reports required by the regulations in this part and for access by the Secretary or the Secretary's authorized representatives to those records and reports for inspection and copying; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) May keep records and copies of reports on microfilm, optical disk, or in other machine readable format.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Loan record requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to records required by 34 CFR part 668, for each Federal Direct Stafford, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford, and Federal Direct PLUS loan received under this part by or on behalf of its students, a school shall maintain a copy of the loan application or data electronically submitted to the Secretary and shall, upon request, produce a record of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The amount of the loan and the loan period;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The data used to construct an individual student budget or the school's itemized standard budget used in calculating the student's estimated cost of attendance;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The sources and amounts of financial assistance available to the student that the school used in determining the student's estimated financial assistance for the loan period in accordance with ยง685.102;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The amount of the student's tuition and fees paid for the loan period and the date the student paid the tuition and fees;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) The amount and basis of its calculation of any refund paid to or on behalf of a student;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) In the case of a Federal Direct Stafford loan under ยง685.200, the data used to determine the student's expected family contribution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) In the case of a Federal Direct Stafford, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford, or Federal Direct PLUS loan_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The date the school received a completed promissory note from the borrower; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The date of each disbursement of the loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) The student's job placement, if known; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) Any other matter for which a record would be required for the school to be able to document its compliance with applicable requirements with respect to the loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Inspection requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Upon request, a school or its agent shall cooperate with an independent auditor, the Secretary, the Department of Education Office of Inspector General, and the Comptroller General of the United States, or their authorized representatives, in the conduct of audits, investigations, and program reviews authorized by law. This cooperation must include_</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
