<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-1-00010</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-1-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Accordingly, pursuant to the authority delegated to me by the Administrator, the Federal Aviation Administration proposes to amend 14 CFR part 39 of the Federal Aviation Regulations as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 39_AIRWORTHINESS DIRECTIVES</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 39 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>49 U.S.C. App. 1354(a), 1421 and 1423; 49 U.S.C. 106(g); and 14 CFR 11.89.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง39.13</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 39.13 is amended by removing amendment 39-8526 (58 FR 19571, April 15, 1993), and by adding a new airworthiness directive (AD), to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Boeing:</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket 93-NM-174-AD. Supersedes AD 93-06-01, Amendment 39-8526.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicability:</textblock>
    <textblock>Model 747 series airplanes, as listed in Section 3.0 of Boeing Document No. D6-35022, Volumes 1 and 2, ``Supplemental Structural Inspection Document (SSID) for Model 747 Airplanes,'' Revision E, dated June 17, 1993; and manufacturer's line numbers 42, 174, 221, 231, 234, 239, 242, and 254; certificated in any category.</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance:</textblock>
    <textblock>Required as indicated, unless accomplished previously.</textblock>
    <textblock>To ensure the continued structural integrity of the total Boeing Model 747 fleet, accomplish the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) For airplanes listed in Boeing Document No. D6-35022, Volumes I and II, ``Supplemental Structural Inspection Document (SSID),'' Revision D, dated February 1992: Within 12 months after May 17, 1993 (the effective date of AD 93-06-01, Amendment 39-8526), incorporate a revision into the FAA-approved maintenance inspection program which provides no less than the required Damage Tolerance Rating (DTR) for each Structural Significant Item (SSI) listed in Boeing Document No.</textblock>
    <textblock>D6-35022, Revision D, dated February 1992. (The required DTR value for each SSI is listed in the document.) The revision to the maintenance program shall include Sections 5.0 and 6.0 of the SSID and shall be implemented in accordance with the procedures contained in those sections.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) For airplanes listed in Boeing Document No. D6-35022, Volumes 1 and 2, ``Supplemental Structural Inspection Document (SSID) for Model 747 Airplanes,'' Revision E, dated June 17, 1993; and manufacturer's line numbers 42, 174, 221, 231, 234, 239, 242, and 254: Within 12 months after the effective date of this AD, replace the revision of the FAA-approved maintenance inspection program required by paragraph (a) of this AD with a revision that provides no less than the required DTR for each SSI listed in Boeing Document No.</textblock>
    <textblock>D6-35022, Volumes 1 and 2, ``Supplemental Structural Inspection Document (SSID) for Model 747 Airplanes,'' Revision E, dated June 17, 1993. (The required DTR value for each SSI is listed in the document.) The revision to the maintenance program shall include Sections 5.0 and 6.0 of the SSID and shall be implemented in accordance with the procedures contained in those sections.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Cracked structure must be repaired, prior to further flight, in accordance with an FAA-approved method.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) An alternative method of compliance or adjustment of the compliance time that provides an acceptable level of safety may be used if approved by the Manager, Seattle Aircraft Certification Office (ACO), FAA, Transport Airplane Directorate. Operators shall submit their requests through an appropriate FAA Principal Maintenance Inspector, who may add comments and then send it to the Manager, Seattle ACO.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information concerning the existence of approved alternative methods of compliance with this AD, if any, may be obtained from the Seattle ACO.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Special flight permits may be issued in accordance with FAR 21.197 and 21.199 to operate the airplane to a location where the requirements of this AD can be accomplished.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Renton, Washington, on December 28, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Darrell M. Pederson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Manager, Transport Airplane Directorate, Aircraft Certification Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-23 Filed 1-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
