<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00007</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00003</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Inquiry Into Alleged Anticompetitive Practices Related to Marketing Affiliates of Interstate Pipelines and Ozark Gas Transmission System; Order on Rehearing and Extending Sunset Date</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued December 23, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>18 CFR Parts 161 and 250</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket Nos. RM87-5-012 and CP87-238-003; Order No. 497-E]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule; order on rehearing and extending sunset date.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This order rules on requests for rehearing of the Commission's order on remand issued following the decision of the U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit which upheld in substantial part the Commission's final rule governing the relationship between interstate natural gas pipelines and their marketing or brokering affiliates. The order on remand, among other things, narrowed the scope of the contemporaneous disclosure requirement by pipelines with respect to sales and marketing information and extended the sunset date of the final rule's reporting requirements. The order on rehearing, among other things, deletes the remaining categories of gas sales and marketing information from the contemporaneous disclosure requirement and further extends the sunset date.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>This final rule is effective January 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>David Faerberg, Office of the General Counsel, Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, (202) 208-1275.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to publishing the full text of this document in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, the Commission also provides all interested persons an opportunity to inspect or copy the contents of this document during normal business hours in room 3104, 941 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission Issuance Posting System (CIPS), an electronic bulletin board service, provides access to the texts of formal documents issued by the Commission. CIPS is available at no charge to the user and may be accessed using a personal computer with a modem by dialing (202) 208-1397. To access CIPS, set your communications software to use 300, 1200, or 2400 bps, full duplex, no parity, 8 data bits and 1 stop bit. CIPS can also be accessed at 9600 bps by dialing (202) 208-1781. The full text of this rule will be available on CIPS for 30 days from the date of issuance. The complete text on diskette in WordPerfect format may also be purchased from the Commission's copy contractor, La Dorn Systems Corporation, also located in room 3104, 941 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
