<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00018</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Department of the Army</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Fort Ord, California Disposal and Reuse Environmental Impact Statement (EIS)</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Army, Department of Defense.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability of record of decision (ROD).</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Record of Decision (ROD) states the Army's intention to dispose of Fort Ord property, establish a Presidio of Monterey Annex, and retain the existing reserve center at Fort Ord. Because the local communities' reuse plan has not been finalized, the Army does not adopt a specific plan in this ROD. Rather, in this document the Army certifies that it has adequately analyzed the environmental impacts of its decision to dispose of property at Fort Ord.</textblock>
    <textblock>Consistent with the President's Five-Point Initiative to Revitalize Base Closure Communities, the Army will dispose of property in accordance with the local communities' reuse plan to the maximum extent possible. The Army will develop, if necessary, additional environmental analysis following this ROD to address the impacts of those uses in the local communities' reuse plan not already addressed in the Environmental Impact Statement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Based on this ROD, the Army will initiate the property disposal process at Fort Ord consistent with the analysis in the EIS.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>For more information or to obtain a copy of the ROD, contact Mr. Bob Verkade, Sacramento District, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, 1325 J Street, Sacramento, CA or call (916) 557-7423.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 9, 1993.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lewis D. Walker,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Assistant Secretary of the Army (Environment, Safety &amp; Occupational Health OASA (I, L&amp;E)).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-67 Filed 1-3-93; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3710-08-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
