<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00049</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00032</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[AK-080-4230-05; F-85687]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Realty Action: Conveyance of Public Lands in Alaska for Airport Purposes</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of realty action.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The State of Alaska Department of Transportation and Public Facilities has requested conveyance of certain lands near the Fairbanks International Airport. The additional lands are necessary for the use, operation, and maintenance of the existing airport facility.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments on this Notice should be submitted to the District Manager, Bureau of Land Management, Steese/White Mountains District Office, 1150 University Avenue, Fairbanks, Alaska, 99709.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Rodney G. Everett, Realty Specialist, at the address given above or at telephone (907) 474-2365.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The following public lands in Fairbanks, Alaska are being considered for conveyance to the State of Alaska for airport purposes pursuant to Section 516 of the Airport and Airway Improvement Act of September 3, 1982 (96 Stat. 692; 49 U.S.C. 2215):</textblock>
    <textblock>Fairbanks Meridian, Alaska</textblock>
    <textblock>T.1 S., R.2 W.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 13, Tract XIV, Parcel B;</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 23, Tract XIV, Parcel A.</textblock>
    <textblock>T.1 S., R.1 W.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 18, Tract XVIII, Parcels A, B, and C.</textblock>
    <textblock>Containing 72.79 acres</textblock>
    <textblock>The above described lands have been, and remain, segregated from all appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining laws but not the mineral leasing laws.</textblock>
    <textblock>For a period of 45 days from the date of publication of this Notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register,</textblock>
    <textblock>interested parties may submit written comments to the District Manager at the above address. Any adverse comments will be reviewed by the State Director, who may vacate, sustain, or modify the realty action and issue a final determination. In the absence of any objection, the final determination of the Department of the Interior will be made in accordance with this Notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 16, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Roger Bolstad,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>District Manager.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-78 Filed 1-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-JA-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
