<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00006</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-0-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with the foregoing, title 17, chapter II of the Code of Federal Regulations is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 239_FORMS PRESCRIBED UNDER THE SECURITIES ACT OF 1933</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for Part 239 continues to read in part as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 77f, 77g, 77h, 77j, 77s, 77sss, 78c, 78</textblock>
    <textblock>l</textblock>
    <textblock>, 78m, 78n, 78</textblock>
    <textblock>o</textblock>
    <textblock>(d), 78w(a), 78</textblock>
    <textblock>ll</textblock>
    <textblock>(d), 79e, 79f, 79g, 79j, 79</textblock>
    <textblock>l</textblock>
    <textblock>, 79m, 79n, 79q, 79t, 80a-8, 80a-29, 80a-30 and 80a-37, unless otherwise noted.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>2. By amending §239.39 by revising the Instruction following paragraph (a)(2) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§239.39</textblock>
    <textblock>Form F-9, for registration under the Securities Act of 1933 of certain investment grade debt or investment grade preferred securities of certain Canadian issuers.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>Instruction</textblock>
    <textblock>Securities shall be ``investment grade'' if, at the time of sale, at least one nationally recognized statistical rating organization (as that term is used in relation to Rule 15c3-1(c)(2)(vi)(F) under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (the ``Exchange Act'') (§240.15c3-1(c)(2)(vi)(F) of this chapter)) or at least one Approved Rating Organization (as defined in National Policy Statement No. 45 of the Canadian Securities Administrators, as the same may be amended from time to time) has rated the security in one of its generic rating categories that signifies investment grade; typically the four highest rating categories (within which there may be subcategories or gradations indicating relative standing) signify investment grade.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>3. By amending Form F-9 (§239.39) by revising the Instruction following paragraph A. of General Instruction I, to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>Form F-9 does not and these amendments will not appear in the Code of Federal Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Form F-9</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>General Instructions</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Eligibility Requirements for Use of Form F-9</textblock>
    <textblock>A. *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>Instruction</textblock>
    <textblock>Securities shall be ``investment grade'' if, at the time of sale, at least one nationally recognized statistical rating organization (as that term is used in relation to Rule 15c3-1(c)(2)(vi)(F) under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (the ``Exchange Act'')) or at least one Approved Rating Organization (as defined in National Policy Statement No. 45 of the Canadian Securities Administrators, as the same may be amended from time to time) has rated the security in one of its generic rating categories that signifies investment grade; typically the four highest rating categories (within which there may be subcategories or gradations indicating relative standing) signify investment grade.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 27, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-14 Filed 1-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
