<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-1-00034</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-1-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>On October 17, 1988 (53 FR 40656), USEPA promulgated PSD air quality increments for NO</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>. The States were required to submit to USEPA by July 17, 1990, plan revisions to protect the NO</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>increments. Wisconsin submitted such increments to USEPA on November 24, 1992. This submittal meets the NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>increment requirements and is approvable.</textblock>
    <textblock>H. Particulate Matter (PM) Significant Level</textblock>
    <textblock>On July 1, 1987 (52 FR 24713), USEPA promulgated the significant level for PM at 15 tons per year. Wisconsin submitted two PM SIP revisions on March 13, 1989 and May 10, 1990 to meet the Federal PM requirements. These submittals were proposed for approval on March 13, 1989 (NR 400.02, 404.02, 405.02, 406.04, 484.03) which contain the PM significant level, and May 10, 1990 (NR 404.04, 484.03). USEPA then proposed to disapprove the package on December 23, 1992. After receiving comments from the State, USEPA moved to approve the package. The final rulemaking approving these rules was published on June 28, 1993 (58 FR 34528).</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Action</textblock>
    <textblock>Because of the deficiencies noted above, USEPA is proposing to disapprove Wisconsin's Prevention of Significant Deterioration Permit Program as not meeting the requirements of part C of the Clean Air Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Agency reviewed this PSD SIP revision request for conformance with the provisions of the 1990 Amendments enacted on November 15, 1990. The Agency has determined that this action did not conform with the statute before it was amended, that the Amendments did not in any way affect this determination, and that the revision does not conform to the Act, as amended. If resubmitted, Wisconsin's PSD SIP submission should include all requirements and changes added by the 1990 Amendments. Thus, USEPA is proposing that the revision be disapproved.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the provisions of 5 U.S.C., section 605(b), I certify that this action will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities (see 46 FR 8709). If USEPA were to disapprove this rule, its disapproval would not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities because USEPA's PSD program remains in effect under delegated authority. Sources would remain subject to the same requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under Executive Order 12291, this action is not ``Major''. It has been submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for review.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 40 CFR Part 52</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental protection, Air pollution control, Carbon monoxide, Hydrocarbons, Intergovernmental relations, Lead, Nitrogen dioxide, Ozone, Particulate matter, Sulfur oxides.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 7401-7671q.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: November 15, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Valdas V. Adamkus,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Regional Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-75 Filed 1-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
