<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00032</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00023</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Establishment of and Invitation for Nominations for the Dietary Guidelines Advisory Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>AGENCIES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health, Department of Health and Human Services, and Food and Consumer Services, Department of Agriculture.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dietary Guidelines Advisory Committee: Invitation for Nominations.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the National Nutrition Monitoring and Related Research Act of 1990 (Pub. L. 101-445), the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) and the Department of Agriculture (USDA), announce the establishment by the Secretaries of HHS and USDA of the Dietary Guidelines Advisory Committee and invite nominations for the Committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Committee shall review the 1990 edition of Nutrition and Your Health: Dietary Guidelines for Americans and determine if, on the basis of current scientific and medical knowledge, revision is warranted at this time. If so, the Committee will proceed to develop recommendations for revisions in a report to the Secretaries of HHS and USDA. The Committee shall be terminated upon delivery of its final report or at the end of two years, whichever is first.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Departments invite nominations for committee membership of individuals qualified to carry out the above-mentioned tasks. Nominations should describe and document the nominee's qualifications in the relevant subject areas.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Elena T. Carbone, M.S., R.D., Co-executive Secretary from HHS to the Dietary Guidelines Advisory Committee, Office of Disease Prevention and Health Promotion, Public Health Service, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, room 2132 Switzer Building, 330 C Street, SW., Washington, DC 20201, (202) 205-9007; or Debra Reed, M.S., L.N., Co-executive Secretary from USDA to the Dietary Guidelines Advisory Committee, Human Nutrition Information Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, room 366, 6505 Belcrest Road, Hyattsville, Maryland 20782, (301) 436-8457.</textblock>
  </further>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nominations may be submitted either to Elena T. Carbone or Debra Reed at the addresses above for up to 15 days after publication of this notice.</textblock>
  </address>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Philip R. Lee,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary for Health, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Ellen Haas,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary for Food and Consumer Services, U.S. Department of Agriculture.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-42 Filed 1-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-17-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
