<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00064</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940104-2-00043</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Drug Enforcement Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Controlled Substances; Established 1993 Aggregate Production Quotas</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Drug Enforcement Administration, Justice.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule establishing 1993 aggregate production quotas.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The interim rule (58 FR 51382, October 1, 1993) which established 1993 revised aggregate production quotas for some controlled substances in Schedules I and II, as required under the Controlled Substances Act (CSA) (21 U.S.C. 826) is adopted without change.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Howard McClain, Jr., Chief, Drug &amp; Chemical Evaluation Section, Drug Enforcement Administration, Washington, DC 20537, telephone: (202) 307-7183.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 306 of the Controlled Substances Act, (21 U.S.C. 826), requires the Attorney General to establish aggregate production quotas for controlled substances in Schedules I and II each year. This responsibility has been delegated to the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration pursuant to §0.100 of title 28 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 1, 1993, an interim rule establishing revised 1993 aggregate production quotas for controlled substances in Schedules I and II was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 51382). One comment was received from a company supporting the use of the interim rule in establishing aggregate production quotas under certain circumstances. The interim rule is adopted without change.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule is not a significant regulatory action and therefore has not been reviewed by the Office of Management and Budget pursuant to Executive Order 12866.</textblock>
    <textblock>These actions have been analyzed in accordance with the principles and criteria contained in Executive Order 12612, and it has been determined that this matter does not have sufficient federalism implications to warrant the preparation of a Federalism Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Administrator hereby certifies that this action will have no significant impact upon small entities whose interests must be considered under the Regulatory Flexibility Act, 5 U.S.C. 601, et seq. The establishment of annual aggregate production quotas for Schedules I and II controlled substances is mandated by law and by international commitments of the United States. Such quotas impact predominantly upon major manufacturers of the affected controlled substance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, under the authority vested in the Attorney General by section 306 of the CSA of 1970 (21 U.S.C. 826) and delegated to the Administrator by §0.100 of title 28 of the Code of Federal Regulations, the Administrator of the DEA hereby establishes the following revised 1993 aggregate production quotas for the listed controlled substances, expressed in grams of anhydrous base:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 22, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Basic class</textblock>
    <textblock>1Established 1993 quotas (in grams)</textblock>
    <textblock>Schedule I:</textblock>
    <textblock>Methaqualone</textblock>
    <textblock>12</textblock>
    <textblock>3,4-Methylenedioxyamphetamine</textblock>
    <textblock>12</textblock>
    <textblock>3,4-Methylenedioxymethamphetamine</textblock>
    <textblock>12</textblock>
    <textblock>Schedule II:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dextropropoxyphene</textblock>
    <textblock>115,162,000</textblock>
    <textblock>Methadone (for sale)</textblock>
    <textblock>3,675,000</textblock>
    <textblock>Methadone Intermediate (for conv)</textblock>
    <textblock>4,598,000</textblock>
    <textblock>Oxycodone (for sale)</textblock>
    <textblock>3,520,000</textblock>
    <textblock>Phencyclidine</textblock>
    <textblock>54</textblock>
    <textblock>Thebaine</textblock>
    <textblock>7,795,000</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Stephen H. Greene,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Administrator of Drug Enforcement.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-108 Filed 1-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-09-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
