<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00068</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00041</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Inventory Completion for Native American Human Remains From Hawaii in the Possession of the Peabody Museum of Archaeology and Ethnology, Harvard</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Park Service, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given in accordance with provisions of the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act, 25 U.S.C. 3003(d), of the completion of the inventory of human remains from Hawaii in the possession of the Peabody Museum of Archaeology and Ethnology, Harvard.</textblock>
    <textblock>The human remains came to the Peabody Museum as part of 16 collections between 1867 and 1959. There are no associated funerary objects. A detailed inventory and assessment of the human remains has been made by the staff of the Peabody Museum in consultation with representatives of</textblock>
    <textblock>Hui Mlama I N Kpuna 'O Hawai'i Nei</textblock>
    <textblock>, the Office of Hawaiian Affairs, and the Kaua'i/Nihau, Maui/Lanai, Molokai, and O'ahu Burial Councils.</textblock>
    <textblock>The human remains consist of the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>One cranium (19-5-70/59745) from Nohile sand dunes, Kaua'i County, Kaua'i Island.</textblock>
    <textblock>Twenty-one crania (36-96-70/N3482-N3502) and eight mandibles (36-96-70/N3503) from dune burials in Kaua'i County.</textblock>
    <textblock>Twenty-one crania (67-39-70/1115-1135) from southerly shore sand dunes, Kaua'i County.</textblock>
    <textblock>One cranium (72-20-70/6792) from Kaua'i County.</textblock>
    <textblock>Two crania (16-8-70/59647 and 59648) from an ``ancient burial place'', Maui County</textblock>
    <textblock>Twenty-one crania, two partial crania, and one partial cranium together with fragmentary axial elements</textblock>
    <textblock>(78-45-70/15267-15290) from Maui County.</textblock>
    <textblock>One skeleton (80-25-70/23518), complete except for fragmentary extremities, from an ancient burial place, Maui County.</textblock>
    <textblock>Five crania (16-8-70/59641-59645) from the beach beyond Diamond Sand Dunes Hill, Oahu.</textblock>
    <textblock>Six crania (23-5-70/60363-60368) found during the excavation of a canal in Waikiki, Oahu.</textblock>
    <textblock>Two almost complete skeletons and fragmentary postcranial remains from five more individuals (23-5-70/60369-60372) found while excavating for a sewer system in Honolulu County, Oahu.</textblock>
    <textblock>Three partial crania and six crania (36-4-70/N1324-N1332) from lava caves near Honolulu, Oahu.</textblock>
    <textblock>Four crania and three fragmentary crania (85-7-70/37592-37397a) that, from circumstantial documentary evidence, may come from Oahu.</textblock>
    <textblock>One cranium, one partial cranium and one partial cranium with two right femurs (86-58-70/61492-61494) from Honolulu, Oahu.</textblock>
    <textblock>Twenty seven crania (00/N939; 16-8-70/59646; 20-4-70/59931 and 59932; 50-70-70/N7476; 59-27-70/N8615-N8620; 80-25-70/23503-23517), fragmentary appendicular elements (27-5-70/60797), and twenty four mandibles (00/N1013; 80-25-70/23519) are attributed to Hawai'i with no further information. Six of these crania (59-27-70/N8615-N8620) came to the Peabody Museum from the Warren Anatomical Museum.</textblock>
    <textblock>Based on the above mentioned information, officials of the Museum have determined pursuant to 25 U.S.C. 3001 (2) that there is a relationship of shared group identity which can be reasonably traced between these remains and present-day Native Hawaiian organizations.</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice has been sent to officials of</textblock>
    <textblock>Hui Mlama I N Kpuna 'O Hawai'i Nei</textblock>
    <textblock>and the Office of Hawaiian Affairs. Representatives of any other Native Hawaiian organization which believes itself to be culturally affiliated with these human remains should contact Mrs. Barbara Isaac, Assistant Director, Peabody Museum of Archaeology and Ethnology, Harvard University, 11 Divinity Avenue, Cambridge MA 02138, or call (617) 495-2248, before March 30, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </action>
  <signer>
    <textblock>C. Timothy McKeown,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Departmental Consulting Archeologist,</textblock>
    <textblock>Chief, Archeological Assistance Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4492 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-70-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
