<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00149</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(iv) The proceeds of the first disbursement of the loan</textblock>
    <textblock>were delivered to the student or credited to the student's</textblock>
    <textblock>account prior to the end of the participation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) For the purposes of this section_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A commitment under the Federal Pell Grant and PAS</textblock>
    <textblock>programs occurs when a student is enrolled and attending the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution and has submitted a valid Student Aid Report to the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution or when an institution has received a valid</textblock>
    <textblock>institutional student information report;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A commitment under the campus-based programs occurs</textblock>
    <textblock>when a student is enrolled and attending the institution and has</textblock>
    <textblock>received a notice from the institution of the amount that he or</textblock>
    <textblock>she can expect to receive and how and when that amount will be</textblock>
    <textblock>paid; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) A commitment under the Federal Stafford and Federal SLS</textblock>
    <textblock>programs occurs when the Secretary or a guaranty agency notifies</textblock>
    <textblock>the lender that the loan is guaranteed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1094, 1099a-3)</textblock>
    <textblock>15. Section 668.81, as proposed to be amended in a Notice</textblock>
    <textblock>of Proposed Rulemaking published on February 17, 1994 (59 FR 8062), is further amended by removing paragraph (a)(2);</textblock>
    <textblock>redesignating paragraph (a)(1) introductory text as paragraph (a)</textblock>
    <textblock>introductory text; redesignating paragraphs (a)(1)(i) through (iv)</textblock>
    <textblock>as paragraphs (a)(1) through (4), respectively; removing the word</textblock>
    <textblock>``or'' after the semi-colon in paragraph (c)(1); revising</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (c)(2); adding paragraphs (c)(3) and (4); and revising</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (d) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.81</textblock>
    <textblock>Scope and special definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) An institution fails to qualify for initial</textblock>
    <textblock>certification or provisional certification to participate in any</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program because the institution does not meet the</textblock>
    <textblock>factors of financial responsibility and standards of</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability contained in subpart B of this part;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) A participating institution's or a provisionally</textblock>
    <textblock>certified participating institution's period of participation, as</textblock>
    <textblock>specified under §668.13, has expired; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) A participating institution's provisional certification</textblock>
    <textblock>is revoked under the procedures in §668.13.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) This subpart does not apply to a determination by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary of the system to be used to disburse Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program funds to a participating institution (i.e., advance</textblock>
    <textblock>payments and payments by way of reimbursements).</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>16. A new Appendix A to Part 668 is added to read as</textblock>
    <textblock>follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix A to Part 668_Standards for Acceptable Refund Policies by</textblock>
    <textblock>Participating Institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of §668.22(b)(1)(iv)(A), the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>considers an institution to have a fair and equitable refund</textblock>
    <textblock>policy if the institution uses a policy that meets the minimum</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of this appendix. These requirements are a modified</textblock>
    <textblock>version of guidelines developed by the National Association of</textblock>
    <textblock>College and University Business Officers. These requirements do</textblock>
    <textblock>not affect an institution's obligation to comply with other</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(I)</textblock>
    <textblock>The governing board of the institution must review and</textblock>
    <textblock>approve the schedule of all institutional charges and refund</textblock>
    <textblock>policies applicable to students.</textblock>
    <textblock>The pricing of services and</textblock>
    <textblock>refund policies have important consequences to students, parents,</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution, and society; as such, pricing and refund</textblock>
    <textblock>policies must receive board attention and approval.</textblock>
    <textblock>(II)</textblock>
    <textblock>The institution must seek consumer views in the</textblock>
    <textblock>process of establishing and amending charge and refund</textblock>
    <textblock>structures.</textblock>
    <textblock>Decisions regarding institutional funds are</textblock>
    <textblock>ultimately the sole responsibility of the institution's legally</textblock>
    <textblock>designated fund custodians. However, consumer concerns do affect</textblock>
    <textblock>decision making, and involving consumers in decision making</textblock>
    <textblock>related to charges and refunds is an essential approach for</textblock>
    <textblock>assessing student needs and creating public awareness of</textblock>
    <textblock>institutional requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(III)</textblock>
    <textblock>The institution must publish a current schedule of</textblock>
    <textblock>all student charges (including the costs of required supplies and</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment), publish a statement of the purpose for such charges</textblock>
    <textblock>and related refund policies, have those statements readily</textblock>
    <textblock>available free of charge to current and prospective students, and</textblock>
    <textblock>substantiate that the costs of required supplies and equipment</textblock>
    <textblock>are reasonably related to the cost of providing the supplies and</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment to the students.</textblock>
    <textblock>Students and parents have a right to</textblock>
    <textblock>know what charges they will be expected to pay and what will or</textblock>
    <textblock>will not be refunded. They also have a right to know what</textblock>
    <textblock>services accompany payment of the charges. Informational</textblock>
    <textblock>materials published free for students and prospective students</textblock>
    <textblock>are ideal for this purpose.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
