<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00003</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>2. In §800.71(a), Schedule A, is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Schedule A._Fees for Official Inspection, Weighing, and Appeal Inspection Services, Performed in the United States1</textblock>
    <textblock>1Inspection &amp; weighing service (bulk or sacked grain)</textblock>
    <textblock>1Regular workday (Monday to Saturday)</textblock>
    <textblock>1Nonregular workday (Sunday and Holiday)</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Original inspection and official weighing:2</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Contract (per hour per service representative)</textblock>
    <textblock>$31.50</textblock>
    <textblock>$43.10</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Noncontract (per hour per service representative)</textblock>
    <textblock>41.90</textblock>
    <textblock>57.00</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Reinspection, appeal inspection, Board appeal inspection, and review of weighing services:34</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Grading service:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Grade and factors (per sample)</textblock>
    <textblock>61.10</textblock>
    <textblock>79.50</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Protein test (per sample)</textblock>
    <textblock>15.30</textblock>
    <textblock>19.90</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Factor determination (per factor)</textblock>
    <textblock>30.60</textblock>
    <textblock>39.75</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) Vomitoxin Test (per test) Qualitative</textblock>
    <textblock>35.00</textblock>
    <textblock>44.00</textblock>
    <textblock>Quantitative</textblock>
    <textblock>40.00</textblock>
    <textblock>50.00</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Sampling services (per hour per service representative)</textblock>
    <textblock>61.10</textblock>
    <textblock>79.50</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Review of weighing service (per hour per service representative)</textblock>
    <textblock>61.10</textblock>
    <textblock>79.50</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Extra copies of certificates (per copy)</textblock>
    <textblock>3.00</textblock>
    <textblock>3.00</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Official track scale testing service</textblock>
    <textblock>44.00</textblock>
    <textblock>59.90</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Pesticide Residue Testing:5</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Routine Compounds (per sample)</textblock>
    <textblock>200.00</textblock>
    <textblock>300.00</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Special Compounds (per hour per service representative)</textblock>
    <textblock>100.00</textblock>
    <textblock>150.00</textblock>
    <textblock>1Official inspection and weighing services include, but are not limited to: grading, weighing, sampling, stowage examination, equipment testing, scale testing and certification, test weight reverification, evaluation of inspection and weighing equipment, demonstrating official inspection and weighing functions, furnishing standard illustrations, and certifying inspection and weighing results.</textblock>
    <textblock>2For vomitoxin tests, a charge of $7.50 per qualitative test and a charge of $12.00 per quantitative test will be assessed in addition to the applicable hourly rate for original inspection service.</textblock>
    <textblock>3Fees for reinspection and appeal inspection services performed at locations where FGIS is providing original inspection service shall be assessed at the applicable contract or noncontract hourly rate as the original inspection, except that for vomitoxin tests, a charge of $7.50 per qualitative test and a charge of $12.00 per quantitative test will be assessed in addition to the applicable hourly rate. If additional personnel are required to perform the reinspection or appeal inspection service, the applicant will be assessed the noncontract original inspection hourly fee.</textblock>
    <textblock>4If at the request of the Service a file sample is located and forwarded by an agency for an official appeal, the agency may, upon request, be reimbursed at the rate of $2.50 per sample by the Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>5Testing fees are applicable to any level of service (original inspection, reinspection, appeal inspection, or Board appeal inspection) and do not include a sampling service fee which, if applicable will be assessed separately in accordance with the fees in this schedule.</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David R. Galliart,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4421 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-EN-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
