<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00070</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00043</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Office of Management and Budget (OMB) has been sent the following collection(s) of information proposals for review under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. chapter 35) and the Paperwork Reduction Reauthorization Act since the last list was published. Entries are grouped into submission categories, with each entry containing the following information:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The title of the form/collection;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The agency form number, if any, and the applicable component of the Department sponsoring the collection;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) How often the form must be filled out or the information is collected;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Who will be asked or required to respond, as well as a brief abstract;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) An estimate of the total number of respondents and the amount of time estimated for an average respondent to respond;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) An estimate of the total public burden (in hours) associated with the collection; and,</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) An indication as to whether section 3504(h) of Public Law 96-511 applies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments and/or suggestions regarding the item(s) contained in this notice, especially regarding the estimated public burden and associated response time, should be directed to the OMB reviewer, Mr. Jeff Hill on (202) 395-7340 and to the Department of Justice's Clearance Officer, Mr. Lewis Arnold, on (202) 514-4305. If you anticipate commenting on a form/collection, but find that time to prepare such comments will prevent you from prompt submission, you should notify the OMB reviewer and the DOJ Clearance Officer of your intent as soon as possible. Written comments regarding the burden estimate or any other aspect of the collection may be submitted to Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503, and to Mr. Lewis Arnold, DOJ Clearance Officer, SPS/JMD/5031 CAB, Department of Justice, Washington, DC 20530.</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension of the Expiration Date of a Currently Approved Collection Without Any Change in the Substance or the Method of Collection</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Procedures for the Administration of Section 5 of the Voting Rights Act of 1965.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) None. Civil Rights Division.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) On occasion.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) State or local governments. Jurisdictions under the Voting Rights Act are required to obtain preclearance from the Attorney General before instituting changes affecting voting. They must convince the Attorney General that changes are not racially discriminatory. These procedures facilitate the provision of information that will enable the Attorney General to make the required determination.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) 5,800 annual responses at 13.2 hours per response.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) 76,560 annual burden hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Not applicable under section 3504(h).</textblock>
    <textblock>Public comment on this item is encouraged.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 23, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Information Collections Under Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lewis Arnold,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Department Clearance Officer, Department of Justice.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4493 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
