<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00137</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(ii) The institution meets the following criteria:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A)(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) Fifteen percent or fewer of the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>students who are enrolled on at least a half-time basis receive</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Stafford or Federal SLS loans for any twenty-four month</textblock>
    <textblock>period ending not more than six months prior to the date the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution submits its appeal; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) For any twenty-four month period ending not more than</textblock>
    <textblock>six months prior to the date the institution submits its appeal,</textblock>
    <textblock>two-thirds or more of the institution's students who are enrolled</textblock>
    <textblock>on at least a half-time basis are individuals from disadvantaged</textblock>
    <textblock>economic backgrounds, as established by documentary evidence</textblock>
    <textblock>submitted by the institution. Such evidence must relate to</textblock>
    <textblock>qualification by those students for an Expected Family</textblock>
    <textblock>Contribution (EFC) (formerly institutions were required to use</textblock>
    <textblock>the Pell Grant index), as defined in 34 CFR 690.2, of zero for</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicable award year or attribution to those students of an</textblock>
    <textblock>adjusted gross income of the student and his or her parents or</textblock>
    <textblock>spouse, if applicable, reported for the applicable award year of</textblock>
    <textblock>less than the poverty level, as determined under criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>established by the Department of Health and Human Services; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B)(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) Two-thirds or more of the institution's students who</textblock>
    <textblock>were enrolled on a full-time basis in any twenty-four month</textblock>
    <textblock>period ending not more than six months prior to the date the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution submits its appeal completed the educational programs</textblock>
    <textblock>in which they were enrolled. This rate is calculated by</textblock>
    <textblock>comparing the number of students who were classified as full-time</textblock>
    <textblock>at their initial enrollment in the institution, and were</textblock>
    <textblock>originally scheduled, at the time of enrollment, to complete</textblock>
    <textblock>their programs within the relevant twenty-four month period, with</textblock>
    <textblock>the number of these students who received a degree, certificate,</textblock>
    <textblock>or other recognized educational credential from the institution;</textblock>
    <textblock>transferred from the institution to a higher level educational</textblock>
    <textblock>program at another institution for which the prior program</textblock>
    <textblock>provided substantial preparation; or, at the end of the twenty-</textblock>
    <textblock>four month period, remained enrolled and were making satisfactory</textblock>
    <textblock>academic progress toward completion of their educational</textblock>
    <textblock>programs. The calculation does not include students who did not</textblock>
    <textblock>complete their programs because they left the institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>serve in the armed forces; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) The institution had a placement rate of two-thirds or</textblock>
    <textblock>more with respect to its former students who received a degree,</textblock>
    <textblock>certificate, or other recognized educational credential from the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution in any twenty-four month period ending not more than</textblock>
    <textblock>six months prior to the date the institution submits its appeal.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rate is calculated by determining the percentage of all</textblock>
    <textblock>those students who, based on evidence submitted by the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution, are on that date employed, or had been employed for</textblock>
    <textblock>at least 13 weeks following receipt of the credential from the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution, in the occupation for which the institution provided</textblock>
    <textblock>training, or are enrolled or had been enrolled for at least 13</textblock>
    <textblock>weeks following receipt of the credential from the institution,</textblock>
    <textblock>in a higher level educational program at another institution for</textblock>
    <textblock>which the prior educational program provided substantial</textblock>
    <textblock>preparation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For purposes of paragraph (d)(1)(iii)(A) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, a student is originally scheduled, at the time of</textblock>
    <textblock>enrollment, to complete the educational program on the date when</textblock>
    <textblock>the student will have been enrolled in the program for the amount</textblock>
    <textblock>of time normally required to complete the program. The ``amount</textblock>
    <textblock>of time normally required to complete the program'' is the period</textblock>
    <textblock>of time specified in the institution's enrollment contract,</textblock>
    <textblock>catalog, or other materials, for completion of the program by a</textblock>
    <textblock>full-time student, or the period of time between the date of</textblock>
    <textblock>enrollment and the anticipated graduation date appearing on the</textblock>
    <textblock>student's loan application, if any, whichever is less.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) An appeal submitted under paragraph (d)(1)(i) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section is considered to be filed in a timely manner if the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution submits a letter of appeal by the 30-day deadline</textblock>
    <textblock>notifying the Secretary's designated department official that it</textblock>
    <textblock>is appealing on this basis, including with that letter a copy of</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution's request to each cognizant guaranty agency for</textblock>
    <textblock>verification of the cohort default rate data, and submits the</textblock>
    <textblock>verified data to the Secretary's designated Department official</textblock>
    <textblock>within five working days of its receipt from the guaranty agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of paragraph (d)(4) of this section, the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's appeal is not considered complete until the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution submits the verified data to the Secretary's</textblock>
    <textblock>designated Department official.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The Secretary issues a decision on the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>appeal within 45 days after the institution submits a complete</textblock>
    <textblock>appeal that addresses the applicable criteria in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraphs (d)(1)(i) through (iii) of this section to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's designated Department official.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) The Secretary's decision is based on the consideration</textblock>
    <textblock>of written material submitted by the institution. No oral</textblock>
    <textblock>hearing is provided.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
