<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00142</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(5) For purposes of paragraph (c)(1) of this section, ``the</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of the period of enrollment for which the student has</textblock>
    <textblock>been charged that remains'' is determined_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) In the case of an educational program that is measured</textblock>
    <textblock>in credit hours, by dividing the total number of weeks comprising</textblock>
    <textblock>the period of enrollment for which the student has been charged</textblock>
    <textblock>into the number of weeks remaining in that period as of the</textblock>
    <textblock>student's withdrawal date;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) In the case of an educational program that is measured</textblock>
    <textblock>in clock hours, by dividing the total number of clock hours</textblock>
    <textblock>comprising the period of enrollment for which the student has</textblock>
    <textblock>been charged into the number of scheduled clock hours remaining</textblock>
    <textblock>to be completed by the student in that period as of the student's</textblock>
    <textblock>withdrawal date; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) In the case of an educational program that consists</textblock>
    <textblock>predominantly of correspondence courses, by dividing the total</textblock>
    <textblock>number of lessons comprising the period of enrollment for which</textblock>
    <textblock>the student has been charged into the number of lessons not</textblock>
    <textblock>submitted by the student.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Period of enrollment for which the student has been</textblock>
    <textblock>charged.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) For purposes of this section, ``the period of</textblock>
    <textblock>enrollment for which the student has been charged,'' means the</textblock>
    <textblock>actual period for which an institution charges a student, except</textblock>
    <textblock>that the minimum period must be_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) In the case of an educational program that is measured</textblock>
    <textblock>in credit hours and uses semesters, trimesters, quarters, or</textblock>
    <textblock>other academic terms, the semester, trimester, quarter or other</textblock>
    <textblock>academic term; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) In the case of an educational program that is measured</textblock>
    <textblock>in credit hours and does not use semesters, trimesters, quarters,</textblock>
    <textblock>or other academic terms, or an educational program that is</textblock>
    <textblock>measured in clock hours, the lesser of the length of the</textblock>
    <textblock>educational program or an academic year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If an institution charges by different periods for</textblock>
    <textblock>different charges, the ``period of enrollment for which the</textblock>
    <textblock>student has been charged'' for purposes of this section is the</textblock>
    <textblock>longest period for which the student is charged. The institution</textblock>
    <textblock>must include any charges assessed the student for the period of</textblock>
    <textblock>enrollment or any portion of that period of enrollment when</textblock>
    <textblock>calculating the refund.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Overpayments.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) An institution shall determine</textblock>
    <textblock>whether a student has received an overpayment for</textblock>
    <textblock>noninstitutional costs for the period of enrollment for which the</textblock>
    <textblock>student has been charged if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The student officially withdraws, drops out, or is</textblock>
    <textblock>expelled on or after his or her first day of class of that</textblock>
    <textblock>period; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The student received Title IV, HEA program assistance</textblock>
    <textblock>other than from the FWS, Federal Stafford Loan, Federal PLUS, or</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal SLS Program for that period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) (i) To determine if the student owes an overpayment, the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution shall subtract the noninstitutional costs that the</textblock>
    <textblock>student incurred for that portion of the period of enrollment for</textblock>
    <textblock>which the student has been charged from the amount of all</textblock>
    <textblock>assistance (other than from the FWS, Federal Stafford Loan,</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal PLUS, or Federal SLS Program) that the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>disbursed to the student.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Noninstitutional costs may include, but are not</textblock>
    <textblock>limited to, room and board for which the student does not</textblock>
    <textblock>contract with the institution, books, supplies, transportation,</textblock>
    <textblock>and miscellaneous expenses.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Repayments to Title IV, HEA programs of institutional</textblock>
    <textblock>refunds and overpayments.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)(i) An institution shall return a</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of the refund calculated in accordance with paragraph (b)</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section to the Title IV, HEA programs if the student to</textblock>
    <textblock>whom the refund is owed received assistance under any Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA program other than the FWS Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The portion of the refund that an institution shall</textblock>
    <textblock>return to the Title IV, HEA programs may not exceed the amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>assistance that the student received under the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs other than under the FWS Program for the period of</textblock>
    <textblock>enrollment for which the student has been charged.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For purposes of this section, except for the</textblock>
    <textblock>calculation of a</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>refund required under paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)(1)(iii) of this section_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) An institutional refund means the amount paid for</textblock>
    <textblock>institutional charges for the period of enrollment for which the</textblock>
    <textblock>student has been charged minus the amount that the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>may retain under paragraph (f)(2)(iii) of this section for the</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of the period of enrollment for which the student has</textblock>
    <textblock>been charged that the student was actually enrolled at the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) An institution may not include any unpaid amount of a</textblock>
    <textblock>scheduled cash payment in determining the amount that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution may retain for institutional charges. A scheduled</textblock>
    <textblock>cash payment is the amount of institutional charges that has not</textblock>
    <textblock>been paid by financial aid for the period of enrollment for which</textblock>
    <textblock>the student has been charged, exclusive of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Any amount scheduled to be paid by Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program assistance that the student has been awarded that is</textblock>
    <textblock>payable to the student even though the student has withdrawn; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Late disbursements of loans made under the Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Stafford, Federal SLS, and Federal PLUS programs in accordance</textblock>
    <textblock>with 34 CFR 682.207(d);</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) In determining the amount that the institution may</textblock>
    <textblock>retain for the portion of the period of enrollment for which the</textblock>
    <textblock>student has been charged during which the student was actually</textblock>
    <textblock>enrolled, an institution shall_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Compute the unpaid amount of a scheduled cash payment</textblock>
    <textblock>by subtracting the amount paid by the student for that period of</textblock>
    <textblock>enrollment for which the student has been charged from the</textblock>
    <textblock>scheduled cash payment for the period of enrollment for which the</textblock>
    <textblock>student has been charged; and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
