<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00053</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(e) If a practitioner or other person relocates to another PRO area prior to a determination of a violation or sanction recommendation, and the originating PRO_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Is able to make a determination, the originating PRO must, as appropriate, close the case or forward a sanction recommendation to the OIG; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Cannot make a determination, the originating PRO must forward all documentation regarding the case to the PRO with jurisdiction, and notify the practitioner or other person of this action.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) The PRO must deny payment for services or items furnished or ordered (or at the medical direction or on the prescription of an excluded physician) by an excluded practitioner or other person when the PRO identifies the services or items. It must report the findings to the Health Care Financing Administration.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง1004.40</textblock>
    <textblock>Action on identification of a violation.</textblock>
    <textblock>When a PRO identifies a violation, it must_</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Indicate whether the violation is a gross and flagrant violation or is a substantial violation in a substantial number of cases; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Send the practitioner or other person written notice of the identification of a violation containing the following information_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The obligation(s) involved;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The situation, circumstances or activity that resulted in a violation;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The authority and responsibility of the PRO to report violations of obligations;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) A suggested method for correcting the situation and a time period for corrective action, if appropriate;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) The sanction that the PRO could recommend to the OIG if the violation continues;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) The right of the practitioner or other person to submit to the PRO within 30 days of receipt of the notice additional information or a written request for a meeting with the PRO to review and discuss the finding, or both. The date of receipt is presumed to be 5 days after the date on the notice, unless there is a reasonable showing to the contrary. The notice will also state that if a meeting is requested_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) It will be held within 30 days of receipt by the PRO of the request, but may be extended for good cause;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The practitioner or other person may have an attorney present; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The attorney, if present, will be permitted to make opening and closing remarks, ask clarifying questions at the meeting and assist the practitioner or other person in presenting the testimony of expert witnesses who may appear on the practitioner's or other person's behalf; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) A copy of the material used by the PRO in arriving at its finding.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง1004.50</textblock>
    <textblock>Meeting with a practitioner or other person.</textblock>
    <textblock>If the practitioner or other person requests a meeting with the PRO_</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The PRO panel that meets with the practitioner or other person must consist of a minimum of 3 physicians;</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) No physician member of the PRO panel may be in direct economic competition with the practitioner or other person being considered for sanction;</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The PRO must ensure that no physician member of the PRO panel has a substantial personal bias against the practitioner or other person being considered for sanction;</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) At least one member of the PRO panel meeting with the practitioner or other person should practice in a similar area, e.g., urban or rural, and at least one member of the panel must be in the same specialty (both requirements could be met by a single individual);</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) If the practitioner or other person has an attorney present, that attorney will be permitted to make opening and closing remarks, ask clarifying questions and assist the practitioner or other person in presenting the testimony of expert witnesses who may appear on the practitioner's or other person's behalf;</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) A reviewing physician who recommends to the PRO that a practitioner or other person be sanctioned may not vote on the sanction panel's determination;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
