<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00084</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>General Standards of Financial Responsibility</textblock>
    <textblock>In paragraph (b) of proposed ยง668.15, the Secretary would</textblock>
    <textblock>list general standards of financial responsibility. The first</textblock>
    <textblock>six standards are applicable to all institutions. Section</textblock>
    <textblock>498(c)(1) of the HEA specifies that an institution's financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility must be determined based on whether the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution is able to provide the services that the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>claims to provide, to provide administrative resources necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>to comply with Title IV, HEA program requirements, and to meet</textblock>
    <textblock>all of the institution's financial obligations, including refunds</textblock>
    <textblock>and liabilities and debts incurred in programs administered by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary. These standards were adopted from current</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations and the Secretary proposes to continue to use them</textblock>
    <textblock>unchanged.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add to the list of proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility requirements for all institutions the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement that an institution be current on any debt service</textblock>
    <textblock>payments. An institution normally has variable costs that</textblock>
    <textblock>fluctuate to meet the demand created by increasing or decreasing</textblock>
    <textblock>volume in those costs such as those for educational supplies and</textblock>
    <textblock>expenses and instructor salaries associated with educating an</textblock>
    <textblock>increasing or decreasing number of students. Debt service</textblock>
    <textblock>represents a fixed cost, such as mortgage or lease payments, to</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution that generally does not fluctuate with that</textblock>
    <textblock>volume. Thus, in a situation in which an institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>experiencing a decline in revenue due to a decrease in new</textblock>
    <textblock>enrollments, debt service would remain unchanged. The</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's flexibility to deal financially with the decline is</textblock>
    <textblock>reduced because management typically is unable to adjust the</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of payment for debt service without the consent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>creditor to whom the debt is owed. This situation places some</textblock>
    <textblock>degree of control outside the institution and beyond the scope of</textblock>
    <textblock>management's ability to deal with a deteriorating situation by</textblock>
    <textblock>reducing costs. Furthermore, a failure to meet debt service</textblock>
    <textblock>payments might precipitate collective action on the part of</textblock>
    <textblock>creditors to place the institution in an involuntary liquidation</textblock>
    <textblock>situation under Federal bankruptcy laws.</textblock>
    <textblock>Alternatively, a growing institution usually must take on</textblock>
    <textblock>more debt to fund its operations. Should the growth fail to</textblock>
    <textblock>continue, the institution might be unable to service the</textblock>
    <textblock>increasing debt service associated with its expansion. Thus, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes an institution's failure to remain current on</textblock>
    <textblock>its debt service payments would be a strong indicator of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's inability to meet its financial obligations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 498(c)(5) of the HEA provides that the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>must establish requirements for an institution to maintain</textblock>
    <textblock>sufficient cash reserves to ensure repayment of any required</textblock>
    <textblock>refunds. Section 498(c)(5) of the HEA also provides for an</textblock>
    <textblock>exemption to this requirement which is discussed below under</textblock>
    <textblock>exceptions to the general standards of financial responsibility.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to require an institution to maintain, at</textblock>
    <textblock>all times, a minimum cash reserve of at least 10 percent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's total deferred tuition income at the end of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's most recent fiscal year for repayment of refunds.</textblock>
    <textblock>The cash reserve would have to be maintained in a cash reserve</textblock>
    <textblock>account and would have to consist of cash or cash equivalents, as</textblock>
    <textblock>those terms are defined in accordance with generally acceptable</textblock>
    <textblock>accounting principles.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary believes that it would be unreasonable and</textblock>
    <textblock>unduly burdensome to require an institution to calculate the</textblock>
    <textblock>percentage of its cash reserve on a continual basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, the Secretary would require an institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine its total deferred income at the end of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's fiscal year and calculate the percentage based on</textblock>
    <textblock>that total. Once that percentage is determined, the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>would have to maintain that amount of cash reserve at all times</textblock>
    <textblock>until a new calculation is performed at the end of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's subsequent fiscal year. The calculation would be</textblock>
    <textblock>based on the institution's total deferred tuition income because</textblock>
    <textblock>deferred tuition income is an indicator of the value of services</textblock>
    <textblock>that the institution will provide for the coming year. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary requests comment on a comparable way to determine the</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate level for the cash reserve.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ten percent of this amount represents roughly the equivalent</textblock>
    <textblock>of a month's worth of an institution's revenue. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>considers this amount a reasonable amount for an institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>have available to pay refunds in the event of the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>precipitous closure. Generally, under this proposal, an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution would demonstrate its compliance with this provision</textblock>
    <textblock>once a year with the submission of the institution's audited</textblock>
    <textblock>financial statements. However, because an institution would be</textblock>
    <textblock>expected to maintain this cash reserve at all times, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary would reserve the right to evaluate an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance with the requirement at any time. Finally, the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal to allow cash equivalents to be included in the cash</textblock>
    <textblock>reserve is consistent with generally accepted accounting</textblock>
    <textblock>principles.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
