<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00108</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00063</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Safeguards:</textblock>
    <textblock>Computers provide privacy and access limitations by requiring a user name and password match. Access to decentralized segments are similarly controlled. Only those personnel with a need to have access to the system are given user names and passwords. The magnetic tape backups have limited access in that users must justify the need and obtain tape numbers and volume identifiers from a central source before they are provided data tapes. Paper record and microfilm records are in limited access areas in locking storage cabinets.</textblock>
    <textblock>Retention and disposal:</textblock>
    <textblock>Leave and Earnings Statements, and pay records are microfilmed and retained on site four years, then archived at the Federal Record Center, and destroyed when 50 years old. The official copy of the personnel record is maintained in the Official Officer Service Records, DOT/CG 626 for active duty officers, the Enlisted Personnel Record System, DOT/CG 629 for active duty enlisted personnel or the Official Coast Guard Reserve Service Record, OST/CG 576 for inactive duty reservists. Duplicate magnetic copies of the pay and personnel record are retained at an off site facility for a useful life of seven years. Paper records for waivers and remissions are retained on site six years three months after the determination and then destroyed. Paper records to determine legal sufficiency for garnishment are retained on site six years three months after the member separates from the service or the garnishment is terminated and then destroyed.</textblock>
    <textblock>System managers and address:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. All information on Coast Guard members other than b., c., and d. below:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) For active duty members of the Coast Guard:</textblock>
    <textblock>Chief, Office of Personnel,</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Transportation,</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Coast Guard Headquarters,</textblock>
    <textblock>2100 2nd Street, SW.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20593-0001.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For Coast Guard inactive duty reserve members and retired Coast Guard reservists awaiting pay at age 60:</textblock>
    <textblock>Chief, Office of Readiness and Reserve,</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Transportation,</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Coast Guard Headquarters,</textblock>
    <textblock>2100 2nd Street, SW.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20593-0001.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. For Coast Guard Waivers and Remissions:</textblock>
    <textblock>Chief, Personnel Services Division (G-PMP),</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Personnel,</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Coast Guard Headquarters,</textblock>
    <textblock>2100 2nd Street, SW.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20590-0001.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. For records used to determine legal sufficiency for garnishment of wages and pay records:</textblock>
    <textblock>Commanding Officer (LGL),</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Coast Guard Pay and Personnel Center,</textblock>
    <textblock>444 SE. Quincy Street,</textblock>
    <textblock>Topeka, KS 66683-3591.</textblock>
    <textblock>d. For data added to the decentralized data segment the commanding officer, officer-in-charge of the unit handling the individual's pay and personnel record, or Chief, Administrative Services Division for individuals whose records are handled by Coast Guard Headquarters.</textblock>
    <textblock>e. For NOAA members:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration,</textblock>
    <textblock>Commissioned Personnel Division,</textblock>
    <textblock>11400 Rockville Pike,</textblock>
    <textblock>Rockville, MD 20852.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notification procedure:</textblock>
    <textblock>Inquiries should be directed to:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. For all information on Coast Guard members other than b., c., and d. Below:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Transportation,</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Coast Guard Headquarters (G-TPS),</textblock>
    <textblock>2100 2nd Street, SW.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20593-0001.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
