<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00139</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(B) In determining the number of students who default</textblock>
    <textblock>before the end of that following fiscal year, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>includes only loans for which the Secretary or a guaranty agency</textblock>
    <textblock>has paid claims for insurance.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) (A) In the case of a student who has attended and</textblock>
    <textblock>borrowed at more than one institution, the student (and his or</textblock>
    <textblock>her subsequent repayment or default) is attributed to each</textblock>
    <textblock>institution for attendance at which the student received a loan</textblock>
    <textblock>that entered repayment in the fiscal year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) A loan on which a payment is made by the institution,</textblock>
    <textblock>its owner, agent, contractor, employee, or any other affiliated</textblock>
    <textblock>entity or individual, in order to avoid default by the borrower,</textblock>
    <textblock>is considered as in default for purposes of this definition.</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Any loan that has been rehabilitated under section 428F</textblock>
    <textblock>of the HEA before the end of that following fiscal year is not</textblock>
    <textblock>considered as in default for purposes of this definition.</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) For the purposes of this definition, a loan made in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with section 428A of the HEA (or a Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Consolidation Loan a portion of which is used to repay a Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>SLS loan) shall not be considered to enter repayment until after</textblock>
    <textblock>the borrower has ceased to be enrolled in an educational program</textblock>
    <textblock>leading to a degree, certificate, or other recognized educational</textblock>
    <textblock>credential at the participating institution on at least a half-</textblock>
    <textblock>time basis (as determined by the institution) and ceased to be in</textblock>
    <textblock>a period of forbearance based on such enrollment. Each eligible</textblock>
    <textblock>lender of a loan made under section 428A (or a Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Consolidation Loan a portion of which is used to repay a Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>SLS loan) of the HEA shall provide the guaranty agency with the</textblock>
    <textblock>information necessary to determine when the loan entered</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment for purposes of this definition, and the guaranty</textblock>
    <textblock>agency shall provide that information to the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) (A) A cohort default rate of an institution applies to</textblock>
    <textblock>all locations of the institution as the institution exists on the</textblock>
    <textblock>first day of the fiscal year for which the rate is calculated.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) A cohort default rate of an institution applies to all</textblock>
    <textblock>locations of the institution from the date the institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>notified of that rate until the institution is notified by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary that the rate no longer applies.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) (A) For an institution that changes its status from</textblock>
    <textblock>that of a location of one institution to that of a free-standing</textblock>
    <textblock>institution, the Secretary determines the cohort default rate</textblock>
    <textblock>based on the institution's status as of October 1 of the fiscal</textblock>
    <textblock>year for which a cohort default rate is being calculated.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) For an institution that changes its status from that of</textblock>
    <textblock>a free-standing institution to that of a location of another</textblock>
    <textblock>institution, the Secretary determines the cohort default rate</textblock>
    <textblock>based on the combined number of students who enter repayment</textblock>
    <textblock>during the applicable fiscal year and the combined number of</textblock>
    <textblock>students who default during the applicable fiscal years from both</textblock>
    <textblock>the former free-standing institution and the other institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>This cohort default rate applies to the new, consolidated</textblock>
    <textblock>institution and all of its current locations.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
