<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00079</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Current regulations governing program participation</textblock>
    <textblock>agreements state only the basic terms of participation in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs and the purpose and scope of the agreement</textblock>
    <textblock>between the Secretary and individual institutions. All of the</textblock>
    <textblock>specific provisions of the program participation agreement that</textblock>
    <textblock>are listed in section 487(a) of the HEA are not restated in the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations. Instead, all the specific statutory provisions are</textblock>
    <textblock>included in the actual agreement signed between the Secretary and</textblock>
    <textblock>individual institutions. The Secretary proposes to revise this</textblock>
    <textblock>section of the regulations to include not only the new provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>of program participation agreements added by the Amendments of</textblock>
    <textblock>1992, but also those provisions previously prescribed by the HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>but not specifically spelled out in this section. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>will specify which proposed changes have been made to this</textblock>
    <textblock>section as a result of the Amendments of 1992 to distinguish them</textblock>
    <textblock>from the provisions that the Secretary proposes to add that</textblock>
    <textblock>already existed under the HEA, but have not been codified in</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The additional provisions of program participation</textblock>
    <textblock>agreements enumerated in the HEA, as well as other changes the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary is proposing in order to clarify what the agreements</textblock>
    <textblock>cover and to reflect new procedures and statutory language, are</textblock>
    <textblock>described below.</textblock>
    <textblock>By providing a comprehensive list of the provisions of the</textblock>
    <textblock>basic program participation agreement in one section, thus making</textblock>
    <textblock>reference to all the provisions more convenient, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>hopes to facilitate institutions' understanding of their</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibilities with respect to initial and continued</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to clarify the scope of the program</textblock>
    <textblock>participation agreement. By signing a program participation</textblock>
    <textblock>agreement, an institution indicates it understands that its</textblock>
    <textblock>initial or continued participation in the Title IV, HEA programs</textblock>
    <textblock>is contingent on compliance with the Student Assistance General</textblock>
    <textblock>Provisions regulations, the regulations of the specific Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA programs in which the institution participates, and any</textblock>
    <textblock>additional requirements specific to that institution that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary requires the institution to meet. Further, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary proposes to make clear the long-standing practice that</textblock>
    <textblock>the program participation agreement applies to each branch or</textblock>
    <textblock>other additional location of the institution that meets the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable requirements of the Student Assistance General</textblock>
    <textblock>Provisions, unless the Secretary specifies otherwise.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to specify that by entering into a</textblock>
    <textblock>program participation agreement the institution agrees to comply</textblock>
    <textblock>not only with statutory and regulatory requirements, but also</textblock>
    <textblock>with any special arrangement, agreement, or limitation. The</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed expansion of this provision is necessary to make it</textblock>
    <textblock>clear that if it is to participate in a Title IV, HEA program, an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution must adhere not only to those requirements listed in</textblock>
    <textblock>the statute and regulations, but to any conditions of provisional</textblock>
    <textblock>certification, any limitation imposed on the institution to which</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution has agreed, or any other special arrangement that</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution makes pursuant to statutory or regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>authority under Title IV of the HEA. The Secretary also believes</textblock>
    <textblock>it is necessary to clarify the Secretary's longstanding</textblock>
    <textblock>interpretation that to begin or continue to participate in a</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program, an institution must comply with each</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement applicable to that program, not just selected</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add a clause specifically</textblock>
    <textblock>requiring that institutions that receive Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>funds under an advance payment method must time their requests</textblock>
    <textblock>for funds to meet immediate programs needs. The Secretary finds</textblock>
    <textblock>that this addition is necessary because, in the absence of this</textblock>
    <textblock>specifically stated requirement, too many institutions have drawn</textblock>
    <textblock>down funds in excess of immediate need, thereby adding</textblock>
    <textblock>unnecessarily to the Federal debt by causing the Treasury to</textblock>
    <textblock>incur interest costs on funds given to institutions that were not</textblock>
    <textblock>required to meet immediate needs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Amendments of 1992, as clarified by the Technical</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendments of 1993, has removed the requirement that an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution may not request from or charge any student a fee for</textblock>
    <textblock>processing or handling the Federal Student Assistance Report, to</textblock>
    <textblock>conform with other statutory provisions of the Amendments of 1992</textblock>
    <textblock>that eliminated previous references to that report. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary would remove the corresponding regulatory language from</textblock>
    <textblock>this section. No change has been made to the general requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>that an institution may not request from or charge any student a</textblock>
    <textblock>fee for processing or handling any application, form, or data</textblock>
    <textblock>required to determine a student's eligibility for, and amount of,</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the HEA, an institution must establish</textblock>
    <textblock>and maintain necessary administrative and fiscal procedures and</textblock>
    <textblock>records to ensure proper and efficient administration of Title</textblock>
    <textblock>IV, HEA program funds that the institution receives from the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary or from students. Further, the Amendments of 1992</textblock>
    <textblock>require that the institution provide, upon request and in a</textblock>
    <textblock>timely manner, information relating to its administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>capability and financial responsibility of the institution to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary, the appropriate State postsecondary review entity</textblock>
    <textblock>designated under Part H of Title IV of the HEA, any applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency under the FFEL programs, and the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>accrediting agency or agencies. The Secretary proposes to add to</textblock>
    <textblock>this list of agencies the institution's State agency with legal</textblock>
    <textblock>jurisdiction over the institution and, where appropriate, the</textblock>
    <textblock>State agency recognized by the Secretary for the approval of</textblock>
    <textblock>public postsecondary education as an alternative to accreditation</textblock>
    <textblock>or preaccreditation. The Secretary believes that it is important</textblock>
    <textblock>that these agencies also have access to information regarding an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's financial responsibility and administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>capability.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
