<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00072</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Monday</textblock>
    <textblock>February 28, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part IV</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency</textblock>
    <textblock>40 CFR Part 280</textblock>
    <textblock>Underground Storage Tanks Containing Petroleum; Financial Responsibility Requirements; Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 39␣/␣Monday, February 28, 1994␣/␣Rules and Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>Underground Storage Tanks Containing Petroleum; Financial Responsibility Requirements</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>40 CFR Part 280</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4842-6]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) is today promulgating a rule to amend the financial responsibility requirements for underground storage tanks (USTs) containing petroleum that appear in subpart H of 40 CFR part 280. Specifically, this rule modifies the financial responsibility compliance date under 40 CFR 280.91(e) for one category of UST owners. Under this modification, Federally-recognized Indian tribes that own USTs on Indian lands are required to comply with Federal Financial Responsibility requirements of 40 CFR part 280 subpart H_Financial Responsibility_by December 31, 1998 if those USTs are in compliance with applicable technical requirements for USTs in 40 CFR part 280. Today's rule extends the deadline for certain USTs owned by Indian tribes from the previous date of February 18, 1994. This change will allow EPA, the Bureau of Indian Affairs and Indian tribes additional time to explore options for solving the root problem of lack of funding for past contamination on Indian lands and further assist tribes with future technical requirements, such as tank upgrading. EPA is not changing the financial responsibility deadline for rural petroleum marketers or local governments. A discussion of the Agency rationale behind this decision can be found in section III. C. under ``</textblock>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION</textblock>
    <textblock>''.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>This rulemaking is effective on February 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The public docket for this rule is in room M2616, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, 401 M Street SW., Washington, DC 20460. Call (202) 260-9720 for an appointment to review docket materials.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>The RCRA/Superfund Hotline at (800) 424-9346 (toll free) or (703) 412-9810 in Virginia. For technical questions, contact Sammy Ng in the Office of Underground Storage Tanks at (703) 308-8882.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA is today finalizing a rule that would allow certain Federally-recognized Indian tribes that own USTs containing petroleum on Indian lands additional time to comply with the financial responsibility requirements. Specifically, this rule modifies the compliance date under 40 CFR 280.91(e). Under this modification, Indian tribes that own USTs containing petroleum on Indian lands must comply with the financial responsibility requirements by December 31, 1998. To qualify for the 1998 financial responsibility deadline, tribally-owned USTs must be in compliance with the technical requirements for USTs described in 40 CFR part 280. Technical compliance for USTs includes, for example, leak detection and reporting. The technical requirements criterion has been included to protect human health and the environment on Indian lands. EPA is not changing the financial responsibility deadline for rural petroleum marketers or local governments. A discussion of Agency rationale behind this decision can be found in section III C.</textblock>
    <textblock>The contents of today's preamble are listed in the following outline:</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Authority</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Effective Date</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Background</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Final Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Indian Tribes</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Implementation of Final Rule</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
