<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00161</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>•If books and supplies are provided by the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>and the institution has delivered the books and</textblock>
    <textblock>supplies to the student, the books and supplies should</textblock>
    <textblock>be excluded from the</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>refund policy.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Certain fees assessed by the institution should be</textblock>
    <textblock>included in the</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>refund where the students do</textblock>
    <textblock>not realize the benefits over the enrollment period to</textblock>
    <textblock>include one time charges, i.e., application fee,</textblock>
    <textblock>orientation charges, testing fees, and deferred payment</textblock>
    <textblock>fees. Other charges assessed by the institution should</textblock>
    <textblock>be excluded from the</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>refund when the student</textblock>
    <textblock>does not realize the benefit over the enrollment period</textblock>
    <textblock>to include fines, penalties, and individual charges</textblock>
    <textblock>(i.e., parking fines, and health center charges.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Books and supplies should not be included in</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>refund unless they are considered a mandatory charge by</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution (i.e, not when the student has the</textblock>
    <textblock>option of buying from the institution or some other</textblock>
    <textblock>source.) [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>•If all equipment and books are purchased at one time or</textblock>
    <textblock>issued to the student before he or she terminates his</textblock>
    <textblock>or her enrollment, the cost should be included in the</textblock>
    <textblock>refund. The institution should charge the whole amount</textblock>
    <textblock>which is not returnable. Equipment must be returned</textblock>
    <textblock>and able to be used again. If equipment has not yet</textblock>
    <textblock>been issued, the student would be eligible for a</textblock>
    <textblock>100 percent refund. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Should the regulations address a time frame for student</textblock>
    <textblock>refunds? Should the regulations have a minimum program length</textblock>
    <textblock>that a student must complete before the student will not be</textblock>
    <textblock>considered to be attending ``for the first time?''</textblock>
    <textblock>•The time frame for all refunds should be uniformly</textblock>
    <textblock>60 days from the date the institution becomes aware</textblock>
    <textblock>that a student has withdrawn. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The regulations should indicate the time frame for</textblock>
    <textblock>issuing student refunds to be the same as current</textblock>
    <textblock>refund requirements- within 60 days of determination</textblock>
    <textblock>that a refund is in order. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Refunds should be made 30 days from date of</textblock>
    <textblock>determination. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Regulations should not address a time frame for refunds</textblock>
    <textblock>since it is already addressed by the State or</textblock>
    <textblock>accrediting agencies. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Should the regulations address how institutions will account</textblock>
    <textblock>for credit balances? Should these funds be kept in a restrictive</textblock>
    <textblock>account rather than the institution's general operating account?</textblock>
    <textblock>•The regulations should not address how institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>account for credit balances nor restrictive or general</textblock>
    <textblock>operating accounts. A minority of the group felt that</textblock>
    <textblock>students with a baccalaureate degree should be exempt</textblock>
    <textblock>from the language. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The group recommends that regulations remain silent on</textblock>
    <textblock>the method by which institutions account for credit</textblock>
    <textblock>balances. [San Francisco, Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>•After all returns have been made to the Federal program</textblock>
    <textblock>from which the funds came, there should be a reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>period of time for the student to request his account</textblock>
    <textblock>balance if there are educational costs outstanding.</textblock>
    <textblock>[San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Since the statute would imply than an institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>required to calculate all three policies and make the payment on</textblock>
    <textblock>the one most generous, should the institution be allowed to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine which is generally most generous an make that the</textblock>
    <textblock>official refund policy?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Institutions should be allowed to determine the refund</textblock>
    <textblock>policy that is generally most generous and use that</textblock>
    <textblock>policy. Institutions would define ``generally most</textblock>
    <textblock>generous.'' [Kansas City, San Francisco, Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The Department should issue guidelines for institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>to use in determining which method to use. If the</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions use average costs in awarding and</textblock>
    <textblock>packaging, average costs should be used in refunds.</textblock>
    <textblock>[San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Institutions should not be allowed to determine which</textblock>
    <textblock>refund is ``generally most generous.'' This is</textblock>
    <textblock>inconsistent with the statute. The statute does,</textblock>
    <textblock>however, permit institution to develop an algorithm</textblock>
    <textblock>that integrates the three refund policies and yields</textblock>
    <textblock>the calculation ``most generous'' to each individual</textblock>
    <textblock>student. The requirements should apply only to the</textblock>
    <textblock>calculation of refunds for students who are recipients</textblock>
    <textblock>of financial aid under Title IV. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>8. How should ``fair and equitable'' be defined?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Fair and equitable'' should be defined as most generous</textblock>
    <textblock>to the student. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•It is not necessary to define ``fair and equitable''</textblock>
    <textblock>separately from the requirements of the statute and the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations. The Student Commission addresses</textblock>
    <textblock>adequately the definition of ``fair and equitable.''</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City, Atlanta]</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
