<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00162</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>•The statutory mandates requiring</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>refund should</textblock>
    <textblock>be viewed as a limitation and not as an example for the</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of Title IV refund only. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>VI. Student Consumerism Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Under section 485(a), additional provisions have been added</textblock>
    <textblock>to the list of information an institution must disclose, upon</textblock>
    <textblock>request, to students and prospective students as part of the</textblock>
    <textblock>student consumerism requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>The institution's refund policy must identify that refunds</textblock>
    <textblock>will be credited in the following order:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) To outstanding balances on Federal Family Education</textblock>
    <textblock>Loans;</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) To outstanding balances on Federal Direct Loans;</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) To outstanding balances on Federal Perkins Loans;</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) To awards under Federal Pell Grants program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) To awards under Federal SEOG program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) To awards under Federal Work Study program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(g) To other Title IV assistance; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(h) To the student.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issues that the community was asked to address and the</textblock>
    <textblock>community's views:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Should regulations require institutions to publicize how</textblock>
    <textblock>refunds will be processed and what refunds students are entitled</textblock>
    <textblock>to receive in the event that the institution closes?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Regulations should require institutions to publicize</textblock>
    <textblock>how refunds will be processed and what funds students</textblock>
    <textblock>are entitled to receive in the event the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>closes. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Institutions should not have to publicize how refunds</textblock>
    <textblock>will be processed and what funds students are entitled</textblock>
    <textblock>to receive in the event the institution closes. This</textblock>
    <textblock>is not a consumer information issue. This is</textblock>
    <textblock>information to be disbursed if the institution closes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Information should be available to students upon</textblock>
    <textblock>request. A statement could be put in the catalog that</textblock>
    <textblock>will lead the student to ask relevant questions. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Department should work with State Agencies to develop</textblock>
    <textblock>plans that should be made available to students on</textblock>
    <textblock>request. There is very little probability that certain</textblock>
    <textblock>strong institutions will close. All institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>should not be required to disclose this.</textblock>
    <textblock>[San Francisco, Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Should consumer information address teachouts or other State</textblock>
    <textblock>or accrediting agency mandated requirements to protect student</textblock>
    <textblock>consumers in the case of school closure?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Consumer information should not address teachouts or</textblock>
    <textblock>other state or accrediting agency mandated requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>to protect student consumers in the case of institution</textblock>
    <textblock>closure. [Kansas City, Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Should institutional discretion be permitted when</textblock>
    <textblock>determining the order in which loan funds under the FFEL program</textblock>
    <textblock>are returned?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Institutional discretion should be permitted when</textblock>
    <textblock>determining the order in which loan funds under the</textblock>
    <textblock>FFEL program are returned. [Kansas City,</textblock>
    <textblock>San Francisco, Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Should guarantee and origination fees be included in the</textblock>
    <textblock>refund to totally pay off a FFEL program loan?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Guaranty and origination fees should not be included in</textblock>
    <textblock>the refund to totally payoff an FFEL program loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Guaranty and origination fees should be included in the</textblock>
    <textblock>refund to totally payoff an FFEL program loan.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The full amount should be included in the refund as a</textblock>
    <textblock>deterrent to default on the small remaining amount.</textblock>
    <textblock>This should be done at the institution's discretion.</textblock>
    <textblock>Institutions should not be required to pay back money</textblock>
    <textblock>they have not received, i.e., guaranty and origination</textblock>
    <textblock>fees. Institution should be permitted to include these</textblock>
    <textblock>fees if they choose. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>5. How should the guaranty agencies monitor students to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>that multiple FFEL funds are treated as one for the purposes of</textblock>
    <textblock>billing and deferments from one lender?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Guaranty agency monitoring of students to ensure that</textblock>
    <textblock>multiple FFEL funds are treated as one for the purpose</textblock>
    <textblock>of billing and deferments from one lender should be</textblock>
    <textblock>handled under the FFEL program. This is not a consumer</textblock>
    <textblock>information issue. [Kansas City, San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Guaranty agency monitoring of students to ensure that</textblock>
    <textblock>multiple FFEL funds are treated as one for the purpose</textblock>
    <textblock>of billing and deferments from one lender should be</textblock>
    <textblock>done through the National Student Loan Data Bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agencies should identify all loans obtained through</textblock>
    <textblock>that agency. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>VII. Institutional Eligibility and Certification Procedures_Part H, Subpart 3</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Section 498(a), (b), and (f) of the HEA establish application</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements and procedures for the Secretary to use to determine</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution's legal authority to operate within a State,</textblock>
    <textblock>accreditation, financial responsibility, and administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>capability.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
