<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00121</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(3) Subtract from the total obtained under paragraph (f)(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section the number of students who were enrolled in the</textblock>
    <textblock>program at the end of that award year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Determine the number of regular students who, during</textblock>
    <textblock>that award year, received the degree, certificate, or other</textblock>
    <textblock>recognized educational credential awarded for successfully</textblock>
    <textblock>completing the program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Divide the number determined under paragraph (f)(4) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section by the total obtained under paragraph (f)(3) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Calculation of placement rate.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) An institution</textblock>
    <textblock>shall calculate its placement rate for an educational program for</textblock>
    <textblock>any award year as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Determine the number of students who, during the award</textblock>
    <textblock>year, received the degree, certificate, or other recognized</textblock>
    <textblock>educational credential awarded for successfully completing the</textblock>
    <textblock>program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Subtract from the number determined under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (g)(1)(i) of this section the number of students</textblock>
    <textblock>described in paragraph (g)(1)(i) of this section who were</textblock>
    <textblock>employed by the institution either before or after their receipt</textblock>
    <textblock>of the degree, certificate, or other recognized educational</textblock>
    <textblock>credential.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Of the total obtained under paragraph (g)(1)(ii) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section, determine the number of students who, within 180</textblock>
    <textblock>days of the day they received their degree, certificate, or other</textblock>
    <textblock>recognized educational credential, obtained gainful employment in</textblock>
    <textblock>the recognized occupation for which they were trained or in a</textblock>
    <textblock>related comparable recognized occupation and, on the date of this</textblock>
    <textblock>calculation, are employed or have been employed for at least 13</textblock>
    <textblock>weeks following receipt of the credential from the institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Divide the number of students determined under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (g)(1)(iii) of this section by the total obtained under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (g)(1)(ii) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) An institution shall document that each student</textblock>
    <textblock>described in paragraph (g)(1)(iii) of this section obtained</textblock>
    <textblock>gainful employment in the recognized occupation for which he or</textblock>
    <textblock>she was trained or in a related comparable recognized occupation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Examples of satisfactory documentation of a student's gainful</textblock>
    <textblock>employment include, but are not limited to_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) A written statement from the student's employer;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Signed copies of State or Federal income tax forms;</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Written evidence of payments of Social Security</textblock>
    <textblock>taxes.</textblock>
    <textblock>(h)</textblock>
    <textblock>Eligibility for Federal Pell Grant and FSEOG programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to satisfying other relevant provisions of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, an educational program qualifies as an eligible program</textblock>
    <textblock>for purposes of the Federal Pell Grant or FSEOG Program only if</textblock>
    <textblock>the educational program is an undergraduate program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Flight training.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to satisfying other</textblock>
    <textblock>relevant provisions of this section, for a program of flight</textblock>
    <textblock>training to be an eligible program, it must have a current valid</textblock>
    <textblock>certification from the Federal Aviation Administration.</textblock>
    <textblock>(j)</textblock>
    <textblock>English as a second language (ESL).</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) In addition</textblock>
    <textblock>to satisfying the relevant provisions of this section, an</textblock>
    <textblock>educational program that consists solely of instruction in ESL</textblock>
    <textblock>qualifies as an eligible program if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The institution admits to the program only students who</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution determines need the ESL instruction to use</textblock>
    <textblock>already existing knowledge, training, or skills; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The program leads to a degree, certificate, or other</textblock>
    <textblock>recognized educational credential.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) An institution shall test each student at the end of</textblock>
    <textblock>the educational program to substantiate that the student has</textblock>
    <textblock>attained adequate proficiency in written and spoken English to</textblock>
    <textblock>use already existing knowledge, training, or skills. The</textblock>
    <textblock>institution shall identify the test or tests given to the</textblock>
    <textblock>students and the basis for the judgment that the student has</textblock>
    <textblock>attained the adequate proficiency.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) An institution shall document its determination that</textblock>
    <textblock>ESL instruction is necessary to enable each student enrolled in</textblock>
    <textblock>its ESL program to use already existing knowledge, training, or</textblock>
    <textblock>skills with regard to the students that it admits to its ESL</textblock>
    <textblock>program under paragraph (j)(1)(i) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) An ESL program that qualifies as an eligible program</textblock>
    <textblock>under this paragraph is eligible for purposes of the Federal Pell</textblock>
    <textblock>Grant Program only.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
