<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00087</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes that a for-profit institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>financially responsible if it has not had operating losses over</textblock>
    <textblock>both of its two latest fiscal years that cause an operating loss</textblock>
    <textblock>exceeding 10 percent of the institution's previous year's</textblock>
    <textblock>tangible net worth for its latest fiscal year. While it may not</textblock>
    <textblock>be unusual for an institution to record a loss in any fiscal</textblock>
    <textblock>year, this loss is not harmful so long as the loss is not</textblock>
    <textblock>excessive, is not indicative of a deteriorating trend in the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's financial condition, and the institution otherwise</textblock>
    <textblock>meets the factors substantiating its financial strength. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary proposes to define an operating loss, for purposes of</textblock>
    <textblock>these provisions, as total net income minus extraordinary gains</textblock>
    <textblock>or losses, income or losses from discontinued operations, prior</textblock>
    <textblock>period adjustments, and the cumulative effect of changes in</textblock>
    <textblock>accounting principle, estimate, or reporting entity. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary proposes that the calculation of tangible net worth</textblock>
    <textblock>shall exclude all assets defined as intangible in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>generally accepted accounting principles. The Secretary believes</textblock>
    <textblock>this standard will measure whether a profit-seeking entity is</textblock>
    <textblock>operating from current cash flow to the extent possible. The</textblock>
    <textblock>aggregate residual effect of these activities on the</textblock>
    <textblock>organization's individual net assets is represented, along with</textblock>
    <textblock>any interfund transfers that may have taken place during the</textblock>
    <textblock>period.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes that a for-profit institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>financially responsible if it had, for its latest fiscal year, a</textblock>
    <textblock>positive tangible net worth. The Secretary proposes that, for</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of this section, a positive tangible net worth occurs</textblock>
    <textblock>when the institution's tangible assets exceed its liabilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further, the Secretary proposes that the calculation of tangible</textblock>
    <textblock>net worth shall exclude all assets defined as intangible in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with generally accepted accounting principles. In</textblock>
    <textblock>applying this proposed standard, the Secretary could consider the</textblock>
    <textblock>effect of extraordinary gains or losses resulting from unusual</textblock>
    <textblock>and infrequent events, and could take into consideration the</textblock>
    <textblock>cumulative effect of changes in accounting principle, estimate or</textblock>
    <textblock>reporting entity to the extent that such a change results in a</textblock>
    <textblock>more accurate representation of the institution's financial</textblock>
    <textblock>position in accordance with generally accepted accounting</textblock>
    <textblock>principles. For the past fourteen years, the Department has had</textblock>
    <textblock>a standard for net worth that states that an institution is not</textblock>
    <textblock>financially responsible if it has a deficit net worth (i.e., the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's liabilities exceed its assets.), a measure of</textblock>
    <textblock>long-term solvency. Therefore, an institution with a net worth</textblock>
    <textblock>of zero meets this current requirement. The proposed change from</textblock>
    <textblock>penalizing a deficit net worth to requiring a positive net worth</textblock>
    <textblock>is only a technical change in form that should affect few, if any</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions.</textblock>
    <textblock>By excluding all assets classified as intangible, all assets</textblock>
    <textblock>such as goodwill, organization costs, and</textblock>
    <textblock>covenants-not-to-compete, which have little market value in the</textblock>
    <textblock>determination of an institution's overall solvency will be</textblock>
    <textblock>eliminated in the calculation of net worth. In purchasing a</textblock>
    <textblock>business, the new owner pays an amount and allocates the market</textblock>
    <textblock>value to individual tangible assets in order to prepare financial</textblock>
    <textblock>statements. After applying the proper market value to the</textblock>
    <textblock>various assets, any residual amount that appears on the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's balance sheet as goodwill, organization costs, or</textblock>
    <textblock>covenant-not-to-compete, is classified as an intangible asset.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is the Secretary's intent to identify those institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>that do not have sufficient capital assets. For example,</textblock>
    <textblock>businesses that operate on month-to-month leases with minimum</textblock>
    <textblock>capital actually invested in the business are a potential risk to</textblock>
    <textblock>students, and ultimately to the taxpayers in terms of possible</textblock>
    <textblock>collapse and bailout. In these cases loans to students are often</textblock>
    <textblock>automatically discharged in accordance with provisions in the</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA. Preventing institutions that have no real assets from</textblock>
    <textblock>participating in the programs should enhance the gatekeeping</textblock>
    <textblock>process.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
