<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00071</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00044</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with Departmental policy, notice is hereby given that three proposed consent decrees in</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Lowe,</textblock>
    <textblock>Civil Action No. H-91-0830, were lodged on February 14, 1993 with the United States District Court for the Southern District of Texas. The consent decrees resolve the liability under CERCLA of defendants Ralph Lowe, Dixie Oil Processors, Tex Tin Corporation, and Lowenco, Inc. for the Dixie Oil Processors Superfund Site in Harris County, Texas.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Justice will receive, for a period of thirty (30) days from the date of this publication, comments relating to the proposed consent decrees. Comments should be addressed to the Assistant Attorney General for the Environment and Natural Resources Division, Department of Justice, Washington, DC 20530, and should refer to</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Lowe,</textblock>
    <textblock>DOJ Ref.</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>90-11-2-323.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed consent decrees may be examined at the office of the United States Attorney, 440 Louisiana, Suite 900, Houston, Texas 77002; the Region 6 Office of the Environmental Protection Agency, 1445 Ross Avenue, Dallas, Texas 75202; and at the Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., 4th Floor, Washington, DC 20005, (202) 624-0892. A copy of the proposed consent decrees may be obtained in person or by mail from the Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., 4th Floor, Washington, DC 20005. In requesting a copy please refer to the referenced case and enclose a check in the amount of $18.00 (25 cents per page reproduction costs), payable to the Consent Decree Library.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Lodging of Consent Decree Pursuant to the Comprehensive, Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (``CERCLA`'')</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John C. Cruden,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Environmental Enforcement Section, Environment and Natural Resources Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4513 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
