<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00038</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 22, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on August 2, 1991, Ozark Gas Transmission System (Ozark) made a filing, under protest, in the above-captioned docket concerning its compliance with Order Nos. 497 et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 23, 1993, in Order No. 497-E, the Commission confirmed that Ozark is subject to Order Nos. 497 et al. This notice of Ozark's prior compliance filing is being issued in accord with Order No. 497-E.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ozark states that copies of this filing were served upon all parties on the official service list complied by the Secretary of the Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC, 20426, in accordance with Rules 211 or 214 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (18 CFR 385.211 or 385.214). All such motions to intervene or protest should be filed on or before March 9, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. MG91-7-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Ozark Gas Transmission System; Filing</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Inquiry Into Alleged Anticompetitive Practices Related to Marketing Affiliates of Interstate Pipelines, Order No. 497, 53 FR 22139 22139 (June 14, 1988), FERC Stats. &amp; Regs. [Regulations Preambles 1986-1990] ¶ 30,820 (1988), order on reh'g, Order No. 497-A, 54 FR 52781 (Dec. 22, 1989), FERC Stats. &amp; Regs. [Regulations Preambles 1986-1990] ¶ 30,868 (1989), order extending sunset date, Order No. 497-B, 55 FR 53291 (Dec. 28, 1990), FERC Stats. &amp; Regs. [Regulations Preambles 1986-1990] ¶ 30,908 (1990), order extending sunset date and amending final rule, Order No. 497-C, 57 FR 9 (Jan. 2, 1992), III FERC Stats. &amp; Regs. ¶ 30,934 (1991), reh'g denied, 57 FR 5815 (Feb. 18, 1992), 58 FERC ¶ 61,139 (1992), aff'd in part and remanded in part, Tenneco Gas v.</textblock>
    <textblock>FERC, 969 F.2d 1187 (DC Cir. 1992); Order No. 497-D, (order on remand and extending sunset date), 57 FR 58,978 (December 4, 1992), III FERC Stat. and Reg. ¶ 30,958 (1992); Order No. 497-E, Order on rehearing and extending sunset date), 59 FR 243 (January 4, 1994), III FERC Stat. and Reg. ¶ 30,987 (December 23, 1993).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4417 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
