<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00054</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Mobile-Satellite Service at 1610-1626.5 and 2483.5-2500 MHz</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL COMMUNICATIONS COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>47 CFR Part 2</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[ET Docket No. 92-28; FCC 93-547]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This Report and Order allocates the 1610-1626.5 and 2483.5-2500 MHz bands on a co-primary basis to the mobile-satellite service (MSS). This action responds to seven petitions for rule making that were filed with the Commission and conforms to the international frequency allocation that was adopted at the World Administrative Radio Conference (WARC-92) last year. Further, this action is taken to accommodate the need for additional mobile-satellite spectrum that can be used to provide many new services both domestically and internationally.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 30, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ray LaForge, Office of Engineering and Technology, telephone (202) 653-8117.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a summary of the Commission's Report and Order in ET Docket No. 92-28 adopted on December 13, 1993 and released January 12, 1994. The complete text of this Report and Order is available for inspection and copying during normal business hours in the FCC Public Reference Center (room 239), 1919 M Street, NW., Washington, DC. The complete text of this Report and Order also may be purchased from the Commission's duplication contractor, International Transcription Service, Inc., 2100 M Street, NW., suite 140, Washington, DC 20036, (202) 857-3800.</textblock>
    <textblock>Summary of Report and Order</textblock>
    <textblock>1. In this Report and Order the Commission allocates 33 MHz of spectrum, the 1610-1626.5 and 2483.5-2500 MHz bands, for the mobile-satellite service (MSS). A total of 16.5 MHz, 1610-1626.5 MHz, is provided for primary space-to-Earth (uplink) operations and 16.5 MHz, 2483.5-2500 MHz, is provided for primary Earth-to-space (downlink) operations. Also, 12.7 MHz, 1613.8-1626.5 MHz, is allocated for secondary MSS space-to-Earth (downlink) operations. In addition, the Commission elevates the radio astronomy service allocation in the 1610.6-1613.8 MHz band from secondary to co-primary status.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The 1610-1626.5 and 2483.5-2500 MHz bands currently are allocated to a number of other services. The radiodetermination satellite service (RDSS), is allocated in these bands on a primary basis but only interim RDSS systems have been authorized.</textblock>
    <textblock>See</textblock>
    <textblock>Newcomb Communications, Inc., 8 FCC Rcd 3631 (1993); and letter to Counsel, Mobile Data Communications, Inc. from Chief, Domestic Facilities Division (August 19, 1993). Currently, the 1610-1626.5 MHz band is allocated to the aeronautical radionavigation service on a co-primary basis, and the 1610.6-1613.8 MHz segment of this band also is allocated to the radio astronomy service (RAS) on a secondary basis. Frequencies adjacent to the 1610-1626.5 MHz band are allocated to aeronautical radionavigation satellite and maritime mobile satellite services.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
