<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00168</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>•Any schedule developed for the review of institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>for this purpose should be published. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Regulations and standards in this area are not</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary; the statute is specific enough.</textblock>
    <textblock>[San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•In cases where the eligibility process requires a site</textblock>
    <textblock>visit, and the Secretary is unable to perform the site</textblock>
    <textblock>visit in a timely manner, eligibility should continue</textblock>
    <textblock>beyond the expiration date until the eligibility</textblock>
    <textblock>process is completed. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Section 498(h) provides that the Secretary may provisionally</textblock>
    <textblock>certify an institution for not more than one year for initial</textblock>
    <textblock>certification, or three years under certain conditions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Provisional certification may be withdrawn if the institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>unable to meet its responsibilities. Also, if an accrediting</textblock>
    <textblock>agency's recognition is withdrawn, the Secretary may continue the</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility of accredited institutions for up to 18 months.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issues that the community was asked to address and the</textblock>
    <textblock>community's views:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. What standards should be used to determine whether an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution may be granted provisionally certification?</textblock>
    <textblock>•An institution could be provisionally certified if it</textblock>
    <textblock>does not meet the third criterion for financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility in section 498(c) of the HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•For an initial application, the Secretary should rely</textblock>
    <textblock>on the statutory language. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•An institution should be provisionally certified if it</textblock>
    <textblock>is unable to meet a regulatory standard for a reason</textblock>
    <textblock>beyond the institution's control. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The Secretary should use the same standards that are</textblock>
    <textblock>used for determining financial responsibility and</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•An institution that meets all requirements for</textblock>
    <textblock>certification other than the completion of a required</textblock>
    <textblock>site visit should be provisionally certified if the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary is unable to conduct the site visit in a</textblock>
    <textblock>timely manner. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. What procedures and standards should the Secretary use to</textblock>
    <textblock>decide whether an institution that has received provisional</textblock>
    <textblock>certification is unable to meet its responsibilities?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Before revoking an institution's participation, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary should conduct proceedings for a hearing, and</textblock>
    <textblock>should provisionally certify an institution until the</textblock>
    <textblock>completion of those proceedings. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The Secretary should use the same standards that are</textblock>
    <textblock>used for determining financial responsibility and</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The Secretary should use the results of audits, audited</textblock>
    <textblock>financial statements, and program reviews to determine</textblock>
    <textblock>whether to certify an institution provisionally and</textblock>
    <textblock>conduct a site visit at the institution. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Under what circumstances should the Secretary continue the</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility of accredited institutions where their accrediting</textblock>
    <textblock>agency loses its recognition? Should the period of extension be</textblock>
    <textblock>the same for all institutions?</textblock>
    <textblock>•According to a minority of participants, an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>identified as having administrative capability problems</textblock>
    <textblock>should be provisionally certified for no more than one</textblock>
    <textblock>year. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•All institutions should be provisionally certified for</textblock>
    <textblock>18 months, and the Secretary should ensure that a</textblock>
    <textblock>process is available for such institutions to become</textblock>
    <textblock>accredited by another agency. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Eligibility should be continued in all cases and for</textblock>
    <textblock>the same period of time for all institutions. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary should notify an institution promptly of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's action, the institution should promptly</textblock>
    <textblock>apply for accreditation with another agency and notify</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution of that fact, and the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>should make a good-faith effort to expedite its</textblock>
    <textblock>accreditation. [Atlanta]</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3879 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4000-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
