<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00009</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Unexpended sums.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any unexpended sums, which have been collected by the Board through default of a handler on the handler's bond, remaining in the possession of the Board at the end of a marketing year, shall be used to reimburse the Board for its expenses, including administrative and other costs incurred in the collection of such sums, and in the purchase of restricted credits as provided in paragraph (d) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Transfer of restricted credit purchases.</textblock>
    <textblock>Restricted credits purchased as provided for in this section shall be turned over to those handlers who have defaulted on their bonds for liquidation of their restricted obligation. The quantity delivered to each handler shall be that quantity represented by sums collected through default.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposal No. 11</textblock>
    <textblock>In §982.57, revise paragraph (b) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§982.57</textblock>
    <textblock>Exemptions.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Sales by growers direct to consumers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any hazelnut grower may sell hazelnuts of such grower's own production free of the regulatory and assessment provisions of this part if such grower sells such hazelnuts in the area of production directly to end users at such grower's ranch or orchard or at roadside stands and farmers' markets. The Board, with the approval of the Secretary, may establish such rules, regulations, and safeguards and require such reports, certifications, and other conditions, as are necessary to ensure that such hazelnuts are disposed of only as authorized. Mail order sales to destinations outside the area of production are not considered to be exempt sales under this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposal No. 12</textblock>
    <textblock>In §982.58, revise the last sentence of paragraph (a) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§982.58</textblock>
    <textblock>Research, promotion, and market development.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣* The expenses of such projects shall be paid from funds collected pursuant to §982.61, §982.63, or credited pursuant to paragraph (b) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Revise §982.61 by designating the present text as paragraph (a) and adding a new paragraph (b) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§982.61</textblock>
    <textblock>Assessments.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) In order to provide funds for the administration of the provisions of this part during the first part of a fiscal period before sufficient operating income is available from assessments on the current year's shipments, the Board may accept the payment of assessments in advance, and may also borrow money for such purpose. Further, payment discounts may be authorized by the Board upon the approval of the Secretary to handlers making such advance assessment payments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Add a new §982.63 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§982.63</textblock>
    <textblock>Contributions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board may accept voluntary contributions but these shall only be used to pay expenses incurred pursuant to §982.58. Furthermore, such contributions shall be free from any encumbrances by the donor and the Board shall retain complete control of their use.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposal No. 13</textblock>
    <textblock>The Fruit and Vegetable Division, Agricultural Marketing Service, proposes to make such changes to the order as may be necessary to conform with any amendment thereto that may result from the hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lon Hatamiya,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4609 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
