<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00115</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00069</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Airborne Area Navigation Equipment Using Multi-Sensor Inputs</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice announces the availability of and requests comments on a proposed technical standard order (TSO) pertaining to airborne area navigation equipment using multi-sensor inputs. The proposed TSO prescribes the minimum performance standards that airborne area navigation equipment using multi-sensor inputs must meet to be identified with the marking ``TSO-C115b.''</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before April 19, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send all comments on the proposed technical standard order to: Technical Analysis Branch, AIR-120, Aircraft Engineering Division Aircraft Certification Service_File No. TSO-C115b, Federal Aviation Administration, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591. Or deliver comments to: Federal Aviation Administration, room 335, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Bobbie J. Smith, Technical Analysis Branch, AIR-120, Aircraft Engineering Division, Aircraft Certification Service, Federal Aviation Administration, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591, Telephone (202) 267-9546.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments Invited</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to comment on the proposed TSO listed in this notice by submitting such written data, views, or arguments as they desire to the above specified address. Comments must identify the TSO file number. Comments received on the proposed technical standard order may be examined, before and after the comment closing date, in room 335, FAA Headquarters Building (FOB-10A), 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591, weekdays except Federal holidays, between 8:30 a.m. and 4:30 p.m. All communications received on or before the closing date for comments specified above will be considered by the Director of the Aircraft Certification Service before issuing the final TSO.</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>This Technical Standard Order (TSO) is being revised to incorporate standards for Global Positioning System (GPS) technology into the standards for multi-sensor navigation systems. In December 1992, TSO-C129 was issued to provide minimum operational standards for GPS navigation equipment. This TSO established requirements on multi-sensor equipment that uses GPS as a navigation source. This revision to TSO-C115a incorporates those criteria in the multi-sensor standard. No new criteria have been established by these changes. This revision incorporates only previously published standards into this TSO.</textblock>
    <textblock>How to Obtain Copies</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the proposed TSO-C115b may be obtained by contacting ``For Further Information Contact.'' Copies of RTCA Document No. DO-187, ``Minimum Operational Performance Standards for Airborne Area Navigation Equipment Using Multi-Sensor Inputs,'' may be purchased from RTCA, Inc., 1140 Connecticut Avenue, NW., suite 1020, Washington, DC 20036.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on February 22, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John K. McGrath,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Aircraft Engineering Division, Aircraft Certification Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4465 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
