<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00065</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>•This NPRM proposes, in §668.16 (currently §§668.14 and</textblock>
    <textblock>668.15) to strengthen and expand the standards of</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability for participating institutions,</textblock>
    <textblock>addressing areas previously not regulated or for which there</textblock>
    <textblock>were only guidelines, such as: The maximum time frame</textblock>
    <textblock>allowed in the standards for satisfactory academic progress</textblock>
    <textblock>for completion of a student's educational program and the</textblock>
    <textblock>expansion of standards to include those general areas that</textblock>
    <textblock>will be reviewed by State postsecondary review entities</textblock>
    <textblock>(SPREs). The SPRE review areas are included because these</textblock>
    <textblock>areas may have a significant bearing on an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability and thus should be considered as</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary reviews the administrative capability of an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, the NPRM does solicit comments on whether these</textblock>
    <textblock>additional proposed standards should be implemented across</textblock>
    <textblock>the board or be made applicable only to institutions that</textblock>
    <textblock>meet specific criteria or thresholds, e.g., institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>with short-term programs and institutions with a history of</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative problems. For example, this section of the</textblock>
    <textblock>NPRM includes the proposed requirement that an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>that offers a vocational program of less than two years in</textblock>
    <textblock>length that prepares students to enter recognized</textblock>
    <textblock>occupations must demonstrate that the borrower's increased</textblock>
    <textblock>annual expected earnings, based on completion of the</textblock>
    <textblock>training, will exceed the annual amount of Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program assistance received for the programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>•The provisions in proposed §668.17 (currently §668.15)</textblock>
    <textblock>governing default reduction measures reflect statutory</textblock>
    <textblock>changes made by the Amendments of 1992 and current</textblock>
    <textblock>departmental practices. The provisions in the Technical</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendments of 1993 that address institutional appeals of</textblock>
    <textblock>cohort default rates are not included in this NPRM and will</textblock>
    <textblock>be addressed separately.</textblock>
    <textblock>•As mandated by statute, all participating institutions are</textblock>
    <textblock>required to implement a fair and equitable refund policy.</textblock>
    <textblock>This statutory provision is similar to the requirement for</textblock>
    <textblock>fair and equitable refunds prescribed by the FFEL program</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations for institutions that participate in the FFEL</textblock>
    <textblock>programs. Section 668.22 proposes to clarify the terms used</textblock>
    <textblock>in the statutory definition of a fair and equitable refund</textblock>
    <textblock>policy. The NPRM also proposes to mandate a refund policy</textblock>
    <textblock>(Appendix A) that an institution must use to calculate a</textblock>
    <textblock>student's refund if the student is not entitled to a</textblock>
    <textblock>pro</textblock>
    <textblock>rata</textblock>
    <textblock>refund and an institution's State and accrediting</textblock>
    <textblock>agency do not have specific refund standards. In addition,</textblock>
    <textblock>because of a new statutory provision that specifies the</textblock>
    <textblock>order of return of refunds to the Title IV, HEA programs and</textblock>
    <textblock>other sources of aid without regard to the amount of aid</textblock>
    <textblock>received from State or private sources, this NPRM proposes</textblock>
    <textblock>to remove the fraction that is currently used to determine</textblock>
    <textblock>the portion of the refund attributable to the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs and that attributable to other sources of aid.</textblock>
    <textblock>•In accordance with the statute, institutions will now be</textblock>
    <textblock>required to have compliance audits every year rather than</textblock>
    <textblock>every two years, as required by current regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.23 proposes to allow institutions that do not</textblock>
    <textblock>pose a great financial risk to the Title IV, HEA programs</textblock>
    <textblock>(i.e., institutions that received less than $100,000 in</textblock>
    <textblock>total annual funding under the Title IV, HEA programs or</textblock>
    <textblock>have not had deficiencies identified in their most recently</textblock>
    <textblock>submitted audit reports) to submit audits biennially.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further, under this proposal, an institution would not be</textblock>
    <textblock>required to submit a compliance audit for any year in which</textblock>
    <textblock>the total Title IV, HEA program funds it received were less</textblock>
    <textblock>than $25,000. This section also proposes to extend audit</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements to foreign institutions.</textblock>
    <textblock>This NPRM also contains a proposed change to the Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Pell Grant Program regulations. This NPRM proposes to implement</textblock>
    <textblock>section 487(c)(7) of the HEA that provides that an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>may offset the amount of Title IV, HEA program disbursements</textblock>
    <textblock>against liabilities or may receive reimbursement from the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department for those amounts if, in the course of any audit</textblock>
    <textblock>conducted after December 31, 1988, the Department discovers or is</textblock>
    <textblock>informed of any Title IV, HEA program assistance (specifically,</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Pell Grant Program funds) that an institution has</textblock>
    <textblock>provided to its students in accordance with program requirements,</textblock>
    <textblock>but the institution has not previously received credit or</textblock>
    <textblock>reimbursement for these disbursements. Although this provision</textblock>
    <textblock>relates directly to the Federal Pell Grant Program and is</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed to be included in the Federal Pell Grant Program</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations, it is contained in Part G of the HEA and is subject</textblock>
    <textblock>to the negotiated rulemaking process explained below. Therefore,</textblock>
    <textblock>it has been included in this NPRM instead of the Federal Pell</textblock>
    <textblock>Grant Program NPRM, which was not subject to the negotiated</textblock>
    <textblock>rulemaking process.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
