<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00122</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(k)</textblock>
    <textblock>Undergraduate educational program in credit hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>If an institution offers an undergraduate educational program in credit hours, the institution must use the formula contained in paragraph (l) of this section to determine whether that program satisfies the requirements contained in paragraph (c)(3) or (d) of this section, and the number of credit hours in that educational program for purposes of the Title IV, HEA programs, unless_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The program is at least two academic years in length and provides an associate degree, a bachelor's degree, a professional degree, or an equivalent degree as determined by the Secretary; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Each course within the program is acceptable for full credit toward that institution's associate degree, bachelor's degree, professional degree, or equivalent degree as determined by the Secretary, provided that the institution's degree requires at least two academic years of study.</textblock>
    <textblock>(l)</textblock>
    <textblock>Formula.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of determining whether a program described in paragraph (k) of this section satisfies the requirements contained in paragraph (c)(3) or (d) of this section, and the number of credit hours in that educational program with regard to the Title IV, HEA programs_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A semester hour must include at least 30 clock hours of instruction;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A trimester hour must include at least 30 clock hours of instruction; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) A quarter hour must include at least 20 hours of instruction.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1070a, 1070b, 1070c-1070c-2, 1085, 1087aa-1087hh, 1088, 1091, and 1141; 42 U.S.C. 2753)</textblock>
    <textblock>§§668.12-668.16</textblock>
    <textblock>[Redesignated as §§668.14-668.18]</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Sections 668.12 through 668.16 are redesignated as §§668.14 through 668.18, respectively.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. A new §668.12 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.12</textblock>
    <textblock>Application procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications for initial participation.</textblock>
    <textblock>An institution that wishes to participate in a Title IV, HEA program must first apply to the Secretary for a certification that the institution meets the standards in this subpart.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications for continued participation.</textblock>
    <textblock>A participating institution must apply to the Secretary for a certification that the institution continues to meet the standards in this subpart upon the request of the Secretary or if the institution wishes to_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Continue to participate in a Title IV, HEA program beyond the scheduled expiration of the institution's current period of participation in the program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Include in the institution's participation in a Title IV, HEA program_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) A branch campus that is not currently included in the institution's participation in the program; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Another location that is not currently included in the institution's participation in the program, if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) That location offers 100 percent of an educational program; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The Secretary requires the institution to apply for certification under paragraph (c) of this section;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Reestablish participation in a Title IV, HEA program following a change in ownership that results in a change in control according to the provisions of 34 CFR part 600.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Notification and application requirements for additional locations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A participating institution must notify the Secretary, in writing, if the institution wishes to_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Include in its participation in a Title IV, HEA program a location that is not currently included in the institution's participation in the program and that offers at least 50 percent, but less than 100 percent, of an educational program; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Continue to include in its participation in a Title IV, HEA program a location that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Offers at least 50 percent, but less than 100 percent, of an educational program; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Has changed its name, location, or address.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The Secretary considers the submission of the required notification under 34 CFR 600.30 with respect to that location to satisfy the notification requirement of this paragraph.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
