<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00062</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Monday</textblock>
    <textblock>February 28, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part II</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education</textblock>
    <textblock>34 CFR Parts 668 and 690</textblock>
    <textblock>Student Assistance General Provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>and Federal Pell Grant Program;</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 39␣/␣Monday, February 28, 1994␣/␣Proposed Rules</textblock>
    <textblock>Student Assistance General Provisions and Federal Pell Grant</textblock>
    <textblock>Program</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>34 CFR Parts 668 and 690</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1840-AB85</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of proposed rulemaking.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to amend Subparts A and B of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Student Assistance General Provisions regulations and the Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Pell Grant Program regulations to reflect changes made by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Higher Education Amendments of 1992 and the Higher Education</textblock>
    <textblock>Technical Amendments of 1993 to the Higher Education Act of 1965,</textblock>
    <textblock>as amended (HEA). These proposed regulations would seek to</textblock>
    <textblock>improve the efficiency of Federal student aid programs and, by so</textblock>
    <textblock>doing, to improve their capacity to enhance opportunities for</textblock>
    <textblock>postsecondary education.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before March 30, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>All comments concerning these proposed regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>should be addressed to Wendy L. Macias, Program Specialist, U.S.</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education, 400 Maryland Avenue, SW. (Regional</textblock>
    <textblock>Office Building 3, room 4318), Washington, DC 20202-5346.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Wendy L. Macias. Telephone</textblock>
    <textblock>(202) 708-7888. Individuals who use a telecommunications device</textblock>
    <textblock>for the deaf (TDD) may call the Federal Information Relay Service</textblock>
    <textblock>(FIRS) at 1-800-877-8339 between 8 a.m. and 6 p.m., Eastern time,</textblock>
    <textblock>Monday through Friday.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>In order to approve a postsecondary</textblock>
    <textblock>education institution to participate in the student financial</textblock>
    <textblock>assistance programs authorized by Title IV of the HEA (Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA programs) and many other Federal programs, the Secretary must</textblock>
    <textblock>determine, in part, that the institution satisfies the statutory</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of an ``institution of higher education.'' Under the</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA and other Federal statutes, one element of that definition</textblock>
    <textblock>requires an eligible institution of higher education to be</textblock>
    <textblock>accredited or preaccredited by an accrediting agency recognized</textblock>
    <textblock>by the Secretary as a reliable authority as to the quality of the</textblock>
    <textblock>education or training provided by the institution. Another</textblock>
    <textblock>element requires an eligible institution to be legally authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>to provide an educational program beyond the secondary level in</textblock>
    <textblock>the State in which it is located. Thus, the statutory definition</textblock>
    <textblock>of an institution of higher education provides the framework for</textblock>
    <textblock>a shared responsibility among accrediting agencies, States, and</textblock>
    <textblock>the Federal government to ensure that the ``gate'' to the Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA programs is opened to only those institutions that provide</textblock>
    <textblock>students with quality education or training worth the time,</textblock>
    <textblock>energy, and money they invest in it. The three ``gatekeepers''</textblock>
    <textblock>sharing this responsibility have traditionally been referred to</textblock>
    <textblock>as ``the triad.'' While the concept of a triad of entities</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible for gatekeeping has had a long history, the triad has</textblock>
    <textblock>not always worked as effectively as it should to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>educational quality, nor has it served as an effective deterrent</textblock>
    <textblock>to abuse by institutions participating in the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs. For several years, certain institutions participating</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Title IV, HEA programs have failed to provide students</textblock>
    <textblock>with education or training of an acceptable level of quality;</textblock>
    <textblock>they have also failed to treat students fairly. In addition,</textblock>
    <textblock>they have failed to meet acceptable standards of financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility and administrative capability and to adequately</textblock>
    <textblock>protect Title IV, HEA program funds entrusted to them. The</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions that have engaged in these abusive practices are not</textblock>
    <textblock>restricted to a particular sector of higher education. Rather,</textblock>
    <textblock>the abuses have been found in all types of institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>participating in the Title IV, HEA programs, including those in</textblock>
    <textblock>the private non-profit and public sectors of higher education as</textblock>
    <textblock>well as those in the proprietary sector.</textblock>
    <textblock>At the same time, gatekeeping functions have not been</textblock>
    <textblock>carried out effectively. For example, some accrediting agencies</textblock>
    <textblock>have not taken sufficient care to ensure the quality of the</textblock>
    <textblock>education or training provided by the institutions or programs</textblock>
    <textblock>they accredit or to protect student interests when they accredit</textblock>
    <textblock>particular institutions or programs. Moreover, some States have</textblock>
    <textblock>also not taken sufficient care to ensure the quality of the</textblock>
    <textblock>education or training provided by the institutions they authorize</textblock>
    <textblock>or license to operate in the State or to protect student</textblock>
    <textblock>interests. Finally, the Federal government's management of its</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibilities to determine eligibility and to certify</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions to participate in the Title IV, HEA programs has not</textblock>
    <textblock>always been adequate to prevent abusive practices at institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>that participate in those programs.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
