<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00153</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>5. How does the new definition affect less-than-full-time students?</textblock>
    <textblock>•The definition does not affect part-time students.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•A student who completes fewer than the required minimum</textblock>
    <textblock>number of clock or credit hours during the 30-week</textblock>
    <textblock>period should be considered less-than-full-time.</textblock>
    <textblock>[San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The length of the academic year is irrelevant to</textblock>
    <textblock>determining the enrollment status of students.</textblock>
    <textblock>Enrollment status is determined by the length of time</textblock>
    <textblock>(in terms of credit or clock hours) that a student</textblock>
    <textblock>takes to complete a ``program.'' [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Eligible Program</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Effective July 1, 1993, section 481(b) and (c) of the HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>require a proprietary institution of higher education or a</textblock>
    <textblock>postsecondary vocational institution to provide an eligible</textblock>
    <textblock>program of training that prepares students for gainful employment</textblock>
    <textblock>in a recognized occupation. Section 481(e) of the HEA requires</textblock>
    <textblock>an eligible program to consist of at least 600 clock hours,</textblock>
    <textblock>16 semester hours, or 24 quarter hours offered during a minimum</textblock>
    <textblock>of 15 weeks, if the program admits students who have not</textblock>
    <textblock>completed the equivalent of an associate degree. An eligible</textblock>
    <textblock>program must consist of at least 300 clock hours, eight semester</textblock>
    <textblock>hours, or 12 quarter hours offered during a minimum of ten weeks,</textblock>
    <textblock>if the program is an undergraduate program requiring the</textblock>
    <textblock>equivalent of an associate degree for admission or if the program</textblock>
    <textblock>is a graduate or professional program.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary is required to develop regulations to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine the quality of educational programs of less than 600</textblock>
    <textblock>clock hours. Those regulations must, at a minimum, require those</textblock>
    <textblock>educational programs to have verified completion and placement</textblock>
    <textblock>rates of at least 70 percent. An educational program of more</textblock>
    <textblock>than 300 clock hours and less than 600 clock hours that meets the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's regulations qualifies for eligibility under the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Family Education Loan programs even if the educational</textblock>
    <textblock>program is not an undergraduate program requiring the equivalent</textblock>
    <textblock>of an associate degree for admission, and even if the educational</textblock>
    <textblock>program is not a graduate or professional program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issues that the community was asked to address and the</textblock>
    <textblock>community's views:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. What is the equivalent of an associates degree?</textblock>
    <textblock>•An associates degree should be a degree which meets the</textblock>
    <textblock>degree requirements of any State for an associate</textblock>
    <textblock>degree. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•An associates degree should represent the completion of</textblock>
    <textblock>any educational program that meets State licensure</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements and that equals at least the length of a</textblock>
    <textblock>typical associate degree program. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•An associates degree should represent the completion of</textblock>
    <textblock>any educational program leading to a vocational</textblock>
    <textblock>objective if the program is at least 1,800 clock hours,</textblock>
    <textblock>(60 or 48) semester hours, or (90 or 64) quarter hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The variation in credit hours depends on whether the</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiators decide to use the number of credits</textblock>
    <textblock>required to earn an associate degree or the number of</textblock>
    <textblock>credits required for completion of at least two</textblock>
    <textblock>academic years.) [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•An associates degree should represent the completion of</textblock>
    <textblock>an educational program that is at least two academic</textblock>
    <textblock>years in length. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•An associates degree should represent the completion of</textblock>
    <textblock>an educational program leading to licensure in an</textblock>
    <textblock>occupation, if a community college offers an associate</textblock>
    <textblock>degree program for that occupation. [Kansas City]</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
