<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00152</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>This appendix will not appear in the Code of Federal Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix to Preamble</textblock>
    <textblock>Subparts A and B of the Student Assistance General Provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Academic Year</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Section 481(d)(2) of the HEA provides that an ``academic year''</textblock>
    <textblock>must require a minimum of 30 weeks of instruction time in which a</textblock>
    <textblock>student is expected to complete at least 24 semester or trimester</textblock>
    <textblock>hours or 36 quarter hours at an institution that measures program</textblock>
    <textblock>length in credit hours or at least 900 clock hours at an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution that measures program length in clock hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issues that the community was asked to address and the</textblock>
    <textblock>community's views:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. How should prorations be calculated? For example, if</textblock>
    <textblock>22 weeks are offered, how does an institution determine the</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of an academic year that applies?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Prorations of an academic year in educational programs</textblock>
    <textblock>shorter than an academic year should be based solely on</textblock>
    <textblock>the number of credit or clock hours provided, without</textblock>
    <textblock>regard to the number of weeks required. Proration</textblock>
    <textblock>should not be used for educational programs of one</textblock>
    <textblock>academic year or longer. Attempts to prorate the</textblock>
    <textblock>length of an academic year using both weeks and credit</textblock>
    <textblock>or clock hours would be inconsistent and confusing,</textblock>
    <textblock>because credit or clock hours are not always evenly</textblock>
    <textblock>distributed over the calendar length of an educational</textblock>
    <textblock>program. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Prorations should be based on the minimum number of</textblock>
    <textblock>clock or credit hours that a full-time student in an</textblock>
    <textblock>eligible program is scheduled to take in an academic</textblock>
    <textblock>year. Prorations should not be based on the number of</textblock>
    <textblock>weeks in the academic year. A minority opposed</textblock>
    <textblock>inclusion of a reference to ``eligible program'' in this</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendation. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. What is a week? How should portions of a week be treated?</textblock>
    <textblock>•A week should include any week during a portion of</textblock>
    <textblock>which the educational process takes place.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•A majority of participants recommended that an</textblock>
    <textblock>instructional week be defined in terms of a fixed</textblock>
    <textblock>standard of clock hours of instruction. Thus, for</textblock>
    <textblock>example, if regulations define an instructional week as</textblock>
    <textblock>the completion of 30 clock hours, a student who</textblock>
    <textblock>completes 90 clock hours of instruction in two calendar</textblock>
    <textblock>weeks should be considered to have completed the</textblock>
    <textblock>equivalent of three instructional weeks. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•A week should be defined as a seven-day period that can</textblock>
    <textblock>begin on any day of the week. The seven-day periods</textblock>
    <textblock>continue for 30 periods of time. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•A ``week'' should be defined as either each seven-day</textblock>
    <textblock>period within an enrollment period; or each seven-day</textblock>
    <textblock>period (within an enrollment period) during which any</textblock>
    <textblock>instruction occurred. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>3. What is instructional time? Should periods provided for</textblock>
    <textblock>orientation, testing, and vacation count?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Instructional time should be measured on the basis of</textblock>
    <textblock>calendar weeks that begin on Monday and end on Sunday.</textblock>
    <textblock>Instructional time should consist of a period of</textblock>
    <textblock>continuous enrollment beginning with the first week of</textblock>
    <textblock>classes and ending with the conclusion of the period of</textblock>
    <textblock>enrollment, including any normally scheduled breaks in</textblock>
    <textblock>the academic calendar. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Instructional time should include time spent reading</textblock>
    <textblock>and taking examinations. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The interests of students, institutions, and other</textblock>
    <textblock>constituents need to be considered in determining</textblock>
    <textblock>instructional time. Some participants recommended that</textblock>
    <textblock>the determination be left to accrediting agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other participants recommended that the determination</textblock>
    <textblock>be left to the Secretary. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>4. What consideration should be given to programs with</textblock>
    <textblock>condensed class schedules, or to weekend programs?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Because instructional time should be measured on the</textblock>
    <textblock>basis of periods of continuous enrollment, special</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration for condensed schedules or weekend</textblock>
    <textblock>programs is unnecessary. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The interests of students, institutions, and other</textblock>
    <textblock>constituents need to be considered in determining how</textblock>
    <textblock>to treat condensed schedules and weekend programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Some participants recommended that the determination be</textblock>
    <textblock>left to accrediting agencies. Other participants</textblock>
    <textblock>recommended that the determination be left to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Condensed programs that include the equivalent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>workload of a regular academic-year program should be</textblock>
    <textblock>considered to meet the definition of academic year.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Atlanta]</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
