<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00140</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(C) For free-standing institutions that merge to form a</textblock>
    <textblock>new, consolidated institution, the Secretary determines the</textblock>
    <textblock>cohort default rate based on the combined number of students who</textblock>
    <textblock>enter repayment during the applicable fiscal year and the</textblock>
    <textblock>combined number of students who default during the applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>fiscal years from all of the institutions that are merging. This</textblock>
    <textblock>cohort default rate applies to the new consolidated institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) For a location of one institution that becomes a</textblock>
    <textblock>location of another institution, the Secretary determines the</textblock>
    <textblock>cohort default rate based on the combined number of students who</textblock>
    <textblock>enter repayment during the applicable fiscal year and the number</textblock>
    <textblock>of students who default during the applicable fiscal years from</textblock>
    <textblock>both of the institutions in their entirety, not limited solely to</textblock>
    <textblock>the respective locations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Fiscal year</textblock>
    <textblock>means the period from and including</textblock>
    <textblock>October 1 of a calendar year through and including September 30</textblock>
    <textblock>of the following calendar year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal SLS Program participation.</textblock>
    <textblock>An institution</textblock>
    <textblock>loses its participation in the Federal SLS Program if the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary determines that the institution's cohort default rate</textblock>
    <textblock>for the most recent fiscal year for which that rate is available</textblock>
    <textblock>is equal to or greater than 30 percent. However, the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's loss of participation does not apply to a student</textblock>
    <textblock>who is not an undergraduate student or who has received a Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>SLS loan previously for enrollment in the same educational</textblock>
    <textblock>program at the institution (except that previous receipt of a</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal SLS loan shall not qualify a student for a Federal SLS</textblock>
    <textblock>loan with respect to an extension of the duration of that</textblock>
    <textblock>educational program that was effected on or after</textblock>
    <textblock>November 8, 1989).</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1082, 1085, 1094, 1099c)</textblock>
    <textblock>12. Section 668.22 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง668.22</textblock>
    <textblock>Institutional refunds and repayments.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>General.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) An institution shall have a fair and</textblock>
    <textblock>equitable refund policy under which the institution makes a</textblock>
    <textblock>refund of unearned tuition, fees, room and board, and other</textblock>
    <textblock>charges to a student who received Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>assistance, or whose parent received a Federal PLUS loan on</textblock>
    <textblock>behalf of the student if the student_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Does not register for the period of enrollment for</textblock>
    <textblock>which the student was charged; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Withdraws, drops out, is expelled from the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>or otherwise fails to complete the program on or after his or her</textblock>
    <textblock>first day of class of the period of enrollment for which he or</textblock>
    <textblock>she was charged.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The institution shall provide a clear and conspicuous</textblock>
    <textblock>written statement containing its refund policy, including the</textblock>
    <textblock>allocation of refunds and repayments to sources of aid, together</textblock>
    <textblock>with examples of the application of this policy, to a prospective</textblock>
    <textblock>student prior to the earlier of the student's enrollment or the</textblock>
    <textblock>execution of the student's enrollment agreement. The institution</textblock>
    <textblock>shall make its policy known to currently enrolled students. The</textblock>
    <textblock>institution shall include in its statement the procedures that a</textblock>
    <textblock>student must follow to obtain a refund, but the institution shall</textblock>
    <textblock>return the portion of a refund allocable to the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs in accordance with paragraph (f) of this section whether</textblock>
    <textblock>the student follows those procedures or not. If the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>changes its refund policy, the institution shall ensure that all</textblock>
    <textblock>students are made aware of the new policy.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The institution shall publish the costs of required</textblock>
    <textblock>supplies and equipment and shall substantiate to the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>upon request that the costs are reasonably related to the cost of</textblock>
    <textblock>providing the supplies and equipment to students.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Fair and equitable refund policy.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) For purposes of</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (a) of this section, an institution's refund policy is</textblock>
    <textblock>fair and equitable if the policy provides for a refund of at</textblock>
    <textblock>least the larger of the amount provided under_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The requirements of applicable State law;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The specific refund standards established by the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's nationally recognized accrediting agency if those</textblock>
    <textblock>standards are approved by the Secretary;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>refund calculation described in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (c) of this section, for any student attending the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution for the first time whose withdrawal date is on or</textblock>
    <textblock>before the 60 percent point in time in the period of enrollment</textblock>
    <textblock>for which the student has been charged; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) For purposes of determining a refund when the</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>refund calculation under paragraph (b)(1)(iii) of this section</textblock>
    <textblock>does not apply, and no standards for refund calculations exist</textblock>
    <textblock>under paragraph (b)(1) (i) and (ii) of this section, the larger</textblock>
    <textblock>of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The specific refund standards contained in Appendix A</textblock>
    <textblock>to this part; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The institution's refund policy.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For purposes of paragraph (b)(1)(iii) of this section,</textblock>
    <textblock>``the 60 percent point in time in the period of enrollment for</textblock>
    <textblock>which the student has been charged'' is_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) In the case of an educational program that is measured</textblock>
    <textblock>in credit hours, the point in calendar time when 60 percent of</textblock>
    <textblock>the period of enrollment for which the student has been charged,</textblock>
    <textblock>as defined in paragraph (d) of this section, has elapsed; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) In the case of an educational program that is measured</textblock>
    <textblock>in clock hours, the point in time when the student completes 60</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of the clock hours scheduled for the period of enrollment</textblock>
    <textblock>for which the student is charged as defined in paragraph (d) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
