<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00033</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 22, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that the following filings have been made with the Commission:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Wisconsin Public Service Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-327-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 14, 1994, Wisconsin Public Service Corporation (the Company) of Green Bay, Wisconsin, filed a proposed Supplement No. 4 to Supplement No. 9 to the Company's Service Agreement with WPPI which relates to WPPI peak shaving for the period January 1, 1996 through October 15, 1997.</textblock>
    <textblock>WPPI is the only customer currently peak shaving under the Company's W-1 full requirements tariff. WPPI supports the filing and the proposed effective date of January 1, 1996.</textblock>
    <textblock>The filing does not change the level of the Company's rates. The Company states that it has furnished copies of the filing to WPPI, its other customers who are served under the full requirements tariff, the Michigan Public Service Commission and the Public Service Commission of Wisconsin.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 7, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Florida Power Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-961-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that the Notice of Filing issued in the above-referenced docket on February 15, 1994 is rescinded.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Florida Power Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-961-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that Florida Power Corporation (``Florida Power'') on February 8, 1994 tendered for filing a wholesale change in its full requirements, partial requirements and transmission rates.</textblock>
    <textblock>The rates filed herein reflect a pre-filing settlement agreement between the Company and its wholesale customers that have participated in the Company's recent wholesale rate proceedings. Under that agreement, the rates for all classes of service except transmission service on a 1994 test year basis will increase on March 2, 1994, in the amount of (i) $9.9 million as compared to the 1993 settlement rates pending for approval by the Commission in Docket No. ER93-299-000, or (ii) $7.6 million as compared to the existing rates to be replaced by those 1993 settlement rates. The rates for transmission service on a 1994 test year basis will decrease on March 2, 1994, in the amount of (i) $l.l millon as compared to the 1993 settlement rates pending for approval or (ii) $1.8 million as compared to the existing rates to be replaced by those 1993 settlement rates. The rates for transmission service on a 1994 test year basis will subsequently increase on May 1, 1994, in an amount of $1.0 million as compared with the March 2, 1994 level rates. The settlement rates are extended to all wholesale customers not participating in the pre-filing settlement agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Florida Power requests that the Commission waive the 60 day minimum notice requirement of the Federal Power Act to achieve the March 2, 1994 effective date for the rate changes proposed for that date for (1) the parties to the pre-filing settlement agreement, (2) customers not parties to the pre-filing settlement agreement but consenting to the pre-filing settlement procedures and (3) any other customers who do not oppose the March 2, 1994 requested effective date. Florida Power further requests that the Commission establish an effective date of April 9, 1994, 60 days from the date of the filing, for any customers who oppose the March 2, 1994 effective date. The Company further requests that the rate increases proposed for March 2, 1994, April 9, 1994, if applicable, and May 1, 1994 be permitted to become effective without suspension or, if suspended, that the suspension be for the minimum one day period.</textblock>
    <textblock>Florida Power states that it has served copies of its filing on the affected customers and the Florida Public Service Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 7, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Atlantic City Electric Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-970-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 14, 1994, Atlantic City Electric Company (ACE) tendered for filing as an initial rate under Section 205 of the Federal Power Act and part 35 of the regulations issued thereunder, an Agreement between ACE and Delmarva Power &amp; Light Company (DPL) dated February 2, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>ACE states that the Agreement sets forth the terms and conditions for the sale of short-term energy which it expects to have available for sale from time to time and the purchase of which will be economically advantageous to DPL. ACE requests that the Commission waive its standard notice period and allow this Agreement to become effective on February 14, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>ACE states that a copy of this filing has been sent to DPL and will be furnished to the New Jersey Board of Regulatory Commissioners, the Delaware Public Service Commission, the Maryland Public Service Commission, and the Virginia State Corporation Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 7, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Central Maine Power Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-972-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 15, 1994, Central Maine Power Company (CMP), tendered for filing a proposed Power Sales Tariff revision to expand the available market for transactions under the Tariff.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 7, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. West Penn Power Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-973-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 15, 1994, West Penn Power Company, tendered for filing Addenda adding new delivery points for borderline service provided to Pennsylvania Power &amp; Light Company in accordance with FERC Electric Tariff, First Revised Volume No. 1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the filing were served upon the jurisdictional customers and the Pennsylvania Public Utility Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 7, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. New England Power Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-975-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 16, 1994, New England Power Company (NEP), tendered fourteen agreements with the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority. One agreement concerns the installation and maintenance of metering equipment. The other thirteen agreements are long-term service agreements under NEP's FERC Electric Tariff, Original Volume No. 8.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 7, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard Paragraphs</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rules 211 and 214 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (18 CFR 385.211 and 18 CFR 385.214). All such motions or protests should be filed on or before the comment date. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-327-000, et al.]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Wisconsin Public Service Corporation, et al.; Electric Rate and Corporate Regulation Filings</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4469 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
