<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00144</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(2) The institution must apply the allocation policy</textblock>
    <textblock>described in paragraph (g)(1) of this section consistently to all</textblock>
    <textblock>students who have received Title IV, HEA program assistance and</textblock>
    <textblock>must conform that policy to the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) No amount of the refund or of the overpayment may be</textblock>
    <textblock>allocated to the FWS Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) No amount of overpayment may be allocated to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Stafford Loan, Federal PLUS, or Federal SLS Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The amount of the Title IV, HEA program portion of</textblock>
    <textblock>the refund allocated to the Federal Stafford Loan, Federal PLUS,</textblock>
    <textblock>and Federal SLS programs must be returned to the appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower's lender by the institution in accordance with program</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations (34 CFR part 682).</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The amount of the Title IV, HEA program portion of the</textblock>
    <textblock>refund allocated to the Title IV, HEA programs other than the</textblock>
    <textblock>FWS, Federal Stafford Loan, Federal PLUS, and Federal SLS</textblock>
    <textblock>programs must be returned to the appropriate program account or</textblock>
    <textblock>accounts by the institution within 30 days of the date that the</textblock>
    <textblock>student officially withdraws or is expelled or the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>determines that a student has unofficially withdrawn.</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) The amount of the Title IV, HEA program portion of the</textblock>
    <textblock>overpayment allocated to the Title IV, HEA programs other than</textblock>
    <textblock>the FWS, Federal Stafford Loan, Federal PLUS, and Federal SLS</textblock>
    <textblock>programs must be returned to the appropriate program account or</textblock>
    <textblock>accounts within 30 days of the date that the student repays the</textblock>
    <textblock>overpayment.</textblock>
    <textblock>(h)</textblock>
    <textblock>Financial aid.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of this section ``financial</textblock>
    <textblock>aid'' is assistance that a student has been or will be awarded</textblock>
    <textblock>(including Federal PLUS loans received on the student's behalf)</textblock>
    <textblock>from Federal; State; institutional; or other scholarship, grant,</textblock>
    <textblock>or loan programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Refund dates_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Withdrawal date.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Except as</textblock>
    <textblock>provided in paragraphs (i)(1) (ii) and (iii) of this section, a</textblock>
    <textblock>student's withdrawal date is the earlier of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The date that the student notifies an institution of</textblock>
    <textblock>the student's withdrawal, or the date of withdrawal specified by</textblock>
    <textblock>the student, whichever is later; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) If the student drops out of the institution without</textblock>
    <textblock>notifying the institution (does not withdraw officially), the</textblock>
    <textblock>last recorded date of class attendance by the student, as</textblock>
    <textblock>documented by the institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) If the student has not returned to the institution at</textblock>
    <textblock>the expiration of a leave of absence approved under paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)(2) of this section, the student's withdrawal date is the last</textblock>
    <textblock>recorded date of class attendance by the student, as documented</textblock>
    <textblock>by the institution. If the student returns to the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>after the expiration of the leave of absence but during the award</textblock>
    <textblock>year or (for the Federal Stafford Loan, Federal PLUS, and Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>SLS programs) during the period of enrollment in which the</textblock>
    <textblock>student was granted the leave of absence, the student may not</textblock>
    <textblock>receive additional Title IV, HEA program assistance for</textblock>
    <textblock>coursework that he or she has not completed.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) If the student is enrolled in an educational program</textblock>
    <textblock>that consists predominantly of correspondence courses, the</textblock>
    <textblock>student's withdrawal date is normally the date of the last lesson</textblock>
    <textblock>submitted by the student, if the student failed to submit the</textblock>
    <textblock>subsequent lesson in accordance with the schedule for lessons</textblock>
    <textblock>established by the institution. However, if the student</textblock>
    <textblock>establishes in writing, within 60 days of the date of the last</textblock>
    <textblock>lesson that he or she submitted, a desire to continue in the</textblock>
    <textblock>program and an understanding that the required lessons must be</textblock>
    <textblock>submitted on time, the institution may restore that student to</textblock>
    <textblock>``in school'' status for purposes of funds received under the Title</textblock>
    <textblock>IV, HEA programs. The institution may not grant the student more</textblock>
    <textblock>than one restoration to ``in school'' status on this basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Leaves of absence.</textblock>
    <textblock>A student who has been absent from</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution and has been granted a leave of absence by the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution, in accordance with this paragraph, is not considered</textblock>
    <textblock>to have withdrawn from the institution for purposes of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section. In any twelve-month period, an institution may grant a</textblock>
    <textblock>single leave of absence to a student provided that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The student has made a written request to be granted a</textblock>
    <textblock>leave of absence;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The leave of absence involves no additional charges by</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution to the student; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The leave of absence does not exceed_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Sixty days;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
