<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00068</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Groundfish of the Gulf of Alaska; Groundfish Fishery of the Bering Sea and Aleutian Islands Area</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>50 CFR Parts 672 and 675</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 930955-4039; I.D. 092493C]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule; technical amendment.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>NMFS implements a regulatory amendment that prohibits the retention of groundfish caught with unauthorized gear in the exclusive economic zone (EEZ) off Alaska. In addition, this action implements a technical amendment that organizes all fishing gear definitions as paragraphs under the single definition of ``authorized fishing gear''. This action is necessary to prevent fishing with unauthorized gear and associated preemption of fishing grounds and gear conflicts, and undermining prohibited species bycatch measures in the groundfish fishery. It is intended to support the goals and objectives contained in the Fishery Management Plans (FMPs) for Groundfish of the Gulf of Alaska (GOA) and the Groundfish Fishery of the Bering Sea and Aleutian Islands Area (BSAI).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 30, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the environmental assessment/regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>impact review (EA/RIR) prepared for this regulatory amendment may be obtained from the North Pacific Fishery Management Council, P.O. Box 103136, Anchorage, AK 99510, (telephone 907-271-2809).</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ellen R. Varosi, Fisheries</textblock>
    <textblock>Management Division, 907-586-7228.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>Fishing for groundfish by U.S. vessels in the EEZ of the GOA and the BSAI is managed by the Secretary of Commerce according to the FMP for Groundfish of the GOA and the FMP for the Groundfish Fishery of the BSAI. The FMPs were prepared by the North Pacific Fishery Management Council (Council) under the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act (16 U.S.C. 1801</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.) (Magnuson Act), and are implemented by regulations governing the U.S. groundfish fisheries at 50 CFR parts 672 and 675. General regulations that also pertain to U.S. fisheries are codified at 50 CFR part 620.</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulatory action amends 50 CFR 672.7 and 675.7 to prohibit the retention of groundfish caught with other than authorized fishing gear types. Authorized fishing gear are all fishing gear types currently defined at §§672.2 and 675.2.</textblock>
    <textblock>A proposed rule was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on November 12, 1993 (58 FR 59980). A complete description of, and justification for, changes to regulations that prohibit the retention of groundfish caught with other than authorized fishing gear types were discussed in the proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public comment on the proposed rule was invited through December 13, 1993. One letter opposing and one letter supporting the proposed action were received within the comment period and are summarized and responded to below in the ``Response to Comment'' section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Upon reviewing the reasons for and the comments on this action, NMFS has determined that this rule is necessary for fishery conservation and management and has approved it.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
