<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00131</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(i) The institution notifies the Secretary, in accordance</textblock>
    <textblock>with 34 CFR 600.30, that the person referenced in paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)(1) of this section exercises substantial control over the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)(A) The person repaid to the Secretary a portion of the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable liability, and the portion repaid equals or exceeds</textblock>
    <textblock>the greater of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) The total percentage of the ownership interest held in</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution or third-party servicer that owes the liability</textblock>
    <textblock>by that person or any member or members of that person's family,</textblock>
    <textblock>either alone or in combination with one another;</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) The total percentage of the ownership interest held in</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution or servicer that owes the liability that the</textblock>
    <textblock>person or any member or members of the person's family, either</textblock>
    <textblock>alone or in combination with one another, represents or</textblock>
    <textblock>represented under a voting trust, power of attorney, proxy, or</textblock>
    <textblock>similar agreement; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>) Twenty-five percent, if the person or any member of the</textblock>
    <textblock>person's family is or was a member of the board of directors,</textblock>
    <textblock>chief executive officer, or other executive officer of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution or servicer that owes the liability, or of an entity</textblock>
    <textblock>holding at least a 25 percent ownership interest in the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution that owes the liability;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The applicable liability described in paragraph (c)(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section is currently being repaid in accordance with a</textblock>
    <textblock>written agreement with the Secretary; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) The institution demonstrates why_</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) The person who exercises substantial control over the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution should nevertheless be considered to lack that</textblock>
    <textblock>control; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) The person who exercises substantial control over the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution and each member of that person's family nevertheless</textblock>
    <textblock>does not or did not exercise substantial control over the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution or servicer that owes the liability.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Documentation of financial responsibility.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary determines whether an institution is financially</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible under this section by evaluating documents submitted</textblock>
    <textblock>by the institution and information obtained from other sources,</textblock>
    <textblock>including outside sources of credit information. To enable the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary to make this determination, the institution shall</textblock>
    <textblock>submit to the Secretary for its two latest complete fiscal years,</textblock>
    <textblock>a set of financial statements of the institution, prepared in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with generally accepted accounting principles</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate to that institution as established by the American</textblock>
    <textblock>Institute of Certified Public Accountants, audited by an</textblock>
    <textblock>independent certified public accountant in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>generally accepted auditing standards, and accordingly including</textblock>
    <textblock>such tests of the institution's accounting records and such other</textblock>
    <textblock>auditing procedures that the independent auditor considered</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary in the circumstances. The Secretary may also require</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution to submit or otherwise make available the</textblock>
    <textblock>accountant's work papers. If an institution submits audited</textblock>
    <textblock>consolidated financial statements of its parent corporation for</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary to use in determining the institution's level of</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility, the consolidated financial statements</textblock>
    <textblock>must be supplemented with consolidating schedules showing the</textblock>
    <textblock>consolidation of each of the parent corporation's subsidiaries</textblock>
    <textblock>(each separate institution participating in the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs must be shown separately), intercompany eliminating</textblock>
    <textblock>entries, and derived consolidated totals. The Secretary may also</textblock>
    <textblock>require the institution to submit additional substantive</textblock>
    <textblock>information.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) An institution shall submit the documents required in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (e)(1) of this section annually within four months</textblock>
    <textblock>after the end of the institution's fiscal year, unless the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary requests a more frequent submission. Upon a showing of</textblock>
    <textblock>good cause, the Secretary may grant a filing extension to an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions and terms.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the purposes of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)(i) An</textblock>
    <textblock>ownership interest</textblock>
    <textblock>is a share of the legal or</textblock>
    <textblock>beneficial ownership or control of, or a right to share in the</textblock>
    <textblock>proceeds of the operation of, an institution, institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>parent corporation, a third-party servicer, or a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer's parent corporation;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The term</textblock>
    <textblock>ownership interest</textblock>
    <textblock>includes, but is not</textblock>
    <textblock>limited to_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) An interest as tenant in common, joint tenant, or</textblock>
    <textblock>tenant by the entireties;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) A partnership; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) An interest in a trust;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The term</textblock>
    <textblock>ownership interest</textblock>
    <textblock>does not include any</textblock>
    <textblock>share of the ownership or control of, or any right to share in</textblock>
    <textblock>the proceeds of the operation of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) A mutual fund that is regularly and publicly traded;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) An institutional investor; or</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
