<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary is proposing to add or amend the following</textblock>
    <textblock>definitions:</textblock>
    <textblock>Academic Year</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 481(d)(2) of the HEA provides a definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>academic year</textblock>
    <textblock>to be used for all the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The statute specifies that in an academic year, a full-time</textblock>
    <textblock>student is expected to complete at least twenty-four semester or</textblock>
    <textblock>trimester hours or thirty-six quarter hours at an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>that measures program length in credit hours, or at least nine</textblock>
    <textblock>hundred clock hours at an institution that measures program</textblock>
    <textblock>length in clock hours. The definition delineates not only the</textblock>
    <textblock>minimum amount of work that a full-time student enrolled in an</textblock>
    <textblock>undergraduate educational program is expected to complete during</textblock>
    <textblock>an academic year, but also the minimum period of time over which</textblock>
    <textblock>the work in any educational program must be completed.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Technical Amendments of 1993 specify that this provision</textblock>
    <textblock>is only applicable with respect to an undergraduate course of</textblock>
    <textblock>study. The Secretary expects that institutions would continue to</textblock>
    <textblock>use their own academic standards, within the framework of current</textblock>
    <textblock>program regulations, to determine the amount of work full-time</textblock>
    <textblock>graduate and professional students are expected to complete over</textblock>
    <textblock>a minimum of thirty weeks of instruction.</textblock>
    <textblock>The minimum time period specified is thirty weeks of</textblock>
    <textblock>instructional time. The Technical Amendments of 1993 further</textblock>
    <textblock>amended section 481 of the HEA definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>academic year</textblock>
    <textblock>to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide that the Secretary may reduce, for good cause on a</textblock>
    <textblock>case-by-case basis, the 30-week minimum to not less than 26 weeks</textblock>
    <textblock>of instructional time in the case of an institution of higher</textblock>
    <textblock>education that provides a 2-year or 4-year program of instruction</textblock>
    <textblock>for which it awards an associate or baccalaureate degree. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary has been unable to determine a definition of ``good</textblock>
    <textblock>cause'' that would justify using this authority. In addition, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary is concerned that regulatory standards for those</textblock>
    <textblock>reductions would encourage many institutions to seek that</textblock>
    <textblock>treatment routinely and this implementation would result in the</textblock>
    <textblock>inequitable treatment of Federal student aid recipients from</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to institution. Further, the Secretary is concerned</textblock>
    <textblock>that widespread implementation would result in increased costs to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Title IV, HEA programs. Therefore, the Secretary has not</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed specific criteria to implement this technical amendment</textblock>
    <textblock>at this time. The Secretary requests comments on a definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>``good cause'' and ways of implementing this provision through</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations that address the Secretary's concerns.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary has determined that the terms used in the</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>academic year</textblock>
    <textblock>must be clarified if the definition</textblock>
    <textblock>is to be well-understood and applied consistently. In</textblock>
    <textblock>determining what constitutes the 30-week period, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>would count the period that begins on the first day of classes</textblock>
    <textblock>and ends on the last day of classes or examinations. For</textblock>
    <textblock>example, if an institution's first day of classes begins on a</textblock>
    <textblock>Tuesday, the first week of the academic year would begin on that</textblock>
    <textblock>Tuesday and end the following Monday. The institution would not</textblock>
    <textblock>begin counting with the Sunday preceding the first day of</textblock>
    <textblock>classes.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes that, for purposes of this</textblock>
    <textblock>definition, a</textblock>
    <textblock>week</textblock>
    <textblock>would be a consecutive seven-day period, as</textblock>
    <textblock>opposed to a five-day or six-day</textblock>
    <textblock>school week</textblock>
    <textblock>or seven individual</textblock>
    <textblock>days that are spread out over more than one calendar week. This</textblock>
    <textblock>approach would facilitate counting and readily accommodate</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions that start and end on different days of the week.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of this definition, a</textblock>
    <textblock>week of instructional</textblock>
    <textblock>time</textblock>
    <textblock>would be any week in which at least one day of regularly</textblock>
    <textblock>scheduled instruction, examinations, or preparation for</textblock>
    <textblock>examination occurs. The Secretary recognizes that there may be</textblock>
    <textblock>certain weeks during an academic year during which fewer than</textblock>
    <textblock>five days of instruction occur. An institution should not be</textblock>
    <textblock>prohibited from counting those weeks in its 30-week period,</textblock>
    <textblock>provided at least one day of regularly scheduled classes occurs</textblock>
    <textblock>in each of those weeks. Further, this proposal would accommodate</textblock>
    <textblock>innovative educational programs such as those offered only on</textblock>
    <textblock>weekends or condensed schedules. At the same time, the proposal</textblock>
    <textblock>does not open the door to abuse, because regardless of the number</textblock>
    <textblock>of days of study that occur in any week, an institution must</textblock>
    <textblock>still provide enough instruction for a full-time student to be</textblock>
    <textblock>able to earn the minimum number of credit or clock hours needed</textblock>
    <textblock>to meet the definition. Finally, the Secretary would make clear</textblock>
    <textblock>that an institution cannot count, as instructional time, periods</textblock>
    <textblock>consisting purely of noninstructional activities, such as</textblock>
    <textblock>orientation, counseling, or vacations.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
