<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00167</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>4. Should the Secretary compile and maintain a list of State</textblock>
    <textblock>tuition recovery funds if that meets the requirements that permit</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution's participation in that fund to operate in lieu of</textblock>
    <textblock>its cash reserve requirements?</textblock>
    <textblock>•The Secretary should compile and maintain a list of</textblock>
    <textblock>State tuition recovery funds that meet the requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>that permit an institution's participation in that fund</textblock>
    <textblock>to operate in lieu of the cash reserve requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>[New York, San Francisco, Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>•An institution should provide the name and address of</textblock>
    <textblock>the State tuition recovery fund to confirm that they</textblock>
    <textblock>will be able to use the State tuition recovery fund to</textblock>
    <textblock>pay refunds. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>G. Section 498(d) authorizes the Secretary to establish</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures and standards relating to administrative capability,</textblock>
    <textblock>including the consideration of past performance of institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>or individuals in control of such institutions and maintenance of</textblock>
    <textblock>records.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issues that the community was asked to address and the</textblock>
    <textblock>community's views:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. What measures of past performance will be used, and what</textblock>
    <textblock>time periods should be included in the review?</textblock>
    <textblock>•No other standards of administrative capability or</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility should be considered. There</textblock>
    <textblock>is an inundation of oversight responsibility and the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements placed on institutions is sufficient.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City, San Francisco, Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>•In certain cases, institutional administrators should</textblock>
    <textblock>meet a minimum experience requirement (e.g., five years</textblock>
    <textblock>of prior experience in administration.) [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•School owners, corporate directors and officers, and</textblock>
    <textblock>the chief school administrator should be required to</textblock>
    <textblock>monitor and investigate school compliance, take</textblock>
    <textblock>whatever steps are within the person's authority to</textblock>
    <textblock>effect the correction of non-compliance, and report to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Department, the accrediting agency, and the State</textblock>
    <textblock>licensing agency any non-compliance that has not been</textblock>
    <textblock>corrected. California law requires this.</textblock>
    <textblock>[San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The current §668.14 and §668.15 should be used to</textblock>
    <textblock>measure administrative capability with the exception of</textblock>
    <textblock>the withdrawal rates. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•A minority of the group recommended that the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>look into all complaints filed against institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>with the local law enforcement authorities even though</textblock>
    <textblock>the complaint may not warrant pulling of an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's license or loss of accreditation.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The Department should look at the past two audits to</textblock>
    <textblock>see that performance reviews have corrected all the</textblock>
    <textblock>deficiencies as a basis that the institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>administratively capable. This should not be</textblock>
    <textblock>determined arbitrarily, but should be determined by a</textblock>
    <textblock>review. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Research data is needed to establish a basis for past</textblock>
    <textblock>performance. Other measures of past performance that</textblock>
    <textblock>should be used: Placement, default and withdrawal</textblock>
    <textblock>rates, past performance reviews and implementation of</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendations, personnel turnover, and</textblock>
    <textblock>faculty/student ratio. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Default rates, course completion and withdrawal rates,</textblock>
    <textblock>and job placement rates must be considered together.</textblock>
    <textblock>These should be triggers that, in certain combinations,</textblock>
    <textblock>should cause more review of administrative capability.</textblock>
    <textblock>Mitigating circumstances must be considered.</textblock>
    <textblock>[New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Standards for default rates, course completion and</textblock>
    <textblock>withdrawal rates, and job placement rates should be</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable to all institutions. No new standards</textblock>
    <textblock>should be set without historical data. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Student or consumer complaints against an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>should be taken into consideration if a pattern of</textblock>
    <textblock>legitimate complaints indicate a need for review by an</textblock>
    <textblock>outside entity. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•There should be no standard measure of an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability with respect to student or</textblock>
    <textblock>consumer complaints against an institution. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Department should review trends and the nature of</textblock>
    <textblock>complaints. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>H. Section 498(g) provides that the Secretary may certify an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's eligibility for a period not to exceed four years.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issues that the community was asked to address and the</textblock>
    <textblock>community's views:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Should the Secretary adopt rules addressing the length of a</textblock>
    <textblock>period of eligibility and if so what should these standards be?</textblock>
    <textblock>•The four-year periods of eligibility should be based on</textblock>
    <textblock>award years. [Kansas City]</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
