<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00091</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Second, the Technical Amendments of 1993 provide that an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution that is not financially responsible under the general</textblock>
    <textblock>standards of financial responsibility (except the cash reserve</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement) is financially responsible if it establishes to the</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfaction of the Secretary, with the support of a financial</textblock>
    <textblock>statement audited by an independent certified accountant with</textblock>
    <textblock>generally accepted accounting standards, that the institution has</textblock>
    <textblock>sufficient resources to ensure against the precipitous closure of</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution, including the ability to meet all of its</textblock>
    <textblock>financial obligations, including refunds of institutional charges</textblock>
    <textblock>and repayments to the Secretary for liabilities and debts</textblock>
    <textblock>incurred in programs administered by the Secretary. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary proposes to restate the statute, modifying it only to</textblock>
    <textblock>propose to require that the financial statement be submitted in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with the proposed requirements for documentation of</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility that will be discussed later.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Technical Amendments of 1993 further provide that an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution is not required to meet the general standards of</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility (except for the cash reserve</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement) if the institution is an institution that provides a</textblock>
    <textblock>2-year or 4-year educational program for which the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>awards an associate or baccalaureate degree that demonstrates to</textblock>
    <textblock>the satisfaction of the Secretary that there is not reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>doubt as to its continued solvency and ability to deliver quality</textblock>
    <textblock>educational services, it is current in its payment of all current</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities, including student refunds, repayments to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary, payroll, and payment of trade creditors and</textblock>
    <textblock>withholding taxes, and it has substantial equity in</textblock>
    <textblock>school-occupied facilities, the acquisition of which was the</textblock>
    <textblock>direct cause of its failure to meet the current operating ratio</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement. The Secretary proposes to restate the statute</textblock>
    <textblock>without modification.</textblock>
    <textblock>Documentation of Financial Responsibility</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 498(c)(4) of the HEA provides that the determination</textblock>
    <textblock>of an institution's financial responsibility be based on an</textblock>
    <textblock>audited and certified financial statement of the institution or,</textblock>
    <textblock>where appropriate, its parent corporation, conducted by a</textblock>
    <textblock>qualified independent organization or person in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>standards established by the American Institute of Certified</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Accountants. The statement must be submitted to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary when the institution is applying to begin or continue</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the Title IV, HEA programs. The statute further</textblock>
    <textblock>provides that the Secretary may require the submission of</textblock>
    <textblock>additional audits if the first submission does not establish</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance with the general standards of financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility. Although audited financial statements should be</textblock>
    <textblock>rendered in a uniform manner, there is some leeway with regards</textblock>
    <textblock>to contents of the statements. The Secretary proposes to require</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions to submit financial statements on an annual basis</textblock>
    <textblock>within four months after the end of the institution's fiscal</textblock>
    <textblock>year. The Secretary believes that four months from the end of an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's fiscal year is a sufficient period of time for an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to submit a financial statement. The Secretary also</textblock>
    <textblock>clarifies that, upon request, the institution must provide or</textblock>
    <textblock>otherwise make available the accountant's work papers in order to</textblock>
    <textblock>ensure that all information relevant to preparing an audited</textblock>
    <textblock>financial statement is readily available. Institutions are</textblock>
    <textblock>already required to provide access to such information pursuant</textblock>
    <textblock>to current ยง668.23, and the Secretary proposes to reference that</textblock>
    <textblock>access to records in this proposed section. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes that an institution may be granted a filing extension to</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution upon a showing of good cause. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>intends that this extension would be granted on an infrequent</textblock>
    <textblock>basis, as the Secretary believes it is imperative to have the</textblock>
    <textblock>financial information from the institution that most accurately</textblock>
    <textblock>reflects the current financial situation of the institution.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
