<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00046</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00023</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[PR Docket No. 93-80; DA 94-132]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Private Land Mobile Radio Services; Hawaii Public Safety Plan Amendment</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Deputy Chief, Land Mobile and Microwave Division and the Acting Chief, Spectrum Engineering Division released this Order amending the Public Safety Radio Plan for Hawaii (Region 11). As a result of accepting the amendment for the Plan for Region 11, the interests of the eligible entities within the region will be furthered.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 17, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Betty Woolford, Private Radio Bureau, Policy and Planning Branch, (202) 632-6497.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Order</textblock>
    <textblock>Adopted:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 7, 1994;</textblock>
    <textblock>Released:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 17, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Deputy Chief, Land Mobile and Microwave Division and the Acting Chief, Spectrum Engineering Division:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The Private Radio Bureau and the Office of Engineering and Technology, acting under delegated authority, accepted the Hawaii (Region 11) Public Safety Plan (Plan) on June 2, 1993, 58 FR 34049 (June 23, 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. By letter dated November 18, 1993, the Region proposed to amend its Plan. The proposed amendment would revise the current channel allotments. The Commission placed the letter on public notice for comments due on January 18, 1994, 58 FR 65712 (December 16, 1993), and received no comments.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. We have reviewed the proposed amendment to the Region 11 Plan and, having received no comments to the contrary, conclude it furthers the interests of the eligible entities within the Region.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Accordingly, it is ordered, That the Public Safety Radio Plan for Hawaii (Region 11) is amended, as set forth in the Region's letter of November 18, 1993. This Amendment is effective immediately.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Edward R. Jacobs,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Chief, Land Mobile and Microwave Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4405 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
