<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00114</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes that, notwithstanding the regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for submission of reports, if an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution has provided Federal Pell Grants in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>the Federal Pell Grant Program regulations, but has not received</textblock>
    <textblock>credit or payment for those grants, the institution may receive</textblock>
    <textblock>payment or a reduction in accountability for those grants. The</textblock>
    <textblock>institution would have to demonstrate that it qualifies for a</textblock>
    <textblock>credit or payment by means of a finding contained in an audit</textblock>
    <textblock>report as initially submitted to the Department that was</textblock>
    <textblock>conducted after December 31, 1988. The audit would have to have</textblock>
    <textblock>been timely submitted in accordance with 34 CFR 668.23(c), with</textblock>
    <textblock>respect to grants made during the period of that audit. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary specifies that, in determining whether the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>qualifies for a payment or reduction in accountability, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary would take into account any liabilities of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution arising from that audit or any other source. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary collects those liabilities by offset in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>34 CFR part 30.</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12866</textblock>
    <textblock>These proposed regulations have been reviewed in accordance</textblock>
    <textblock>with Executive Order 12866. Under the terms of the order the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary has assessed the potential costs and benefits of this</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory action.</textblock>
    <textblock>The potential costs associated with the proposed regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>are those resulting from statutory requirements and those</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by the Secretary to be necessary for administering</textblock>
    <textblock>this program effectively and efficiently. Burdens specifically</textblock>
    <textblock>associated with information collection requirements, if any, are</textblock>
    <textblock>identified and explained elsewhere in this preamble under the</textblock>
    <textblock>heading</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980.</textblock>
    <textblock>In assessing the potential costs and benefits_both</textblock>
    <textblock>quantitative and qualitative_of these proposed regulations, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary has determined that the benefits of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations justify the costs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary has also determined that this regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>action does not unduly interfere with State, local, and tribal</textblock>
    <textblock>governments in the exercise of their governmental function.</textblock>
    <textblock>To assist the Department in complying with the specific</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of Executive Order 12866, the Secretary invites</textblock>
    <textblock>comment on whether there may be further opportunities to reduce</textblock>
    <textblock>any potential costs or increase potential benefits resulting from</textblock>
    <textblock>these proposed regulations without impeding the effective and</textblock>
    <textblock>efficient administration of the program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act Certification</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary certifies that these proposed regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>would not have a significant economic impact on a substantial</textblock>
    <textblock>number of small entities. The small entities affected by these</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations are small institutions of postsecondary</textblock>
    <textblock>education. These regulations make modifications that reduce</textblock>
    <textblock>potential abuse in the Title IV, HEA programs. These changes</textblock>
    <textblock>will not impose excessive regulatory burdens or require</textblock>
    <textblock>unnecessary Federal supervision. The regulations would impose</textblock>
    <textblock>minimal requirements to ensure the proper expenditure of program</textblock>
    <textblock>funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 668.8, 668.12, 668.13, 668.14, 668.15, 668.16,</textblock>
    <textblock>668.17, 668.22, 668.23, 668.26, 690.83 and Appendix A contain</textblock>
    <textblock>information collection requirements. As required by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980, the Department of Education will</textblock>
    <textblock>submit a copy of these sections to the Office of Management and</textblock>
    <textblock>Budget (OMB) for its review. (44 U.S.C. 3504(h)).</textblock>
    <textblock>This NPRM contains provisions that would affect</textblock>
    <textblock>postsecondary institutions who wish to participate in the Title</textblock>
    <textblock>IV student financial assistance programs. Annual public</textblock>
    <textblock>reporting and recordkeeping burden contained in the collection of</textblock>
    <textblock>information proposed in these regulations is estimated to be</textblock>
    <textblock>10,488 hours, including the time for searching existing data</textblock>
    <textblock>sources, gathering and maintaining the data needed, completing</textblock>
    <textblock>and reviewing the collection of information, and submitting</textblock>
    <textblock>materials.</textblock>
    <textblock>Organizations and individuals desiring to submit comments on</textblock>
    <textblock>the information collection requirements should direct them to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, OMB, Room 3002, New</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Office Building, Washington D.C. 20503; Attention</textblock>
    <textblock>Daniel J. Chenok.</textblock>
    <textblock>Invitation to Comment</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to submit comments and</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendations regarding these proposed regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>All comments submitted in response to these proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations will be available for public inspection, during and</textblock>
    <textblock>after the comment period, in room 4318, Regional Office Building</textblock>
    <textblock>3, 7th and D Streets, SW., Washington, DC, between the hours</textblock>
    <textblock>of 8:30 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through Friday of each week</textblock>
    <textblock>except Federal holidays.</textblock>
    <textblock>Assessment of Educational Impact</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary particularly requests comments on whether the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations in this document would require transmission</textblock>
    <textblock>of information that is being gathered by or is available from any</textblock>
    <textblock>other agency or authority of the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects</textblock>
    <textblock>34 CFR Part 668</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedure, Colleges and</textblock>
    <textblock>universities, Consumer protection, Education, Grant</textblock>
    <textblock>programs_education, Loan programs_education, Reporting and</textblock>
    <textblock>recordkeeping requirements, Student aid.</textblock>
    <textblock>34 CFR Part 690</textblock>
    <textblock>Education of disadvantaged, Grant programs_education, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Student aid.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Numbers: 84.007</textblock>
    <textblock>Supplemental Educational Opportunity Grant Program; 84.032</textblock>
    <textblock>Guaranteed Student Loan Program; 84.032 PLUS Program; 84.032</textblock>
    <textblock>Supplemental Loans for Students Program; 84.033 College</textblock>
    <textblock>Work-Study Program; 84.038 Perkins Loan Program; 84.063 Pell</textblock>
    <textblock>Grant Program; 84.069 State Student Incentive Grant Program; and</textblock>
    <textblock>84.226 Income Contingent Loan Program)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 16, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard W. Riley,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of Education.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
