<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00051</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00027</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Compressed Medical Gas Industry; Notice of Public Workshops</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration, HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of public workshops.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Food and Drug Administration's (FDA's), Atlanta District Office, Center for Drug Evaluation and Research, and Office of Small Business, Scientific and Trade Affairs are sponsoring three public workshops on FDA requirements and guidelines that apply to the compressed medical gas industry. These workshops are designed to assist the industry in complying with and conforming to legal requirements or guidelines for manufacturing and repacking medical gases.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The public workshops will be held on March 21, 1994; March 23, 1994; and on March 25, 1994; 8:30 a.m. to 4 p.m.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The public workshops will be held at the following locations:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 21, 1994: Sheraton Colony Square Hotel, 188 14th St. NE., Atlanta, GA.</textblock>
    <textblock>March 23, 1994: Radisson Inn-Airport, 5991 Rivers Ave., North Charleston, SC.</textblock>
    <textblock>March 25, 1994: North Raleigh Hilton, 3415 Wake Forest Rd., Raleigh, NC.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Eric S. Weilage or Dawn Todd, Investigations Branch, Food and Drug Administration, 60 Eighth St. NE., Atlanta, GA 30309, 404-347-32l8 or FAX 404-347-l9l3, or</textblock>
    <textblock>Jeanne White or Sharon Schneider, Office of Small Business, Scientific and Trade Affairs (HF-51), Food and Drug Administration, 5600 Fishers Lane, Rockville, MD 20857, 30l-443-6776.</textblock>
    <textblock>Those persons interested in attending any of these workshops should FAX their registration by March 10, 1994, including name, firm name, address, and telephone number to 404-347-1913. There is no registration fee for these workshops, but advance registration is required. Space is limited and all interested parties are encouraged to register early.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA's inspectional history of the compressed medical gas industry shows that a high percentage of medical gas firms are unaware of applicable regulations and guidelines or are not operating in compliance with or conformance to applicable requirements or guidelines. These workshops are designed to assist the medical gas industry and are free of charge to attendees.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 17, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Michael R. Taylor,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Commissioner for Policy.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4411 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
