<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00059</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>878_Removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>881A_Use of the 25.25-27.5 GHz band by the inter-satellite service is limited to space research and Earth exploration-satellite applications, and also transmissions of data originating from industrial and medical activities in space.</textblock>
    <textblock>881B_Space services using non-geostationary satellites operating in the inter-satellite service in the band 27-27.5 GHz are exempt from the provisions of No. 2613.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>882E_The inter-satellite service shall not claim protection from harmful interference from airport surface detection equipment stations of the radionavigation service.</textblock>
    <textblock>882F_</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional allocation:</textblock>
    <textblock>in Japan, the band 24.65-25.25 GHz is also allocated to the radionavigation service on a primary basis until 2008.</textblock>
    <textblock>882G_In the band 24.75-25.25 GHz, feeder links to stations of the broadcasting-satellite service shall have priority over other users in the fixed-satellite service (Earth-to-space). Such other uses shall protect and shall not claim protection from existing and future operating feeder-link networks to such broadcasting satellite stations.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>890_Removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>891_Removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>United States (US) Footnotes</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>US319_In the 137-138, 148-149.9, 149.9-150.05, 399.9-400.05, 400.15-401, 1610-1626.5, and 2483.5-2500 MHz bands, Government stations in the mobile-satellite service shall be limited to earth stations operating with non-Government space stations.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>NG147_Stations in the broadcast auxiliary service and private radio services licensed as of July 25, 1985, or on a subsequent date following as a result of submitting an application for license on or before July 25, 1985, may continue to operate on a radiodetermination satellite service.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4409 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
