<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00158</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>IV. Annual Audits</textblock>
    <textblock>A. The Secretary is authorized to prescribe regulations for</textblock>
    <textblock>institutional and third-party servicer audits. Section</textblock>
    <textblock>487(c)(1)(A)(i) requires an annual audit of the financial</textblock>
    <textblock>condition of the institution in its entirety and an annual audit</textblock>
    <textblock>of the institution's compliance with the requirements governing</textblock>
    <textblock>the Title IV programs. The institution must make these audits</textblock>
    <textblock>available to cognizant guaranty agencies, eligible lenders, State</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies, and the State review entities designated under subpart</textblock>
    <textblock>1 of part H of Title IV of the HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issues that the community was asked to address and the</textblock>
    <textblock>community's views:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. To what extent, if any, should the annual audit requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>be waived or limited? Should this requirement for annual audits</textblock>
    <textblock>be waived for institutions participating in the Quality Assurance</textblock>
    <textblock>Program?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Annual financial audit should be waived in all</textblock>
    <textblock>instances except in the case of new institutions,</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions undergoing a change in ownership,</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions with a cohort default rate in excess of 25</textblock>
    <textblock>percent for one year, and institutions that did not</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfy all factors of financial responsibility in</textblock>
    <textblock>their most recent financial statement issued to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department. Furthermore, institutions would be required</textblock>
    <textblock>to submit no more than two consecutive annual audits</textblock>
    <textblock>before being considered released from the annual audit</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual compliance audit should be waived for all</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions except in the case of new institutions,</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions undergoing a change of ownership, and</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions which have undergone a compliance audit</textblock>
    <textblock>within the past three years which resulted in Title IV</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities in excess of one percent of Title IV funds</textblock>
    <textblock>disbursed.</textblock>
    <textblock>A further suggestion was made to truncate the audit</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements if the Secretary continues to require an</textblock>
    <textblock>annual audit. A minority of the group felt that annual</textblock>
    <textblock>audits, both financial and compliance, should be</textblock>
    <textblock>required and not waived. Those institutions that meet</textblock>
    <textblock>quality assurance criteria would be required to submit</textblock>
    <textblock>a short form audit on a biannual basis. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>•No further burden should be placed on institutions than</textblock>
    <textblock>their State already requires or than the IRS requires</textblock>
    <textblock>of them. If someone else wants the audit, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department should be responsible for distributing them.</textblock>
    <textblock>There should be diminishing filing requirements based</textblock>
    <textblock>upon performance evaluation factors and general</textblock>
    <textblock>longevity of institutions to exempt an institution from</textblock>
    <textblock>an annual audit. A minority suggested that pledged</textblock>
    <textblock>assets be accepted at some level in lieu of a certified</textblock>
    <textblock>annual audit. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The annual audit requirement could be waived in certain</textblock>
    <textblock>areas, e.g., the institution could be exempt from the</textblock>
    <textblock>student compliance components but not from a financial</textblock>
    <textblock>audit if the institution is in the quality assurance</textblock>
    <textblock>program. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The Department should develop a set of guidelines that</textblock>
    <textblock>would permit exemptions. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. How should guaranty agencies, lenders, and other parties</textblock>
    <textblock>request audit information from institutions?</textblock>
    <textblock>•An audit correction action plan should be sent to</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agencies and lenders. Requests should be in</textblock>
    <textblock>writing with explanations of why the request is made.</textblock>
    <textblock>Freedom of Information Act procedures could be used. Requests should be made to the appropriate official on</textblock>
    <textblock>campus. Information may not be given to any</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party without the approval of the institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>[San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Requests should be in writing to the Chief Executive</textblock>
    <textblock>Officer and the Chief Financial Officer. A minority of</textblock>
    <textblock>the group believed that all requests should be made in</textblock>
    <textblock>writing to the Chief Financial Officer only.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Institutions should be notified of any requests for</textblock>
    <textblock>information and when information is released to</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate agencies. The information should be</textblock>
    <textblock>released only to the parties already listed in the</textblock>
    <textblock>statute. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Information should be provided to guaranty agencies,</textblock>
    <textblock>lenders, and other parties upon request. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>B. In matters not governed by specific provisions, section</textblock>
    <textblock>487(c)(1)(B) provides for the establishment of standards of</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility and administrative capability that</textblock>
    <textblock>include any matter the Secretary deems necessary for the sound</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of the financial aid programs (such as the</textblock>
    <textblock>pertinent actions of any owner, shareholder, or person exercising</textblock>
    <textblock>control over an eligible institution.)</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
