<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00069</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00042</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Inventory Completion of Native American Human Remains and Funerary Objects From Hawaii in the Control of the U.S. Marine Corps Air Station, Kaneohe Bay</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Park Service, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given in accordance with provisions of the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act, 25 U.S.C. 3003(d), of the completion of the inventory of human remains and funerary objects from Hawaii in the control of the U.S. Marine Corps Air Station, Kaneohe Bay. The remains are curated in the Bernice Pauahi Bishop Museum, Honolulu, HI.</textblock>
    <textblock>A detailed inventory and assessment of these human remains and funerary objects has been made for the U.S. Marine Corps by the staff of the Bishop Museum, in consultation with representatives of</textblock>
    <textblock>Hui Mlama I N Kpuna 'O Hawai'i Nei</textblock>
    <textblock>and the Office of Hawaiian Affairs. The latter two organizations qualify as Native Hawaiian organizations as defined in 25 U.S.C. 3001(11).</textblock>
    <textblock>The human remains and funerary objects represent a minimum of 1582 individuals and 281 funerary objects recovered from the Mokapu Peninsula, U.S. Marine Corps Air Station, Kaneohe Bay, Island of Oahu, and curated at the Bishop Museum. The majority of the remains were recovered during archaeological excavations conducted in 1938-1940 by Gordon T. Bowles (University of Hawaii) and Kenneth P. Emory (Bishop Museum), and in 1957 by Robert N. Bowen (University of Hawaii). The rest of the remains were recovered from inadvertent discoveries and archaeological monitoring of construction activities on the peninsula.</textblock>
    <textblock>A minimum of 1,544 individuals were recovered from pre-contact (prior to 1778) graves. A number of these individuals were represented by incomplete sets of skeletal remains, and several of the isolated individuals represented secondarily deposited incomplete sets of remains removed from their original context. The pre-contact funerary objects included</textblock>
    <textblock>kupe'e</textblock>
    <textblock>(wristlets made of dog teeth), basalt flakes, marine shells,</textblock>
    <textblock>kukui</textblock>
    <textblock>(Aleurites moluccana) nuts, and the bones of fish, birds, pigs, dogs, and turtles.</textblock>
    <textblock>A minimum of 38 individuals were recovered from post-Contact (after 1778) graves during a construction project in 1975. The post-Contact funerary objects included</textblock>
    <textblock>kupe'e</textblock>
    <textblock>, and</textblock>
    <textblock>lei 'opu'u</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>lei niho</textblock>
    <textblock>(pendants made of calcite, shell, and whale bone), as well as bone and shell buttons, metal fragments, mirror glass, bottle fragments, a metal ring, ivory beads, bone and glass, metal nails, and metal parts of a smoking pipe.</textblock>
    <textblock>Based on the Bishop Museum report of the results of the inventory and assessment, officials of the U.S. Marine Corps have determined that, pursuant to 25 U.S.C. 3001 (2), there is a relationship of shared group identity which can be reasonably traced between these remains and present-day Native Hawaiian organizations. U.S. Marine Corps officials, based on the Bishop Museum report, determined that no lineal descendants of the human remains could be identified.</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice has been sent to officials of</textblock>
    <textblock>Hui Mlama I N Kpuna 'O Hawai'i Nei</textblock>
    <textblock>and the Office of Hawaiian Affairs. Representatives of any other Native Hawaiian organization which believes itself to be culturally affiliated with these human remains and funerary objects should contact Mr. John Bigay, Planner-in-Charge, Pacific Division, Naval Engineering Facilities Command, Pearl Harbor, HI, 96860-7300, (808) 471-9338, before April 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 23, 1994.</textblock>
  </action>
  <signer>
    <textblock>C. Timothy McKeown,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Departmental Consulting Archeologist,</textblock>
    <textblock>Chief, Archeological Assistance Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4491 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-70-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
