<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00026</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[I.D. 020994C]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Marine Mammals</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), NOAA, Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Issuance of scientific research permit no. 888 (P559).</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that Mr. Hiroyuki Suganuma, Ogasawara Marine Center, Byobudani, Chichijima Ogasawara-mura, Tokyo, 100-21, Japan, has been issued a permit to take humpback whales (</textblock>
    <textblock>Megaptera novaeangliae</textblock>
    <textblock>) for purposes of scientific research.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The permit and related documents are available for review upon written request or by appointment, in the following office(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>Permits Division, Office of Protected Resources, NMFS, 1315 East-West Highway, room 13130, Silver Spring, MD 20910 (301/713-2289);</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, Southwest Region, NMFS, 501 West Ocean Boulevard, suite 4200, Long Beach, CA 90802, (310/980-4016); and</textblock>
    <textblock>Marine Mammal Coordinator, Pacific Area Office, NMFS, 2570 Dole Street, room 106, Honolulu, HI 96822</textblock>
    <textblock>(808/955-8831).</textblock>
  </address>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 4, 1994, notice was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(59 FR 296) that a request for a scientific research permit to take humpback whales had been submitted by the above-named individual. The requested permit has been issued under the authority of the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972, as amended (16 U.S.C. 1361</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>), the Regulations Governing the Taking and Importing of Marine Mammals (50 CFR part 216), the Endangered Species Act of 1973, as amended (16 U.S.C. 1531</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>), and the regulations governing the taking, importing, and exporting of endangered fish and wildlife (50 CFR part 222).</textblock>
    <textblock>Issuance of this permit, as required by the Endangered Species Act of 1973, was based on a finding that such permit: (1) Was applied for in good faith; (2) will not operate to the disadvantage of the endangered species which is the subject of this permit; and (3) is consistent with the purposes and policies set forth in Section 2 of the Endangered Species Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William W. Fox, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Protected Resources,</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4445 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
