<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00083</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Amendments of 1992 require that an institution comply</textblock>
    <textblock>with the institutional refund policy established in accordance</textblock>
    <textblock>with §668.22. The Secretary considers this provision to be</textblock>
    <textblock>self-explanatory and proposes to add this statutory requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>to the regulations without substantive modifications.</textblock>
    <textblock>Finally, in addition to the statutory requirements for</textblock>
    <textblock>program participation agreements, an institution would have to</textblock>
    <textblock>agree to be liable for all improperly spent or unspent funds</textblock>
    <textblock>received under the title IV, HEA programs, including funds</textblock>
    <textblock>administered by a third-party servicer, and refunds that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution or its servicer may be required to make. This</textblock>
    <textblock>provision was proposed and discussed in the NPRM published on</textblock>
    <textblock>February 17, 1994 (in part II) that deals with third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicers.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Amendments of 1992 and the Technical Amendments of 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>amended the HEA to require that an institution that has a change</textblock>
    <textblock>in ownership resulting in a change in control reestablish</textblock>
    <textblock>institutional eligibility and undergo a certification review</textblock>
    <textblock>before it may participate in any title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, the Secretary is proposing to remove the provision in</textblock>
    <textblock>current regulations that permitted the new participation</textblock>
    <textblock>agreement of an institution that changed ownership to be</textblock>
    <textblock>effective on the date of the change of ownership. Instead, under</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed regulations, the program participation agreement of</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution that changes ownership would be effective on the</textblock>
    <textblock>date that the Secretary signs the agreement, just as any other</textblock>
    <textblock>new program participation agreement would.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to specify that a program</textblock>
    <textblock>participation agreement expires if the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation ends because: (1) The institution closes or stops</textblock>
    <textblock>providing educational programs for a reason other than a normal</textblock>
    <textblock>vacation period or a natural disaster that directly affects the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution or the institution's students; (2) the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>loses its institutional eligibility under 34 CFR part 600; (3)</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution's period of participation, as specified under</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.13, expires (that is, the four-year limit on participation,</textblock>
    <textblock>the limits on participation established pursuant to provisional</textblock>
    <textblock>certification, or shorter periods established by the Secretary),</textblock>
    <textblock>or the institution's provisional certification is revoked under</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.13; (4) the Secretary determines under §668.13(c) that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution that is applying for certification has jeopardized</textblock>
    <textblock>its ability to perform its financial responsibilities by not</textblock>
    <textblock>meeting the factors of financial responsibility under §668.15 or</textblock>
    <textblock>the standards of administrative capability under §668.16 (in the</textblock>
    <textblock>case of an institution whose participation has been limited or</textblock>
    <textblock>suspended under subpart G of this part, or voluntarily enters</textblock>
    <textblock>into provisional certification); or (5) the Secretary receives a</textblock>
    <textblock>notice from the appropriate SPRE that the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation should be withdrawn.</textblock>
    <textblock>These provisions would conform to the provisions in proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.26 governing the end of an institution's participation in a</textblock>
    <textblock>title IV, HEA program. The first of these circumstances listed</textblock>
    <textblock>above is purely a clarification of existing practice. The last</textblock>
    <textblock>three describe circumstances mandated by the change made to the</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA by the Amendments of 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.15␣Factors of Financial Responsibility</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to redesignate §668.13 as §668.15.</textblock>
    <textblock>This section includes provisions dealing with third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicers that were proposed in the NPRM published on</textblock>
    <textblock>February 17, 1994 (in part II). The Secretary will not repeat</textblock>
    <textblock>the discussion of those provisions here. However, this third-party servicer NPRM proposed to apply the general standards of</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility that are proposed in this NPRM to third-party servicers that contract with lenders or guaranty agencies</textblock>
    <textblock>to administer any aspect of the title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>General</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 487 of the HEA requires the Secretary to develop</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations to determine the financial responsibility of an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution as a part of the Secretary's determination that an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution is able to participate in a title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 498 of the HEA mandates some of the standards that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary must use in making a determination of financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility. In general, section 498 of the HEA adopted, with</textblock>
    <textblock>modifications, the standards used by the Secretary in current</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.13 of the Student Assistance General Provisions regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to require an institution to demonstrate</textblock>
    <textblock>that it is financially responsible under the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements in this section.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
