<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00129</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(3) If the Secretary or the institution terminates a</textblock>
    <textblock>program participation agreement under paragraph (g) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, the Secretary establishes the termination date.</textblock>
    <textblock>(h) An institution's program participation agreement</textblock>
    <textblock>automatically expires on the date that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The institution changes ownership that results in a</textblock>
    <textblock>change in control as determined by the Secretary under</textblock>
    <textblock>34 CFR part 600; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The institution's participation ends under the</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions of ยง668.26(a) (1), (2), (4), or (7).</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) An institution's program participation agreement no</textblock>
    <textblock>longer applies to or covers a location of the institution as of</textblock>
    <textblock>the date on which that location ceases to be a part of the</textblock>
    <textblock>participating institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1085, 1088, 1091, 1092, 1094, 1099a-3,</textblock>
    <textblock>1099c, and 1141)</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Newly redesignated ยง668.15, is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง668.15</textblock>
    <textblock>Factors of financial responsibility.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>General.</textblock>
    <textblock>To begin and to continue to participate in</textblock>
    <textblock>any Title IV, HEA program, an institution must demonstrate to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary that the institution is financially responsible under</textblock>
    <textblock>the requirements established in this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>General standards of financial responsibility.</textblock>
    <textblock>In</textblock>
    <textblock>general, the Secretary considers an institution to be financially</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible only if it_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Is able to provide the services described in its</textblock>
    <textblock>official publications and statements;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Is able to provide the administrative resources</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to comply with the requirements of this subpart;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Is able to meet all of its financial obligations,</textblock>
    <textblock>including but not limited to_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Refunds that it is required to make; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Repayments to the Secretary for liabilities and debts</textblock>
    <textblock>incurred in programs administered by the Secretary;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Is current on any debt service payments;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Maintains, at all times, a minimum cash reserve equal</textblock>
    <textblock>to at least 10 percent of the institution's total deferred</textblock>
    <textblock>tuition income at the end of the institution's most recent fiscal</textblock>
    <textblock>year for repayment of refunds. The cash reserve must be</textblock>
    <textblock>maintained in a cash reserve account, consisting of cash or cash</textblock>
    <textblock>equivalents as defined in accordance with generally accepted</textblock>
    <textblock>accounting principles;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Has not had, as part of the audit report for the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's most recently completed fiscal year_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) A statement by the accountant acknowledging substantial</textblock>
    <textblock>doubt about the institution's ability to continue operation as a</textblock>
    <textblock>going concern;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A finding of unauthorized use of donor restricted net</textblock>
    <textblock>assets to meet current operating expenses; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) A disclaimed or adverse opinion by the accountant;</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) For a for-profit institution_(i) Demonstrates at the end of its latest fiscal year, a ratio of current assets to current liabilities of at least</textblock>
    <textblock>1.25:1. For purposes of this section, the calculation of this</textblock>
    <textblock>ratio must exclude uncollateralized loans receivable from owners</textblock>
    <textblock>and related parties. Should application of paragraph (b)(5) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section cause a portion of the institution's cash reserves</textblock>
    <textblock>to be classified as a restricted asset, those cash reserves may</textblock>
    <textblock>be included in current assets in calculating the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>current ratio;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Has not had operating losses over both of its two</textblock>
    <textblock>latest fiscal years that causes an operating loss exceeding 10</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of the institution's previous year's tangible net worth</textblock>
    <textblock>for its latest fiscal year. For purposes of this subsection, an</textblock>
    <textblock>operating loss will be calculated by subtracting from total net</textblock>
    <textblock>income: extraordinary gains or losses; income or losses from</textblock>
    <textblock>discontinued operations; prior period adjustments; and, the</textblock>
    <textblock>cumulative effect of changes in accounting principle, estimate or</textblock>
    <textblock>reporting entity. The calculation of tangible net worth must</textblock>
    <textblock>exclude all assets defined as intangible in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>generally accepted accounting principles; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Had, for its latest fiscal year, a positive tangible</textblock>
    <textblock>net worth. For purposes of this section, a positive tangible net</textblock>
    <textblock>worth occurs if the institution's tangible assets exceed its</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities. The calculation of tangible net worth must exclude</textblock>
    <textblock>all assets defined as intangible in accordance with generally</textblock>
    <textblock>accepted accounting principles. In applying this standard, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary may consider the effect of extraordinary gains or</textblock>
    <textblock>losses resulting from unusual and infrequent events, and may take</textblock>
    <textblock>into consideration the cumulative effect of changes in accounting</textblock>
    <textblock>principle, estimate or reporting entity to the extent that such a</textblock>
    <textblock>change results in a more accurate representation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's financial position in accordance with generally</textblock>
    <textblock>accepted accounting principles;</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) For a nonprofit institution_(i) Prepares a classified statement of financial position in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles or provides the required information as footnotes to the audit;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Demonstrates at the end of its latest fiscal year, a</textblock>
    <textblock>ratio of current assets to current liabilities of at least 1:1;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Has not had, at the end of its latest fiscal year, a</textblock>
    <textblock>decrease in total net assets of such significance that, if</textblock>
    <textblock>continued, would result in a ratio of current assets to current</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities of less than 1:1. The Secretary may consider the</textblock>
    <textblock>effect of extraordinary gains or losses resulting from unusual</textblock>
    <textblock>and infrequent events, and may take into consideration the</textblock>
    <textblock>cumulative effect of a change in accounting principle, estimate</textblock>
    <textblock>or reporting entity to the extent that such a change results in a</textblock>
    <textblock>more accurate representation of the institution's financial</textblock>
    <textblock>position in accordance with generally accepted accounting</textblock>
    <textblock>principles. For purposes of this analysis, the Secretary may</textblock>
    <textblock>exclude unrealized gains and losses on investments that have been</textblock>
    <textblock>reported as changes in unrestricted net assets; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) For a public institution, has its liabilities backed by</textblock>
    <textblock>the full faith and credit of a State, or by an equivalent</textblock>
    <textblock>governmental entity.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
