<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00154</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>•An associates degree should be determined by the</textblock>
    <textblock>professional judgment of the Secretary. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•An associates degree should be determined by an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's State licensing agency. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•An associates degree should consist of previous</textblock>
    <textblock>training in the same field of study as that for which</textblock>
    <textblock>the eligible program prepares training. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•An associates degree should, for occupations with</textblock>
    <textblock>apprenticeship programs, require the completion of</textblock>
    <textblock>five-year apprenticeship programs. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•An associates degree should represent the completion of</textblock>
    <textblock>the equivalent of two years of successful academic work</textblock>
    <textblock>in a postsecondary environment or a professional</textblock>
    <textblock>license that required a specific period of training and</textblock>
    <textblock>perhaps work experience. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•An associates degree should represent the completion of</textblock>
    <textblock>the equivalent of at least two academic years of study,</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to compliance with applicable State laws and</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•An associates degree should represent the completion of</textblock>
    <textblock>60 semester hours or the equivalent. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. What are other measures of ``quality'' for programs of less</textblock>
    <textblock>than 600 hours?</textblock>
    <textblock>•An educational program should be considered to satisfy</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary's quality measures if a program that</textblock>
    <textblock>prepares students for State licensure in an occupation;</textblock>
    <textblock>a program that prepares students for certification by a</textblock>
    <textblock>nationally recognized professional or industry</textblock>
    <textblock>association; or a program that is approved by a</textblock>
    <textblock>nationally recognized accrediting agency or</textblock>
    <textblock>association. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•No additional measures should be included.</textblock>
    <textblock>[New York, Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>3. How should the required job placement and graduation rates</textblock>
    <textblock>be calculated? How often should the rates be calculated?</textblock>
    <textblock>•The methodology and timing for the calculations should</textblock>
    <textblock>be identical to those required under the</textblock>
    <textblock>Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Applied Technology</textblock>
    <textblock>Education Act and the Student Right-to-Know and Campus</textblock>
    <textblock>Security Act. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Calculation of completion rates should be based on the</textblock>
    <textblock>formula used under the Student Right-to-Know and Campus</textblock>
    <textblock>Security Act, except that the calculation should not</textblock>
    <textblock>include time-specific constraints. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Calculation of placement rates should be based on the</textblock>
    <textblock>formula used under the Student Right-to-Know and Campus</textblock>
    <textblock>Security Act, except that only completers should be</textblock>
    <textblock>counted in the denominator. No time frame should be</textblock>
    <textblock>used in the calculation. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Regulations should define completion rate, graduation</textblock>
    <textblock>rate, and full-time employment (which should specify a</textblock>
    <textblock>period of time in a job). [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Calculations should be based over a two-three year</textblock>
    <textblock>period to reflect long-term trends and avert the</textblock>
    <textblock>adverse impact of short-term problems such as those</textblock>
    <textblock>caused by economic conditions. Institutions that fall</textblock>
    <textblock>below the minimum rates ought to be provided appeal</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Because there are many State regulations and</textblock>
    <textblock>accrediting agency standards governing this area,</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions should be allowed to follow the most</textblock>
    <textblock>restrictive ones. Institutions following the most</textblock>
    <textblock>restrictive regulations and standards should not be</textblock>
    <textblock>required to maintain multiple sets of documentation</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrating compliance with a variety of regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>and standards. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The cohort for calculation of placement rates should</textblock>
    <textblock>include placement in jobs related to the occupation for</textblock>
    <textblock>which students are trained. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•In calculating placement rates, students should be</textblock>
    <textblock>counted as employed if they obtain jobs within 180 days</textblock>
    <textblock>of graduation. Students should be counted as employed</textblock>
    <textblock>if they obtain jobs in the field for which they were</textblock>
    <textblock>trained or a related field. Students (such as those in</textblock>
    <textblock>continuing education or in the military) who are not</textblock>
    <textblock>looking for a job should be excluded from the</textblock>
    <textblock>calculation. The calculation should be based on a</textblock>
    <textblock>percentage of graduates. Incarcerated or physically</textblock>
    <textblock>incapacitated students should be excluded from the</textblock>
    <textblock>calculation. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>4. What documentation is required to support the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>completion and job placement rates?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Documentation should be identical to that required</textblock>
    <textblock>under the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Applied</textblock>
    <textblock>Technology Education Act and the Student Right-to-Know</textblock>
    <textblock>and Campus Security Act. [Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Documentation should be any documentation required by</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution's State or accrediting agency. The</textblock>
    <textblock>rates can be verified through required compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>audits. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>Calculations should be included in the Fiscal</textblock>
    <textblock>Operations Report and Application to Participate</textblock>
    <textblock>(FISAP) for the campus-based programs. The time-frame</textblock>
    <textblock>for reporting this data should be relatively short, to</textblock>
    <textblock>ensure that the data is relevant. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•A student's placement information should be maintained</textblock>
    <textblock>in each student's file. Placement information should</textblock>
    <textblock>be available for the purposes of audits.</textblock>
    <textblock>[San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Institutions should maintain employment records on file</textblock>
    <textblock>to confirm placements. Employment records should not</textblock>
    <textblock>be submitted to the Department of Education. [Atlanta]</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
