<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00071</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(5) The institution would divide the number determined in</textblock>
    <textblock>item (4) by the total obtained under item (3) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposed methodology instructs institutions to subtract</textblock>
    <textblock>from the denominator all students who were enrolled in the</textblock>
    <textblock>program at the end of the award year without regard to any time</textblock>
    <textblock>frame established for the completion of the program. In view of</textblock>
    <textblock>the fact that the Secretary is addressing the effect of the</textblock>
    <textblock>expectation that a student complete a program in a reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>period of time on the calculation of completion rates in the</textblock>
    <textblock>forthcoming NPRM concerning the Student Right-to-Know provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>in section 485(a) of the HEA, the Secretary particularly invites</textblock>
    <textblock>comment on whether that expectation should also be considered in</textblock>
    <textblock>the calculation under this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Calculation of Placement Rate</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) An institution would determine the number of students</textblock>
    <textblock>who, during the award year, received the degree, certificate, or</textblock>
    <textblock>other recognized educational credential awarded for successfully</textblock>
    <textblock>completing the program. The Secretary believes it would not be</textblock>
    <textblock>fair or accurate to include in the placement rate calculation</textblock>
    <textblock>those students who have not yet completed the program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The institution would subtract from the number of</textblock>
    <textblock>students described in item (1) the number of those students who</textblock>
    <textblock>were employed by the institution either before or after their</textblock>
    <textblock>receipt of the degree, certificate, or other recognized</textblock>
    <textblock>educational credential. The Secretary believes that excluding</textblock>
    <textblock>employees of the institution will help curb abuse by those</textblock>
    <textblock>schools who may hire their own students in order to increase</textblock>
    <textblock>placement rates. The Secretary specifically requests comment on</textblock>
    <textblock>whether there are methods of distinguishing legitimate hiring by</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution of its graduates or students from hiring simply to</textblock>
    <textblock>improve the results of a placement rate calculation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Of the total obtained under item (2), the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>would determine the number of students who, within 180 days of</textblock>
    <textblock>the day they received their degree, certificate, or other</textblock>
    <textblock>recognized education credential, obtained gainful employment in</textblock>
    <textblock>the recognized occupation for which they were trained or in a</textblock>
    <textblock>related comparable recognized occupation and, on the date of this</textblock>
    <textblock>calculation, are employed or have been employed for at least 13</textblock>
    <textblock>weeks following receipt of the credential from the institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary believes that only students who have been</textblock>
    <textblock>placed within 180 days should be counted in the calculation. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary proposes 180 days because it is consistent with the</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum period of time that a payment on a student's loan under</textblock>
    <textblock>the FFEL loan program may be deferred. These FFEL deferments</textblock>
    <textblock>include provisions for deferments for periods of unemployment.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary considers this time frame to be adequate and</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonable, and provides ample time for an institution to place a</textblock>
    <textblock>student.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulation allows an institution to include in</textblock>
    <textblock>its placement rate a student who is placed in a recognized</textblock>
    <textblock>occupation which is comparable and related to the occupation for</textblock>
    <textblock>which the student has been trained. For instance, if a student</textblock>
    <textblock>were trained as an auto mechanic, he could be included in the</textblock>
    <textblock>placement rate calculation if he were placed as a boat mechanic.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, if a student completed a retail sales management</textblock>
    <textblock>program, he could not be included in the calculation if he were</textblock>
    <textblock>placed as a counterman at a fast food establishment.</textblock>
    <textblock>To be included in the placement rate, a student must have</textblock>
    <textblock>been employed for at least 13 weeks following graduation from the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution. The Secretary believes that this requirement will</textblock>
    <textblock>help stem abuse by institutions that may arrange to have students</textblock>
    <textblock>hired for short term jobs in order to boost placement rates. The</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed 13-week period is consistent with the period of time a</textblock>
    <textblock>student must be employed to be counted in the calculation of an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's placement rate under the procedures delineated in</textblock>
    <textblock>current ยง668.15(g) for the appeal of an institution's loss of</textblock>
    <textblock>participation due to an unacceptable cohort default rate.</textblock>
    <textblock>As stated above, for purposes of this calculation, a student</textblock>
    <textblock>has up to 180 days after he or she receives his or her degree,</textblock>
    <textblock>certificate, or other recognized education credential to obtain</textblock>
    <textblock>gainful employment and then must be employed for at least 13</textblock>
    <textblock>weeks following receipt of the credential from the institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary understands that, because of the total length of</textblock>
    <textblock>time allowed for obtaining and maintaining employment, an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's calculations may not accurately reflect placement</textblock>
    <textblock>results for programs that are offered in the latter half of the</textblock>
    <textblock>award year. The Secretary specifically requests comments on ways</textblock>
    <textblock>to address this issue.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
