<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00146</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(iii) To meet the requirements of paragraph (c)(1)(ii) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section, a third-party servicer that contracts with more</textblock>
    <textblock>than one participating institution may submit a single financial</textblock>
    <textblock>and compliance audit report that covers every aspect of the</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer's administration of the participation in the Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA programs for each institution with which the servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>contracts.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The audit required under paragraph (c)(1) (i) or (ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section shall be conducted by an independent auditor in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with the general standards and the standards for</textblock>
    <textblock>financial and compliance audits in the U.S. General Accounting</textblock>
    <textblock>Office's (GAO's) Standards for Audit of Governmental</textblock>
    <textblock>Organizations, Programs, Activities, and Functions. (This publication is available from the Superintendent of Documents, U.S. Government Printing Office, Washington, DC 20402.)</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) (i) The institution shall have an audit performed at</textblock>
    <textblock>least once every year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The servicer shall have an audit performed at least</textblock>
    <textblock>once every year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) If the institution is participating in the Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA programs for the first time, the institution shall have the</textblock>
    <textblock>audit performed at least once every year for the first five years</textblock>
    <textblock>of the institution's participation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Notwithstanding paragraph (c)(2) of this section_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The institution shall have an audit performed at least</textblock>
    <textblock>once every two years if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The institution receives less than $100,000 in total</textblock>
    <textblock>annual funding under the Title IV, HEA programs for the period</textblock>
    <textblock>covered by the audit; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The institution had no deficiencies identified in its</textblock>
    <textblock>most recently submitted audit report and that report was</textblock>
    <textblock>submitted in a timely fashion; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The servicer shall have an audit performed at least</textblock>
    <textblock>once every two years if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The servicer administers less than $1,000,000 under the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs for the period covered by the audit; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The servicer had no material exceptions identified in</textblock>
    <textblock>the servicer's most recently submitted audit report and that</textblock>
    <textblock>report was submitted in a timely fashion.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) (i) The institution is not required to have an audit</textblock>
    <textblock>performed for any year in which the institution receives less</textblock>
    <textblock>than $25,000 in total annual funding under the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The servicer is not required to have an audit</textblock>
    <textblock>performed for any year in which the servicer administers less</textblock>
    <textblock>than $250,000 under the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) (i) The institution's first audit must cover the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's activities for the entire period of time since the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution began to participate in the Title IV, HEA program for</textblock>
    <textblock>which the audit is performed. Each subsequent audit must cover</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution's activities for the entire period of time since</textblock>
    <textblock>the preceding audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The servicer's first audit must cover the servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>activities for its first full fiscal year beginning after the</textblock>
    <textblock>effective date of these regulations, and include any period from</textblock>
    <textblock>the effective date to the beginning of the first full fiscal</textblock>
    <textblock>year. Each subsequent audit that the servicer has performed must</textblock>
    <textblock>cover the servicer's activities for the entire period of time</textblock>
    <textblock>since the servicer's preceding audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Notwithstanding paragraph (c) (4) and (5) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, the Secretary may, as the Secretary deems necessary,</textblock>
    <textblock>request any institution or third-party servicer to have an audit</textblock>
    <textblock>performed on an annual basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) The institution or servicer, as applicable, shall</textblock>
    <textblock>submit its audit report to the Department of Education's</textblock>
    <textblock>Inspector General in accordance with the deadlines established in</textblock>
    <textblock>audit guides developed by the Department of Education's Office of</textblock>
    <textblock>Inspector General.</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) The Secretary may require the institution or servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>to provide, upon request, to cognizant guaranty agencies and</textblock>
    <textblock>eligible lenders under the FFEL programs, State agencies,</textblock>
    <textblock>nationally recognized accrediting agencies, and State</textblock>
    <textblock>postsecondary review entities designated under subpart 1 of part</textblock>
    <textblock>H of Title IV of the HEA, the results of any audit conducted</textblock>
    <textblock>under this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Procedures for audits are contained in audit guides</textblock>
    <textblock>developed by, and available from, the Department of Education's</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Inspector General. These audit guides do not impose</textblock>
    <textblock>any requirements beyond those imposed under applicable statutes</textblock>
    <textblock>and regulations and GAO's Standards for Audit of Governmental</textblock>
    <textblock>Organizations, Programs, Activities, and Functions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) (1) An institution, a foreign institution as defined 34</textblock>
    <textblock>CFR 600.52, or a third-party servicer that has an audit conducted</textblock>
    <textblock>in accordance with this section shall_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Give the Secretary and the Inspector General access to</textblock>
    <textblock>records or other documents necessary to review the audit; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Include in any arrangement with an individual or firm</textblock>
    <textblock>conducting an audit described in this section a requirement that</textblock>
    <textblock>the individual or firm shall give the Secretary and the Inspector</textblock>
    <textblock>General access to records or other documents necessary to review</textblock>
    <textblock>the audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A third-party servicer shall give the Secretary and the</textblock>
    <textblock>Inspector General access to records or other documents necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>to review an institution's audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) An institution shall give the Secretary and the</textblock>
    <textblock>Inspector General access to records or other documents necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>to review a third-party servicer's audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) The Secretary considers the audit requirement in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (c) of this section to be satisfied by an audit</textblock>
    <textblock>conducted in accordance with_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The Single Audit Act (Chapter 75 of title 31, United States Code); or</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
