<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00101</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Appeal Procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>The Technical Amendments of 1993 amended section 435(a) and</textblock>
    <textblock>(m) of the HEA as those sections relate to institutional appeals</textblock>
    <textblock>of cohort default rates. These amendments are not reflected in</textblock>
    <textblock>this NPRM but will be addressed separately. However, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary proposes to remove the provision that provides that an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution may appeal its loss of participation in the FFEL</textblock>
    <textblock>programs under the provisions of this section on the grounds that</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution has reduced its cohort default rate for each of</textblock>
    <textblock>the two most recent fiscal years for which the Secretary has</textblock>
    <textblock>calculated a cohort default rate for that institution by 50</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of the amount by which its cohort default rate for the</textblock>
    <textblock>previous year exceeds the applicable threshold percentage</textblock>
    <textblock>specified in this section. This provision is no longer</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable because it was limited to notices of loss of</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility that were received by an institution in the fiscal</textblock>
    <textblock>year that ended September 30, 1991.</textblock>
    <textblock>Current regulations allow an institution to appeal its loss</textblock>
    <textblock>of participation in the FFEL programs under the provisions of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section on the grounds that, for any twenty-four month</textblock>
    <textblock>period ending not more than six months prior to the date the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution submits its appeal, two-thirds or more of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's students who are enrolled on at least a half-time</textblock>
    <textblock>basis are individuals from disadvantaged economic backgrounds as</textblock>
    <textblock>established by documentary evidence submitted by the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>such as a Pell Grant Index of zero, or an AGI of less than the</textblock>
    <textblock>poverty level, as determined by criteria developed by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Health and Human Services. The Secretary proposes</textblock>
    <textblock>that the term ``such as'' be eliminated to reflect the current</textblock>
    <textblock>practice; i.e., the institution must establish the grounds for</textblock>
    <textblock>its appeal based only on the information specified in the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations. The Department would only accept the specific</textblock>
    <textblock>evidence listed in the regulations although the current</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations suggest that other evidence is acceptable. This</textblock>
    <textblock>change reflects the current practice of the Secretary. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary solicits comment on other acceptable forms of</textblock>
    <textblock>acceptable documentation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions</textblock>
    <textblock>The Student Loan Reform Act (Pub. L. 103-66) amended the</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>cohort default rate</textblock>
    <textblock>to include Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Consolidation Loans which are used to repay Federal Stafford and</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal SLS loans. The Secretary proposes to amend this section</textblock>
    <textblock>to reflect this change.</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions applicable to this section would be revised to</textblock>
    <textblock>reflect changes to the definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>cohort default rate</textblock>
    <textblock>in</textblock>
    <textblock>section 435(m) of the HEA. In accordance with the statute, as in</textblock>
    <textblock>the past, for any fiscal year in which 30 or more current and</textblock>
    <textblock>former students at the institution enter repayment on Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Stafford or Federal SLS program loans received for attendance at</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution, the cohort default rate is the percentage of</textblock>
    <textblock>those current and former students who enter repayment in that</textblock>
    <textblock>fiscal year on Federal Stafford or Federal SLS program loans</textblock>
    <textblock>received for attendance at that institution who default before</textblock>
    <textblock>the end of the following fiscal year. Formerly, for any fiscal</textblock>
    <textblock>year in which fewer than 30 of the institution's current and</textblock>
    <textblock>former students entered repayment on a Federal Stafford or</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal SLS loans received for attendance at the institution, the</textblock>
    <textblock>cohort default rate was the average over the three most recent</textblock>
    <textblock>fiscal years of the rates calculated in the manner described for</textblock>
    <textblock>any fiscal year in which 30 or more current and former students</textblock>
    <textblock>enter repayment on a Federal Stafford or Federal SLS program</textblock>
    <textblock>loan. The HEA now requires that, for any fiscal year in which</textblock>
    <textblock>fewer than 30 of the institution's current and former students</textblock>
    <textblock>enter repayment, the cohort default rate is the percentage of</textblock>
    <textblock>those current and former students who entered repayment on</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Stafford loans or Federal SLS loans in any of the three</textblock>
    <textblock>most recent fiscal years who default before the end of the fiscal</textblock>
    <textblock>year in which they entered repayment.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Technical Amendments of 1993 changed section</textblock>
    <textblock>435(m)(1)(B) of the HEA to make clear that the issue of improper</textblock>
    <textblock>loan servicing is only part of the appeal process and does not</textblock>
    <textblock>relate to the Secretary's initial release of cohort default</textblock>
    <textblock>rates. Thus, in issuing the rates initially, the Secretary is</textblock>
    <textblock>not obligated to consider allegations of improper loan servicing.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to amend the regulations to reflect this</textblock>
    <textblock>change by removing the requirement that the Secretary must</textblock>
    <textblock>exclude any loans that, due to improper servicing or collection,</textblock>
    <textblock>would result in an inaccurate or incomplete calculation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>cohort default rate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 435(m) of the HEA requires the addition of the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement that a Federal SLS loan not be considered to enter</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment until after the borrower has ceased to be enrolled in</textblock>
    <textblock>an educational program leading to a degree or certificate at the</textblock>
    <textblock>eligible institution on at least a half-time basis (as determined</textblock>
    <textblock>by the institution) and ceased to be in a period of forbearance</textblock>
    <textblock>based on that enrollment. Section 435(m) further requires that</textblock>
    <textblock>each eligible lender of a Federal SLS loan to provide the</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency with the information necessary to determine when</textblock>
    <textblock>the loan entered repayment for purposes of this definition and</textblock>
    <textblock>requires the guaranty agency to provide that information to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
