<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00068</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>It should be noted that because the statute specifies both</textblock>
    <textblock>the amount of work expected to be completed and the minimum</textblock>
    <textblock>timeframe for an academic year for use in the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs, an institution might need to prorate or adjust</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program assistance for its students. For example,</textblock>
    <textblock>if the span of time from the first scheduled class at the</textblock>
    <textblock>beginning of the school year until the last examination at the</textblock>
    <textblock>end of the school year (excluding any weeks that consist</textblock>
    <textblock>exclusively of vacation time and all other activities not</textblock>
    <textblock>directly related to instruction, preparation for examinations or</textblock>
    <textblock>examinations) is twenty-five weeks, the institution would need to</textblock>
    <textblock>make adjustments in accordance with individual program</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations. Because summer sessions generally would not be long</textblock>
    <textblock>enough to constitute the equivalent of a complete semester or</textblock>
    <textblock>quarter, as they are under various current program regulations,</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program funds awarded for summer sessions would</textblock>
    <textblock>need to be adjusted to reflect the lengths of the sessions. A</textblock>
    <textblock>comprehensive discussion of the potential effect of this new</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of academic year on Federal Pell Grant calculations</textblock>
    <textblock>may be found in the NPRM on the Federal Pell Grant Program to be</textblock>
    <textblock>published shortly.</textblock>
    <textblock>Full-Time Student</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary believes it is necessary to have a definition</textblock>
    <textblock>of</textblock>
    <textblock>full-time student</textblock>
    <textblock>that is applicable to all Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs. A definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>full-time student</textblock>
    <textblock>is needed because</textblock>
    <textblock>the definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>academic year</textblock>
    <textblock>is based, in part, on the</textblock>
    <textblock>workload of a full-time student, and because the term is used</textblock>
    <textblock>elsewhere for other purposes in part 668. The Secretary has</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed a definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>full-time student</textblock>
    <textblock>that would be based on</textblock>
    <textblock>a slightly modified definition found in the Federal Pell Grant</textblock>
    <textblock>and the campus-based program regulations. This definition also</textblock>
    <textblock>would incorporate parts of the definition of full-time student</textblock>
    <textblock>found in the FFEL program regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Generally, the Secretary proposes to define a</textblock>
    <textblock>full-time</textblock>
    <textblock>student</textblock>
    <textblock>as an enrolled student who is carrying a full-time</textblock>
    <textblock>academic workload (other than by correspondence) as determined by</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution under a standard applicable to all students</textblock>
    <textblock>enrolled in a particular educational program. In determining a</textblock>
    <textblock>student's workload, an institution would be permitted to include</textblock>
    <textblock>combinations of courses, work, research, or special studies that</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution considers sufficient to classify the student as a</textblock>
    <textblock>full-time student. Under this proposal, for an undergraduate</textblock>
    <textblock>student, an institution's minimum standard must equal or exceed:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) 12 semester hours or 12 quarter hours per academic term in</textblock>
    <textblock>an educational program using a semester, trimester, or quarter</textblock>
    <textblock>system; (2) 24 semester hours or 36 quarter hours per academic</textblock>
    <textblock>year for an educational program using credit hours but not using</textblock>
    <textblock>a semester, trimester, or quarter system (or the prorated</textblock>
    <textblock>equivalent for a program of less than one academic year); or</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) 24 clock hours per week for an educational program using</textblock>
    <textblock>clock hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>This definition also provides for a method for determining</textblock>
    <textblock>full-time status for students enrolled in an educational program</textblock>
    <textblock>using both credit and clock hours. In order to evaluate the</textblock>
    <textblock>combined workload of the student, an institution could determine</textblock>
    <textblock>full-time status based on the sum of the proportionate workload</textblock>
    <textblock>carried in terms of credit hours and the proportionate workload</textblock>
    <textblock>carried in terms of clock hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further, an undergraduate student could be considered a</textblock>
    <textblock>full-time student if he or she undertakes a series of courses or</textblock>
    <textblock>seminars that equals at least 12 semester hours or 12 quarter</textblock>
    <textblock>hours in a maximum of 18 weeks. For cooperative education</textblock>
    <textblock>programs, an undergraduate student could be considered a</textblock>
    <textblock>full-time student if the work portion of a cooperative education</textblock>
    <textblock>program in which the amount of work performed is equivalent to</textblock>
    <textblock>the academic workload of a full-time student.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary is particularly interested in establishing a</textblock>
    <textblock>minimum standard for a full-time academic workload for students</textblock>
    <textblock>who receive funds under the FFEL programs. Currently, for the</textblock>
    <textblock>purpose of those programs, an institution determines what a</textblock>
    <textblock>full-time academic workload is for these students. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>recognizes that, because no minimum requirement for an academic</textblock>
    <textblock>workload of a full-time student exists under the FFEL programs,</textblock>
    <textblock>there is the potential for abuse of FFEL program funds through</textblock>
    <textblock>the use of the definition of an academic year. For example, an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution might have educational programs that are measured in</textblock>
    <textblock>credit hours and do not use academic terms. The institution</textblock>
    <textblock>could claim that it offers a full academic year's worth of work</textblock>
    <textblock>over a thirty-week period by giving a full-time student a small</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of instruction, which the institution claims to be</textblock>
    <textblock>equivalent to 24 semester or 36 quarter hours. This situation</textblock>
    <textblock>would result in the receipt of an inordinately large amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>FFEL program funds for the amount of work actually accomplished.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary requests comments on whether, to further address</textblock>
    <textblock>this potential abuse, he should also establish a weekly minimum</textblock>
    <textblock>full-time workload for educational programs that are measured in</textblock>
    <textblock>credit hours but do not use academic terms.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
