<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00060</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Statement of Financial Accounting Standards No. 96, Accounting for Income Taxes</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>47 CFR Part 32</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[CC Docket No. 89-360, FCC 94-28]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission has adopted a Report and Order to incorporate the liability method of accounting for income taxes into the Uniform System of Accounts for Telecommunications Companies. This action brings the method of accounting for income taxes in line with the generally accepted method of accounting for income taxes prescribed for the American business community.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>August 29, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Thaddeus Machcinski, Common Carrier Bureau, Accounting and Audits Division, 202-634-1861.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a synopsis of the Commission's Report and Order in CC Docket No. 89-360, adopted January 31, 1994 and released February 8, 1994. The complete text of this Report and Order is available for inspection and copying during normal business hours in the FCC Dockets Branch (room 230), 1919 M Street NW., Washington, DC, and may also be purchased from the Commission's copy contractor, International Transcription Service, Inc., at (202) 857-3800, 2100 M Street NW., suite 140, Washington, DC 20037.</textblock>
    <textblock>Synopsis of Report and Order</textblock>
    <textblock>1. This Report and Order amends part 32 to incorporate the new accounting procedures for income taxes prescribed in Statement of Financial Accounting Standards No. 109 (SFAS-109) and it also establishes new accounts to properly implement those procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. This Report and Order adds three new accounts to the Uniform System of Accounts to incorporate the requirements of SFAS-109 into part 32. The new accounts are Account 1437, Deferred Tax Regulatory Asset; Account 4341, Net Deferred Tax Liability Adjustments; and Account 4361, Deferred Tax Regulatory Liability. These new accounts will reflect the adjustments to existing carrier deferred tax balances that are necessary as a result of adopting SFAS-109.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The type of SFAS-109 adjustments that will be shown in the above accounts relate to changes in tax rates, recording tax liabilities for items that were previously accounted for under the flow through method, and recording taxes on items that were formerly considered permanent differences by the accounting profession.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. The Report and Order will be effective six months after it is published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. However, the Report and Order permits carriers to adopt SFAS-109 for federal accounting purposes on January 1, 1993 if the carriers so desire.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Finally, the new accounts that are established in the Report and Order will be excluded from interstate rate base and revenue requirement determinations. This insures that the adoption of SFAS-109 for federal accounting purposes will not increase or decrease the interstate revenue requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule Changes</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Accordingly,</textblock>
    <textblock>it is ordered that,</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to sections 1, 4(i), 201-205, 218, 220, and 403 of the Communications Act of 1934, as amended, 47 U.S.C. 151, 154(i)201-205, 218, 220, 403, part 32 is amended as set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>7.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is further ordered that,</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 220(g) of the Communications Act of 1934, as amended, 47 U.S.C. ยง220(g) and ยง1.427(c) of the Commission's Rules, 47 CFR 1.427(c), the amendments to part 32 of the Commission's Rules, 47 CFR 32.1</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.,</textblock>
    <textblock>as set forth below, shall be effective August 29, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>8.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is further ordered that,</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 4(i) of the Communications Act of 1934, as amended, 47 U.S.C. 154(i), ยง32.16 of the Commission's rules 47 CFR 32.16 is waived to the extent that it requires the filing of a revenue requirement study in regard to SFAS-109.</textblock>
    <textblock>9.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is further ordered that,</textblock>
    <textblock>Carriers may implement SFAS-109 for federal regulatory purposes prior to the effective date of the new rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>10.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is further ordered that,</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary shall provide a copy of this Report and Order to each state utility commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 47 CFR Part 32</textblock>
    <textblock>Communications common carriers, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Telephone, Uniform System of Accounts.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William F. Caton,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 32 of title 47 of the CFR is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 32_UNIFORM SYSTEM OF ACCOUNTS FOR TELECOMMUNICATIONS COMPANIES</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 32 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
