<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00113</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to specify that an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation ends on the date that an institution's period of</textblock>
    <textblock>participation, as specified under proposed §668.13 governing</textblock>
    <textblock>certification procedures, expires, or the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>provisional certification is revoked in accordance with the</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures outlined in that proposed section. This change would</textblock>
    <textblock>be made pursuant to provisions of section 498(g) and (h) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to specify that an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the FFEL programs ends on the date that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary has determined that the institution's cohort default</textblock>
    <textblock>rate, for each of the three most recent fiscal years for which</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary has determined the institution's rate, is equal to</textblock>
    <textblock>or greater than the threshold rates listed under proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.17(c)(2). This change simply makes the provisions of</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed §668.26 consistent with those of proposed §668.17.</textblock>
    <textblock>Finally, the Secretary proposes to specify that an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation ends on the date that the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>receives a notice from the appropriate SPRE that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation should be withdrawn. This change is</textblock>
    <textblock>mandated by section 494C(h) of the HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add to the requirements for an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution when the institution's participation in a Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA program ends, that the institution shall, if the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation in the NEISP or SSIG Program ended,</textblock>
    <textblock>inform immediately the State in which the institution is located</textblock>
    <textblock>of that fact. Further, notwithstanding the requirements for the</textblock>
    <textblock>treatment of Title IV, HEA program funds found in this section,</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution must follow the instructions of that State</textblock>
    <textblock>concerning the end of that participation. The Secretary also</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes to add that if the institution's participation in all</textblock>
    <textblock>the Title IV, HEA programs end has ended, the institution must</textblock>
    <textblock>inform the Secretary of how the institution will arrange for the</textblock>
    <textblock>collection of any outstanding loans made under the National</textblock>
    <textblock>Defense/Direct Student Loan and ICL programs. These changes are</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to make the Student Assistance General Provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations consistent with specific program regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart G_Fine, Limitation, Suspension and Termination</textblock>
    <textblock>Proceedings</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.81␣Scope and Special Definitions</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to make technical changes to this</textblock>
    <textblock>section consistent with changes proposed throughout these</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations. The Secretary proposes to clarify in this</textblock>
    <textblock>section that the procedures under this section do not apply in</textblock>
    <textblock>the case of an institution that fails to qualify for provisional</textblock>
    <textblock>certification because the institution does not meet the factors</textblock>
    <textblock>of financial responsibility. In addition, the procedures under</textblock>
    <textblock>this section would not apply in the case of an institution where</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution's period of provisional certification has</textblock>
    <textblock>expired, nor would they apply in the case of an institution that</textblock>
    <textblock>has its provisional certification revoked. These changes are</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to make the scope of Subpart G of these regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>consistent with provisions in section 498(g) and (h) of the HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 690.83␣Submission of Reports</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 487(c)(7) of the HEA provides that, if, in the</textblock>
    <textblock>course of any audit conducted after December 31, 1988 pursuant to</textblock>
    <textblock>the audit requirements of section 487(c) of the HEA and</textblock>
    <textblock>Department regulations implementing those requirements, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department discovers or is informed of any Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>assistance (specifically, Federal Pell Grant Program funds) that</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution has provided to its students in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>program requirements, but the institution has not previously</textblock>
    <textblock>received credit or reimbursement for these disbursements, the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution may offset the amount of those disbursements against</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities owed under the audit, or if no liabilities arise from</textblock>
    <textblock>the audit, may receive reimbursement from the Department for</textblock>
    <textblock>those amounts.</textblock>
    <textblock>The HEA requires that the development of NPRMs for</textblock>
    <textblock>implementation of changes made by the Amendments to Parts B</textblock>
    <textblock>(Federal Family Education Loan programs), G (general provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>relating to the student assistance programs) or H (Program</textblock>
    <textblock>Integrity Triad) of Title IV of the HEA, is subject to the</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiated rulemaking process. Although this provision relates</textblock>
    <textblock>directly to the Federal Pell Grant Program, it is contained in</textblock>
    <textblock>Part G of the HEA. Therefore, it has been included in this NPRM</textblock>
    <textblock>instead of the Federal Pell Grant Program NPRM, which was not</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to the negotiated rulemaking process.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
