<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00066</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Under new section 492 of the HEA, these proposed changes are</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to the negotiated rulemaking process, which includes a</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement for the Secretary to convene regional meetings to</textblock>
    <textblock>obtain public involvement in the development of proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations. Accordingly, issues related to these proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>changes were discussed in meetings held in September 1992 in New</textblock>
    <textblock>York City; San Francisco; Atlanta; and Kansas City, Missouri. At</textblock>
    <textblock>these meetings, the Secretary provided the attendees with a list</textblock>
    <textblock>of issues to be addressed in these proposed regulations. A</textblock>
    <textblock>summary of the responses of the attendees is contained in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Appendix to this preamble.</textblock>
    <textblock>Groups that attended the regional meetings nominated</textblock>
    <textblock>individuals to participate in the regulation negotiations. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary selected regulation negotiators from the names</textblock>
    <textblock>nominated and chose negotiators to reflect all the groups that</textblock>
    <textblock>participate in the Title IV, HEA programs, such as students,</textblock>
    <textblock>student financial aid administrators, and various types of</textblock>
    <textblock>eligible institutions.</textblock>
    <textblock>These proposed regulations also address statutory changes</textblock>
    <textblock>required by the Higher Education Technical Amendments of 1993,</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Law 103-208 (the Technical Amendments of 1993). Those areas</textblock>
    <textblock>affected by the Technical Amendments of 1993 are identified in</textblock>
    <textblock>the discussion of regulatory changes. The Secretary notes that</textblock>
    <textblock>the statutory changes required by the Technical Amendments of</textblock>
    <textblock>1993 are not subject to the negotiated rulemaking process of</textblock>
    <textblock>section 492 of the HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Changes</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 492(b) of the HEA, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>prepared draft proposed regulations and negotiated the provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>of that draft with negotiators. The great majority of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed changes do not reflect consensus reached at the</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiations (as consensus was rarely obtained). The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>has identified in the discussion of changes the areas where</textblock>
    <textblock>consensus was reached.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following discussion reflects proposed significant</textblock>
    <textblock>changes to the existing Student Assistance General Provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations and the Federal Pell Grant Program regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed changes are discussed in the order in which they appear</textblock>
    <textblock>in the proposed regulatory text. If a provision applied to more</textblock>
    <textblock>than one section or is included in more than one section, it is</textblock>
    <textblock>discussed the first time it appears with an appropriate reference</textblock>
    <textblock>to its other appearances.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart A_General</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.1␣Scope</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to revise this section to remove</textblock>
    <textblock>vocational school from the list of what the term institution</textblock>
    <textblock>includes, because vocational schools are no longer eligible</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions under the HEA. The Secretary proposes to revise</textblock>
    <textblock>this section to reflect a listing of currently existing Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA programs that would be subject to part 668. Programs added</textblock>
    <textblock>to the list would include the National Early Intervention</textblock>
    <textblock>Scholarship and Partnership, Presidential Access Scholarship, and</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Direct Student Loan programs. The Income Contingent Loan</textblock>
    <textblock>Program, which no longer exists, would be removed from the list.</textblock>
    <textblock>These revisions reflect statutory changes made to the HEA by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendments of 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.2␣General Definitions</textblock>
    <textblock>This section includes definitions proposed in NPRMs</textblock>
    <textblock>published on October 4, 1993 (58 FR 51716), and on February 17,</textblock>
    <textblock>1994 (in part II) (59 FR 8044). Those definitions are:</textblock>
    <textblock>designated department</textblock>
    <textblock>official, initiating official, output document, show-cause</textblock>
    <textblock>official,</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary will not</textblock>
    <textblock>repeat the discussion of those definitions here.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to remove the definitions of</textblock>
    <textblock>Award</textblock>
    <textblock>year, Regular student,</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>State,</textblock>
    <textblock>because they would be included</textblock>
    <textblock>in 34 CFR part 600, governing institutional eligibility under the</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA. The Secretary proposed to move these definitions to 34 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 600 in the NPRM published on February 10, 1994 (59 FR 6446).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary is proposing technical changes to clarify the</textblock>
    <textblock>definitions of the current Title IV, HEA programs and to add</textblock>
    <textblock>definitions of the newly authorized Title IV, HEA programs to</textblock>
    <textblock>conform with statutory changes and for consistency with</textblock>
    <textblock>terminology used in the individual program regulations. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary also proposes to make technical changes in the</textblock>
    <textblock>definitions of</textblock>
    <textblock>Independent student,</textblock>
    <textblock>to reflect statutory changes,</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>Enrolled, Valid student aid report,</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>Valid institutional</textblock>
    <textblock>student information report</textblock>
    <textblock>for consistency with other program</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations. The Secretary would move the definition of</textblock>
    <textblock>Participating institution</textblock>
    <textblock>from §668.81 to this section.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
