<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00141</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(3) The institution must determine which policy under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (b)(1) of this section provides for the largest refund</textblock>
    <textblock>to that student.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Pro rata refund.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Pro rata refund,</textblock>
    <textblock>as used in</textblock>
    <textblock>this section, means a refund by an institution to a student</textblock>
    <textblock>attending that institution for the first time of not less than</textblock>
    <textblock>that portion of the tuition, fees, room, board, and other charges</textblock>
    <textblock>assessed the student by the institution equal to the portion of</textblock>
    <textblock>the period of enrollment for which the student has been charged</textblock>
    <textblock>that remains on the withdrawal date, rounded downward to the</textblock>
    <textblock>nearest 10 percent of that period, less_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) (A) Any unpaid amount of a scheduled cash payment for</textblock>
    <textblock>the period of enrollment for which the student has been charged.</textblock>
    <textblock>A scheduled cash payment is the amount of institutional charges</textblock>
    <textblock>that is not paid for by financial aid for the period of</textblock>
    <textblock>enrollment for which the student has been charged exclusive of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) Any amount scheduled to be paid by Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program assistance that the student has been awarded that is</textblock>
    <textblock>payable to the student even though the student has withdrawn; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) Late disbursements of loans made under the Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Stafford Loan, Federal SLS, and Federal PLUS programs in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with 34 CFR 682.207(d).</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The unpaid amount of a scheduled cash payment is</textblock>
    <textblock>computed by subtracting the amount paid by the student for the</textblock>
    <textblock>period of enrollment for which the student has been charged from</textblock>
    <textblock>the scheduled cash payment for the period of enrollment for which</textblock>
    <textblock>the student has been charged;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A reasonable administrative fee not to exceed the</textblock>
    <textblock>lesser of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Five percent of the tuition, fees, room and board, and</textblock>
    <textblock>other charges assessed the student; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) One hundred dollars;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Any application fee charged by the institution; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The portion of ``board'' charges (i.e., meal tickets)</textblock>
    <textblock>that have been expended by the student that exceed the portion</textblock>
    <textblock>attributable to the period for which the student attended at the</textblock>
    <textblock>time of withdrawal. The institution must include in the refund</textblock>
    <textblock>any unexpended ``board'' credits.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) (i) For purposes of this section, ``other charges</textblock>
    <textblock>assessed the student by the institution'' include, but are not</textblock>
    <textblock>limited to, charges for any equipment (including books and</textblock>
    <textblock>supplies) issued by an institution to the student. The</textblock>
    <textblock>institution may deduct from the refund owed under this paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>the documented cost to the institution of equipment issued to the</textblock>
    <textblock>student if the institution specifies in the enrollment agreement</textblock>
    <textblock>a separate charge for equipment which the student actually</textblock>
    <textblock>obtains or if the institution refers the student to a vendor</textblock>
    <textblock>operated by an affiliated or related entity and the student does</textblock>
    <textblock>not return the equipment in good condition, allowing for</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonable wear and tear, within 20 days following the date of</textblock>
    <textblock>the student's withdrawal. The student shall be liable for the</textblock>
    <textblock>amount, if any, by which the documented cost for equipment not</textblock>
    <textblock>returned in good condition exceeds the refund under this</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph. Equipment is not considered to be returned in good</textblock>
    <textblock>condition if the equipment cannot be reused because of clearly</textblock>
    <textblock>recognized health and sanitary reasons, and this fact is clearly</textblock>
    <textblock>and conspicuously disclosed in the enrollment agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) An institution may not delay its payment of the</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of a refund allocable under this section to a Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA program or a lender under 34 CFR 682.607 by reason of the</textblock>
    <textblock>process for return of equipment prescribed in paragraph (c)(4)(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) For purposes of this section_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) ``Room'' charges do not include charges that are passed</textblock>
    <textblock>through the institution from an entity that is not under the</textblock>
    <textblock>control of, related to, or affiliated with the institution; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) ``Other charges assessed the student by the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution'' do not include fees for group health insurance, if</textblock>
    <textblock>this insurance is required for all students and the purchased</textblock>
    <textblock>coverage remains in effect for the student throughout the period</textblock>
    <textblock>for which the student was charged.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) (i) For purposes of this section, a student attending an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution for the first time is a student who_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Has not previously attended at least one class at the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Received a refund of 100 percent of his or her tuition</textblock>
    <textblock>and fees (less any permitted administrative fee) under the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's refund policy for previous attendance at the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A student remains a first-time student until the</textblock>
    <textblock>student either_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Withdraws, drops out, or is expelled from the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution after attending at least one class; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Completes the period of enrollment for which he or she</textblock>
    <textblock>has been charged.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
