<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00125</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Revocation of provisional certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) If,</textblock>
    <textblock>before the expiration of a provisionally certified institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>period of participation in a Title IV, HEA program, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>determines that the institution is unable to meet its</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibilities under its program participation agreement, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary may revoke the institution's provisional certification</textblock>
    <textblock>for participation in that program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)(i) If the Secretary revokes the provisional</textblock>
    <textblock>certification of an institution under paragraph (e)(1) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, the Secretary sends the institution a notice by</textblock>
    <textblock>registered mail, return receipt requested. The Secretary also</textblock>
    <textblock>may transmit the notice by other, more expeditious means, if</textblock>
    <textblock>practical.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The revocation takes effect on the date that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary mails the notice to the institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The notice states the basis for the revocation, the</textblock>
    <textblock>consequences of the revocation to the institution, and that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution may request the Secretary to reconsider the</textblock>
    <textblock>revocation. The consequences of a revocation are described in</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง668.26.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)(i) An institution may request reconsideration of a</textblock>
    <textblock>revocation under this section by submitting to the Secretary,</textblock>
    <textblock>within 20 days of the institution's receipt of the Secretary's</textblock>
    <textblock>notice, written evidence that the revocation is unwarranted. The</textblock>
    <textblock>institution must file the request with the Secretary by</textblock>
    <textblock>hand-delivery, mail, or facsimile transmission.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The filing date of the request is the date on which</textblock>
    <textblock>the request is_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Hand-delivered;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Mailed; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Sent by facsimile transmission.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Documents filed by facsimile transmission must be</textblock>
    <textblock>transmitted to the Secretary in accordance with instructions</textblock>
    <textblock>provided by the Secretary in the notice of revocation. An</textblock>
    <textblock>institution filing by facsimile transmission is responsible for</textblock>
    <textblock>confirming that a complete and legible copy of the document was</textblock>
    <textblock>received by the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The Secretary discourages the use of facsimile</textblock>
    <textblock>transmission for documents longer than five pages.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)(i) The Secretary promptly considers an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>request for reconsideration of a revocation and notifies the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution, by registered mail, return receipt requested, of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's final decision. The Secretary also may transmit the</textblock>
    <textblock>notice by other, more expeditious means, if practical.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) If the Secretary determines that the revocation is</textblock>
    <textblock>warranted, the Secretary's notice informs the institution that</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution may apply for reinstatement of participation only</textblock>
    <textblock>after the later of the expiration of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Eighteen months after the effective date of the revocation; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) A debarment or suspension of the institution under</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12549 or the Federal Acquisition Regulations,</textblock>
    <textblock>48 CFR part 9, subpart 9.4.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) If the Secretary determines that the revocation of</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution's provisional certification is unwarranted, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's notice informs the institution that the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>provisional certification is reinstated, effective on the date</textblock>
    <textblock>that the Secretary's original revocation notice was mailed, for a</textblock>
    <textblock>specified period of time.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)(i) The mailing date of a notice of revocation or a</textblock>
    <textblock>request for reconsideration of a revocation is the date evidenced</textblock>
    <textblock>on the original receipt of mailing from the U.S. Postal Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The date on which a request for reconsideration of a</textblock>
    <textblock>revocation is submitted is_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) If the request was sent by a delivery service other</textblock>
    <textblock>than the U.S. Postal Service, the date evidenced on the original</textblock>
    <textblock>receipt by that service; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) If the request was sent by facsimile transmission, the</textblock>
    <textblock>date that the document is recorded as received by facsimile</textblock>
    <textblock>equipment that receives the transmission.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1099c and E.O. 12549 (3 CFR, 1986 Comp.,</textblock>
    <textblock>p. 189) and 12689 (3 CFR, 1989 comp., p.235)</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Newly designated ยง668.14 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
