<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00005</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>A-549-801, A-412-801]</textblock>
    <textblock>Antifriction Bearings (Other Than Tapered Roller Bearings)</textblock>
    <textblock>and Parts Thereof From France, Germany, Italy, Japan,</textblock>
    <textblock>Singapore, Sweden, Thailand, and the United Kingdom;</textblock>
    <textblock>Preliminary Results of Antidumping Duty</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative Reviews, Partial Termination of</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative Reviews, and Notice of Intent</textblock>
    <textblock>To Revoke Orders (in Part)</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>International Trade Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[A-427-801, A-428-801, A-475-801, A-588-804, A-559-801, A-401-801</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>International Trade Administration/Import Administration, Department of Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of preliminary results of antidumping duty administrative reviews, partial termination of administrative reviews, and notice of intent to revoke order (in part).</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In response to requests from interested parties, the Department of Commerce has conducted administrative reviews of the antidumping duty orders on antifriction bearings (other than tapered roller bearings) and parts thereof from France, Germany, Italy, Japan, Singapore, Sweden, Thailand, and the United Kingdom. The classes or kinds of merchandise covered by these orders are ball bearings, cylindrical roller bearings, and spherical plain bearings. The reviews cover 38 manufacturers/exporters and the period May 1, 1992, through April 30, 1993 (the POR). Although we initiated reviews for nine other manufacturers/exporters, we are terminating the reviews because the requests for these reviews were withdrawn in a timely manner. As a result of these reviews, the Department has preliminarily determined the weighted-average dumping margins for the reviewed firms to range from 0.37 percent to 132.25 percent for BBs, from zero to 51.82 percent for CRBs, and from zero to 92.00 percent for SPBs.</textblock>
    <textblock>We invite interested parties to comment on these preliminary results.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>The appropriate case analyst, for the various respondent firms listed below, at the Office of Antidumping Compliance, International Trade Administration, U.S. Department of Commerce, Washington, DC 20230; Telephone: (202) 482-4733.</textblock>
    <textblock>France</textblock>
    <textblock>Jacqueline Arrowsmith (SNR), Kris Campbell (SNFA), Joseph Hanley (SKF, Rollix Defontaine), David Levy (Hoesch Rothe Erde), Philip Marchal (Franke &amp; Heydrich), or Michael Rill.</textblock>
    <textblock>Germany</textblock>
    <textblock>Kris Campbell (FAG), Joseph Hanley (Rollix Defontaine), David Levy (NTN Kugellagerfabrik, INA, Hoesch Rothe Erde), Philip Marchal (SKF, Franke &amp; Heydrich), Charles Riggle (Fichtel &amp; Sachs, GMN), or Michael Rill.</textblock>
    <textblock>Italy</textblock>
    <textblock>Charles Riggle (Meter), Joseph Hanley (SKF, FAG), or Michael Rill.</textblock>
    <textblock>Japan</textblock>
    <textblock>Carlo Cavagna (Honda, Nachi), William Czajkowski (Takeshita), Michael Diminich (NSK), J. David Dirstine (Koyo), Joseph Fargo (Nankai Seiko), David Levy (NTN), Michael Panfeld (IKS, NPBS), or Richard Rimlinger.</textblock>
    <textblock>Singapore</textblock>
    <textblock>Joanna Schlesinger (NMB/Pelmec), or Richard Rimlinger.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sweden</textblock>
    <textblock>Philip Marchal (SKF), or Michael Rill.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thailand</textblock>
    <textblock>Joanna Schlesinger (NMB/Pelmec), or Richard Rimlinger.</textblock>
    <textblock>United Kingdom</textblock>
    <textblock>Jacqueline Arrowsmith (RHP/NSK), Kris Campbell (Barden/FAG), or Michael Rill.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On May 15, 1989, the Department of Commerce (the Department) published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(54 FR 20909) the antidumping duty orders on ball bearings (BBs), cylindrical roller bearings (CRBs) and spherical plain bearings (SPBs) and parts thereof from France, Germany, Italy, Japan, Singapore, Sweden, Thailand and the United Kingdom.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
