<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00163</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Issues that the community was asked to address and the</textblock>
    <textblock>community's views:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. What information should the Secretary require on the form to</textblock>
    <textblock>supplement the specific information required by the statute?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Information should include documentation of an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's accreditation or preaccreditation,</textblock>
    <textblock>degree-granting authority, authority to provide</textblock>
    <textblock>postsecondary education, and State licensure.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•With one exception, participants were satisfied that</textblock>
    <textblock>information currently collected on the Department's</textblock>
    <textblock>application forms is adequate, and new requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>would needlessly add burden. One participant</textblock>
    <textblock>recommended a separate application for proprietary</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Specific categories should be established for different</textblock>
    <textblock>types of institutions and academic functions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Information should include the names and social</textblock>
    <textblock>security numbers of key administrative personnel and</textblock>
    <textblock>board members. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Provided that new information required by statute is</textblock>
    <textblock>collected (financial statements, description of student</textblock>
    <textblock>aid processing at the institution, information on main</textblock>
    <textblock>and branch campuses, and information on the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's third-party servicers), information</textblock>
    <textblock>currently collected is sufficient. However, additional</textblock>
    <textblock>information should be collected on whether an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's owner has had substantial control over a</textblock>
    <textblock>closed institution that owes refunds to students or</textblock>
    <textblock>lenders. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Should the Audit Guide be revised to require the auditor to</textblock>
    <textblock>verify the information on the application form?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Participants recommended no changes in the audit guide.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City, New York, San Francisco, Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>•A minority of participants indicated that there should</textblock>
    <textblock>be changes, without specifying what changes are needed.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Section 498(c)(1) addresses financial responsibilities and</textblock>
    <textblock>requires an institution to show that it is able to provide</textblock>
    <textblock>promised services, to provide administrative resources necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>to Title IV duties, and the meet all of its financial obligations</textblock>
    <textblock>including refunds and repayments to the Secretary for Title IV</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issues that the community was asked to address and the</textblock>
    <textblock>community's views:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. What information should be required from an institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>permit the Secretary to determine that the institution provides</textblock>
    <textblock>the services described in its official publications and</textblock>
    <textblock>statements?</textblock>
    <textblock>•No additional information needs to be collected from</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions. [Kansas City, San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•If the Secretary needs additional information, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary should be able to collect it from data made</textblock>
    <textblock>available through State and accrediting functions.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City, New York, Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The best way to obtain information would be through</textblock>
    <textblock>site visits. [New York, Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The Department needs to take action on institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>with failing financial statements, rather than simply</textblock>
    <textblock>collect them. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The establishment of uniform financial standards would</textblock>
    <textblock>be difficult, because different standards need to apply</textblock>
    <textblock>to different types of institutions. [New York]</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
