<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00132</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(C) A profit-sharing plan, provided that all employees are covered by the plan;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The Secretary generally considers a person to exercise</textblock>
    <textblock>substantial control over an institution or third-party servicer,</textblock>
    <textblock>if the person_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Directly or indirectly holds at least a 25 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>ownership interest in the institution or servicer;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Holds, together with other members of his or her</textblock>
    <textblock>family, at least a 25 percent ownership interest in the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution or servicer;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Represents, either alone or together with other</textblock>
    <textblock>persons, under a voting trust, power of attorney, proxy, or</textblock>
    <textblock>similar agreement one or more persons who hold, either</textblock>
    <textblock>individually or in combination with the other persons represented</textblock>
    <textblock>or the person representing them, at least a 25 percent ownership</textblock>
    <textblock>in the institution or servicer; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Is a member of the board of directors, the chief</textblock>
    <textblock>executive officer, or other executive officer of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The institution or servicer; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) An entity that holds at least a 25 percent ownership</textblock>
    <textblock>interest in the institution or servicer; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The Secretary considers a member of a person's family</textblock>
    <textblock>to be a parent, sibling, spouse, child, spouse's parent or</textblock>
    <textblock>sibling, or sibling's or child's spouse.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1094 and 1099c and Section 4 of</textblock>
    <textblock>Pub. L. 95-452, 92 Stat. 1101-1109)</textblock>
    <textblock>10. Newly designated ยง668.16 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง668.16</textblock>
    <textblock>Standards of administrative capability.</textblock>
    <textblock>To begin and to continue to participate in any Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program, an institution shall demonstrate to the Secretary that</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution is capable of adequately administering that</textblock>
    <textblock>program under each of the standards established in this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary considers an institution to have that</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability if the institution_</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Administers the Title IV, HEA programs in accordance</textblock>
    <textblock>with any statutory provisions of or applicable to Title IV of the</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA, any regulatory provisions prescribed under that statutory</textblock>
    <textblock>authority, or any applicable special arrangement, agreement or</textblock>
    <textblock>limitation;</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)(1) Designates a capable individual to be responsible</textblock>
    <textblock>for administering all the Title IV, HEA programs in which it</textblock>
    <textblock>participates and for coordinating those programs with the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's other Federal and non-Federal programs of student</textblock>
    <textblock>financial assistance. The Secretary considers an individual to</textblock>
    <textblock>be ``capable'' under this paragraph if the individual is certified</textblock>
    <textblock>by the State in which the institution is located, if the State</textblock>
    <textblock>requires certification of financial aid administrators. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary may consider other factors in determining whether an</textblock>
    <textblock>individual is capable, including, but not limited to, the</textblock>
    <textblock>individual's successful completion of Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>training provided or approved by the Secretary;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Uses an adequate number of qualified persons to</textblock>
    <textblock>administer the Title IV, HEA programs in which the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>participates. The Secretary considers the following factors to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine whether an institution uses an adequate number of</textblock>
    <textblock>qualified persons_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The number and types of programs in which the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution participates;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The number of applications evaluated;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The number of students who receive any student</textblock>
    <textblock>financial assistance at the institution and the amount of funds</textblock>
    <textblock>administered;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The financial aid delivery system used by the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) The degree of office automation used by the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>in the administration of the Title IV, HEA programs;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Communicates to the individual designated to be</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible for administering Title IV, HEA programs, all the</textblock>
    <textblock>information received by any institutional office that bears on a</textblock>
    <textblock>student's eligibility for Title IV, HEA program assistance; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Has written procedures for or written information</textblock>
    <textblock>indicating_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The nature and frequency of communication of pertinent</textblock>
    <textblock>information among all the offices that have an impact on the</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of the Title IV, HEA programs. Examples of this</textblock>
    <textblock>information may include information on a student's admissions</textblock>
    <textblock>status, enrollment status, attendance (if applicable), prior or</textblock>
    <textblock>concurrent attendance at another postsecondary institution,</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfactory academic progress, and payment or disbursement</textblock>
    <textblock>status; and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
