<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00090</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Past Performance of an Institution or Persons Affiliated With An Institution</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to remove from the factors of</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility the provisions in current ยง668.13 (c)(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>and (d)(2) governing the effect on an institution's financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility of criminal conduct and fraud involving Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>funds. Those provisions have been superseded by a similar</textblock>
    <textblock>statutory provision that is addressed in the discussion on</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed ยง668.14 governing program participation agreements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under proposed ยง668.15(c)(2), an institution would not be</textblock>
    <textblock>considered financially responsible, despite meeting all other</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of this proposed section, if: (1) The institution</textblock>
    <textblock>has been limited, suspended, terminated, or entered into a</textblock>
    <textblock>settlement agreement, to resolve such an action by the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>or a guaranty agency within the preceding five years; (2) the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution had an audit finding during its two most recent</textblock>
    <textblock>audits, or a program review finding during its two most recent</textblock>
    <textblock>program reviews, that resulted in the institution's being</textblock>
    <textblock>required to repay an amount greater than five percent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA funds that the institution received for any award</textblock>
    <textblock>year covered by the audit or the program review; or (3) the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution failed to address satisfactorily any compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>problems identified in program review or audit reports based upon</textblock>
    <textblock>a final decision of the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>The consequences of this proposed provision are described</textblock>
    <textblock>more fully earlier in this preamble in the discussion on</textblock>
    <textblock>provisional certification. Essentially, institutions that fall</textblock>
    <textblock>into one of these categories not only would not be considered</textblock>
    <textblock>financially responsible, but could not be provisionally certified</textblock>
    <textblock>without the submission of certain financial guarantees or</textblock>
    <textblock>personal assumptions of liability arising from participation in</textblock>
    <textblock>the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Exceptions to the General Standards of Financial Responsibility</textblock>
    <textblock>The Amendments of 1992, as amended by the Technical</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendments of 1993, provide that the Secretary shall determine an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to be financially responsible even though it does not</textblock>
    <textblock>meet certain general standards of financial responsibility, under</textblock>
    <textblock>various conditions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 498(c)(5)(B) of the HEA provides that the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>shall establish a process whereby an institution is exempt from</textblock>
    <textblock>the cash reserve requirement if the institution is located in,</textblock>
    <textblock>and is legally authorized to operate within, a State that has a</textblock>
    <textblock>tuition recovery fund that ensures that the institution is able</textblock>
    <textblock>to pay all required refunds and the institution contributes to</textblock>
    <textblock>that tuition recovery fund. The Secretary proposes that an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution is exempt from the proposed cash reserve requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>if it meets these conditions; however, the Secretary proposes to</textblock>
    <textblock>stipulate that a State's tuition recovery fund must be acceptable</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Secretary. The Secretary would like to ensure that a</textblock>
    <textblock>State's tuition recovery fund truly has the resources to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>payment of all required refunds if necessary. To this end, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary would expect States to provide as much information as</textblock>
    <textblock>possible to demonstrate that their tuition recovery fund can pay</textblock>
    <textblock>all required refunds on behalf of an institution that closed</textblock>
    <textblock>precipitously. The Secretary invites comment on what specific</textblock>
    <textblock>standards should be used to measure the acceptability of a</textblock>
    <textblock>State's tuition recovery fund.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 498(c)(3) of the HEA provides that an institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>financially responsible even though it does not meet the other</textblock>
    <textblock>general standards of financial responsibility, under the</textblock>
    <textblock>following circumstances. First, an institution that is not</textblock>
    <textblock>financially responsible under the general standards of financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility (except the cash reserve requirement) is</textblock>
    <textblock>financially responsible if the institution submits to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary third-party financial guarantees, such as performance</textblock>
    <textblock>bonds or letters of credit payable to the Secretary, that equal</textblock>
    <textblock>not less than one-half of the annual potential Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program liabilities of the institution. The Secretary proposes</textblock>
    <textblock>that a letter of credit that is payable to the Secretary and</textblock>
    <textblock>effective for a period of time as determined by the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>would be the only acceptable type of third-party guarantee for</textblock>
    <textblock>this requirement. The determination by the Secretary that</textblock>
    <textblock>payment from a third-party guarantee requires that funds become</textblock>
    <textblock>immediately available to make refunds or to reimburse the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary for debts incurred in the programs. It has been the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's experience that letters of credit are the only method</textblock>
    <textblock>by which funds do become immediately available; however, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary requests comments on other standard forms of publicly</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranteed security that would provide the same level of security</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Secretary. The Secretary notes that an institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>liable for all mishandled Title IV, HEA program funds that it</textblock>
    <textblock>receives. Further, the Secretary believes that the total Title</textblock>
    <textblock>IV, HEA program funds received by an institution during the last</textblock>
    <textblock>complete award year is the best indicator of the amount of Title</textblock>
    <textblock>IV, HEA program assistance that the institution will receive for</textblock>
    <textblock>the next award year. Therefore, the Secretary proposes to</textblock>
    <textblock>require an institution to submit a letter of credit equal to not</textblock>
    <textblock>less than one-half of the Title IV, HEA program funds received by</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution during the last complete award year for which</textblock>
    <textblock>figures are available in order to meet this requirement.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
