<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00042</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00019</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>•Has IRP had (or is likely to have) an effect on the level of public involvement with utility planning? If so, how? Please explain. What studies, reports, or other information underlie your comments?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Has IRP had (or is likely to have) an effect on the environmental performance of the utility(s)? If so, how? Please explain. What studies, reports, or other information underlie your comments?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Has IRP affected (or is likely to affect) the way in which risk and uncertainty is treated in your business and/or regulatory planning process? If so, how? Please explain. What studies, reports, or other information underlie your comments?</textblock>
    <textblock>•On net, has IRP been (or is likely to be) a positive or negative force? Please explain. What studies, reports, or other information underlie your comments?</textblock>
    <textblock>V. DOE Plans for EPAct Report and Future IRP Evaluation Efforts</textblock>
    <textblock>The staff of DOE's IRP Program will tabulate and summarize public comments received by the due date of April 1, 1994. Depending on the number of responses, the report to the President and Congress will identify areas of agreement and disagreement among respondents by type of stakeholder group (utilities, States, interest groups), and regions of the country, and other key segmentation variables as appropriate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on February 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Christine A. Ervin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary, Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4477 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
