<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00159</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Issues that the community was asked to address and the</textblock>
    <textblock>community's views:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. What other administrative capability or financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility standards should be considered?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Agencies other than the Department that are permitted</textblock>
    <textblock>to request the same information should only be allowed</textblock>
    <textblock>to request documents used by the Department.</textblock>
    <textblock>[New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•No other standards of financial responsibility should</textblock>
    <textblock>be considered. [Kansas City, San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>V. Institutional Refund Policy</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 484B(b)(2) requires that each institution participating</textblock>
    <textblock>in any Title IV, HEA program shall have a fair and equitable</textblock>
    <textblock>refund policy under which the institution refunds unearned</textblock>
    <textblock>tuition, fees, room and board, and other charges, to a student</textblock>
    <textblock>who received Title IV assistance (including Federal PLUS loans</textblock>
    <textblock>received on the student's behalf) for a student who does not</textblock>
    <textblock>register for the period of attendance for which assistance was</textblock>
    <textblock>intended or withdraws or otherwise fails to complete the period</textblock>
    <textblock>of enrollment for which assistance is provided.</textblock>
    <textblock>An institution's refund policy is considered to be fair and</textblock>
    <textblock>equitable if the policy provides for a refund in an amount of at</textblock>
    <textblock>least the largest of the amounts provided under_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The requirements of applicable State law;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The specific refund standards established by the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's nationally recognized accrediting agency if those</textblock>
    <textblock>standards are approved by the Secretary;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>refund calculation described in the</textblock>
    <textblock>statute for any student whose withdrawal date is on or before the</textblock>
    <textblock>60 percent point in time in the period of enrollment for which</textblock>
    <textblock>the student has been charged.</textblock>
    <textblock>The term ``</textblock>
    <textblock>pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>refund,'' means a refund by the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to a student attending that institution for the first</textblock>
    <textblock>time of not less than that portion of the tuition, fees, room,</textblock>
    <textblock>board, and other charges assessed the student by the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>equal to the portion of the period of enrollment for which the</textblock>
    <textblock>student has been charged that remains on the last recorded day of</textblock>
    <textblock>attendance by the student, rounded downward to the nearest 10</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of that period, less any unpaid charges owed by the</textblock>
    <textblock>student for the period of enrollment for which the student has</textblock>
    <textblock>been charged, and less a reasonable administrative fee not to</textblock>
    <textblock>exceed the lesser of five percent of the tuition, fees, room and</textblock>
    <textblock>board, and other charges assessed the student, or $100.</textblock>
    <textblock>``The portion of the period of enrollment for which the</textblock>
    <textblock>student has been charged that remains,'' is determined_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) In the case of an educational program that is measured</textblock>
    <textblock>in credit hours, by dividing the total number of weeks comprising</textblock>
    <textblock>the period of enrollment for which the student has been charged</textblock>
    <textblock>into the number of weeks remaining in that period as of the last</textblock>
    <textblock>recorded day of attendance by the student;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) In the case of an educational program that is measured</textblock>
    <textblock>in clock hours, by dividing the total number of clock hours</textblock>
    <textblock>comprising the period of enrollment for which the student has</textblock>
    <textblock>been charged into the number of clock hours remaining to be</textblock>
    <textblock>completed by the student in that period as of the last recorded</textblock>
    <textblock>day of attendance by the student; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) In the case of a correspondence program, by dividing</textblock>
    <textblock>the total number of lessons comprising the period of enrollment</textblock>
    <textblock>for which the student has been charged into the number of lessons</textblock>
    <textblock>not submitted by the student.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issues that the community was asked to address and the</textblock>
    <textblock>community's views:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. How should the ``60 percent point in time'' be determined?</textblock>
    <textblock>Should this be based on scheduled time in the program or actual</textblock>
    <textblock>attendance?</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
