<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00092</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 668.16␣Standards of Administrative Capability</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to redesignate §668.14 as §668.16.</textblock>
    <textblock>In matters not governed by specific provisions, section</textblock>
    <textblock>487(c)(1)(B) of the HEA provides for the establishment of</textblock>
    <textblock>standards of administrative capability for participating</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions that include any matter the Secretary deems</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary for the sound administration of the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs. Section 498(d) of the HEA, which was added by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendments of 1992, authorizes the Secretary to establish</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures and requirements relating to administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>capability, including the consideration of past performance of</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions or individuals in control of those institutions and</textblock>
    <textblock>maintenance of records. In addition, section 498(d) authorizes</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary to establish other reasonable procedures that will</textblock>
    <textblock>contribute to ensuring that institutions will be administratively</textblock>
    <textblock>capable.</textblock>
    <textblock>Given this framework, the Secretary proposes to strengthen</textblock>
    <textblock>and modify the administrative capability standards in the current</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations by making significant, substantive changes to the</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative standards as well as some technical changes; the</textblock>
    <textblock>significant proposed changes to the current regulations are</textblock>
    <textblock>described below.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to clarify the Secretary's current</textblock>
    <textblock>principle that an institution must demonstrate that it is capable</textblock>
    <textblock>of meeting each of the administrative standards in this section</textblock>
    <textblock>to be considered administratively capable. During negotiated</textblock>
    <textblock>rulemaking, alternatives to requiring that institutions meet each</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative standard were discussed. Among the options</textblock>
    <textblock>considered were that the various factors be ``weighted,'' i.e., the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary would identify which factors he considered to be the</textblock>
    <textblock>most critical and would incur the greatest penalty if they were</textblock>
    <textblock>not met. Some of the negotiators suggested that the various</textblock>
    <textblock>factors be used only as indicators of capability; that is, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary would be required to review each institution that did</textblock>
    <textblock>not comply with one or more standard to determine the seriousness</textblock>
    <textblock>of noncompliance. However, the negotiators did not reach</textblock>
    <textblock>consensus on an approach. Therefore, the Secretary is proposing</textblock>
    <textblock>that to be fully certified as meeting the standards in this</textblock>
    <textblock>section (as well as the other standards in Subpart B of these</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations) an institution must demonstrate that it is</textblock>
    <textblock>administratively capable by meeting all the administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>standards. An institution that fails to demonstrate compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>with one or two administrative standards could be certified</textblock>
    <textblock>provisionally (see the earlier discussion on provisional</textblock>
    <textblock>certification) if the Secretary were to determine the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>capable of meeting all the standards within a specific time</textblock>
    <textblock>period and that the noncompliance did not necessitate taking a</textblock>
    <textblock>stronger sanction such as a fine, limitation, suspension, or</textblock>
    <textblock>termination proceeding against the institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>For example, an initial applicant would not be able to</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrate compliance with all standards prior to participation.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, the Secretary expects such an institution to demonstrate</textblock>
    <textblock>that it is capable of complying with all the standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, the Secretary currently provisionally certifies an</textblock>
    <textblock>initial applicant if the Secretary determines that the applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>is capable of meeting the current standards within a specified</textblock>
    <textblock>period of time. The Secretary will continue this practice, using</textblock>
    <textblock>any additional standards proposed in this section if they are</textblock>
    <textblock>adopted in final.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to make explicit the requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>that, to be considered administratively capable, an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>must administer all the Title IV, HEA programs in which it</textblock>
    <textblock>participates in accordance with all applicable statutory and</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory provisions and special arrangements, agreements, and</textblock>
    <textblock>limitations. This expectation has been implicit. However, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes it is important to lay out this standard</textblock>
    <textblock>together with all the other administrative standards.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
