<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00025</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[I.D. 021094C]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Endangered Species; Permits</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), NOAA, Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Receipt of Two Applications (P561 and P770</textblock>
    <textblock>#66)</textblock>
    <textblock>for Scientific Research Permits and Two Applications for Modifications to Scientific Research Permit 818 (P211C).</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), Washington State Office (P561) and the NMFS Northwest Fisheries Science Center (P770</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>66) have applied in due form for permits, and the Oregon Department of Fish and Wildlife (ODFW) has applied in due form for two modifications to Permit 818 (211C), to take listed species of Snake River salmon, as authorized by the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (16 U.S.C. 1531-1543) and the NMFS regulations governing listed fish and wildlife permits (50 CFR parts 217-227).</textblock>
    <textblock>The USDA, Washington State Office requests authorization to take listed juvenile Snake River spring/summer and fall chinook salmon (</textblock>
    <textblock>Oncorhynchus tshawytscha</textblock>
    <textblock>) in research activities to determine the presence or absence of those species in various backwater side channels and farm ponds associated with the Tucannon River and Asotin Creek. The purpose of the research is to prepare for habitat restoration in those streams, in coordination with local landowners, state agencies, the Bonneville Power Administration, and affected tribes. The applicant requests this authorization for a duration of two years.</textblock>
    <textblock>The NMFS Northwest Fisheries Science Center requests authorization to conduct eight scientific research studies involving the take of listed juvenile Snake River spring/summer and fall chinook salmon and juvenile Snake River sockeye salmon (</textblock>
    <textblock>O. nerka</textblock>
    <textblock>). The applicant requests this authorization for a duration of one to five years for the different studies.</textblock>
    <textblock>ODFW requests two modifications to their scientific research Permit 818. The first request is for authorization to install trap boxes on eight diversion screens to enable the collection of information on species composition and migration timing of listed Snake River spring/summer chinook salmon. In addition, these traps would allow the movement of trapped fish to available water when the water supply in the irrigation stream channels is insufficient. The second request is for authorization to take scale samples from adult and juvenile Snake River spring/summer chinook salmon. The applicant requests authorization for both modifications for the duration of the permit, through December 31, 1996.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written data or views, or requests for a public hearing on an application should be submitted to the Director, Office of Protected Resources, National Marine Fisheries Service, 1335 East-West Hwy., Silver Spring, MD 20910, within 30 days of the publication of this notice. Those individuals requesting a hearing should set forth the specific reasons why a hearing on the particular application would be appropriate. The holding of such hearing is at the discretion of the Assistant Administrator for Fisheries. All statements and opinions contained in these application summaries are those of the applicant and do not necessarily reflect the views of the National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>Documents submitted in connection with the above applications are available for review by interested persons in the following offices by appointment:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Protected Resources, National Marine Fisheries Service, 1335 East-West Hwy., Silver Spring, MD 20910 (301-713-2322); and</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental and Technical Services Division, National Marine Fisheries Service, 911 North East 11th Ave., room 620, Portland, OR 97232 (503-230-5400).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </action>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William W. Fox, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Protected Resources, National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4501 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
