<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00119</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00073</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>[T.D. 94-16]</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension of Camin Cargo Control, Inc.'s, Customs Gauger Approval and Laboratory Accreditation to the Site Located in Ingleside, TX</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock/>
  <doctitle/>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Customs Service, Department of the Treasury.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of the extension of Camin Cargo Control, Inc.'s Customs gauger approval and laboratory accreditation to include their Ingleside, Texas facility.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Camin Cargo Control, Inc., of Linden, New Jersey, a Customs approved gauger and accredited laboratory under Section 151.13 of the Customs Regulations (19 CFR 151.13), has been given an extension of its Customs gauger approval and laboratory accreditation to include the Ingleside, Texas site. Specifically, the extension given to the Ingleside site will include the approval to gauge petroleum and petroleum products, organic compounds in bulk and liquid form and animal and vegetable oils; and accreditation to perform the following laboratory analyses: API gravity, sediment and water by centrifuge, antiknock index, distillation characteristic, Reid Vapor Pressure, Saybolt Universal Viscosity, sediment by extraction, sulfur percent by weight and lead percent by weight.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 151 of the Customs Regulations provides for the acceptance at Customs Districts of laboratory analyses and gauging reports for certain products from Customs accredited commercial laboratories and approved gaugers. Camin Cargo Control, Inc., a Customs commercial approved gauger and accredited laboratory, has applied to Customs to extend its Customs gauger approval and certain laboratory accreditations to its Ingleside, Texas facility. Review of the qualifications of the Ingleside site shows that the extension is warranted and, accordingly, has been granted.</textblock>
    <textblock>Approved-Accredited Sites</textblock>
    <textblock>Camin Cargo Control, Inc., has been approved and/or accredited by the U.S. Customs Service at the following locations: Linden, New Jersey; Thorofare, New Jersey; Everett, Massachusetts; Deer Park, Texas; and Ingleside, Texas.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ira S. Reese, Chief, Technical Branch, Office of Laboratories and Scientific Services, U.S. Customs Service, 1301 Constitution Ave., NW., Washington, DC 20229 at (202) 927-1060.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>George D. Heavey,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Laboratories and Scientific Services.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4508 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4820-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
