<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00073</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Currently, the Department of Education uses a single</textblock>
    <textblock>application form that addresses both institutional eligibility</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements (as found in 34 CFR part 600) and the standards for</textblock>
    <textblock>certification of administrative capability and financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility. In recent years, although institutions filed a</textblock>
    <textblock>single application form, they received separate notifications of</textblock>
    <textblock>action from the Department: an institutional eligibility notice</textblock>
    <textblock>and a certification letter. This created confusion because some</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions misinterpreted the institutional eligibility notice</textblock>
    <textblock>also to be the notice informing the institution that it met the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements for ``certification'' and that the institution was now</textblock>
    <textblock>able to participate in a Title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order to reduce confusion, the Secretary is now combining</textblock>
    <textblock>these notices of ``institutional eligibility'' and ``certification'',</textblock>
    <textblock>issuing one ``Institutional Approval Notice'' to an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>that meets the institutional eligibility and certification</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements. The Institutional Approval Notice advises the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution that it is an eligible institution, and is approved</textblock>
    <textblock>to participate in the Title IV, HEA programs listed in the Notice</textblock>
    <textblock>and indicated in the institution's program participation</textblock>
    <textblock>agreement. The effective date of approval, which is specified in</textblock>
    <textblock>the Institutional Approval Notice, is the date that the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>signs the institution's program participation agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under current practice, an institution that wishes to</textblock>
    <textblock>participate in a Title IV, HEA program for the first time must</textblock>
    <textblock>first apply to the Secretary for a certification that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution meets the standards for participation found in</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart B of these regulations. A currently participating</textblock>
    <textblock>institution must apply to the Secretary for a certification that</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution continues to meet these standards under a number</textblock>
    <textblock>of conditions.</textblock>
    <textblock>First, the institution must apply for certification if the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary requests the institution to apply. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>reserves the right to require a participating institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>apply at any time if the Secretary is concerned about the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's continued participation in a Title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Currently, the Secretary exercises this authority only rarely,</textblock>
    <textblock>and generally when the Secretary receives reliable information</textblock>
    <textblock>that could affect the institution's eligibility under 34 CFR part</textblock>
    <textblock>600 or the institution's financial responsibility or</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability under subpart B of these regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>For example, if the Secretary receives information that an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution that does not grant degrees has received</textblock>
    <textblock>authorization from its State and accrediting agency to award</textblock>
    <textblock>degrees, the Secretary would require the institution to apply</textblock>
    <textblock>under 34 CFR part 600 to determine whether the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>satisfies the definition for a different type of institution and</textblock>
    <textblock>therefore might be eligible to apply to participate in HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs for which the institution earlier was not qualified. At</textblock>
    <textblock>the same time, the Secretary requires the institution to apply</textblock>
    <textblock>for recertification under this subpart. Similarly, if the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary receives reliable information that could affect whether</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution meets the factors of financial responsibility in</textblock>
    <textblock>this subpart, the Secretary requires the institution to apply for</textblock>
    <textblock>recertification. The Secretary does not intend to exercise this</textblock>
    <textblock>authority more frequently than under current practice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Second, a participating institution must apply for</textblock>
    <textblock>certification if the institution wishes to include in its</textblock>
    <textblock>participation a branch campus (as that term would be defined in</textblock>
    <textblock>34 CFR part 600) or another location that offers 100 percent of</textblock>
    <textblock>an educational program. Adding a branch campus or additional</textblock>
    <textblock>location that offers 100 percent of an educational program can</textblock>
    <textblock>have a great effect on the ability of an institution to continue</textblock>
    <textblock>to participate in the Title IV, HEA programs. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>considers it is appropriate to scrutinize the effect of such an</textblock>
    <textblock>addition. In particular, the Secretary believes it is necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>to examine whether the institution has the financial resources</textblock>
    <textblock>and the administrative capability necessary to support such an</textblock>
    <textblock>addition.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
