<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00078</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>D. Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule does not contain any new information collection requirements subject to review by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act, 44 U.S.C. 3501</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 40 CFR Part 280</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental protection, Administrative practice and procedure, Hazardous materials insurance, Oil pollution, Penalties, Petroleum, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, State program approval, Surety bonds, Underground storage tanks, Water pollution control.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Carol M. Browner,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set out in the preamble, part 280 of title 40 of the Code of Federal Regulations is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 280_TECHNICAL STANDARDS AND CORRECTIVE ACTION REQUIREMENTS FOR OWNERS AND OPERATORS OF UNDERGROUND STORAGE TANKS (UST)</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 280 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 6912, 6991, 6991a, 6991b, 6991c, 6991d, 6991e, 6991f, and 6991h.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 280.91 is amended by revising paragraph (e) and adding paragraph (f), to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง280.91</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance dates.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) All local government entities (including Indian tribes) not included in paragraph (f) of this section; February 18, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) Indian tribes that own USTs on Indian lands which meet the applicable technical requirements of this part; December 31, 1998.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4375 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
