<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00097</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to require each institution to have</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures for receiving, investigating, and resolving student</textblock>
    <textblock>complaints.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to require that if the stated</textblock>
    <textblock>objectives of an educational program are to prepare students for</textblock>
    <textblock>gainful employment, the institution must be able to show that</textblock>
    <textblock>there is a reasonable relationship between the length of the</textblock>
    <textblock>program and entry level requirements for employment. In addition</textblock>
    <textblock>to supporting the length of a program, the institution should be</textblock>
    <textblock>able to substantiate the need for the number of hours of</textblock>
    <textblock>training. The Secretary proposes to consider the relationship</textblock>
    <textblock>between the quantity of training provided in the program and</textblock>
    <textblock>entry-level requirements to be reasonable if the number of clock</textblock>
    <textblock>hours in the program does not exceed by more than 50 percent any</textblock>
    <textblock>State requirement for the minimum number of clock hours necessary</textblock>
    <textblock>to train the student in the occupation for which the program</textblock>
    <textblock>prepares the student. For example, the Secretary is aware of an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution that sought approval of a 600-hour program when the</textblock>
    <textblock>state in which the institution is located requires only 40 hours</textblock>
    <textblock>of training for entry level positions for which the program</textblock>
    <textblock>provided training. The Secretary believes that in situations</textblock>
    <textblock>such as this, the onus is on the institution to demonstrate the</textblock>
    <textblock>value of the longer program. The Secretary believes that the</textblock>
    <textblock>excessive length of programs requires a student to incur</textblock>
    <textblock>additional unnecessary debt.</textblock>
    <textblock>A corollary requirement is that the need for the training</textblock>
    <textblock>provided is established. Over the past several years, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary has been made aware of many schools that have provided</textblock>
    <textblock>three to six months of training for entry-level jobs, some of</textblock>
    <textblock>which required no external training before employment, as the</textblock>
    <textblock>employers have internal training programs or provide on-the-job</textblock>
    <textblock>training. As a basic tenet of student financial assistance is to</textblock>
    <textblock>enable students who would not otherwise be able to afford needed</textblock>
    <textblock>training or education to enroll in an appropriate program, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes that if an institution is administering the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs adequately, it can demonstrate that the</textblock>
    <textblock>training it provides is needed. The Secretary solicits</textblock>
    <textblock>suggestions on the most appropriate documentation to show the</textblock>
    <textblock>need for the training.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add to the administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>capability standards the requirement that the institution make</textblock>
    <textblock>information on job availability and state licensing requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>available to students in occupational, professional and</textblock>
    <textblock>vocational educational programs. The Secretary believes that, in</textblock>
    <textblock>order for a prospective occupational, professional or vocational</textblock>
    <textblock>education student and financial aid applicant to make an informed</textblock>
    <textblock>decision about enrollment and use of student financial assistance</textblock>
    <textblock>in a particular program, the applicant must have access to</textblock>
    <textblock>accurate, up-to-date information on the job market for that</textblock>
    <textblock>field, and the availability of specific jobs for which he or she</textblock>
    <textblock>would be adequately prepared after completion of the program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Similarly, the applicant should have access to information on the</textblock>
    <textblock>extent to which the educational or training program addresses</textblock>
    <textblock>state licensing standards, so the informed student can determine,</textblock>
    <textblock>with reasonable assurance, that necessary topics are covered in</textblock>
    <textblock>the program and the extent to which additional information, not</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary for state licensure, is covered. The Secretary notes</textblock>
    <textblock>that this information may be obtained by the institution from</textblock>
    <textblock>other Federal and State sources, such as Employment Service or</textblock>
    <textblock>State occupational coordinating committees. An institution would</textblock>
    <textblock>not be required to produce this information on its own.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to include within the administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>capability standards a requirement that the institution have</textblock>
    <textblock>advertising, promotion, and student recruitment practices that</textblock>
    <textblock>accurately reflect the content and objectives of the educational</textblock>
    <textblock>programs offered by the institution. The Secretary believes that</textblock>
    <textblock>to administer the Title IV, HEA programs in a responsible manner,</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution must advertise its programs and the financial</textblock>
    <textblock>assistance available in an accurate manner.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to specify that an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>provide all required program and fiscal reports and financial</textblock>
    <textblock>statements in a timely manner. The Secretary believes strongly</textblock>
    <textblock>that adequate, timely submission of accurate reports is an</textblock>
    <textblock>essential element in the proper administration of the Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA programs. The failure to meet requirements for submission of</textblock>
    <textblock>reports is an indication that an institution's administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>capability is impaired.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
