<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00088</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In the case of nonprofit institutions, the Secretary has</textblock>
    <textblock>developed standards in accordance with Statement of Financial</textblock>
    <textblock>Accounting Standards No. 117 (FAS 117) that was issued in June</textblock>
    <textblock>1993 by the Financial Accounting Standards Board (FASB). FAS 117</textblock>
    <textblock>altered the reporting format for not-for-profit organizations</textblock>
    <textblock>after the negotiated rulemaking process was already well</textblock>
    <textblock>underway. FAS 117 is effective for annual financial statements</textblock>
    <textblock>issued for fiscal years beginning after December 15, 1994, except</textblock>
    <textblock>for organizations with less than $5 million in total assets and</textblock>
    <textblock>less than $1 million in annual expenses. For those</textblock>
    <textblock>organizations, the Statement is effective for fiscal years</textblock>
    <textblock>beginning after December 15, 1995 with earlier application</textblock>
    <textblock>encouraged.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to require a nonprofit institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>prepare a classified statement of financial position in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with generally accepted accounting principles to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide the Secretary with the financial information necessary to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine the institution's financial responsibility under these</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations. The Secretary proposes that,</textblock>
    <textblock>alternatively, a nonprofit institution could provide this</textblock>
    <textblock>information as footnotes to the audit. Although FAS 117 does not</textblock>
    <textblock>require a nonprofit institution to submit a classified statement</textblock>
    <textblock>of financial position prior to published implementation dates, it</textblock>
    <textblock>does not prohibit the institution from doing so. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>notes that a financial statement that is not classified is not</textblock>
    <textblock>structured to provide the financial information necessary for the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary to determine an institution's compliance with these</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations; however, the information could be included</textblock>
    <textblock>as footnotes to the audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes that a nonprofit institution is not</textblock>
    <textblock>financially responsible if it cannot demonstrate, at the end of</textblock>
    <textblock>its latest fiscal year, a ratio of current assets to current</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities of at least 1:1. The Secretary proposes to not</textblock>
    <textblock>permit a nonprofit institution to include the cash reserves in</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution's current assets. The Secretary believes that,</textblock>
    <textblock>because the proposed current assets to current liabilities ratio</textblock>
    <textblock>for a nonprofit institution is 1:1, if the institution used</textblock>
    <textblock>designated reserve funds to meet this ratio, there would be no</textblock>
    <textblock>assurance of solvency.</textblock>
    <textblock>The importance of a higher current ratio for for-profit</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions lies in the fact that they are not as likely to be</textblock>
    <textblock>able to draw on fund raising as a source of cash in the event of</textblock>
    <textblock>hampered liquidity because donors are less likely to contribute</textblock>
    <textblock>funds to a for-profit institution where those contributions would</textblock>
    <textblock>not be tax deductible. Many nonprofit institutions have</textblock>
    <textblock>sufficient support in the community and from friends and alumni</textblock>
    <textblock>who are willing to donate to the institution. The cash intake of</textblock>
    <textblock>for-profit institutions is therefore limited to cash generated</textblock>
    <textblock>through profitability, whereas nonprofit institutions have an</textblock>
    <textblock>additional source of cash. Endowments, even when restricted to</textblock>
    <textblock>functions such as providing scholarships, are awarded and may be</textblock>
    <textblock>taken into cash from operations. Consistent profitable</textblock>
    <textblock>operations result in a better liquidity position for for-profit</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions, whereas consistent profitable operations are not</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary for a nonprofit to remain viable. In addition, it is</textblock>
    <textblock>inherent in a nonprofit institution that its final cash position</textblock>
    <textblock>not reflect a profit. In the nonprofit industry, the financial</textblock>
    <textblock>manager has limited authority. The financial manager may make</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendations, but the ultimate authority lies with the</textblock>
    <textblock>governing board. There is, therefore, less control in the hands</textblock>
    <textblock>of financial managers and a corresponding decrease in their</textblock>
    <textblock>ability to control a liquidity situation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Lack of liquidity means that the institution is unable to</textblock>
    <textblock>service its current debt. This can lead to the forced sale of</textblock>
    <textblock>long-term investments and assets. To the owners of an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution, a lack of liquidity will mean reduced profitability</textblock>
    <textblock>or it may mean loss of control or loss of the entire capital</textblock>
    <textblock>investment. To creditors of the enterprise, it means slow</textblock>
    <textblock>collection of principal and interest due or even loss of the</textblock>
    <textblock>amounts due them. Students of these institutions can also be</textblock>
    <textblock>affected by a short-term poor financial condition. These effects</textblock>
    <textblock>may take the form of inability of the institution to perform</textblock>
    <textblock>their contract, inability to make refunds due to students or</textblock>
    <textblock>lenders, or the loss of supplier relationships. Suppliers are</textblock>
    <textblock>interested in an institution's liquidity position, and if it is</textblock>
    <textblock>found to be inadequate, it may cease to do business with the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
