<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00135</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(t)(1) For an institution that has a common academic year</textblock>
    <textblock>for a majority of its students, does not have more than 33</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of the regular students who are enrolled on the first day</textblock>
    <textblock>of classes of an academic year withdraw from enrollment at that</textblock>
    <textblock>institution during that academic year; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For an institution that does not have a common academic</textblock>
    <textblock>year for a majority of its students, does not have more than 33</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of the regular students who are enrolled on the first day</textblock>
    <textblock>of classes of any eight-month period withdraw during that period;</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>(u) Does not otherwise appear to lack the ability to</textblock>
    <textblock>administer the Title IV, HEA programs competently.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1082, 1085, 1094, 1099c; Section 4 of</textblock>
    <textblock>Pub. L. 95-452, 92 Stat. 1101-1109; E.O. 12549 (3 CFR, 1986</textblock>
    <textblock>Comp., p. 189), 12689 (3 CFR, 1989 Comp., p. 235)</textblock>
    <textblock>11. Newly designated ยง668.17 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง668.17</textblock>
    <textblock>Default reduction measures.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Default rates.</textblock>
    <textblock>If the Federal Stafford loan and</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal SLS cohort default rate for an institution exceeds 20</textblock>
    <textblock>percent for any fiscal year, the Secretary notifies the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution of that rate and may, after consultation as the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary deems appropriate with cognizant guaranty agencies take</textblock>
    <textblock>one or more of the following actions:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Initiate a proceeding under Subpart G of this part to</textblock>
    <textblock>limit, suspend, or terminate the participation of the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Title IV, HEA programs, if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The institution's Federal Stafford loan and Federal SLS</textblock>
    <textblock>cohort default rate exceeds 40 percent for any fiscal year after</textblock>
    <textblock>1989 and has not been reduced by an increment of at least 5</textblock>
    <textblock>percent from its rate for the previous fiscal year (e.g., a</textblock>
    <textblock>50-percent rate was not reduced to 45 percent or below); or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The institution's Federal Stafford loan and Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>SLS cohort default rate exceeds_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) 60 percent for fiscal year 1989;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) 55 percent for fiscal year 1990;</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) 50 percent for fiscal year 1991;</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) 45 percent for fiscal year 1992; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(E) 40 percent for any fiscal year after fiscal year 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) To help the Secretary make a preliminary determination</textblock>
    <textblock>as to the appropriate action to be taken by the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>regarding the institution, require the institution to submit to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary and one or more guaranty agencies, as defined in 34</textblock>
    <textblock>CFR 682, any information relating to that determination, as</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonably required by the Secretary, within a time frame</textblock>
    <textblock>specified by the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Default management plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>If the Federal Stafford loan</textblock>
    <textblock>and Federal SLS cohort default rate for an institution_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Is greater than 20 percent but less than or equal to 40</textblock>
    <textblock>percent, the institution must submit a default management plan</textblock>
    <textblock>that implements the measures described in appendix D of this</textblock>
    <textblock>part. An institution that wishes to submit a default management</textblock>
    <textblock>plan that deviates from the measures described in appendix D of this part must</textblock>
    <textblock>submit a justification for the deviation that includes a</textblock>
    <textblock>rationale explaining why the measures from which the plan</textblock>
    <textblock>deviates are not appropriate for the institution's specific</textblock>
    <textblock>situation. The institution must implement the default management</textblock>
    <textblock>plan upon notification from the Secretary that the plan has been</textblock>
    <textblock>approved; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Exceeds 40 percent for any fiscal year, the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>must implement all of the default management reduction measures</textblock>
    <textblock>described in appendix D of this part no later than 60 days after</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution receives the Secretary's notification of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's cohort default rate. An institution is not</textblock>
    <textblock>required to submit any written plans to the Secretary or a</textblock>
    <textblock>guaranty agency unless the Secretary or guaranty agency</textblock>
    <textblock>specifically requests the institution to do so.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>End of participation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Except as provided in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (c)(6) of this section, an institution's participation</textblock>
    <textblock>in the FFEL programs ends if the Secretary determines that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's cohort default rate, for each of the three most</textblock>
    <textblock>recent fiscal years for which the Secretary has determined the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's rate, is equal to or greater than the applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>threshold rates.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For purposes of the determinations made under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (c)(1) of this section, the threshold rates are_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) 35 percent for each of fiscal years 1991 and 1992;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) 30 percent for fiscal year 1993; and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
