<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00124</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Provisional certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The Secretary may</textblock>
    <textblock>provisionally certify an institution if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The institution seeks initial participation in a</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The Secretary is determining for the first time</textblock>
    <textblock>whether the institution meets the factors of financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility under §668.15 and the standards of administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>capability under §668.16;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The institution is an eligible institution that has</textblock>
    <textblock>undergone a change in ownership that results in a change in</textblock>
    <textblock>control according to the provisions of 34 CFR part 600;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The institution is a participating institution_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) That is applying for a certification that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution meets the standards of this subpart;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) That the Secretary determines has jeopardized its</textblock>
    <textblock>ability to perform its financial responsibilities by not meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>the factors of financial responsibility under §668.15 or the</textblock>
    <textblock>standards of administrative capability under §668.16; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Whose participation has been limited or suspended under</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart G of this part, or voluntarily enters into provisional</textblock>
    <textblock>certification;</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) The institution seeks a renewal of participation in a</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program after the expiration of a prior period of</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in that program; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) The institution is a participating institution that</textblock>
    <textblock>was accredited or preaccredited by a nationally recognized</textblock>
    <textblock>accrediting agency on the day before the Secretary withdrew the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's recognition of that agency according to the</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions contained in 34 CFR part 603.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If the Secretary provisionally certifies an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution, the Secretary also specifies the period for which</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution may participate in a Title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Except as provided in paragraphs (c)(3) and (4) of this section,</textblock>
    <textblock>a provisionally certified institution's period of participation</textblock>
    <textblock>expires_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Not later than 12 months from the date on which the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary provisionally certified an institution under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (c)(1)(i) of this section;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Not later than 36 months from the date on which the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary provisionally certified an institution under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraphs (c)(1) (ii), (iii), (iv), or (v) of this section; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) If the Secretary provisionally certified an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution under paragraph (c)(1)(vi) of this section, not later</textblock>
    <textblock>than 18 months after the date that the Secretary withdrew</textblock>
    <textblock>recognition from the institution's nationally recognized</textblock>
    <textblock>accrediting agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Notwithstanding the maximum periods of participation</textblock>
    <textblock>provided for in paragraph (c)(2) of this section, if the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary provisionally certifies an institution, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>may specify a shorter period of participation for that</textblock>
    <textblock>institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) For the purposes of this section, ``provisional</textblock>
    <textblock>certification'' means that the Secretary certifies that an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution has demonstrated to the Secretary's satisfaction that</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Is capable of meeting the standards of this subpart</textblock>
    <textblock>within a specified period; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Is able to meet the institution's responsibilities</textblock>
    <textblock>under its program participation agreement, including compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>with any additional conditions specified in the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>program participation agreement that the Secretary requires the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to meet in order for the institution to participate</textblock>
    <textblock>under provisional certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Requirements for provisional certification to</textblock>
    <textblock>participate on a limited basis for institutions that are not</textblock>
    <textblock>financially responsible.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notwithstanding paragraph (c)(1) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section, the Secretary does not provisionally certify an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Fails to meet the general standards of financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility in §668.15(b), unless the institution_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that</textblock>
    <textblock>it has sufficient financial and administrative resources to</textblock>
    <textblock>participate in the Title IV, HEA programs under a funding</textblock>
    <textblock>arrangement other than the Department of Education's standard</textblock>
    <textblock>advance funding arrangement;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Submits to the Secretary a letter of credit payable to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary equal to not less than 10 percent of the Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA program funds received by the institution during the last</textblock>
    <textblock>complete award year for which figures are available; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Demonstrates that it has met all of its financial</textblock>
    <textblock>obligations during the preceding two award years, including (but</textblock>
    <textblock>not limited to) the payment of required refunds and repayments to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary for liabilities and debts incurred in programs</textblock>
    <textblock>administered by the Secretary; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Is not financially responsible under §668.15(c)(2), or</textblock>
    <textblock>has been determined not to be financially responsible under</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.15 at any time during the five-year period preceding the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's decision to certify the institution provisionally</textblock>
    <textblock>unless_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The institution, or one or more persons or entities</textblock>
    <textblock>that the Secretary determines under the provisions of §668.15</textblock>
    <textblock>exercise substantial control over the institution, or both,</textblock>
    <textblock>submit to the Secretary financial guarantees in an amount</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by the Secretary to be sufficient to satisfy the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's potential liabilities arising from the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation in the Title IV, HEA programs; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) One or more persons or entities that the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>determines under the provisions of §668.15 exercise substantial</textblock>
    <textblock>control over the institution agree to be jointly or severally</textblock>
    <textblock>liable for any liabilities arising from the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the Title IV, HEA programs and civil and</textblock>
    <textblock>criminal monetary penalties authorized under Title IV of the HEA.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
