<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00145</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(B) Six months, under either of the following</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances:</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) The student's educational program does not consist</textblock>
    <textblock>predominantly of correspondence courses, and the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>next period of enrollment after the start of the leave of absence</textblock>
    <textblock>would begin more than 60 days after the first day of the leave of</textblock>
    <textblock>absence.</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) The leave of absence is requested because of the</textblock>
    <textblock>student's medically determinable condition, in which case the</textblock>
    <textblock>student must provide the institution with a written</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendation from a physician for a leave of absence longer</textblock>
    <textblock>than 60 days; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) The length of time between the beginning of the leave</textblock>
    <textblock>of absence and the institution's next period of enrollment, under</textblock>
    <textblock>the following circumstance: The institution's next period of</textblock>
    <textblock>enrollment after the start of the leave of absence begins more</textblock>
    <textblock>than thirty days after the beginning of the leave of absence, and</textblock>
    <textblock>a corresponding period of nonenrollment (i.e., summer break)</textblock>
    <textblock>prevents a student from enrolling in any coursework.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Timely payment.</textblock>
    <textblock>An institution shall pay a refund that</textblock>
    <textblock>is due_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) If a student officially withdraws or is expelled,</textblock>
    <textblock>within 30 days after the student's withdrawal date;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) If a student drops out, within 30 days of the earliest</textblock>
    <textblock>of the_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Date on which the institution determines that the</textblock>
    <textblock>student dropped out;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Expiration of the academic term in which the student</textblock>
    <textblock>withdrew; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Expiration of the period of enrollment for which the</textblock>
    <textblock>student has been charged; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) If a student does not return to the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>before the expiration of an approved leave of absence under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (i)(2) of this section, within 30 days after the last</textblock>
    <textblock>day of the leave of absence.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1091b, 1092, 1094)</textblock>
    <textblock>13. Section 668.23 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง668.23</textblock>
    <textblock>Audits, records, and examinations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) An institution or a foreign institution as defined 34</textblock>
    <textblock>CFR 600.52 that participates in the Federal Perkins Loan, FWS,</textblock>
    <textblock>FSEOG, Federal Stafford Loan, Federal PLUS, Federal Pell Grant,</textblock>
    <textblock>PAS, or FDSL Program shall comply with the regulations for that</textblock>
    <textblock>program concerning_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Fiscal and accounting systems;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Program and fiscal recordkeeping; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Record retention.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) (1) An institution or a foreign institution as defined</textblock>
    <textblock>34 CFR 600.52 that participates in any Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>shall cooperate with an independent auditor, the Secretary, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education's Inspector General, the Comptroller</textblock>
    <textblock>General of the United States, or their authorized</textblock>
    <textblock>representatives, a guaranty agency in whose program the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution participates, and the appropriate State postsecondary</textblock>
    <textblock>review entity designated under subpart 1 of part H of Title IV of</textblock>
    <textblock>the HEA, in the conduct of audits, investigations, and program</textblock>
    <textblock>reviews authorized by law.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A third-party servicer shall cooperate with an</textblock>
    <textblock>independent auditor, the Secretary, the Department of Education's</textblock>
    <textblock>Inspector General, and the Comptroller General of the United</textblock>
    <textblock>States, or their authorized representatives, a guaranty agency in</textblock>
    <textblock>whose program the institution contracting with the servicer</textblock>
    <textblock>participates, and the State postsecondary review entity</textblock>
    <textblock>designated under subpart 1 of part H of Title IV of the HEA, in</textblock>
    <textblock>the conduct of audits, investigations, and program reviews</textblock>
    <textblock>authorized by law.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The institution's or servicer's cooperation must</textblock>
    <textblock>include_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Providing timely access, for examination and copying,</textblock>
    <textblock>to the records (including computerized records) required by the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicable regulations and to any other pertinent books,</textblock>
    <textblock>documents, papers, computer programs, and records;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Providing reasonable access to personnel associated</textblock>
    <textblock>with the institution's or servicer's administration of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs for the purpose of obtaining relevant</textblock>
    <textblock>information. In providing reasonable access, the institution or</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer shall not_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Refuse to supply any relevant information;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Refuse to permit interviews with those personnel that</textblock>
    <textblock>do not include the presence of the institution's or servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>management; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Refuse to permit interviews with those personnel that</textblock>
    <textblock>are not tape recorded by the institution or servicer.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)(1)(i) An institution or a foreign institution as</textblock>
    <textblock>defined 34 CFR 600.52 that participates in the FDSL, Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Perkins Loan, FWS, FSEOG, Federal Stafford Loan, Federal PLUS,</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal SLS, Federal Pell Grant, or PAS Program shall have</textblock>
    <textblock>performed a financial and compliance audit of its Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A third-party servicer that administers funds or</textblock>
    <textblock>determines student eligibility shall have a financial and</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance audit performed of every aspect of the servicer's</textblock>
    <textblock>administration of the participation in the Title IV, HEA programs</textblock>
    <textblock>of each institution with which the servicer has a contract,</textblock>
    <textblock>unless_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The servicer contracts with only one participating</textblock>
    <textblock>institution; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The audit of that institution's participation involves</textblock>
    <textblock>every aspect of the servicer's administration of that Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA program.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
