<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00063</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00037</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Area Closures to ORV/Motorized Vehicles</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[ID-020-406A-02]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management (BLM), Department of the Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given, effective immediately, that the following lands located on the north side of the Snake River and about eight miles down stream of American Falls Dam are closed to ORV/motorized vehicles.</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 9 S., R. 20 E.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1: NE1/4NE1/4, SW1/4NE1/4, NE1/4SW1/4, NW1/4SW1/4</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 2: SE1/4, SE1/4, SW1/4, SE1/4,</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 8 S., R. 30 E.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 20: SE1/4, SE1/4, SW1/4, SE1/4,</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 29: NE1/4NE1/4, NW1/4, NE1/4SW1/4, NW1/4SE1/4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Approximately 600 acres.</textblock>
    <textblock>This action follows the Monument Resource Management Plan (MRMP) prescriptions published in January, 1986. The MRMP designates that these areas of the Cedar Fields Special Recreation Management Area, which are also within the Bureau of Reclamation's (BOR) American Falls Natural Resource Area, be designated as to be consistent with BOR's limitations on adjacent lands. Effective by the December 28, 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>Notices, the BOR activated the enforcement of the off-road motor vehicle closure of the lands within the American Falls Natural Resource Area.</textblock>
    <textblock>Exemptions to this order are granted to the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>Law enforcement patrol and emergency services administratively approved access for actions such as monitoring or research studies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other actions would be considered on a case by case basis.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Tom Dyer, Snake River Resource Area Manager, Rt. 3, Box 1, Burley, ID 83318, (208) 678-5514. A map showing the location of the closed areas is available from the Burley District BLM Office.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 17, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Marvin R. Bagley,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate District Manager.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4418 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-GG-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
