<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00112</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add a requirement that specifies</textblock>
    <textblock>that an institution must establish and maintain, on a current</textblock>
    <textblock>basis, financial and other institutional records necessary to</textblock>
    <textblock>determine the institutional eligibility, financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility, and administrative capability of the institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary believes it is essential for the Department to have</textblock>
    <textblock>access to this information when evaluating an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance with the requirements of the provisions governing the</textblock>
    <textblock>institutional eligibility, financial responsibility, and</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability of the institution. Further, an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution needs to maintain this information because, under its</textblock>
    <textblock>program participation agreement, the institution must agree to</textblock>
    <textblock>make the information available to appropriate authorities</textblock>
    <textblock>specified there (see the discussion on proposed §668.14).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to require that all records required</textblock>
    <textblock>under the applicable Title IV, HEA program regulations be</textblock>
    <textblock>retained by the institution for at least five years from the time</textblock>
    <textblock>the record is established unless specific program regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>require that a record be kept for a period of time longer than</textblock>
    <textblock>five years. Five years is the standard period of time that</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions are required to keep most records under the Title</textblock>
    <textblock>IV, HEA programs. The Secretary believes that this is a</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonable period of time to require institutions to maintain</textblock>
    <textblock>most records so that the Department is able to evaluate the past</textblock>
    <textblock>performance of an institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.26␣End of an Institution's Participation in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to clarify the purpose of the section</textblock>
    <textblock>currently titled ``Loss of institutional eligibility to</textblock>
    <textblock>participate in the Title IV, HEA programs'' by changing the title</textblock>
    <textblock>to ``End of an institution's participation in the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs.'' The Secretary proposes to specify the date on which</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution's participation ends under a variety of</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances to reflect statutory changes and to make clear</textblock>
    <textblock>existing practice. The Secretary has clarified in these proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations the end of participation date currently used by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department to be the date that: The institution closes or stops</textblock>
    <textblock>providing educational programs (the Secretary proposes,</textblock>
    <textblock>consistent with provisions proposed to be included in the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations governing institutional eligibility under the HEA, to</textblock>
    <textblock>specify that this closure must be for a reason other than a</textblock>
    <textblock>normal vacation period or a natural disaster that directly</textblock>
    <textblock>affects the institution or the institution's students); the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution loses its institutional eligibility under</textblock>
    <textblock>34 CFR part 600; the institution's participation is terminated</textblock>
    <textblock>under the proceedings in subpart G of this part; or the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's program participation agreement is terminated or</textblock>
    <textblock>expires.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
