<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00128</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(21) It will not impose any penalty, including, but not</textblock>
    <textblock>limited to, the assessment of late fees, the denial of access to</textblock>
    <textblock>classes, libraries, or other institutional facilities, or the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement that the student borrow additional funds for which</textblock>
    <textblock>interest or other charges are assessed, on any student because of</textblock>
    <textblock>the student's inability to meet his or her financial obligations</textblock>
    <textblock>to the institution as a result of the delayed disbursement of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proceeds of a Title IV, HEA program loan due to compliance with</textblock>
    <textblock>statutory and regulatory requirements of or applicable to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs, or delays attributable to the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(22) It will not provide, nor contract with any entity that</textblock>
    <textblock>provides, any commission, bonus, or other incentive payment based</textblock>
    <textblock>directly or indirectly on success in securing enrollments or</textblock>
    <textblock>financial aid to any persons or entities engaged in any student</textblock>
    <textblock>recruiting or admission activities or in making decisions</textblock>
    <textblock>regarding the awarding of student financial assistance, except</textblock>
    <textblock>that this requirement shall not apply to the recruitment of</textblock>
    <textblock>foreign students residing in foreign countries who are not</textblock>
    <textblock>eligible to receive Federal student assistance;</textblock>
    <textblock>(23) It will meet the requirements established pursuant to</textblock>
    <textblock>Part H of Title IV of the HEA by the Secretary, State</textblock>
    <textblock>postsecondary review entities designated under subpart 1 of</textblock>
    <textblock>Part H of Title IV of the HEA, and nationally recognized</textblock>
    <textblock>accrediting agencies;</textblock>
    <textblock>(24) It will comply with the institutional refund policy</textblock>
    <textblock>established in ยง668.22; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(25) It is liable for all_(i) Improperly spent or unspent funds received under the Title IV, HEA programs, including any funds administered by a</textblock>
    <textblock>third-party servicer; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Refunds that the institution or its servicer may be</textblock>
    <textblock>required to make.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) In order to participate in any Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>(other than the SSIG and NEISP programs), the institution must</textblock>
    <textblock>certify that it_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Has in operation a drug abuse prevention program that</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution has determined to be accessible to any officer,</textblock>
    <textblock>employee, or student at the institution; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)(i) Has established a campus security policy in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with section 485(f) of the HEA; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Has complied with the disclosure requirements of</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง668.48 as required by section 485(f) of the HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) In order to participate in any Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>(other than the SSIG and NEISP programs), an institution that</textblock>
    <textblock>offers athletically related student aid must_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Cause an annual compilation, independently audited not</textblock>
    <textblock>less often than every 3 years, to be prepared within 6 months</textblock>
    <textblock>after the end of the institution's fiscal year, of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The revenues derived by the institution from the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's intercollegiate athletics activities, according to</textblock>
    <textblock>the following categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Total revenues.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Revenues from football.</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Revenues from men's basketball.</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) Revenues from women's basketball.</textblock>
    <textblock>(E) Revenues from all other men's sports combined.</textblock>
    <textblock>(F) Revenues from all other women's sports combined;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Expenses made by the institution for the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>intercollegiate athletics activities, according to the following</textblock>
    <textblock>categories:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Total expenses.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Expenses attributable to football.</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Expenses attributable to men's basketball.</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) Expenses attributable to women's basketball.</textblock>
    <textblock>(E) Expenses attributable to all other men's sports</textblock>
    <textblock>combined.</textblock>
    <textblock>(F) Expenses attributable to all other women's sports</textblock>
    <textblock>combined; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The total revenues and operating expenses of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Make the compilation and, where allowable by State law,</textblock>
    <textblock>the audits, required by paragraph (d)(1) of this section</textblock>
    <textblock>available for inspection by the Secretary and the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) For the purposes of paragraph (d) of this section_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Revenues from intercollegiate athletics activities</textblock>
    <textblock>allocable to a sport shall include without limitation gate</textblock>
    <textblock>receipts, broadcast revenues and other conference distributions,</textblock>
    <textblock>appearance guarantees and options, concessions, and advertising;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Revenues such as student activities fees, alumni</textblock>
    <textblock>contributions, and investment interest income that are not</textblock>
    <textblock>allocable to a sport shall be included in the calculation of</textblock>
    <textblock>total revenues only;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Expenses for intercollegiate athletics activities</textblock>
    <textblock>allocable to a sport shall include without limitation</textblock>
    <textblock>grants-in-aid, salaries, travel, equipment, and supplies; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Expenses such as general and administrative overhead</textblock>
    <textblock>that are not allocable to a sport shall be included in the</textblock>
    <textblock>calculation of total expenses only.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)(1) A program participation agreement becomes effective</textblock>
    <textblock>on the date that the Secretary signs the agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A new program participation agreement supersedes any</textblock>
    <textblock>prior program participation agreement between the Secretary and</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)(1) Except as provided in paragraphs (h) and (i) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, the Secretary terminates a program participation</textblock>
    <textblock>agreement through the proceedings in subpart G of this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) An institution may terminate a program participation</textblock>
    <textblock>agreement.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
