<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00061</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Rail Fixed Guideway Systems; State Safety Oversight</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Transit Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>49 CFR Part 659</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 92-D]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 2132-AA39</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Transit Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule; notice of hearing; extension of the</textblock>
    <textblock>comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 9, 1993, the Federal Transit</textblock>
    <textblock>Administration (FTA) issued a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking</textblock>
    <textblock>(NPRM) for its Rail Fixed Guideway Systems State Safety</textblock>
    <textblock>Oversight program. FTA has decided to hold a public hearing in</textblock>
    <textblock>conjunction with an American Public Transit Association meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>which occurs after the close of the comment period announced in</textblock>
    <textblock>the NPRM. This document accordingly reopens the comment period</textblock>
    <textblock>and announces the public hearing.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this proposed rule must be submitted by</textblock>
    <textblock>March 22, 1994. The public hearing will be held at 8 a.m. (EST) on March 8, 1994. For further information see the</textblock>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION</textblock>
    <textblock>section of this preamble.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on the NPRM should be sent, in duplicate,</textblock>
    <textblock>to Docket No. 92-D, Docket Clerk, room 9316, Office of the Chief</textblock>
    <textblock>Counsel, Federal Transit Administration, 400 7th Street, SW.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20590. Those wishing the agency to acknowledge</textblock>
    <textblock>receipt of their comments should include a self-addressed</textblock>
    <textblock>stamped postcard with their comments. All comments will be</textblock>
    <textblock>available for review by the public at this address from 9 a.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>to 5 p.m., Monday through Friday, except Federal holidays. The</textblock>
    <textblock>public hearing will be held at 8:00 a.m. (EST) on March 8, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>at the J. W. Marriott Hotel, 1331 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20004. For further information see the</textblock>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION</textblock>
    <textblock>section of this preamble.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>For program issues: Franz</textblock>
    <textblock>Gimmler, Deputy Associate Administrator for Safety, or Roy</textblock>
    <textblock>Field, Transit Safety Specialist, both of the Office of Safety</textblock>
    <textblock>and Security, Federal Transit Administration, (202) 366-2896</textblock>
    <textblock>(telephone) or (202) 366-3765 (fax). For legal issues: Nancy</textblock>
    <textblock>Zaczek or Daniel Duff, Office of the Chief Counsel, Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Transit Administration, (202) 366-4011.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Introduction</textblock>
    <textblock>FTA published a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPRM) in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 9, 1993, at 58 FR 64856, concerning</textblock>
    <textblock>the creation of a State oversight agency that would develop</textblock>
    <textblock>certain procedures for overseeing the safety of rail fixed</textblock>
    <textblock>guideway systems. FTA has determined that a public hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>would help in the development of the final rule. FTA</textblock>
    <textblock>accordingly will hold the hearing in conjunction with a</textblock>
    <textblock>conference sponsored by the American Public Transit Association</textblock>
    <textblock>(APTA), which will be attended by State and local transit</textblock>
    <textblock>representatives. The hearing will be held on March 8, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because of this action, FTA is extending the comment period.</textblock>
    <textblock>Information on the Public Hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>The hearing will be held on March 8, 1994, in the Grand</textblock>
    <textblock>Ballroom_Salon D at the J.W. Marriott Hotel, 1331 Pennsylvania</textblock>
    <textblock>Avenue NW., Washington, DC 20004. It will begin at 8 a.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>(EST).</textblock>
    <textblock>Those interested in providing comments on the NPRM may respond</textblock>
    <textblock>in writing to the docket or participate in the public hearings</textblock>
    <textblock>and are encouraged to do both.</textblock>
    <textblock>FTA has established the following procedures to facilitate the</textblock>
    <textblock>hearings. Those wishing to participate in the public hearings</textblock>
    <textblock>should contact either Mr. Franz Gimmler or Mr. Roy Field by</textblock>
    <textblock>telephone at (202) 366-2896, by fax at (202) 366-3765, or in</textblock>
    <textblock>writing at the address in the</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT</textblock>
    <textblock>section at least three business days before the hearing is to be</textblock>
    <textblock>held or register with the FTA on the day of the hearing. Those</textblock>
    <textblock>contacting FTA at least three business days before the hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>is scheduled may request a particular time to testify. FTA</textblock>
    <textblock>will try to accommodate those requests.</textblock>
    <textblock>For those who have not contacted FTA at least three business</textblock>
    <textblock>days in advance, a registration desk will be available at the</textblock>
    <textblock>hearing site on the day of the hearing. Individuals may</textblock>
    <textblock>register beginning one hour before the hearing is scheduled to</textblock>
    <textblock>start. The registration desk will remain open until the hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>begins, after which FTA staff will try to accommodate late</textblock>
    <textblock>registrants. Time permitting, individuals will testify in the</textblock>
    <textblock>order in which they have registered.</textblock>
    <textblock>Those who request to testify may be given ten minutes to make a</textblock>
    <textblock>statement or present other relevant documents which will be</textblock>
    <textblock>included in the docket. FTA encourages those individuals to</textblock>
    <textblock>submit a written statement which will also be included in the</textblock>
    <textblock>docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Those individuals in need of an oral interpreter should inform</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Gimmler or Mr. Field of that need also at least three</textblock>
    <textblock>business days before the hearing is to be held. Unless</textblock>
    <textblock>requested three business days before the hearing, an oral</textblock>
    <textblock>interpreter will not be provided.</textblock>
    <textblock>A hearing officer will preside over the hearing. The hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>officer may make a statement to clarify issues or facilitate</textblock>
    <textblock>discussion during the hearing . Any statements the hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>officer makes during a hearing are not intended to be and should</textblock>
    <textblock>not be construed as a position of the FTA with respect to the</textblock>
    <textblock>NPRM or any future rulemaking.</textblock>
    <textblock>The hearing will be recorded by a court reporter. A transcript</textblock>
    <textblock>of the hearing will be included in the official rulemaking</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket 92-D and be available for inspection. Any individual</textblock>
    <textblock>interested in a copy of the transcript of a hearing may contact</textblock>
    <textblock>the court reporter directly.</textblock>
    <textblock>The hearing is designed to solicit public views and information</textblock>
    <textblock>on the NPRM. Therefore, the hearing will be conducted in an</textblock>
    <textblock>informal and nonadversarial manner. However, the hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>officer may ask questions in order to clarify statements made at</textblock>
    <textblock>the hearing. To facilitate comment and get a broad</textblock>
    <textblock>cross-section of views, the FTA may ask some of those who</textblock>
    <textblock>register in advance to participate on a panel during the hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued on: February 23, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Gordon J. Linton,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4495 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-57-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
