<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00089</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes that a nonprofit institution is not</textblock>
    <textblock>financially responsible if it has had a decrease in total net</textblock>
    <textblock>assets at the end of its latest fiscal year of such significance</textblock>
    <textblock>that, if continued, would result in a ratio current assets to</textblock>
    <textblock>current liabilities of less than 1:1. Under this proposal, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary could consider the effect of extraordinary gains or</textblock>
    <textblock>losses resulting from unusual and infrequent events, and could</textblock>
    <textblock>take into consideration the cumulative effect of a change in</textblock>
    <textblock>accounting principle, estimate or reporting entity to the extent</textblock>
    <textblock>that such a change results in a more accurate representation of</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution's financial position in accordance with generally</textblock>
    <textblock>accepted accounting principles. For purposes of this proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>analysis, the Secretary could exclude unrealized gains and losses</textblock>
    <textblock>on investments that have been reported as changes in unrestricted</textblock>
    <textblock>net assets. The standard was revised to reflect the changes</textblock>
    <textblock>brought about with the issuance of FASB 117 and in order to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide parity with the for-profit institutions. The concept of</textblock>
    <textblock>net worth, as it applies to profit-seeking entities, does not</textblock>
    <textblock>exist for a not-for-profit entity. Upon implementation of FASB</textblock>
    <textblock>117, fund accounting will no longer be used for colleges and</textblock>
    <textblock>universities, but these entities will adopt a format that is more</textblock>
    <textblock>similar to the format for-profit entities have been using. The</textblock>
    <textblock>term ``fund balance'' will no longer apply, but will be replaced by</textblock>
    <textblock>total net assets, divided into unrestricted, temporarily</textblock>
    <textblock>restricted and permanently restricted assets. For institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>not required to implement FAS 117 prior to the effective date of</textblock>
    <textblock>these regulations, the regulations applying to nonprofits</textblock>
    <textblock>currently found in 34 CFR 668.13(c), ``the institution shall not</textblock>
    <textblock>have a deficit current unrestricted fund balance'', will remain in</textblock>
    <textblock>effect until the institution adopts FAS 117.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary requests comments on whether the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>should determine a nonprofit institution to be financially</textblock>
    <textblock>responsible even if it does not meet these requirements if the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution has an acceptable ``bond rating''. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>suggests that a type of acceptable bond rating may be a current</textblock>
    <textblock>general obligation or general obligation equivalent debt rating</textblock>
    <textblock>(because such a rating is backed by the full resources of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution) by a nationally recognized debt rating organization,</textblock>
    <textblock>approved by the Secretary, that is at least investment grade.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes that a public institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>financially responsible only if the institution has its</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities backed by the full faith and credit of the State, or</textblock>
    <textblock>by an equivalent government. The Secretary is aware that</textblock>
    <textblock>accounting principles for public institutions differ from those</textblock>
    <textblock>for for-profit and nonprofit institutions. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>solicits comments on other acceptable measures of a public</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's financial responsibility that take the applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>accounting principles into account.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
