<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00028</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(c) Accept our appraisal of the crop on the damaged acreage as production to count against the production guarantee for the damaged acreage, destroy the remaining crop on such acreage, and be eligible for any indemnity due under the terms of the Common Crop Insurance Policy (§457.8) and the Small Grains Crop Provisions (§457.101). The appraisal will be considered production to count in determining any final indemnity on the unit and will be used to settle your claim as described in the provisions of section 11. (Settlement of Claim) of the Small Grains Crop Insurance Provisions (§457.101). You may use such acreage for any purpose, including planting and separately insuring any other crop. If you elect to utilize such acreage for the production of spring wheat, you must:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Plant the spring wheat in a manner which results in a clear and discernable break in the planting pattern at the boundary between it and any remaining winter wheat; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Store or market the production from such acreage in a manner which permits us to verify the amount of spring wheat production separately from any winter wheat production.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the event you are unable to provide records of production that are acceptable to us, the spring wheat acreage will be considered to be a part of the original winter wheat unit. If you elected to insure the spring wheat acreage as a separate optional unit, any premium amount for such acreage will be considered earned and payable to us.</textblock>
    <textblock>§457.103</textblock>
    <textblock>Malting barley option.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Malting Barley Option Provisions for the 1995 and succeeding crop years are as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>United States Department of Agriculture</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Crop Insurance Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>Small Grains Crop Insurance Malting Barley Endorsement</textblock>
    <textblock>(This is a continuous Endorsement. Refer to section 2 of the Common Crop Insurance Policy)</textblock>
    <textblock>In return for payment of the additional premium designated in the actuarial table, it is hereby agreed that the Common Crop Insurance Policy (§457.8) and Small Grains Crop Provisions (§457.101) are amended to incorporate the following terms and conditions:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) This Endorsement must be submitted to us on or before the final date for accepting applications for the initial crop year in which you wish to insure your malting barley acreage under this Option.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) You must have a Common Crop Insurance Policy (§457.8) and a Small Grains Crop Insurance policy (§457.101) in force and elect to insure barley under those policies.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) You must provide:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Acceptable records of the sale of malting barley for malting purposes for three of the previous five crop years by the production reporting date; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Before the acreage reporting date, written contract with a brewery or business that makes or sells malt or processed mash to a brewery, which states the quantity contracted and purchase price or method for determining such price by the acreage reporting date. Our liability under this Option will be limited to the lesser of the number of contracted bushels or your production guarantee.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) All barley acreage in the county planted to an approved malting variety in which you have a share will be insured under this Endorsement. All barley acreage of any non-malting variety will be insured under the terms of the Small Grains Endorsement. Malting barley and basic barley acreage will be separate basic units. Further unit division may be allowed in accordance with the Common Crop Insurance Policy.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Your price election will be provided by the actuarial table.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) In lieu of subparagraphs 11.(d)(2)(i)(B) and 11.(d)(1)(ii) of the Small Grains Crop Provisions:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Mature malting barley production will be reduced .12 percent for each one tenth (.1) percentage point of moisture in excess of 13.0 percent; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Mature malting barley production, which due to insurable causes, is not accepted by a buyer of malting barley and will not meet the applicable standards for two-rowed or six-rowed malting barley will be adjusted by:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Dividing the value per bushel for the insured malting barley by the price election for malting barley; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Multiplying the result not to exceed one (1.0) by the number of bushels of such barley.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) All grade determination must be made by a grader licensed to inspect barley under the United States Grain Standards Act using samples obtained by a licensed sampler or our loss adjuster. Any production which is not sampled and graded as provided by this section will be considered as malting barley meeting the applicable standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g) As used in the Endorsement:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Applicable standards_For two-rowed and six-rowed malting barley are defined in the Official United States Standards for barley.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Approved malting variety_The varieties specified in the Special Provisions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Brewery_A facility where malt liquors are commercially produced for human consumption.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Value per bushel means:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The local market price of U.S. No. 2 barley (basic barley) if the insure mature malting barley production, due to insurable causes, grades U.S. No. 4 or better and does not grade smutty, garlicky, or ergoty; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The local market price of basic barley of the same quality as the insured malting barley, if the malting barley does not grade better than U.S. No. 5.</textblock>
    <textblock>The prices used for this adjustment will be the prices on the earlier of the date such quality-adjusted barley is sold or the date of final inspection for the unit.</textblock>
    <textblock>Done in Washington, DC, on February 16, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Kenneth D. Ackerman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Federal Crop Insurance Corporation.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4230 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-08-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
