<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00133</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(ii) The responsibilities of the various offices with</textblock>
    <textblock>respect to the approval, disbursement, and delivery of Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA program assistance and the preparation and submission of</textblock>
    <textblock>reports to the Secretary;</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)(1) Administers Title IV, HEA programs with adequate</textblock>
    <textblock>checks and balances in its system of internal controls; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Divides the functions of authorizing payments and</textblock>
    <textblock>disbursing or delivering funds so that no office has</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility for both functions with respect to any particular</textblock>
    <textblock>student aided under the programs. For example, the functions of</textblock>
    <textblock>authorizing payments and disbursing or delivering funds must be</textblock>
    <textblock>divided so that for any particular student aided under the</textblock>
    <textblock>programs, the two functions are carried out by at least two</textblock>
    <textblock>organizationally independent individuals who are not members of</textblock>
    <textblock>the same family, as defined in ยง668.15, or who do not together</textblock>
    <textblock>exercise substantial control, as defined in ยง668.15, over the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Establishes and maintains records required under this</textblock>
    <textblock>part and the individual Title IV, HEA program regulations;</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Establishes, publishes, and applies reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>standards for measuring whether an otherwise eligible student is</textblock>
    <textblock>maintaining satisfactory progress in his or her educational</textblock>
    <textblock>program. The Secretary considers an institution's standards to</textblock>
    <textblock>be reasonable if the standards_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Conform with the standards of satisfactory progress of</textblock>
    <textblock>the nationally recognized accrediting agency that accredits or</textblock>
    <textblock>preaccredits the institution, if the institution is accredited</textblock>
    <textblock>or preaccredited, and if the agency has those standards;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For a student enrolled in an eligible program who is to</textblock>
    <textblock>receive assistance under a Title IV, HEA program, are the same as</textblock>
    <textblock>or stricter than the institution's standards for a student</textblock>
    <textblock>enrolled in the same educational program who is not receiving</textblock>
    <textblock>assistance under a Title IV, HEA program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Include the following elements:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Grades, work projects completed, or comparable factors</textblock>
    <textblock>that are measurable against a norm.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A maximum time frame in which a student must complete</textblock>
    <textblock>his or her educational program. The time frame must be_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Based on the student's enrollment status;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) For an undergraduate program, no longer than 150</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of the published length of the educational program; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Divided into increments, not to exceed the lesser of</textblock>
    <textblock>one academic year or one-half the published length of the</textblock>
    <textblock>educational program.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) A schedule established by the institution designating</textblock>
    <textblock>the minimum percentage or amount of work that a student must</textblock>
    <textblock>successfully complete at the end of each increment to complete</textblock>
    <textblock>his or her educational program within the maximum time frame.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) A determination at the end of each increment by the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution whether the student has successfully completed the</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate percentage or amount of work according to the</textblock>
    <textblock>established schedule.</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) Consistent application of standards to all students</textblock>
    <textblock>within categories of students, e.g., full-time, part-time,</textblock>
    <textblock>undergraduate, and graduate students, and educational programs</textblock>
    <textblock>established by the institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) Specific policies defining the effect of course</textblock>
    <textblock>incompletes, withdrawals, repetitions, and noncredit remedial</textblock>
    <textblock>courses on satisfactory progress.</textblock>
    <textblock>(vii) Specific procedures under which a student may appeal</textblock>
    <textblock>a determination that the student is not making satisfactory</textblock>
    <textblock>progress.</textblock>
    <textblock>(viii) Specific procedures for reinstatement of aid; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Meet or exceed the requirements of ยง668.7(c);</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) Develops and applies an adequate system to identify and</textblock>
    <textblock>resolve discrepancies in the information that the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>receives from different sources with respect to a student's</textblock>
    <textblock>application for financial aid under Title IV, HEA programs. In</textblock>
    <textblock>determining whether the institution's system is adequate, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary considers whether the institution obtains and</textblock>
    <textblock>reviews_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) All student aid applications, need analysis documents,</textblock>
    <textblock>Statements of Educational Purpose, Statements of Registration</textblock>
    <textblock>Status, and eligibility notification documents presented by or on</textblock>
    <textblock>behalf of each applicant;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Any documents, including any copies of State and</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal income tax returns, that are normally collected by the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to verify information received from the student or</textblock>
    <textblock>other sources; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Any other information normally available to the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution regarding a student's citizenship, previous</textblock>
    <textblock>educational experience, or other factors relating to the</textblock>
    <textblock>student's eligibility for funds under the Title IV, HEA programs;</textblock>
    <textblock>(g) Refers to the Office of Inspector General of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Education for investigation_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) After conducting the review of an application provided</textblock>
    <textblock>for under paragraph (f) of this section, any information</textblock>
    <textblock>indicating that an applicant for Title IV, HEA program assistance</textblock>
    <textblock>may have engaged in fraud or other criminal misconduct in</textblock>
    <textblock>connection with his or her application. The type of information</textblock>
    <textblock>that an institution must refer is that which is relevant to the</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility of the applicant for Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>assistance, or the amount of the assistance. Examples of this</textblock>
    <textblock>type of information are_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) False claims of independent student status;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) False claims of citizenship;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Use of false identities;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Forgery of signatures or certifications; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) False statements of income; and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
