<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-0-00003</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Official Brucellosis Tests</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>9 CFR Part 78</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93-044-2]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, USDA.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>We are amending the brucellosis regulations by adding the D-Tec</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>Brucella A test to the list of official tests for determining the brucellosis</textblock>
    <textblock>disease status of test-eligible cattle and bison. We are taking this action</textblock>
    <textblock>because the D-Tec</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>Brucella A test has exhibited a high degree of specificity</textblock>
    <textblock>in identifying</textblock>
    <textblock>Brucella abortus</textblock>
    <textblock>antibodies. Adding the D-Tec</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>Brucella A test</textblock>
    <textblock>to the list of official tests for brucellosis in cattle and bison will help</textblock>
    <textblock>prevent the spread of the disease by making available an additional means by</textblock>
    <textblock>which animal health personnel may obtain timely and accurate diagnoses of</textblock>
    <textblock>brucellosis.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 30, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. John D. Kopec, Senior Staff</textblock>
    <textblock>Veterinarian, Cattle Diseases and Surveillance Staff, Veterinary Services,</textblock>
    <textblock>APHIS, USDA, room 731, Federal Building, 6505 Belcrest Road, Hyattsville, MD</textblock>
    <textblock>20782, (301) 436-6188.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>Brucellosis is an infectious disease of animals and humans caused by</textblock>
    <textblock>bacteria of the genus</textblock>
    <textblock>Brucella.</textblock>
    <textblock>In its principal animal hosts_cattle,</textblock>
    <textblock>bison, and swine_brucellosis is characterized by abortion and impaired</textblock>
    <textblock>fertility. The regulations in 9 CFR part 78 (referred to below as the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations) govern the interstate movement of cattle, bison, and swine in</textblock>
    <textblock>order to help prevent the spread of brucellosis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Official brucellosis tests are used to determine the brucellosis disease</textblock>
    <textblock>status of cattle, bison, and swine. The regulations stipulate that certain</textblock>
    <textblock>cattle, bison, and swine must, among other requirements, test negative to an</textblock>
    <textblock>official brucellosis test prior to interstate movement. Official brucellosis</textblock>
    <textblock>tests are also used to determine eligibility for indemnity payments for</textblock>
    <textblock>animals destroyed because of brucellosis. In §78.1 of the regulations, the</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of official test lists those tests that have been designated as</textblock>
    <textblock>official tests for determining the brucellosis disease status of cattle,</textblock>
    <textblock>bison, and swine.</textblock>
    <textblock>On September 27, 1993, we published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR</textblock>
    <textblock>50290-50291, Docket No. 93-044-1) a proposal to amend the regulations by</textblock>
    <textblock>adding the D-Tec</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>Brucella A test to the list of official tests for</textblock>
    <textblock>determining the brucellosis disease status of test-eligible cattle and bison.</textblock>
    <textblock>We solicited comments concerning our proposal for a 30-day comment</textblock>
    <textblock>period ending October 27, 1993. We received one comment by that date, from a</textblock>
    <textblock>veterinary medical association. The commenter supported our proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, based on the rationale set forth in the proposed rule, we are</textblock>
    <textblock>adopting the provisions of the proposal as a final rule without change.</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12866 and Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule has been reviewed under Executive Order 12866.</textblock>
    <textblock>The rule change will not add any costs for agricultural producers. It</textblock>
    <textblock>will, however, benefit farmers and ranchers who, without access to this or the</textblock>
    <textblock>other available diagnostic tests, quarantine or destroy animals on the basis</textblock>
    <textblock>of ``false positive'' reactions to presumptive tests. We estimate that between</textblock>
    <textblock>200 and 300 animals are unnecessarily slaughtered or quarantined each year</textblock>
    <textblock>after having falsely tested positive on presumptive tests. These losses could</textblock>
    <textblock>be prevented by the use of diagnostic tests. The addition of the D-Tec</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>Brucella A test as an official test will prevent losses to farmers and</textblock>
    <textblock>ranchers if they opt to use it. While losses resulting from false positives</textblock>
    <textblock>affect only a few farmers and ranchers each year, this rule could modestly</textblock>
    <textblock>benefit all those entities that avail themselves of the D-Tec</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>Brucella A</textblock>
    <textblock>test.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule is expected to have a beneficial effect on the producer of the</textblock>
    <textblock>D-Tec</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>Brucella A test and a negligible negative impact on the only other</textblock>
    <textblock>producer of diagnostic tests. Both producers are small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under these circumstances, the Administrator of the Animal and Plant</textblock>
    <textblock>Health Inspection Service has determined that this action will not have a</textblock>
    <textblock>significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12372</textblock>
    <textblock>This program/activity is listed in the Catalog of Federal Domestic</textblock>
    <textblock>Assistance under No. 10.025 and is subject to Executive Order 12372, which</textblock>
    <textblock>requires intergovernmental consultation with State and local officials. (See</textblock>
    <textblock>7 CFR part 3015, subpart V.)</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
