<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00098</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to include as a specific</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative standard the requirement that an institution have</textblock>
    <textblock>no outstanding liabilities owed to the Secretary unless the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution has made satisfactory arrangements to repay those</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities and is honoring those arrangements. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>believes that unless a participating institution demonstrates it</textblock>
    <textblock>has met all its programmatic, contractual, and fiscal obligations</textblock>
    <textblock>in the past, and has taken positive steps to rectify problems and</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities in the past, there is no reason to presume that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution has the capability and willingness to administer the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs responsibly in the future.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to take into account whether</textblock>
    <textblock>significant problems have been identified in final reports and</textblock>
    <textblock>determinations issued by the Secretary, the OIG, accrediting</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies, SPREs, guaranty agencies, and State authorizing</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies and findings in criminal, civil, or administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>proceedings, in addition to financial and compliance audit</textblock>
    <textblock>reports and program review reports, in assessing an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability. The Secretary believes that pertinent</textblock>
    <textblock>information from any of the agencies or proceedings identified is</textblock>
    <textblock>relevant to determining whether an institution is</textblock>
    <textblock>administratively capable. An institution should be considered</textblock>
    <textblock>administratively capable only if there is no evidence of</textblock>
    <textblock>significant problems in those reviews or proceedings.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add to the administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>capability standards, the prohibition against debarments,</textblock>
    <textblock>suspensions, and causes of debarment or suspension under E.O.</textblock>
    <textblock>12549 and the FAR, 48 CFR subpart 9.4. The Secretary proposes to</textblock>
    <textblock>amend this section to provide that an institution would not be</textblock>
    <textblock>considered administratively capable if (1) cause exists for</textblock>
    <textblock>debarring the institution under 34 CFR 85.305, or for suspending</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution under 34 CFR 85.405, (2) any principal (as that</textblock>
    <textblock>term is used in 34 CFR part 85) of the institution is debarred or</textblock>
    <textblock>suspended, or (3) the institution is an affiliate (as that term</textblock>
    <textblock>is used in 34 CFR part 85) of any person so debarred or</textblock>
    <textblock>suspended. Under these changes, the Secretary would not certify</textblock>
    <textblock>the administrative capability of an institution that fits into</textblock>
    <textblock>any of these categories. The Secretary would not permit such an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to begin participation in a Title IV, HEA program,</textblock>
    <textblock>and the Secretary would require a participating institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>rectify the problem that adversely affects the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability. A participating institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>inability or unwillingness to rectify the problem would warrant</textblock>
    <textblock>initiation of an emergency action, limitation, suspension, or</textblock>
    <textblock>termination proceeding against the institution under subpart G.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary expects that such a proceeding would be combined</textblock>
    <textblock>with a debarment or suspension proceeding under 34 CFR part 85.</textblock>
    <textblock>These changes are needed to establish appropriate safeguards</textblock>
    <textblock>to protect the Title IV, HEA programs when serious questions are</textblock>
    <textblock>raised about the honesty and lawfulness of the conduct of an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's owners, officers, directors, management, employees,</textblock>
    <textblock>or affiliates whose duties involve the administration of or</textblock>
    <textblock>influence over those programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to require that an institution comply</textblock>
    <textblock>with any standards regarding completion and placement rates and</textblock>
    <textblock>pass rates on State licensing examinations established by the</textblock>
    <textblock>State in which an institution is located as a standard of</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability. The Secretary supports the</textblock>
    <textblock>development of appropriate standards by each State, as individual</textblock>
    <textblock>States will be able to address local concerns and conditions in</textblock>
    <textblock>the development of standards. In the absence of such a State</textblock>
    <textblock>standard, the Secretary believes an institution must comply with</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate standards regarding completion rates, placement rates</textblock>
    <textblock>and pass rates on required State examinations, as established by</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary, in consultation with institutions located in the</textblock>
    <textblock>State.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to require as a standard for full</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the Title IV, HEA programs that institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>have default rates that do not exceed 20 percent for the Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Stafford Loan and Federal SLS programs, and default rates that do</textblock>
    <textblock>not exceed 15 percent for the Federal Perkins Loan program. For</textblock>
    <textblock>the Federal Stafford Loan and Federal SLS programs, a 20 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>trigger is currently used as an indicator of impaired</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability. For the Federal Perkins Loan program,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary has used a 20 percent trigger as an indicator of</textblock>
    <textblock>impaired administrative capability. The Secretary is proposing</textblock>
    <textblock>to change this figure to 15 percent for consistency with the</textblock>
    <textblock>statutory requirement of section 461(g) of the HEA that requires</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution with a cohort default rate of 15 percent in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Perkins Loan program to establish a default management</textblock>
    <textblock>plan pursuant to regulations. Under this proposal, institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>applying for participation under a change of ownership or for a</textblock>
    <textblock>renewal of their participation with default rates exceeding these</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed amounts would be provisionally certified for a lack of</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability if no other serious administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>capability problems were identified that warranted denying the</textblock>
    <textblock>application. The Secretary notes that, under this proposal, an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution applying for a renewal of participation that has a</textblock>
    <textblock>default rate under the Federal Stafford Loan programs that</textblock>
    <textblock>exceeds 20 percent could submit information demonstrating</textblock>
    <textblock>mitigating circumstances as provided in ยง668.15 of current</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations to demonstrate that the institution's default rate is</textblock>
    <textblock>not a basis for denial of full participation. If no other</textblock>
    <textblock>serious administrative capability problems were identified that</textblock>
    <textblock>warrant denying the application for full participation, an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution with default rates over these triggers could receive</textblock>
    <textblock>full participation if it successfully showed that those</textblock>
    <textblock>mitigating circumstances existed.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
