<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00164</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>2. What supporting information should be submitted to establish</textblock>
    <textblock>that an institution has the administrative resources to comply</textblock>
    <textblock>with its program responsibilities?</textblock>
    <textblock>•The financial information concerning each branch campus</textblock>
    <textblock>of an institution should be evaluated, without simply</textblock>
    <textblock>relying on the financial information of an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>as a whole. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Employee biographies with social security numbers</textblock>
    <textblock>should be provided. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>3. What level of financial resources are needed to demonstrate</textblock>
    <textblock>that an institution can meet potential refund and repayment</textblock>
    <textblock>obligations, and should institutions be required to set aside</textblock>
    <textblock>funds for these purposes?</textblock>
    <textblock>•An institution should be able to provide for the</textblock>
    <textblock>payment of refunds that could occur over a 30-day</textblock>
    <textblock>period, but the institution should not be required to</textblock>
    <textblock>set aside funds specifically for this purpose.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Kansas City]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The statutory provisions for institutions to maintain</textblock>
    <textblock>cash reserves unless they are covered by State tuition</textblock>
    <textblock>recovery plans should be sufficient. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•No requirements are necessary. The Department should</textblock>
    <textblock>have the discretion to review and establish amounts</textblock>
    <textblock>when necessary. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Section 498(c)(2) requires that, notwithstanding section</textblock>
    <textblock>498(c)(1), if an institution fails to meet the criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>prescribed by the Secretary with respect to operating losses, net</textblock>
    <textblock>worth, asset-to-liabilities ratios, or operating fund deficits,</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution must provide the Secretary with satisfactory</textblock>
    <textblock>evidence of its financial responsibility in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>section 498(c)(3).</textblock>
    <textblock>Issues that the community was asked to address and the</textblock>
    <textblock>community's views:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. What standards should be set for each of these criteria?</textblock>
    <textblock>•One standard should not be applicable to all</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Institutions should be allowed to explain their</textblock>
    <textblock>financial statements before decisions in this area are</textblock>
    <textblock>reached. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The institutions financial condition should be examined</textblock>
    <textblock>over a certain time period so that decisions regarding</textblock>
    <textblock>its financial responsibility are based on a trend.</textblock>
    <textblock>[New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•The Department should particularly consider an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's statement of cash flow. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Ratios that are used to measure stability in the</textblock>
    <textblock>business world should be used. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Current standards should be used with Departmental</textblock>
    <textblock>discretion. [San Francisco]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Standards for these criteria should be: a ratio of</textblock>
    <textblock>assets to liabilities of 1:1, showing a positive net</textblock>
    <textblock>worth, and not having two consecutive years of negative</textblock>
    <textblock>operating cash flow or its equivalent for fund</textblock>
    <textblock>accounting purposes. These should be indicators of</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility, not absolute minimums. The</textblock>
    <textblock>importance of each criteria should be given its proper</textblock>
    <textblock>weight. [Atlanta]</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Section 498(c)(3) provides that the Secretary may find an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to be financially responsible, notwithstanding</textblock>
    <textblock>failure under 498(c)(1) and 498(c)(2), if the institution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Provides third-party guarantees of at least one-half of</textblock>
    <textblock>annual potential liabilities, (2) is backed by the full faith and</textblock>
    <textblock>credit of a State or its equivalent, (3) establishes that it is a</textblock>
    <textblock>going concern capable of meeting all its obligations, or (4) has</textblock>
    <textblock>met comparable standards set by the Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issues that the community was asked to address and the</textblock>
    <textblock>community's views:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. What type of third-party guarantees will be acceptable to</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Acceptable third-party guarantees should include bonds,</textblock>
    <textblock>institutional collateral, or a tuition recovery fund. [New York]</textblock>
    <textblock>•Acceptable third-party guarantees should include</textblock>
    <textblock>performance bonds, letters of credit, or other</textblock>
    <textblock>comparable instruments. [Kansas City, Atlanta]</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
