<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00072</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(4) The institution would divide the number of students</textblock>
    <textblock>determined in item (3) of this section by the total obtained</textblock>
    <textblock>under item (2).</textblock>
    <textblock>The institution must maintain documentation that each</textblock>
    <textblock>student described in item (3) above, obtained gainful employment</textblock>
    <textblock>in an occupation for which he or she was trained or in a related</textblock>
    <textblock>occupation. Examples of satisfactory documentation of a</textblock>
    <textblock>student's gainful employment include, but are not limited to_</textblock>
    <textblock>•A written statement from the student's employer;</textblock>
    <textblock>•Signed copies of State or Federal income tax forms; and</textblock>
    <textblock>•Written evidence of payments of Social Security taxes.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary believes that requiring institutions to</textblock>
    <textblock>collect this data will help curb abuse by institutions that may</textblock>
    <textblock>overstate their placement rates in order to achieve and maintain</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility for short-term programs. Furthermore, to further</textblock>
    <textblock>avoid potential abuse, the Secretary proposes that in certifying</textblock>
    <textblock>the accuracy of an institution's placement rate, as required</textblock>
    <textblock>under §668.8(e)(2), the institution's auditor should review the</textblock>
    <textblock>above types of documentation collected by the institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>verify each student's inclusion in the placement rate</textblock>
    <textblock>calculation.</textblock>
    <textblock>The statute provides that the Secretary may prescribe other</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations to determine the quality of these programs. Under</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed §668.8(e)(1)(iii), to be eligible, programs less than</textblock>
    <textblock>600 clock hours in length may not exceed by more than 50 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>the minimum number of clock hours required for training in the</textblock>
    <textblock>recognized occupation for which the program prepares students, as</textblock>
    <textblock>established by the State in which the program is offered, if the</textblock>
    <textblock>State has established such a requirement. For example, if a</textblock>
    <textblock>State requires security guard students to complete only 300 clock</textblock>
    <textblock>hours of training, a security guard program in that state will</textblock>
    <textblock>not be eligible if it exceeds 450 clock hours. The Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>believes this regulation will help curb abuse of the programs by</textblock>
    <textblock>preventing institutions from providing unnecessary training to</textblock>
    <textblock>students in order to receive additional Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §668.8(e)(1)(iv) requires that to be eligible,</textblock>
    <textblock>programs less than 600 clock hours must have been in existence</textblock>
    <textblock>for at least one full year. The Secretary believes that this</textblock>
    <textblock>time frame is necessary so programs may demonstrate the</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate completion and placement rates. Institutions will be</textblock>
    <textblock>required under 34 CFR 600 to apply for eligibility of these</textblock>
    <textblock>programs after the one-year requirement is satisfied.</textblock>
    <textblock>English as a Second Language</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to the elements already in place in the current</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations regarding English as a Second Language (ESL)</textblock>
    <textblock>programs, §668.8(j)(2) proposes that in order for an ESL program</textblock>
    <textblock>to be eligible, the institution must test each student at the end</textblock>
    <textblock>of the program to substantiate that the student has attained</textblock>
    <textblock>adequate proficiency in written and spoken English to use already</textblock>
    <textblock>existing knowledge, training or skills. The institution will</textblock>
    <textblock>also be required to identify the test it gives to the students</textblock>
    <textblock>and the basis for the judgment that the student has attained the</textblock>
    <textblock>adequate proficiency. This proposal, based on California law,</textblock>
    <textblock>was suggested during the negotiation process as a method to stem</textblock>
    <textblock>abuse by institutions which offer ESL programs. As established</textblock>
    <textblock>by the current regulations, ESL programs which qualify as</textblock>
    <textblock>eligible programs are eligible for purposes of the Federal Pell</textblock>
    <textblock>Grant program only. This provision remains unchanged.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart B_Standards for Participation in the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.12␣Application Procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to add a new §668.12 to codify the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's current practices with regard to applications to</textblock>
    <textblock>participate or to continue to participate in a Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program. This section also would include proposed procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>whereby the Secretary codifies new statutory provisions governing</textblock>
    <textblock>applications to participate or to continue to participate in a</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 498(b) of the HEA requires the Secretary to develop</textblock>
    <textblock>a single application form to be used by an institution that</textblock>
    <textblock>wishes to apply to participate or to continue to participate in a</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program. The statute requires that this form</textblock>
    <textblock>provide for the collection of various information and</textblock>
    <textblock>documentation. First, the form must require an institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide sufficient information and documentation to determine</textblock>
    <textblock>that the requirements of institutional eligibility,</textblock>
    <textblock>accreditation, and the capability of the institution are met.</textblock>
    <textblock>Second, the form must require an institution to describe the</textblock>
    <textblock>relationship between a main campus of an institution and all of</textblock>
    <textblock>its branches. In particular, the form must require an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to include a description of the student aid</textblock>
    <textblock>processing that is performed by the main campus and that which is</textblock>
    <textblock>performed at its branches. Third, the form must require an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to describe all third-party servicers of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution and supply a copy of any contract with a third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicer. Finally, the form must require an institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>provide any other information that the Secretary determines will</textblock>
    <textblock>ensure compliance with Title IV, HEA program requirements with</textblock>
    <textblock>respect to eligibility, accreditation, administrative capability</textblock>
    <textblock>and financial responsibility.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
