<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00082</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Amendments of 1992 provide that an institution may not</textblock>
    <textblock>impose any penalty on any student because of the student's</textblock>
    <textblock>inability to meet his or her financial obligations to the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution as a result of the delayed disbursement of a</textblock>
    <textblock>title IV, HEA program loan due to compliance with statutory and</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory requirements for the Title IV, HEA programs, or delays</textblock>
    <textblock>attributable to the institution. The statute specifies that</textblock>
    <textblock>those prohibited penalties include the assessment of late fees,</textblock>
    <textblock>the denial of access to classes, libraries, or other</textblock>
    <textblock>institutional facilities, or the requirement that the student</textblock>
    <textblock>borrow additional funds. The Secretary proposes to clarify that</textblock>
    <textblock>the restriction that institutions may not require a student to</textblock>
    <textblock>borrow additional funds would apply only to funds for which</textblock>
    <textblock>interest or other charges are assessed. Therefore, this</textblock>
    <textblock>provision would not apply to any interest-free loans that the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution might require the student to borrow until other</textblock>
    <textblock>sources of aid are available.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Amendments of 1992 provide that an institution may not</textblock>
    <textblock>provide any commission, bonus, or other incentive payment based</textblock>
    <textblock>directly or indirectly on success in securing enrollments or</textblock>
    <textblock>financial aid to any persons or entities engaged in any student</textblock>
    <textblock>recruiting or admission activities. An institution also may not</textblock>
    <textblock>provide such an incentive payment to any persons or entities</textblock>
    <textblock>engaged in making decisions regarding the awarding of student</textblock>
    <textblock>financial assistance. The statute specifies that this</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement does not apply to the recruitment of foreign students</textblock>
    <textblock>residing in foreign countries who are not eligible to receive</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal student assistance. The Secretary proposes to extend</textblock>
    <textblock>this provision to require that institutions also may not contract</textblock>
    <textblock>with entities that improperly provide, any commission, bonus, or</textblock>
    <textblock>other incentive payment as delineated in the statute. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes that this provision is necessary to implement</textblock>
    <textblock>more rigid restrictions than were seen in the past on the</textblock>
    <textblock>practices of ``commissioned salespersons.'' The Secretary proposes</textblock>
    <textblock>to repeat the language of the statute with the addition of this</textblock>
    <textblock>change. The Secretary believes it is clear that this statutory</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement places rigid restrictions on the practice of</textblock>
    <textblock>recruitment, admission activities, and the awarding of student</textblock>
    <textblock>financial assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary is aware that some institutions pay incentives</textblock>
    <textblock>to recruiters or admissions office employees based on the success</textblock>
    <textblock>of those persons in enrolling students, provided that the</textblock>
    <textblock>enrolled students maintain satisfactory progress for and remain</textblock>
    <textblock>enrolled in the institution for a specified period of time. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary considers this practice, which commonly is referred to</textblock>
    <textblock>as an incentive based on ``retention,'' to be an example of an</textblock>
    <textblock>activity that is prohibited by the statute.</textblock>
    <textblock>During the negotiated rulemaking sessions, the Secretary's</textblock>
    <textblock>negotiator requested further examples of prohibited activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>A non-Federal negotiator offered the following examples that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes are not permitted by the statute. (1) An</textblock>
    <textblock>institution might offer payments or gifts to students for</textblock>
    <textblock>referring other prospective students for admission to the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution. (2) An institution might offer payments or gifts to</textblock>
    <textblock>students on the condition that persons whom the students referred</textblock>
    <textblock>to the institution were actually admitted and remained enrolled</textblock>
    <textblock>in the institution for a specified period of time. (3) An</textblock>
    <textblock>institution might present gifts to alumni, such as coffee mugs,</textblock>
    <textblock>sporting events tickets, or contributions in their name for</textblock>
    <textblock>referring students to the institution for admission. (4) An</textblock>
    <textblock>institution might pay bonuses to Directors of Admissions (or</textblock>
    <textblock>other management personnel) based on the number of enrollments</textblock>
    <textblock>received during a particular academic year or the number of</textblock>
    <textblock>students who, after enrolling, remained at the institution until</textblock>
    <textblock>all financial aid had been received. The Secretary specifically</textblock>
    <textblock>requests comments on these examples and others that might serve</textblock>
    <textblock>as useful guidelines in these regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Amendments of 1992 require that an institution comply</textblock>
    <textblock>with applicable requirements established by all members of the</textblock>
    <textblock>``triad''; i.e., the Secretary, State postsecondary review</textblock>
    <textblock>entities, and nationally recognized accrediting agencies pursuant</textblock>
    <textblock>to part H of title IV of the HEA. The Secretary considers this</textblock>
    <textblock>provision to be self-explanatory and proposes to add this</textblock>
    <textblock>statutory requirement to the regulations without substantive</textblock>
    <textblock>modifications.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
