<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00078</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>An institution in these categories could only be</textblock>
    <textblock>provisionally certified if, in addition to meeting whatever</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions the Secretary might reasonably require of a</textblock>
    <textblock>provisionally certified institution, the institution satisfied</textblock>
    <textblock>one of the following conditions. First, the institution, or one</textblock>
    <textblock>or more persons or entities that the Secretary determines to</textblock>
    <textblock>exercise substantial control over the institution, or both, would</textblock>
    <textblock>have to submit to the Secretary financial guarantees in an amount</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by the Secretary to be sufficient to satisfy the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's potential liabilities arising from the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation in the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Second, one or more persons or entities that the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>determines to exercise substantial control over the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>would have to agree to be jointly or severally liable for any</textblock>
    <textblock>liabilities arising from the institution's participation in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs and any civil and criminal monetary</textblock>
    <textblock>penalties authorized under Title IV of the HEA. The law permits</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary to impose these conditions on these institutions;</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary is announcing that he would always impose them,</textblock>
    <textblock>because these circumstances are indicative that extra protection</textblock>
    <textblock>is needed for the institution and their students to be permitted</textblock>
    <textblock>to benefit from the use of Title IV, HEA program funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Generally, provisional certification may be granted for a</textblock>
    <textblock>period of no longer than three award years. In accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>section 498(h) of the HEA, an institution that is applying for</textblock>
    <textblock>initial participation may be provisionally certified for a period</textblock>
    <textblock>of no longer than one award year. A participating institution</textblock>
    <textblock>that was accredited or preaccredited by a nationally recognized</textblock>
    <textblock>accrediting agency on the day before the Secretary withdrew the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's recognition of that agency may be provisionally</textblock>
    <textblock>certified for no longer than 18 months after the date that the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary withdrew that recognition. The Secretary has the</textblock>
    <textblock>authority to specify a shorter period of provisional</textblock>
    <textblock>certification, as necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 498(h) of the HEA, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>may revoke an institution's participation in the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs, at any time before the end of a period of provisional</textblock>
    <textblock>certification, if the Secretary determines that the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>is unable to meet its responsibilities under its program</textblock>
    <textblock>participation agreement. If the Secretary makes that</textblock>
    <textblock>determination, the Secretary would notify the institution of the</textblock>
    <textblock>determination by mail, unless the Secretary chooses more</textblock>
    <textblock>expeditious means, and revocation would take effect on date that</textblock>
    <textblock>notice is mailed. The institution would have to adhere to the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of proposed §668.26 which describes the consequences</textblock>
    <textblock>of revocation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the terms of the provisional certification, the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution does not have the right to a formal appeal under subpart G of this part before the revocation takes effect. However, the Secretary proposes to allow the institution to submit a written request to reconsider the revocation within 20 days of the institution's receipt of the Secretary's notice,</textblock>
    <textblock>after the revocation takes effect. The institution's request for</textblock>
    <textblock>reconsideration would have to include written evidence that the</textblock>
    <textblock>revocation is unwarranted.</textblock>
    <textblock>If the Secretary decides that the revocation is unwarranted,</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution's provisional certification would be reinstated</textblock>
    <textblock>in accordance with the time, terms, and conditions set out in the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's original provisional certification. If, after</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration of the institution's submission, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>denies the institution's request, the institution would not be</textblock>
    <textblock>permitted to reapply for participation in the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs before at least 18 months after the revocation or the</textblock>
    <textblock>expiration of any debarment or suspension of the institution,</textblock>
    <textblock>whichever is later. Generally, an institution whose</textblock>
    <textblock>participation has been terminated because the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>provisional certification was revoked would be able to apply for</textblock>
    <textblock>reinstatement after 18 months. However, a debarment or</textblock>
    <textblock>suspension under E.O. 12549 or the FAR can last 3 or more years.</textblock>
    <textblock>This change would eliminate any doubt that a debarred or</textblock>
    <textblock>suspended institution may apply for reinstatement of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's participation during the period of a debarment or</textblock>
    <textblock>suspension. The Secretary will not accept any application by a</textblock>
    <textblock>debarred or suspended institution until the debarment or</textblock>
    <textblock>suspension has expired or been removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.14␣Program Participation Agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to redesignate §668.12 as §668.14.</textblock>
    <textblock>This section includes provisions dealing with third-party</textblock>
    <textblock>servicers that were proposed in the NPRM published on</textblock>
    <textblock>February 17, 1994 (in part II). The Secretary will not repeat</textblock>
    <textblock>the discussion of those provisions here.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
