<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00076</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Secretary intends to use provisional certification as a</textblock>
    <textblock>mechanism for monitoring an institution that has not previously</textblock>
    <textblock>participated or one that has changed ownership, until it has time</textblock>
    <textblock>to establish a track record. In keeping with current practice,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary does not intend to certify any initial applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>until it has successfully completed a period of provisional</textblock>
    <textblock>certification. Because many of the requirements for</textblock>
    <textblock>certification cannot be met until an institution has participated</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Title IV, HEA programs for a period of time, an initially</textblock>
    <textblock>participating institution would still have the opportunity to</textblock>
    <textblock>participate while establishing a record that demonstrates</textblock>
    <textblock>compliance with all of the proposed current standards for</textblock>
    <textblock>participation. The Secretary notes that certain factors of</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility and administrative capability, such as</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements governing the appropriate handling of Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program funds and timely submission of required audits and other</textblock>
    <textblock>reports, cannot be judged until an institution has Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program funds to administer. In these cases, instead of</textblock>
    <textblock>certifying that an institution meets all the standards of</textblock>
    <textblock>subpart B, the Secretary certifies that an institution has</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrated that it meets all the standards it can currently and</textblock>
    <textblock>that it will be able to meet all the standards in subpart B to</textblock>
    <textblock>qualify it for full certification within a period of time</textblock>
    <textblock>specified by the Secretary. Such an institution will receive a</textblock>
    <textblock>modified program participation agreement. For the same reasons,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary also intends to use provisional certification for</textblock>
    <textblock>all institutions that undergo a change of ownership. Provisional</textblock>
    <textblock>certification would permit them to participate in Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs while demonstrating over time that they can meet the</textblock>
    <textblock>standards for participation under the new ownership.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, the HEA provides that the Secretary may use</textblock>
    <textblock>provisional certification for institutions that are currently</textblock>
    <textblock>participating who will have their financial responsibility and</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative capability determined for the first time. Some</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions have been participating in the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs since before the establishment of the financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility and administrative capability standards, and have</textblock>
    <textblock>never undergone a certification review. These institutions may</textblock>
    <textblock>be allowed the time necessary to establish that they can remedy</textblock>
    <textblock>any deficiencies found and meet the standards for participation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Finally, under the provisions of the Technical Amendments of</textblock>
    <textblock>1993, the Secretary may provisionally certify a participating</textblock>
    <textblock>institution that is undergoing a certification review if the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes that the institution is in a financial or</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative position that could jeopardize the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>ability to perform its financial responsibilities under its</textblock>
    <textblock>program participation agreement. The Secretary may provisionally</textblock>
    <textblock>certify an institution under this provision if the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>participation has been limited or suspended under subpart G of</textblock>
    <textblock>this part, or voluntarily enters into provisional certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thus, the Secretary proposes to use provisional certification as</textblock>
    <textblock>a probationary period for some participating institutions, if the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary determines that the institutions are capable of meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>the standards for full certification by the end of that period.</textblock>
    <textblock>For example, the Secretary might find that an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>applying for recertification on its own fails to meet one of the</textblock>
    <textblock>standards in proposed ยง668.15. If the Secretary determines that</textblock>
    <textblock>the failure could jeopardize the institution's ability to meet</textblock>
    <textblock>its financial responsibilities, such as the payment of refunds,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary would provisionally certify the institution.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
