<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00083</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-2-00053</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 40-8584]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Kennecott Uranium Co.; Sweetwater Uranium Mill</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of receipt of a request to amend Source Material License SUA-1350 to allow for disposal of byproduct material at Kennecott Uranium Company's Sweetwater Uranium Mill.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Proposed Action</textblock>
    <textblock>By letter dated July 21, 1993, Kennecott Uranium Company, holder of Source Material License SUA-1350 for the Sweetwater Uranium Mill, requested an amendment to License Condition No. 10.6 to allow for disposal of byproduct material from U.S. Energy's Green Mountain Ion Exchange Facility, which is being decommissioned.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Reason for Request to Amend License</textblock>
    <textblock>Kennecott Uranium Company's Sweetwater Mill is currently in a standby status. As a result, License Condition No. 10.6 limits disposal in the tailings impoundment to byproduct material in the form of debris generated by routine site maintenance. Kennecott has requested that the license condition be amended to allow for disposal of byproduct material from U.S. Energy Corporation's Green Mountain Ion Exchange Facility. This material is characterized as byproduct material as defined in 10 CFR 40.4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Upon completion of the NRC staff's review of Kennecott's request, notice of the action to be taken regarding the amendment request will be published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>with an opportunity to request a hearing, in accordance with Subpart L of 10 CFR 2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Signed in Denver, Colorado this 15th day of February 1994.</textblock>
  </action>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Ramon E. Hall,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Uranium Recovery Field Office.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4452 Filed 2-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7590-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
