<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00063</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Consequently, in the Higher Education Amendments of 1992,</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Law 102-325, (the Amendments of 1992), Congress provided for</textblock>
    <textblock>a new part H of Title IV entitled ``Program Integrity Triad.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Under that part, States and accrediting agencies are required to</textblock>
    <textblock>assume major new oversight responsibilities, and States,</textblock>
    <textblock>accrediting associations, and the Secretary are linked to create</textblock>
    <textblock>a stronger and more coordinated evaluation of institutions that</textblock>
    <textblock>participate or wish to participate in the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary believes that the most appropriate approach to this</textblock>
    <textblock>coordinated evaluation of institutions by the three components of</textblock>
    <textblock>the triad is a complementary one with each component focusing its</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluation on its obligations within the context of the HEA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thus, the focus for accrediting agencies is the quality of</textblock>
    <textblock>education or training provided by the institutions or programs</textblock>
    <textblock>they accredit. For States, which already had responsibility for</textblock>
    <textblock>determining that institutions have the legal authority to operate</textblock>
    <textblock>within the State, the HEA added a new focus: reviewing</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions that trigger certain statutory review criteria.</textblock>
    <textblock>The focus of the Secretary's evaluation of institutions is the</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative and financial capacity of those institutions to</textblock>
    <textblock>participate in the Title IV, HEA programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>The statute allocates legal responsibility among the</textblock>
    <textblock>entities that compose the program integrity triad. While the</textblock>
    <textblock>specific statutory responsibilities for the three triad entities</textblock>
    <textblock>may overlap, when viewed as a whole the triad brings together in</textblock>
    <textblock>a coordinated fashion three different but very important aspects</textblock>
    <textblock>of institutional review. Within this statutory scheme, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary has sought to assure that the gatekeeping system</textblock>
    <textblock>operates as efficiently as possible, with maximum integration</textblock>
    <textblock>among the three triad entities and without unnecessary burden on</textblock>
    <textblock>postsecondary institutions. In order to assist the Secretary in</textblock>
    <textblock>designing a final regulation that achieves these goals, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary specifically requests comment on the following</textblock>
    <textblock>questions:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) In several areas, the statute specifically requires</textblock>
    <textblock>each triad entity to evaluate an institution under the same or</textblock>
    <textblock>similar standards. For example, a SPRE and an accrediting agency</textblock>
    <textblock>may establish different standards for evaluating the financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility of an institution or for evaluating the success of</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution's educational program. Thus, a reviewed</textblock>
    <textblock>institution would need to satisfy the SPRE's and the accrediting</textblock>
    <textblock>agency's standards even though those standards address the same</textblock>
    <textblock>areas. How should final regulations be structured to both reduce</textblock>
    <textblock>the burden on institutions and enable the triad entities to carry</textblock>
    <textblock>out effectively their statutory functions?</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Should final regulations be more explicit in</textblock>
    <textblock>identifying levels, characteristics, or definitions for any of</textblock>
    <textblock>the assessment or review criteria that a triad entity is expected</textblock>
    <textblock>to consider in its evaluation of an institution?</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart 1 of part H creates a new program, the State</textblock>
    <textblock>Postsecondary Review Program, or SPRP, under which State</textblock>
    <textblock>oversight of institutions participating in the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs is strengthened. Subpart 2 of part H establishes</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures and criteria under which the Secretary recognizes an</textblock>
    <textblock>accrediting agency as a reliable authority as to the quality of</textblock>
    <textblock>the education or training offered by institutions that the agency</textblock>
    <textblock>accredits. Lastly, subpart 3 specifies the procedures the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary uses to determine whether an institution meets the</textblock>
    <textblock>eligibility requirements and has the administrative capacity and</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility to administer the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 24, 1994, the Secretary published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Register</textblock>
    <textblock>the NPRMs to implement the SPRP provisions in subpart 1</textblock>
    <textblock>of part H of the HEA (59 FR 3604) and the accrediting agency</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions in subpart 2 of part H of the HEA (59 FR 3578). The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's publication of this NPRM prior to the publication of</textblock>
    <textblock>final regulations implementing the SPRP and accreditation</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions provides the Department of Education an opportunity to</textblock>
    <textblock>coordinate all comments received on the triad.</textblock>
    <textblock>The provisions of subpart 3 that pertain to the</textblock>
    <textblock>institutional eligibility requirements found in 34 CFR part 600</textblock>
    <textblock>have been addressed in a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (NPRM)</textblock>
    <textblock>published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on February 10, 1994, that</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes changes to 34 CFR part 600. This NPRM addresses those</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions of subpart 3 that pertain to subparts A and B of 34</textblock>
    <textblock>CFR part 668. Subpart A contains definitions applicable to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA programs. Subpart B contains requirements for</textblock>
    <textblock>initial and continued participation in the programs. In</textblock>
    <textblock>particular, the following provisions in this NPRM address</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions of subpart 3: Proposed §§668.15 and 668.16 delineate</textblock>
    <textblock>the standards for the evaluation of an institution's financial</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility and administrative capability, respectively, as</textblock>
    <textblock>required by section 498(a), (c), and (d) of the HEA. Proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.15 also codifies the definition of persons who exercise</textblock>
    <textblock>substantial control of an institution found in section 498(e) of</textblock>
    <textblock>the HEA. Proposed §668.12 addresses the requirements of section</textblock>
    <textblock>498(b) of the HEA that requires the Secretary to develop a single</textblock>
    <textblock>application form to be used by institutions that wish to apply to</textblock>
    <textblock>participate or to continue to participate in a Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program. Proposed §668.13 includes the provisions governing the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement of financial guarantees from owners found in section</textblock>
    <textblock>498(e) of the HEA, addresses the provision that requires the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary to establish a schedule for the expiration of the</textblock>
    <textblock>approval of institutions to participate in the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs found in section 498(g) of the HEA, and codifies the</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions governing provisional certification of institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>found in section 498(h) of the HEA. Pursuant to sections 498(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>and (h) of the HEA, proposed §668.26 delineates the date that an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's period of participation would end, when the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's period of participation expires, or the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's provisional certification is revoked.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
