<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00102</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 668.22␣Institutional Refunds and Repayments</textblock>
    <textblock>General</textblock>
    <textblock>The Amendments of 1992 added section 484B to the HEA to</textblock>
    <textblock>require an institution to have in place, as of July 23, 1992, a</textblock>
    <textblock>fair and equitable institutional refund policy as promulgated in</textblock>
    <textblock>that section. The fair and equitable refund requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>prescribed by law are similar to the fair and equitable refund</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements prescribed by §682.606 of the FFEL program</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations for institutions that participate in the FFEL</textblock>
    <textblock>programs. The HEA extends this requirement to institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>participating in any Title IV, HEA program and makes various</textblock>
    <textblock>modifications.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under this fair and equitable refund policy, an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>must make a refund of unearned tuition, fees, room and board, and</textblock>
    <textblock>other charges to a student who received Title IV, HEA program</textblock>
    <textblock>assistance (including PLUS loans received on behalf of the</textblock>
    <textblock>student) if the student does not register for the period of</textblock>
    <textblock>enrollment for which the student was charged or if the student</textblock>
    <textblock>withdraws, drops out, or is expelled from the institution before</textblock>
    <textblock>completing the period of enrollment for which he or she was</textblock>
    <textblock>charged.</textblock>
    <textblock>The interpretation of the applicability of a fair and</textblock>
    <textblock>equitable refund policy was the subject of extensive discussions</textblock>
    <textblock>among the negotiators. The HEA specifically mandates a refund to</textblock>
    <textblock>any student who received Title IV HEA program assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, at issue during the negotiations was the fairness and</textblock>
    <textblock>equity in having a refund policy for students who receive Title</textblock>
    <textblock>IV, HEA program assistance that is different from the refund</textblock>
    <textblock>policy for those students enrolled in the same educational</textblock>
    <textblock>program who do not receive Title IV, HEA program assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Several negotiators felt that requiring institutions to apply the</textblock>
    <textblock>refund requirements found in this proposed section to all</textblock>
    <textblock>students who attend an institution would be an unauthorized</textblock>
    <textblock>intrusion by the Secretary into the administrative decisions of</textblock>
    <textblock>an institution. Many negotiators felt that compliance with a</textblock>
    <textblock>refund requirement that is applicable to all students would be</textblock>
    <textblock>too costly for an institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, the Secretary proposes to define a fair and</textblock>
    <textblock>equitable refund policy only with respect to students who receive</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program assistance. Although the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes to limit the scope of this provision to those</textblock>
    <textblock>recipients, under this proposed provision an institution would</textblock>
    <textblock>not be prohibited from adopting these refund requirements for all</textblock>
    <textblock>students.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to require that an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>provide a written statement containing its refund policy to</textblock>
    <textblock>prospective students and make its policy known to currently</textblock>
    <textblock>enrolled students. This proposal is based upon requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>currently prescribed by §682.606 of the FFEL program regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Secretary proposes to expand this FFEL provision to require</textblock>
    <textblock>that the written statement must be clear and conspicuous and must</textblock>
    <textblock>include information on the allocation of refunds and repayments</textblock>
    <textblock>to sources of aid. In keeping with current FFEL program</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations, the Secretary proposes that the written statement</textblock>
    <textblock>include examples of the application of the refund policy. This</textblock>
    <textblock>requirement would be met if the institution informs students in</textblock>
    <textblock>the written statement that examples are available and the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution makes the examples readily available to the student</textblock>
    <textblock>upon request.</textblock>
    <textblock>As in the current FFEL program regulations, the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes to require an institution to provide the written</textblock>
    <textblock>statement to prospective students. Section 668.41(b) of current</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations defines a ``prospective student'' as an individual who</textblock>
    <textblock>has contacted an institution participating in any Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program for the purpose of requesting information concerning</textblock>
    <textblock>admission to the institution. The Secretary believes that a</textblock>
    <textblock>student is a ``prospective student'' if he or she is not enrolled</textblock>
    <textblock>in an institution and has not entered into any contractual</textblock>
    <textblock>agreement or incurred a financial obligation to attend an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution. Therefore, the Secretary proposes to require an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution to provide this written statement to a student prior</textblock>
    <textblock>to the earlier of the student's enrollment or the execution of</textblock>
    <textblock>the student's enrollment agreement. If the institution's refund</textblock>
    <textblock>policy changes, the institution would have to ensure that all</textblock>
    <textblock>students are made aware of the new policy and advise the</textblock>
    <textblock>currently enrolled students of any changes that the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>intended to apply to those students for their current enrollment</textblock>
    <textblock>period.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
