<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00064</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Amendments of 1992 amended the HEA in several areas</textblock>
    <textblock>relating to the participation of institutions in the Title IV,</textblock>
    <textblock>HEA programs. The Student Assistance General Provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations contain requirements that are common to educational</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions that participate in the Title IV, HEA programs. The</textblock>
    <textblock>following list summarizes the major issues in this</textblock>
    <textblock>NPRM.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Each participating institution is subject to a new statutory</textblock>
    <textblock>definition of an academic year in which a full-time student</textblock>
    <textblock>(with respect to an undergraduate course of study), during a</textblock>
    <textblock>minimum 30-week period, must complete: At institutions that</textblock>
    <textblock>measure program length in credit hours, at least 24 semester</textblock>
    <textblock>or trimester hours or 36 quarter hours; or at institutions</textblock>
    <textblock>that measure program length in clock hours, at least 900</textblock>
    <textblock>clock hours. Section 668.2 proposes to clarify the terms</textblock>
    <textblock>used in the statutory definition of academic year.</textblock>
    <textblock>•The statute now mandates the definition of an eligible</textblock>
    <textblock>program for proprietary institutions of higher education and</textblock>
    <textblock>postsecondary vocational institutions, including</textblock>
    <textblock>``short-term'' programs (at least 300 but less than 600 clock</textblock>
    <textblock>hours) that would be eligible for the FFEL programs only.</textblock>
    <textblock>The statute requires that these programs must have</textblock>
    <textblock>completion and placement rates of at least 70 percent,</textblock>
    <textblock>measured in accordance with regulations. Section 668.8</textblock>
    <textblock>proposes methodologies for those measurements. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary eventually may propose a single methodology (based</textblock>
    <textblock>on comments on this NPRM, regulations to implement the</textblock>
    <textblock>Student Right-to-Know Act, and other NPRMs) to be used</textblock>
    <textblock>wherever appropriate in regulations for the Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>programs. In accordance with the statute, this NPRM</textblock>
    <textblock>contains further provisions to evaluate the quality of these</textblock>
    <textblock>programs, specifically a requirement proposed by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary that a program may not exceed by more than 50</textblock>
    <textblock>percent the minimum number of clock hours required by the</textblock>
    <textblock>State for training in the recognized occupation for which</textblock>
    <textblock>the program prepares students, and a requirement that a</textblock>
    <textblock>program be in existence for at least one year before</textblock>
    <textblock>applying for eligibility under these criteria.</textblock>
    <textblock>•This NPRM proposes to add two new sections to codify</textblock>
    <textblock>procedures with regard to applications to participate</textblock>
    <textblock>initially or to continue to participate in a Title IV, HEA</textblock>
    <textblock>program (proposed §668.12) and procedures by which the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary certifies that an institution meets the standards</textblock>
    <textblock>in subpart B of these regulations and accordingly may</textblock>
    <textblock>participate in a Title IV, HEA program (proposed §668.13).</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed §668.13 also includes proposed procedures whereby</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary codifies new statutory provisions governing</textblock>
    <textblock>provisional certification procedures for participation in a</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV, HEA program. Provisional certification permits</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary to allow an institution that otherwise would</textblock>
    <textblock>not qualify to participate in a Title IV, HEA program to</textblock>
    <textblock>participate on a limited basis. The institution is subject</textblock>
    <textblock>to shorter periods of participation than a fully certified</textblock>
    <textblock>institution and does not have the right to the extensive</textblock>
    <textblock>appeal proceedings under subpart G of the Student Assistance</textblock>
    <textblock>General Provisions if the Secretary revokes the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's provisional certification. Instead, as</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed by the Secretary in this NPRM, the institution</textblock>
    <textblock>would be offered a modified appeal. Further, an institution</textblock>
    <textblock>that is provisionally certified may be monitored more</textblock>
    <textblock>closely to the extent that the Secretary believes the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution warrants a greater degree of oversight.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Section 668.14 proposes to amend the regulations governing</textblock>
    <textblock>program participation agreements to include numerous new</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions added by the Amendments of 1992 and provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>previously prescribed by the HEA but not specifically</textblock>
    <textblock>spelled out in the regulations. This section also includes</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions proposed by the Secretary. This NPRM proposes to</textblock>
    <textblock>implement statutory requirements regarding disclosure of</textblock>
    <textblock>revenues and expenses for institutions that offer</textblock>
    <textblock>athletically related student aid. This NPRM would also</textblock>
    <textblock>address statutory requirements concerning incentive payments</textblock>
    <textblock>based directly or indirectly on success in securing</textblock>
    <textblock>enrollments or financial aid.</textblock>
    <textblock>•This NPRM proposes significant changes to §668.15 (currently</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.13) the section governing the evaluation of an</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's financial responsibility. The NPRM proposes</textblock>
    <textblock>to strengthen the factors used to evaluate an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility and to reflect statutory changes,</textblock>
    <textblock>including the provision that requires that any standards</textblock>
    <textblock>developed for the determination of an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>financial responsibility take into account any differences</textblock>
    <textblock>in accounting principles between for-profit and nonprofit</textblock>
    <textblock>institutions. For example, this NPRM proposes to require a</textblock>
    <textblock>for-profit institution to have a ratio of current assets to</textblock>
    <textblock>current liabilities of 1.25:1 and a nonprofit institution to</textblock>
    <textblock>have a ratio of current assets to current liabilities of</textblock>
    <textblock>1:1. As the statute requires the establishment of cash</textblock>
    <textblock>reserves sufficient to ensure repayment of any required</textblock>
    <textblock>refunds, the NPRM also proposes to require each institution</textblock>
    <textblock>to maintain a minimum cash reserve of at least 10 percent of</textblock>
    <textblock>the institution's total deferred tuition income at the end</textblock>
    <textblock>of the institution's most recent fiscal year.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
