<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00070</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Minimum Program Length</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations would also add requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>regarding the minimum length of an eligible program. Under</textblock>
    <textblock>section 481(b) of the HEA, a proprietary institution of higher</textblock>
    <textblock>education or a postsecondary vocational institution must, to be</textblock>
    <textblock>eligible, provide an eligible program, as defined in section</textblock>
    <textblock>481(e) of the HEA. Proposed §668.8(d) would implement that</textblock>
    <textblock>definition. The proposed definition would supplant the current</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory definition of a</textblock>
    <textblock>six-month training program</textblock>
    <textblock>in 34 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>600.2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 481(e) of the HEA provides for three types of</textblock>
    <textblock>eligible programs. The first type of eligible program is one</textblock>
    <textblock>that must provide at least 600 clock hours, 16 semester or</textblock>
    <textblock>trimester hours or 24 quarter hours of instruction offered during</textblock>
    <textblock>a minimum of 15 weeks. The program must provide undergraduate</textblock>
    <textblock>training that prepares a student for gainful employment in a</textblock>
    <textblock>recognized occupation. The program may admit as regular students</textblock>
    <textblock>persons who have not completed the equivalent of an associate</textblock>
    <textblock>degree.</textblock>
    <textblock>The second type of eligible program is one that must provide</textblock>
    <textblock>at least 300 clock hours, 8 semester hours, or 12 quarter hours</textblock>
    <textblock>of instruction offered during a minimum of 10 weeks. The program</textblock>
    <textblock>must provide training that prepares a student for gainful</textblock>
    <textblock>employment in a recognized occupation and be a graduate or</textblock>
    <textblock>professional program or admit as regular students only persons</textblock>
    <textblock>who have completed the equivalent of an associate degree. For</textblock>
    <textblock>the first time, this type of program may qualify for purposes of</textblock>
    <textblock>all Title IV, HEA programs, not just the FFEL programs, as under</textblock>
    <textblock>current regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The third type of eligible program would qualify for the</textblock>
    <textblock>FFEL programs only. It must provide at least 300 but less than</textblock>
    <textblock>600 clock hours of instruction offered during a minimum of 10</textblock>
    <textblock>weeks. The program must provide undergraduate training that</textblock>
    <textblock>prepares a student for gainful employment in a recognized</textblock>
    <textblock>occupation, and admit as regular students some persons who have</textblock>
    <textblock>not completed the equivalent of an associate degree. This type</textblock>
    <textblock>of program must also satisfy regulations of the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>governing placement rates, completion rates, and other criteria.</textblock>
    <textblock>These rates and criteria are discussed below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Qualitative Factors</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 481(e)(2) of the HEA requires the third type of</textblock>
    <textblock>eligible program to have a verified completion rate of at least</textblock>
    <textblock>70 percent and a verified placement rate of at least 70 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>in accordance with the Secretary's regulations and to meet other</textblock>
    <textblock>criteria specified by the Secretary in regulations. Proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.8(e) would implement these provisions. Proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>§668.8(e)(2) would require an institution to substantiate the</textblock>
    <textblock>calculation of its completion and placement rates by having its</textblock>
    <textblock>independent auditor who prepares its compliance audit report</textblock>
    <textblock>under §668.23 verify the accuracy of the calculations. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes that the auditor's assurance of these</textblock>
    <textblock>calculations would be a reliable independent substantiation. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary also believes it is practical for an auditor to check</textblock>
    <textblock>this information, inasmuch as he or she is already on site to</textblock>
    <textblock>perform the institution's required compliance audit.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 668.8 would include formulas in paragraphs (f) and</textblock>
    <textblock>(g) for calculating the appropriate completion and placement</textblock>
    <textblock>rates. The Secretary believes a single methodology is desired,</textblock>
    <textblock>and invites comments in this area. The Secretary notes that an</textblock>
    <textblock>NPRM implementing the Student Right-to-Know provisions in section</textblock>
    <textblock>485(a) of the HEA, which addressed the calculation of completion</textblock>
    <textblock>or graduation rates, was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on</textblock>
    <textblock>July 10, 1992 (57 FR 30826). The Secretary will be publishing a</textblock>
    <textblock>second NPRM for implementation of the Student Right-to-Know</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions shortly after publication of this NPRM to further</textblock>
    <textblock>address this calculation. The Secretary would also like to know</textblock>
    <textblock>if any proposals relative to the Student Right-to-Know Act</textblock>
    <textblock>regarding graduation and completion rate calculations should be</textblock>
    <textblock>used instead of the methods proposed here. The proposed formulas</textblock>
    <textblock>would be based on the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>Award Year</textblock>
    <textblock>All calculations would be based on enrollments, completions,</textblock>
    <textblock>and placements during an award year. Thus, an applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>completion or placement rate would be the rate as it existed at</textblock>
    <textblock>the end of a particular award year.</textblock>
    <textblock>Calculation of Completion Rate</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) An institution would base its calculation on the number</textblock>
    <textblock>of regular students who were enrolled in the program during the</textblock>
    <textblock>award year. The rate calculation is based on regular students</textblock>
    <textblock>because those students by definition intend to complete a</textblock>
    <textblock>program. The Secretary believes that inclusion of other students</textblock>
    <textblock>would not provide an accurate picture of the institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>completion rate.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The institution would subtract from the number of</textblock>
    <textblock>regular students the number of those students who, during that</textblock>
    <textblock>award year, withdrew from, dropped out of, or were expelled from</textblock>
    <textblock>the program and were entitled to and actually received in a</textblock>
    <textblock>timely manner in accordance with §668.22(i)(3) a refund of 100</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of their tuition and fees (less any permitted</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative fee) under the institution's refund policy. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary believes that the inclusion of students who have</textblock>
    <textblock>received a 100 percent refund at an institution would unduly</textblock>
    <textblock>penalize the institution because these students would not have</textblock>
    <textblock>participated in the academic component of an institution's</textblock>
    <textblock>program. These students are excluded from the calculation</textblock>
    <textblock>because there would not be a loss of Title IV, HEA program funds</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Department of Education if the institution has refunded</textblock>
    <textblock>all tuition and fees.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The institution would subtract the number of students</textblock>
    <textblock>who were enrolled in the program at the end of that award year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The institution would determine the number of regular</textblock>
    <textblock>students who, during that award year, received the degree,</textblock>
    <textblock>certificate or other recognized education credential awarded for</textblock>
    <textblock>successfully completing the program.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
