<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00138</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940228-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(6) The Secretary withdraws the notification of loss of</textblock>
    <textblock>participation in the FFEL programs sent to an institution under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (c)(1) of this section, if the Secretary determines</textblock>
    <textblock>that the institution's appeal satisfies one of the grounds</textblock>
    <textblock>specified in paragraphs (d)(1) (i) through (iii) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) (i) An institution that appeals under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (d)(1)(i) of this section must submit a written request</textblock>
    <textblock>to the guaranty agency or agencies that guaranteed the loans used</textblock>
    <textblock>in the calculation of its cohort default rate to verify the data</textblock>
    <textblock>used to calculate its cohort default rate and simultaneously</textblock>
    <textblock>provide a copy of that request to the Secretary's designated</textblock>
    <textblock>Department official.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The written request must include the names and social</textblock>
    <textblock>security numbers of the borrowers the institution wishes the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency to verify and detailed information on the nature of the</textblock>
    <textblock>suspected inaccuracy in the data the institution is requesting</textblock>
    <textblock>the agency to verify.</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) An institution must include in its appeal a</textblock>
    <textblock>certification by the institution's chief executive officer that</textblock>
    <textblock>all information provided by the institution in support of its</textblock>
    <textblock>appeal is true and correct.</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) An institution that appeals on the ground that it meets</textblock>
    <textblock>the criteria contained in paragraph (d)(1)(iii) of this section</textblock>
    <textblock>must include in its appeal the following information:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) For purposes of paragraph (d)(1)(iii)(A)(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The number of students who were enrolled on at least a</textblock>
    <textblock>half-time basis at the institution in the relevant twenty-four</textblock>
    <textblock>month period; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The name, address, and social security number of each</textblock>
    <textblock>of the institution's current and former students who received</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Stafford or Federal SLS loans during that twenty-four</textblock>
    <textblock>month period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) For purposes of paragraph (d)(1)(iii)(A)(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The number of students who were enrolled on at least a</textblock>
    <textblock>half-time basis at the institution in the relevant twenty-four</textblock>
    <textblock>month period; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The name, address, social security number and Expected</textblock>
    <textblock>Family Contribution (EFC) (formerly institutions were required to</textblock>
    <textblock>use the Pell Grant index), if applicable, of each student from a</textblock>
    <textblock>disadvantaged economic background who was enrolled on at least a</textblock>
    <textblock>half-time basis at the institution in the relevant twenty-four</textblock>
    <textblock>month period and the measure and data used to determine that the</textblock>
    <textblock>student is from a disadvantaged economic background.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) For purposes of paragraph (d)(1)(iii)(B)(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The number of students who were enrolled on a full-time</textblock>
    <textblock>basis at the institution in the relevant twenty-four month</textblock>
    <textblock>period;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) For each of those former students who received a</textblock>
    <textblock>degree, certificate, or other recognized educational credential</textblock>
    <textblock>from the institution, the student's name, address, and social</textblock>
    <textblock>security number;</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) For each of those former students who transferred to a</textblock>
    <textblock>higher level educational program at another institution, the</textblock>
    <textblock>name, address, social security number of the student, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>name and address of the institution to which the student</textblock>
    <textblock>transferred and the name of the higher level program; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) For each of those students who remained enrolled and</textblock>
    <textblock>was making satisfactory academic progress toward completion of</textblock>
    <textblock>the educational program, the student's name, address, and social</textblock>
    <textblock>security number.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) For purposes of paragraph (d)(1)(iii)(B)(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The number of students who received a degree,</textblock>
    <textblock>certificate, or other recognized educational credential at the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution in the relevant twenty-four month period;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) For each of those former students who is employed or</textblock>
    <textblock>had been employed for at least 13 weeks following receipt of a</textblock>
    <textblock>degree, certificate or other credential from the institution, the</textblock>
    <textblock>student's name, address, and social security number, the</textblock>
    <textblock>employer's name and address, the student's job title, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>dates the student was so employed; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) For each of those former students who enrolled in a</textblock>
    <textblock>higher level educational program at another institution for which</textblock>
    <textblock>the appealing institution's educational program provided</textblock>
    <textblock>substantial preparation, the former student's name, address, and</textblock>
    <textblock>social security number, the subsequent institution's name and</textblock>
    <textblock>address, the name of the educational program, and the dates the</textblock>
    <textblock>former student was so enrolled.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following definitions apply to this</textblock>
    <textblock>section and ยง668.90:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)(i)(A) For purposes of the Federal Stafford loan and</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal SLS cohort default rate, except as provided in paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)(1)(ii) of this section, the term</textblock>
    <textblock>cohort default rate</textblock>
    <textblock>means_</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) For any fiscal year in which 30 or more current and</textblock>
    <textblock>former students at the institution enter repayment on Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Stafford loans or Federal SLS loans (or on the portion of a</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Consolidation Loan that is used to repay such loans)</textblock>
    <textblock>received for attendance at the institution, the percentage of</textblock>
    <textblock>those current and former students who enter repayment in that</textblock>
    <textblock>fiscal year on such loans who default before the end of the</textblock>
    <textblock>following fiscal year; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) For any fiscal year in which fewer than 30 of the</textblock>
    <textblock>institution's current and former students enter repayment on</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Stafford loans or Federal SLS loans (or on the portion of</textblock>
    <textblock>a Federal Consolidation Loan that is used to repay such loans)</textblock>
    <textblock>received for attendance at the institution, the percentage of</textblock>
    <textblock>those current and former students who entered repayment on</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Stafford loans or Federal SLS loans in any of the three</textblock>
    <textblock>most recent fiscal years, who default before the end of the</textblock>
    <textblock>fiscal year immediately following the year in which they entered</textblock>
    <textblock>repayment.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
