<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-1-00063</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(3) The agency has established and implemented guidelines for each member of the decision-making body to avoid conflicts of interest in making decisions;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The agency's dues are paid separately from any dues paid to any related, associated, or affiliated trade association or membership organization; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) The agency's budget is developed and determined by the agency without review by or consultation with any other entity or organization.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) The Secretary considers that any joint use of personnel, services, equipment, or facilities by an accrediting agency and a related, associated, or affiliated trade association or membership organization does not violate the provisions of paragraph (c) of this section if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The agency pays the fair market value for its proportionate share of the joint use; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The joint use does not compromise the independence and confidentiality of the accreditation process.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)(1) Upon request of an accrediting agency described in paragraph (b)(4) of this section, the Secretary waives the ``separate and independent'' requirements of this section if the agency demonstrates that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The agency has been listed by the Secretary as a nationally recognized agency on or before October 1, 1991; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The existing relationship between the agency and the related, associated, or affiliated trade association or membership organization does not compromise the independence of the accreditation process.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) To demonstrate that the existing relationship between the agency and the related, associated, or affiliated trade association or membership organization does not compromise the independence of the accreditation process, the agency must show that_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The related, associated, or affiliated trade association or membership organization plays no role in making or ratifying the accreditation decisions of the agency;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The agency has sufficient budget and administrative autonomy to carry out its accrediting functions; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The agency provides to the related, associated, or affiliated trade association or membership organization only information it makes available to the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1099b)</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง602.4</textblock>
    <textblock>Submission of information to the Secretary by recognized accrediting agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each accrediting agency recognized by the Secretary shall submit to the Secretary_</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Reports of final accrediting actions taken by the agency with respect to the institutions and programs it accredits;</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) A copy of any annual report prepared by the agency;</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) A copy, updated annually, of the agency's directory of accredited institutions and programs;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
