<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-0-00013</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-0-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule does not contain information collection requirements that require approval by the Office of Management and Budget under the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. 3507</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>).</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance With the Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of the Interior has determined that this rule will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities under the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. 601</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>). The State submittal which is the subject of this rule is based upon counterpart Federal regulations for which an economic analysis was prepared and certification made that such regulations would not have a significant economic effect upon a substantial number of small entities. Hence, this rule will ensure that existing requirements previously promulgated by OSM will be implemented by the State. In making the determination as to whether this rule would have a significant economic impact, the Department relied upon the data and assumptions for the counterpart Federal regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 30 CFR Part 950</textblock>
    <textblock>Intergovernmental relations, Surface mining, Underground mining.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Bob Armstrong,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary, Land and Minerals Management.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set out in the preamble, title 30, chapter VII, subchapter T of the Code of Federal Regulations is amended as set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 950_WYOMING</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 950 is revised to read:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>30 U.S.C. 1201</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. In ยง950.11, paragraph (c) is revised to read:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง950.11</textblock>
    <textblock>Terms and conditions of State program approval.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) On or before June 1, 1994, Wyoming must revise section 35-11-437 of the Wyoming Statutes (W.S.) to be consistent with the Federal requirements at section 525(e) of SMCRA (30 U.S.C. 1275(e)) and 43 CFR 4.1290 through 4.1295 concerning the award of costs and expenses incurred in connection with administrative and judicial proceedings. Specifically, the State must revise this section to:</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
