<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00026</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Availability of Draft Environmental Assessments Regarding Habitat Management and Livestock Grazing for Wildlife Habitat on the Monte Vista National Wildlife Refuge</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Availability of draft environmental assessments regarding habitat management and livestock grazing for wildlife habitat on the Monte Vista National Wildlife Refuge.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (Service), has prepared, for public review, a Draft Environmental Assessment regarding habitat management and livestock grazing for wildlife habitat on Monte Vista National Wildlife Refuge. The draft assessment, which may be obtained at the address listed under the heading</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES,</textblock>
    <textblock>includes alternatives in habitat management at the refuge and environmental consequences of each alternative.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on the Draft Environmental Assessment should be submitted no later than February 23, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments and requests for copies of the draft assessment may be addressed to: Assistant Regional Director_Refuges and Wildlife, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Box 25486, Denver Federal Center, Denver, CO 80225; Telephone (303) 236-8145.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Skip N. Ladd, Jr., Refuges and Wildlife, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Box 25486, Denver Federal Center, Denver, CO 80225; Telephone (303) 236-8145.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 22, 1993.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William Hartwig,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Assistant Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1535 Filed 1-21-94; 10:00 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-55-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
