<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-1-00102</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-1-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(2) In determining whether an institution meets one or more of the criteria contained in paragraph (b) of this section, the Secretary uses the most recently available data.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Except as provided in paragraphs (c), (d), and (e) of this section, the Secretary refers an institution to a SPRE if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The institution has a cohort default rate (defined in 34 CFR 668.15) equal to or greater than 25 percent;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)(i) The institution has a cohort default rate equal to or greater than 20 percent; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) During the latest completed award year for which data are available_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) More than two-thirds of the institution's regular undergraduate students who were enrolled as at least half-time students received assistance under any Title IV, HEA program, excluding assistance received from the SSIG, NEISP, and Federal PLUS Programs; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The amount that the institution's students received under the Title IV, HEA programs, excluding funds from the SSIG, NEISP, and Federal PLUS Programs, is equal to or greater than two-thirds of the institution's education and general expenditures;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The amount that the institution's students received under the Federal Pell Grant Program is equal to or greater than two-thirds of the institution's education and general expenditures;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The Secretary initiated a limitation, suspension, or termination action against the institution under 34 CFR part 668, subpart G, within the preceding 5 years;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) An audit finding in the institution's two most recent audits under 34 CFR 668.23 resulted in a required repayment by the institution of an amount greater than 5 percent of the funds the institution received under the Title IV, HEA programs for any one award year covered by those audits;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) The Secretary cited the institution for its failure to submit an audit report by the deadlines established under</textblock>
    <textblock>34 CFR 668.23;</textblock>
    <textblock>(7)(i) The amount that the institution's students received under the Federal Pell Grant Program during any award year differed by more than 25 percent from the amount those students received under that program in the award year that preceded that award year, unless the differences can be accounted for by changes in that program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The amount that the institution's students received under the Federal Stafford Loan Program during any award year differs by more than 25 percent from the amount those students received under that program in the award year that preceded that award year, unless the differences can be accounted for by changes in that program; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The amount that the institution's students received under the Federal SLS Program during any award year differs by more than 25 percent from the amount those students received under that program in the award year that preceded that award year, unless the differences can be accounted for by changes in that program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(8) The institution failed to meet the financial responsibility standards in 34 CFR part 668, subpart B;</textblock>
    <textblock>(9) The institution underwent a change in ownership that resulted in a change of control as defined in 34 CFR 600.31;</textblock>
    <textblock>(10) Except with regard to any public institution affiliated with a State system of higher education, the institution has participated for less than 5 years in_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The Federal Pell Grant Program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The FFEL programs;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The FSEOG Program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) The FWS Program; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) The Federal Perkins Loan Program; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(11) The institution has been subject to a pattern of complaints from students, faculty, or others, including information provided to the Secretary by the SPRE, related to its management or conduct of the Title IV, HEA programs or to misleading or inappropriate advertising and promotion of the institution's educational programs, that in the Secretary's judgment are sufficient to warrant review.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) If the Secretary refers an institution to the SPRE under paragraph (b)(9) with regard to the same change of ownership or (b)(6) of this section, and the SPRE conducts a review of the institution as a result of that referral and finds no significant violations of the State's standards, the Secretary reserves whether to refer that institution again to the SPRE for the same reason that resulted in the initial referral.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) The Secretary reserves whether to refer again to the SPRE an institution that meets only the conditions of paragraph (b)(10) of this section, if the SPRE previously conducted a review of that institution and found no violations of the State's standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)(1) An institution may request the Secretary to confirm the data used by the Secretary in referring that institution to a SPRE.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The Secretary rescinds a referral if confirmation reveals that the data used to make a referral was inaccurate and a referral would not be required under accurate data.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The Secretary does not rescind a referral if the Secretary_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Confirms that the data are accurate; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Is unable to confirm the data.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) In confirming data, the Secretary presumes that records maintained in the normal course of business by the U.S. Department of Education, a guaranty agency under the FFEL programs, a SPRE, a State licensing agency, or another State agency are accurate unless the institution proves to the Secretary's satisfaction that the records are not properly maintained or are inaccurate.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1099a-3)</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
