<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-1-00071</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(c) For purposes of this section, an accrediting agency defines a substantive change in an educational program, but the definition must include_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A substantial change in the number of clock or credit hours, the number of weeks, and the content of that program;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A change in the type of program offered;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) A change in the credential awarded for the successful completion of the program; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) A change from clock hours to credit hours or</textblock>
    <textblock>vice versa.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1099b)</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง602.26</textblock>
    <textblock>Required accreditation standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)(1) To be listed by the Secretary as a nationally recognized accrediting agency, an accrediting agency must demonstrate to the Secretary that its accreditation or preaccreditation standards, or both, are sufficiently rigorous to ensure that the agency is a reliable authority as to the quality of the education or training provided by the institutions or programs it accredits.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For a programmatic accrediting agency that does not serve as an institutional accrediting agency for any of the programs it accredits, the standards must address the areas contained in paragraph (b) of this section in terms of the type and level of the program rather than in terms of the institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) If none of the institutions an agency accredits participates in any Title IV, HEA program, or if the agency only accredits programs within institutions accredited by an accrediting agency recognized by the Secretary, the accrediting agency is not required to have the standards described in paragraphs (b)(7), (b)(8), (b)(10), (b)(12), and (b)(13) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) In order to assure that an accrediting agency is a reliable authority as to the quality of the education or training provided by an institution or program it accredits, the agency must have standards that effectively address the quality of an institution or program in the following areas:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Curricula.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Faculty.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Facilities, equipment, and supplies.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Fiscal and administrative capacity as appropriate to the specified scale of operations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency shall_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Have standards addressing the institution's or program's finances and management that enable it to assess an institution's or program's fiscal and administrative capacity, as appropriate to its scale of operations, for the purpose of determining whether_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The institution or program appears able to continue to be an ongoing, economically viable entity; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The finances of the institution or program appear to be sufficient for it to continue to meet the agency's standards;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Make a determination under this standard_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) When it initially evaluates an institution or program for accreditation or preaccreditation; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) When it periodically reevaluates the institution or program for accreditation or preaccreditation;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Require an institution or program to submit on an annual basis sufficient financial information, which may include the annual audited financial statement the institution or program submits to the Secretary under the Title IV, HEA programs, to enable the agency to determine if the financial capacity of the institution threatens the ability of the institution or program to continue to meet the agency's standards; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Review, as appropriate on an annual basis, the information obtained under paragraph (b)(4)(iii) of this section to determine if there is reason to take any follow-up action based on a reduced financial capacity.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)</textblock>
    <textblock>Student support services.</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Recruiting and admissions practices, academic calendars, catalogs, publications, grading, and advertising.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency shall have standards that enable it to assess an institution's or program's recruiting and admissions practices, academic calendars, catalogs, publications, grading, and advertising in terms of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Whether the institution's or program's academic calendar, catalogs, publications, and advertising are accurate, complete, and consistent with actual practice and agency standards, particularly with respect to costs, financial obligations, refunds, graduation rates, employment prospects, and other statements regarding educational effectiveness; and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
