<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-1-00007</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-1-00003</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>30 CFR Part 944</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Utah Permanent Regulatory Program</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement (OSM), Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule; reopening and extension of public comment period on proposed amendment.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>OSM is announcing receipt of additional revisions pertaining to a previously proposed amendment to the Utah permanent regulatory program (hereinafter, the ``Utah program'') under the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (SMCRA). The additional revisions for Utah's proposed rules pertain to the scope of rulemaking and promulgation of rules, hearing requirements for designating areas unsuitable for coal mining, confidentiality of coal exploration information, and mining in special areas, specifically prime farmland. The amendment is intended to incorporate the additional flexibility afforded by the revised Federal regulations, clarify ambiguities, and improve operational efficiency.</textblock>
    <textblock>This document sets forth the times and locations that the Utah program and proposed amendment to that program are available for public inspection and the dates and times of the reopened comment period during which interested persons may submit written comments on the proposed amendment.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments must be received by 4 p.m., m.s.t., February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments should be mailed or hand delivered to Robert H. Hagen at the address listed below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the Utah program, the proposed amendment, and all written comments received in response to this document will be available for public review at the addresses listed below during normal business hours, Monday through Friday, excluding holidays. Each requester may receive one free copy of the proposed amendment by contacting OSM's Albuquerque Field Office.</textblock>
    <textblock>Robert H. Hagen, Director, Albuquerque Field Office, Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement, 505 Marquette Avenue NW., Suite 1200, Albuquerque, New Mexico 87102, Telephone: (505) 766-1486</textblock>
    <textblock>Utah Division of Oil, Gas and Mining, 355 West North Temple, 3 Triad Center, Suite 350, Salt Lake City, Utah 84180-1203, Telephone: (801) 538-5340</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Robert H. Hagen, Telephone: (505) 766-1486.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Background on the Utah Program</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Proposed Amendment</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Public Comment Procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Procedural Determinations</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Background on the Utah Program</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 21, 1981, the Secretary of the Interior conditionally approved the Utah program. General background information on the Utah program, including the Secretary's findings, the disposition of comments, and the conditions of approval of the Utah program can be found in the January 21, 1981,</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(46 FR 5899). Subsequent actions concerning Utah's program and program amendments can be found at 30 CFR 944.15, 944.16, and 944.30.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
