<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-0-00014</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-0-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(1) Clearly authorize the award of costs and expenses incurred in connection with participation in judicial review proceedings concerning agency actions;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) With respect to awards from the State, clearly authorize the award of costs and expenses incurred in connection with participation in any administrative contested case proceedings under the approved program, not just proceedings concerning enforcement actions under W.S. 35-11-437 or actions taken under W.S. 35-11-406(p);</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Authorize the award of all reasonably incurred costs and expenses without placing any inflexible limits on the meaning of ``reasonably incurred'' or restricting awards to issues raised in the original complaint;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) With respect to administrative review proceedings, clarify that petitions for awards of costs and expenses must be filed with and reviewed and decided by the Environmental Quality Council, not the Director of the Department of Environmental Quality; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) With respect to awards from the State, eliminate the requirement that the person establish the existence of a specific violation of applicable statute or rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. In ยง950.15, paragraph (r) is added to read:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง950.15</textblock>
    <textblock>Approval of regulatory program amendments.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(r) Except for the language noted in paragraph (r)(1) of this section and the addition of paragraph (g), which would establish a maximum hourly rate for fee awards, to section 35-11-437 of the Wyoming Statutes, the following amendments to the laws, rules and regulations of the Wyoming Department of Environmental Quality, as submitted by Wyoming on August 18, 1982, and March 9, 1993, are approved effective January 24, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Section 35-11-437(f) of the Wyoming Statutes as revised by Enrolled Act No. 60 and submitted on March 9, 1993, except the following language appearing in italics:</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) Whenever an order is issued under this section,</textblock>
    <textblock>at the request of any person, a sum equal to the aggregate amount of all costs and expenses (including attorney's fees) as determined</textblock>
    <textblock>by the director</textblock>
    <textblock>to have been reasonably incurred by the person for or in connection with his participation in the proceeding, including any judicial review of agency actions, may be assessed against either party</textblock>
    <textblock>as the court or the director deems proper.</textblock>
    <textblock>This subsection shall apply</textblock>
    <textblock>only</textblock>
    <textblock>to</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative</textblock>
    <textblock>contested case proceedings under the provisions of this act relating to the regulation of surface coal mining and reclamation operations in accordance with Pub. L. 95-87, as that law is worded on August 3, 1977. For payments from the department, the following shall apply:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The issues resolved in the contested proceeding are those in the original complaint that were raised within the statutory time frames under W.S. 35-406(p) or within an enforcement action;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
