<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00039</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00033</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Lodging of Consent Decree Pursuant to the Clean Water Act</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with Departmental Policy 28 CFR 50.7, notice is hereby given that a proposed consent decree in</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Vertac Chemical Corp., et al.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Civil Action No. LR-C-80-109, was lodged on December 30, 1993 with the United States District Court for the</textblock>
    <textblock>Eastern District of Arkansas.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed consent decree resolves the liability of Velsicol Chemical Corporation under Sections 106 and 107 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act, 42 U.S.C. 9606 and 9607, and Section 7003 of the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act, 42 U.S.C. 6973, with respect to the Vertac Site located in Jacksonville, Arkansas.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Justice will receive, for a period on or before February 23, 1994, comments relating to the proposed consent decree. Comments should be addressed to the Assistant Attorney General for the Environment and Natural Resources Division, Department of Justice, Washington, DC 20530, and should refer to</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Vertac Chemical Corp., et al,</textblock>
    <textblock>DOJ Ref.</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>90-7-1-18B.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed consent decree may be examined at the office of the United States Attorney, 425 W. Capital, 5th floor, Little Rock, Arkansas 72201; the Region VI Office of the Environmental Protection Agency, 1445 Ross Avenue, Dallas, Texas 75202; and at the Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., 4th floor, Washington, DC 20005, (202) 624-0892. A copy of the proposed consent decree may be obtained in person or by mail from the Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., 4th floor, Washington, DC 20005. In requesting a copy, please refer to the referenced case and enclose a check in the amount of $7.25 (25 cents per page reproduction costs), payable to the Consent Decree Library.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John C. Cruden,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Environmental Enforcement Section, Environment and Natural Resources Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1519 Filed 1-21-94; 10:00 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
