<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00019</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[NV-010-5700-10; N-56882; 4-00154]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Realty Action; Nevada</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Realty Action, N-56882.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The following described land in Eureka County, Nevada, has been examined and found suitable for airport lease under the Act of May 24, 1928, as amended (49 U.S.C., Appendix 211-213). The lands will not be offered for lease until at least 60 days after the date of publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register.</textblock>
    <textblock>Mount Diablo Meridian, Nevada</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 29 N., R. 48 E.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 4, Lots 3-6, S1/2NW1/4, N1/2SW1/4, SE1/4SW1/4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Containing 365.25 acres, more or less.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Detailed information concerning this action is available for review at the Bureau of Land Management, Elko Resource Area, 3900 E. Idaho Street, Elko, Nevada.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Eureka County Board of Commissioners has applied to lease an existing airstrip which serves the unincorporated Town of Crescent Valley, Nevada, and surrounding vicinity. The lands were previously leased for airport purposes by a succession of private individuals; however, the lease was allowed to expire the Eureka County has now applied to lease the airstrip. The land is not required for any Federal purpose. Issuance of the lease would be consistent with the Bureau's planning for the area.</textblock>
    <textblock>The described lands were previously segregated from mineral entry by virtue of the previous lease, but were never opened to entry upon expiration of the lease. Accordingly, this notice continues to segregate the lands from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining laws. Upon termination of the lease, the segregative effect would terminate as specified in an opening order published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register.</textblock>
    <textblock>The lease when issued, will be subject to the provisions of the Act of May 24, 1928, and applicable regulations (43 CFR 2911) of the Secretary of the Interior.</textblock>
    <textblock>On or before March 10, 1994 interested parties may submit comments to the District Manager, Elko District Office, P.O. Box 831, Elko, NV 89803. Any objections will be evaluated by the State Director, who may sustain, vacate or modify this realty action. In the absence of timely filed objections, this realty action will become a final determination of the Department of the Interior.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 13, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rodney Harris,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>District Manager.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1527 Filed 1-21-94; 10:00 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-HC-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
