<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-1-00068</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(b) If the Secretary denies recognition to a previously recognized accrediting agency, or limits, suspends, or terminates its recognition during a previously granted recognition period, the Secretary publishes a notice of that action in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>and makes available to the public, upon request, the Secretary's determination.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1099b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart C_Criteria for Secretarial Recognition</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง602.20</textblock>
    <textblock>Geographic scope of accrediting activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>To be listed by the Secretary as a nationally recognized accrediting agency, an accrediting agency must demonstrate to the Secretary that the geographical scope of its accrediting activities covers_</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A State, if the agency is a component of a State government;</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) A region of the United States that includes at least three States that are contiguous or in close geographical proximity to one another; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1099b)</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง602.21</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative and fiscal responsibility.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) To be listed by the Secretary as a nationally recognized accrediting agency, an accrediting agency must demonstrate to the Secretary that it has the administrative and fiscal capability to carry out its accreditation activities in light of its requested scope of recognition.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The Secretary considers that an accrediting agency meets the requirements of paragraph (a) of this section if it has, and will likely continue to have_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Adequate administrative staff to_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Carry out its accrediting responsibilities effectively; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Manage its finances effectively;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Competent and knowledgeable individuals, qualified by experience and training, responsible for on-site evaluation, policy-making, and decision-making regarding accreditation and preaccreditation status;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Representation on its evaluation, policy, and decision-making bodies of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) For an institutional accrediting agency, both academic and administrative personnel; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) For a programmatic accrediting agency, both educators and practitioners;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Representation of the public on all decision-making bodies;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Clear and effective controls against conflicts of interest or the appearance of conflicts of interest by the agency's board members, commissioners, evaluation team members, consultants, administrative staff, and other agency representatives;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Adequate financial resources to carry out its accrediting responsibilities, taking into account the funds required to conduct the range of accrediting activities specified in the requested scope of recognition and the income necessary to meet the anticipated costs of its activities in the future; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Complete and accurate records of_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Its last two full accreditation or preaccreditation reviews of each institution or program, including self-study reports, on-site evaluation team reports, institution or program responses to on-site reports, periodic review reports, and any reports of special review conducted by the agency between regular reviews; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Its decisions with respect to all preaccreditation and accreditation actions, including all adverse actions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1099b)</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง602.22</textblock>
    <textblock>Accreditation experience.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) To be listed by the Secretary as a nationally recognized accrediting agency, an accrediting agency must demonstrate to the Secretary that it has adequate experience in accrediting institutions, programs, or both.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The Secretary considers that an accrediting agency satisfies the requirements of paragraph (a) of this section if it has_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Granted accreditation or preaccreditation status to institutions or programs in the geographical area for which it seeks recognition;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Conducted accreditation activities covering the range of the specific degrees, certificates, and programs for which it seeks recognition, including_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Granting accreditation or preaccreditation status; and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
