<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00027</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>U.S. Geological Survey</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Federal Geographic Data Committee (FGDC); Public Review of the United States National Cartographic Standards for Spatial Accuracy (NCSSA)</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Geological Survey, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice; Request for comments.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FGDC is sponsoring a public review of the United States National Cartographic Standards for Spatial Accuracy. The standard specifies the means of calculating horizontal and vertical accuracy for map graphics, the method by which accuracy will be tested, the label to be applied to products that have been tested, and the application of the standard to map series.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FGDC anticipates that the final standard will be submitted to the U.S. Office of Management and Budget for the replacement of the National Map Accuracy Standards, the last revision of which was issued by the former Bureau of the Budget in 1947.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before February 11, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments about the proposed standard should be sent by mail to NCSSA Review, FGDC Secretariat, U.S. Geological Survey, 590 National Center, 12201 Sunrise Valley Drive, Reston, Virginia 22092; by Internet to ``gdc@usgs.gov'', or by facsimile to (703) 648-5755. The draft standard may be requested from the same mailing or Internet addresses or facsimile number. Internet users should include their name, affiliation, mailing address, and telephone number at the bottom of their message.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Jennifer Snyder, FGDC Secretariat, U.S. Geological Survey, 590 National Center, 12201 Sunrise Valley Drive, Reston, Virginia 22092; telephone (703) 648-5514; facsimile (703) 648-5755; Internet ``gdc@usgs.gov''.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed standard is based on work published by the American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing. The society recommended that the draft replace the existing National Map Accuracy Standards. The standard has been reviewed by components of the FGDC, and is now in final review in the committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Allen H. Watkins,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, National Mapping Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1522 Filed 1-21-94; 10:00 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-31-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
