<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00058</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00043</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>UNITED STATES INFORMATION AGENCY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Reporting and Information Collection Requirements Under OMB Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>United States Information Agency.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of reporting requirements submitted for OMB review.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. Chapter 35), agencies are required to submit proposed or established reporting and recordkeeping requirements to OMB for review and approval, and to publish a notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notifying the public that the Agency has made such a submission. The information collection activity involved with this program is conducted pursuant to the mandate given to the United States Information Agency in accordance with Public Law 98-111 as amended by Public Law 101-246. USIA is requesting reinstatement of this collection for a three-year period. The information collection is entitled ``Surveys, Interviews and Other Audience Research for Radio and TV Marti'', under OMB Control Number 3116-0197. Estimated burden hours per response is thirty-five (35) minutes. Respondents will be required to respond only one time.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments are due on or before February 23, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>COPIES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the Request for Clearance (SF-83), supporting statement, transmittal letter and other documents submitted to OMB for approval may be obtained from the USIA Clearance Officer. Comments on the items listed should be submitted to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of OMB, Attention: Desk Officer for USIA, and also to the USIA Clearance Officer.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Agency Clearance Officer, Ms. Debbie Knox, United States Information Agency, M/ADD, 301 Fourth Street, SW., Washington, DC 20547, telephone (202) 619-5503; and OMB review: Mr. Jeffery Hill, Office of Information And Regulatory Affairs, Office of Management and Budget, New Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503, Telephone (202) 395-7340.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Public reporting burden for this collection of information (Paper Work Reduction Project: OMB No. 3116-0197) is estimated to average 35 minutes per response, including the time for reviewing instructions, searching existing data sources, gathering and maintaining the data needed, and completing and reviewing the collection of information. Send comments regarding this burden estimate or any other aspect of this collection of information, including suggestions for reducing this burden to the United States Information Agency, M/ADD, 301 Fourth Street, SW., Washington, DC 20547; and to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, Office of Management and Budget, New Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503.</textblock>
    <textblock>TITLE:</textblock>
    <textblock>Surveys, Interviews and Other Audience Research for Radio and TV Marti.</textblock>
    <textblock>FORM NUMBER:</textblock>
    <textblock>None.</textblock>
    <textblock>ABSTRACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Data from this information collection are used by USIA's Office of Cuba Broadcasting (OCB) to evaluate effectiveness of Radio and TV Marti operations by estimating the audience size and composition for broadcasts. OCB also assesses signal reception, credibility and relevance of programming through this research.</textblock>
    <textblock>PROPOSED FREQUENCY OF RESPONSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>No. of Respondents_5,500. Recordkeeping Hours_.6. Total Annual Burden_3,345.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rose Royal,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Federal Register Liaison.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1534 Filed 1-21-94; 10:00 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8230-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
