<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00038</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00032</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Lodging of a Consent Decree Pursuant to the Toxic Substances Control Act</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with Departmental policy, 28 CFR 50.7, notice is hereby given that on January 7, 1994, a proposed consent decree in</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>New York State Department of Transportation,</textblock>
    <textblock>No. 89-CV-319, was lodged with the United States District Court for the Northern District of New York. The decree resolves claims of the United States for injunctive relief against the Defendant in the above-referenced action under the Toxic Substances Control Act (``TSCA'') relating to PCB-contaminated dredged materials at two areas known as the Buoy 212 Site and the Special Area 13 Site (the ``Sites''). The Buoy 212 Site is located in the Town of Fort Edward, New York. The Special Area 13 Site is located in the Town of Moreau, New York. In the proposed consent decree the Defendant agrees to perform site characterization, temporary remedial work, monitoring, maintenance, and continuing assessment of the future permanent remediation of the Sites. New York State Department of Transportation has already initiated and/or completed actions required by the Decree.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed decree may be examined at the Environmental Enforcement Section Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., Washington, DC 20005, (202) 624-0892. A copy of the proposed decree may be obtained in person or by mail from the Consent Decree Library.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Justice will receive written comments relating to the proposed consent decree on or before February 23, 1994. Comments should be addressed to Assistant Attorney General, Environment and Natural Resources Division, Department of Justice, Washington, DC 20530, and should refer to</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>New York State Department of Transportation,</textblock>
    <textblock>(DOJ Reference No. 90-5-1-1-3297).</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John C. Cruden,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Environmental Enforcement Section, Environment and Natural Resources Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1518 Filed 1-21-94; 10:00 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
