<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00057</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-2-00042</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Delegation of Authority No. 209; Under Secretary for Political Affairs</textblock>
    <textblock>January 7, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Delegation.</textblock>
    <textblock>By virtue of the authority vested in the Secretary of State, including the authority of section 4, of the Act of May 26, 1949 (22 U.S.C. 2658), as amended, I hereby delegate to the Under Secretary for Political Affairs the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Those functions conferred upon the Secretary of State by 18 U.S.C. 3186 relating to ordering delivery of persons committed under 18 U.S.C. 3184 and 3185 to authorized agents of foreign countries; and,</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Those functions conferred upon the Secretary of State by 18 U.S.C. 981(i)(1), 19 U.S.C. 1616a(c)(2), and 21 U.S.C. 881(e)(1)(E), and similar statutes that may be enacted, to approve the transfer of forfeited assets to foreign governments.</textblock>
    <textblock>2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Technical provisions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Notwithstanding this delegation of authority, the Secretary of State may at any time exercise any function delegated by this delegation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Any act affected by this delegation shall be deemed to be such act as amended from time to time.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Nothing herein shall derogate from Department of State Delegation of Authority No. 134, dated March 4, 1976, or Delegation of Authority No. 202, dated March 23, 1993, which delegated the above-enumerated functions to the Deputy Secretary of State.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) This delegation of authority to the Under Secretary for Political Affairs shall remain in effect only until such time as a confirmed nominee assumes the position of Deputy Secretary of State or the President appoints an Acting Deputy Secretary of State under 5 U.S.C. 3347, at which time this delegation of authority shall expire.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF STATE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Public Notice 1935]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Warren Christopher,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of State.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1508 Filed 1-21-94; 10:00 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4710-24-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
