<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-0-00024</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-0-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>For the reasons set out in the preamble, Title 30, Chapter VII, SubChapter T, of the Code of Federal Regulations is amended as set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 950_WYOMING</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for Part 950 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>30 U.S.C. 1201</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. In ยง950.16, paragraphs (bb), (cc), (dd), (ee), (ff), and (gg) are added to read as follows.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง950.16</textblock>
    <textblock>Required program amendments.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(bb) By March 25, 1994, Wyoming shall submit revisions to W.S. 35-11-103(e)(xxviii) to clarify how the definition of ``Agricultural lands'' would not render its program less stringent than SMCRA requirements and less effective than the Federal regulation requirements or repeal the definition.</textblock>
    <textblock>(cc) By March 25, 1994, Wyoming shall submit revisions to W.S. 35-11-103(e) (xxix), that defines ``Critical habitat'', to either repeal this statutory definition or modify it to be in accordance with no less effective than the Federal program requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(dd) By March 25, 1994, Wyoming shall submit revisions to W.S. 35-11-103(e) (xxx), that defines ``Important habitat or crucial habitat'', to either repeal this statutory definition or modify it to be in accordance with and no less effective than the Federal program requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ee) By March 25, 1994, Wyoming shall repeal the provision at W.S. 35-11-402(b) that provides direction to the Environmental Quality Council to use specific statutory definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ff) By March 25, 1994, Wyoming shall submit revisions to W.S. 35-11-402(c), that provides for the reclamation of grazingland to either repeal this statutory provision, modify it to make it consistent with SMCRA and no less effective than the Federal regulations, or provide the required documentation to show that the standard meets the Federal program requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(gg) By March 25, 1994, Wyoming shall submit revisions to amend its program at LQD Rule Chapter IV, Section 2(d)(x)(E) and Appendix A, to establish revegetation shrub density standards in compliance with Section 515(b)(24) of SMCRA and the Federal regulations at 30 CFR 780/784.16, 816/817.97 and 816/817.116.</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1418 Filed 1-21-94; 10:00 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-05-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
