<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940124-1-00103</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940124-1-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>§667.6</textblock>
    <textblock>SPRE selection of institutions for review.</textblock>
    <textblock>A SPRE may review an institution under this part that was not referred by the Secretary if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The SPRE_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)(i) Determines that the institution meets a referral criterion in §667.5 based on more recent data available to the SPRE; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Has reason to believe the institution is engaged in fraudulent practices; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Requests the Secretary to approve its review of that institution; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The Secretary_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Approves that request; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Does not respond to the SPRE's request within 21 days after the date the Secretary receives that request.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1099a-3)</textblock>
    <textblock>§667.7</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice to SPRE of Federal actions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) If the Secretary takes an action against an institution, the Secretary notifies the SPRE of the State in which the institution is located within 10 days of taking that action.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) If the Secretary is informed that another Federal agency is taking an action against an institution, the Secretary notifies the SPRE of the State in which the institution is located as soon as possible but not later than 10 days after learning of that action.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1099a-3)</textblock>
    <textblock>§667.8</textblock>
    <textblock>Institutions with locations in more than one State.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) If an institution that is subject to a referral has locations in more than one State, the Secretary refers the institution to the SPRE in each State in which the institution is located and informs each SPRE of the other States in which the institution is located.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The SPRE of the State in which the main campus of the institution is located has the principal responsibility for reviewing that institution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) If a branch campus or additional location of an institution is in a State other than the State in which the institution's main campus is located, the SPRE of the State in which that branch campus or additional location is located_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) May review that branch campus or additional location before a SPRE review is conducted of the main campus of that institution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) May delay its review of that branch campus or additional location until a SPRE review is conducted of the main campus of that institution; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) May choose not to review that branch campus or additional location if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The SPRE of the State in which the main campus of that institution is located reviews that institution and makes no significant findings; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The State's allotment is insufficient to allow the SPRE to review all referred institutions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) An institution, its branch campuses, and additional locations are subject to the review standards of the State in which they are located.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Notwithstanding paragraphs (b) and (c) of this section, to review a referred institution that has locations in more than one State, the SPREs of those States may enter into an agreement under which the SPREs may alter the review responsibilities set forth in paragraphs (b) and (c) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 20 U.S.C. 1099a-3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart B_Allotment Formula and Funding Procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>§667.11</textblock>
    <textblock>Allotment formula.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) For each fiscal year for which funds are appropriated to carry out this part:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The Secretary_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Allots $20,000 to Guam, $20,000 to American Samoa, $20,000 to the Northern Mariana Islands, $20,000 to the Virgin Islands, and $20,000 to the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Calculates each remaining State's allotment of the remaining funds under paragraph (a)(2) of this section; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Notifies each State of its allotment.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Except for Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Secretary allots those funds to a State by_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Determining the percentage of institutions participating in a Title IV, HEA program in the State by dividing the number of institutions located in that State that are certified to participate in a Title IV, HEA program by the total number of institutions that are certified to participate in all States;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) For the latest award year for which information is available, determining the percentage of Title IV, HEA program funds by dividing the total amount of Title IV, HEA program funds that were made available to students who enrolled in the institutions in that State that participate in a Title IV, HEA program, or to those students' parents, by the total amount of Title IV, HEA program funds that were made available to students, or to those student's parents, who enrolled in institutions that participate in a Title IV, HEA program in all States;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Averaging the two percentages determined in paragraph (a)(2)(i) and (ii) of this section;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Calculating an ``initial distribution'' by multiplying the average percentage determined in paragraph (a)(2)(iii) of this section by the amount appropriated to carry out this part less the total amount allotted to Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands;</textblock>
    <textblock>(v)(A) Determining which States receive less than $50,000 under the initial distribution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Providing each of those States with $50,000; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Calculating the difference between the $50,000 provided to each of those States and those States' initial distribution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi)(A) Determining which States receive more than $50,000 under the initial distribution; and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
