<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00239</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00104</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>7. Knowledge of the location of destination points such as medical</textblock>
    <textblock>facilities, supermarkets, recreational facilities, etc.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Priorities for Operation Lifesaver Program:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Knowledge of railroad and road network in geographical areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Demonstrated ability to network with other organizations, including local</textblock>
    <textblock>law enforcement units and proposed coordination and collaboration with</textblock>
    <textblock>other organizations.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Ability to coordinate and implement a training and certification program,</textblock>
    <textblock>along with local law enforcement departments, and appropriate education</textblock>
    <textblock>departments.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Feasibility of the proposed approach or work plan and the extent to</textblock>
    <textblock>which the project addresses traffic safety objectives.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Administrative capabilities and staff expertise required to successfully</textblock>
    <textblock>complete the proposed project.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Past and present organizational experience in the performance of similar</textblock>
    <textblock>projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Ability to provide sound evaluative information.</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Priorities for Hazardous Materials Transportation Assistance Program:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Feasibility and utility of work program planned for National Service</textblock>
    <textblock>participants.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Ability of program to assist local agencies responsible for hazardous</textblock>
    <textblock>materials planning and training.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Ability of program to address the National Service priorities of</textblock>
    <textblock>Environment and Education, and the DOT Strategic Goals of promoting</textblock>
    <textblock>safe and secure transportation and enhancing the environment through</textblock>
    <textblock>wise transportation decisions.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Ability of program to address currently unmet hazardous materials</textblock>
    <textblock>needs.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Demonstrated strength of current state or local planning and response</textblock>
    <textblock>structure to effectively use national service participation to its full</textblock>
    <textblock>advantage.</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Priorities for Youth Traffic Safety Education Programs:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Knowledge of basic traffic safety issues and status of related state and</textblock>
    <textblock>community efforts within designated locality.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Demonstrated ability to network with other organizations including local</textblock>
    <textblock>law enforcement units and proposed coordination and collaboration with</textblock>
    <textblock>other organizations.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Ability to coordinate and implement a training and certification program</textblock>
    <textblock>along with local law enforcement departments.</textblock>
    <textblock>4.4␣Preferences Applying to Urban Youth Corps Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>Preferences will be given to the following types of projects if urban youth corps are used to implement the projects:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Projects that will provide long-term public benefits</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Projects that will instill in the participant a work ethic and a sense of public</textblock>
    <textblock>responsibility.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Projects that will be labor intensive.</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Projects that can be planned and initiated promptly.</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Projects that will provide academic, experiential, or community education</textblock>
    <textblock>opportunities.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
