<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00237</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00104</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Any service organization submitting a proposal for a DOT program must show evidence that the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal has been reviewed and approved by the community service commission for the state(s)</textblock>
    <textblock>in which the project will be performed.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, DOT requests that each proposal include a preliminary evaluation by the state on</textblock>
    <textblock>national and community service for the state in which the project is to be performed (the ``state</textblock>
    <textblock>commission''). An evaluation form to be completed by the state commission is included as</textblock>
    <textblock>``Attachment 6'' to the attached application form. The evaluation by the state commissions are</textblock>
    <textblock>not mandatory and are not binding on DOT. However, DOT believes that any information from</textblock>
    <textblock>the state commissions would be extremely helpful in our review and, therefore, we strongly</textblock>
    <textblock>encourage all applicants to obtain an evaluation from the state commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Selection Criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>4.1␣General Criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>The following criteria and weights will be used by DOT to select national and community</textblock>
    <textblock>service proposals:</textblock>
    <textblock>1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Need</textblock>
    <textblock>(10%).</textblock>
    <textblock>DOT will take into consideration the extent to which both the overall program and its</textblock>
    <textblock>particular projects will address needs important to the community and be conducted in</textblock>
    <textblock>areas of need as defined in the National and Community Service Trust Act. These</textblock>
    <textblock>areas of need are:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Communities designated by the Federal government or states as</textblock>
    <textblock>empowerment zones or redevelopment areas, targeted for special</textblock>
    <textblock>economic incentives, or otherwise identifiable as having high</textblock>
    <textblock>concentrations of low-income people.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Areas that are environmentally distressed.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Areas adversely affected by Federal actions related to the management</textblock>
    <textblock>of Federal lands that result in significant regional job losses and</textblock>
    <textblock>economic dislocation.</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Areas adversely affected by reduction in Defense spending or the closure</textblock>
    <textblock>or realignment of military installations.</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Areas that have unemployment rates greater than the national average</textblock>
    <textblock>unemployment for the most recent 12 months for which satisfactory data</textblock>
    <textblock>are available.</textblock>
    <textblock>2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Program Design</textblock>
    <textblock>(40%).</textblock>
    <textblock>DOT will consider the quality of the program based on: the potential impact of using</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed national service participants to meet the community needs being addressed;</textblock>
    <textblock>inclusion of a clear and compelling mission statement; identification of specific</textblock>
    <textblock>objectives and indicators of success; development of an effective recruitment, selection,</textblock>
    <textblock>and training plan for staff and participants, including recruitment of participants and</textblock>
    <textblock>staff from the community to be served; ability to provide appropriate supervision,</textblock>
    <textblock>counseling, service-learning and other education opportunities, and outplacement to</textblock>
    <textblock>participants; the involvement of participants and community residents in the design,</textblock>
    <textblock>operation, and leadership of the program; development of a sound plan for continually</textblock>
    <textblock>improving the program based on self-assessment and monitoring of community and</textblock>
    <textblock>participant satisfaction with work performed; inclusion of an appropriate organization</textblock>
    <textblock>and staffing plan; and the program's cost-effectiveness in achieving identified outcomes,</textblock>
    <textblock>including per participant cost.</textblock>
    <textblock>3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Organizational Capacity</textblock>
    <textblock>(30%).</textblock>
    <textblock>DOT will consider organizational capacity based on: the quality of the leadership of the</textblock>
    <textblock>national service program; the past performance of the organization or program; the</textblock>
    <textblock>organization's connection to the community; the extent to which the program builds on</textblock>
    <textblock>existing programs; evidence of strong and broad-based community support for the</textblock>
    <textblock>program; and availability of additional funding sources for the program.</textblock>
    <textblock>An application proposing the replication of an existing program will also be evaluated</textblock>
    <textblock>based on the success of the program in its original site, including the results of any</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluation undertaken; the program's analysis of the strengths and weaknesses of the</textblock>
    <textblock>original program; reasons for selecting the replication site and discussion of adjustments</textblock>
    <textblock>needed for adaptation to a new site; and the qualification of the leaders of the program</textblock>
    <textblock>at the new site.</textblock>
    <textblock>4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sustainability</textblock>
    <textblock>(10%).</textblock>
    <textblock>DOT will consider the ability of the program to sustain itself beyond the period of</textblock>
    <textblock>support from DOT or from the National Service Corporation as evidenced by strong</textblock>
    <textblock>and broad-based community support; presence of multiple or private funding sources;</textblock>
    <textblock>and cost-effectiveness. Additional consideration will be given to programs that</textblock>
    <textblock>significantly exceed the regional match with non-Federal funds.</textblock>
    <textblock>5.</textblock>
    <textblock>Innovation and Replication</textblock>
    <textblock>(10%).</textblock>
    <textblock>DOT will consider the degree to which needs coincide to program design, the</textblock>
    <textblock>innovative aspects of the program, and the appropriateness of replicating the program</textblock>
    <textblock>in the future.</textblock>
    <textblock>4.2␣Priority Consideration</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to the criteria on which individual applications will be rated, DOT may give priority</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration to all or some of the following issues:</textblock>
    <textblock>1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Early Start Date.</textblock>
    <textblock>DOT is interested in programs that will be able to start up</textblock>
    <textblock>quickly after completing an appropriate planning phase (ideally by September</textblock>
    <textblock>of 1994).</textblock>
    <textblock>2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Participant Diversity.</textblock>
    <textblock>DOT seeks a broadly diverse participant pool that includes a large representation</textblock>
    <textblock>of young adults; a mixture of individuals who have not attended college and</textblock>
    <textblock>those with college-education experience; approximately equal numbers of men</textblock>
    <textblock>and women; individuals of all races and ethnicities; and individuals with</textblock>
    <textblock>physical and cognitive disabilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Location.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
