<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00114</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00065</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 223 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended, the Department of Labor herein presents summaries of determinations regarding eligibility to apply for trade adjustment assistance for workers (TA-W) issued during the period of February, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order for an affirmative determination to be made and a certification of eligibility to apply for worker adjustment assistance to be issued, each of the group eligibility requirements of section 222 of the Act must be met.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) That a significant number or proportion of the workers in the workers' firm, or an appropriate subdivision thereof, have become totally or partially separated,</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) That sales or production, or both, of the firm or subdivision have decreased absolutely, and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) That increases of imports of articles like or directly competitive with articles produced by the firm or appropriate subdivision have contributed importantly to the separations, or threat thereof, and to the absolute decline in sales or production.</textblock>
    <textblock>Negative Determinations for Workers Adjustment Assistance</textblock>
    <textblock>In each of the following cases the investigation revealed that criterion (3) has not been met. A survey of customers indicated that increased imports did not contribute importantly to worker separations at the firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,222; Mann Industries, Inc., Williamsburg, VA</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,247; Greenbrier Industries, Clinton, TN</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,098, TA-W-29,099; Northrop Corp., Hawthorn, CA and Anaheim, CA</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,199; The Robbins Co., Kent, WA</textblock>
    <textblock>In the following cases, the investigation revealed that the criteria for eligibility have not been met for the reasons specified.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,305; Decision Data Service, Inc., Horsham, PA</textblock>
    <textblock>The workers' firm does not produce an article as required for certification under section 222 of the Trade Act of 1974.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,300; Lake Stevens Timber, Lake Stevens, VA</textblock>
    <textblock>The preponderant portion of production at the subject firm is exported; therefore, imports could not have contributed importantly to the absolute decline in sales or production of the subject firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,294; Praxair, Inc., Tonawanda, NY</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. imports of gas separators decreased in the twelve month period from November 1992 through October 1993 compared to the previous twelve month period from November 1991 through October 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,257; Ethicon, Inc., San Angelo, TX</textblock>
    <textblock>Increased imports did not contribute importantly to worker separations at the firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-28,986; Southern Shipbuilding Corp., Slidell, LA</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. imports of tug boats and pushers declined absolutely in the twelve month period of October 1992 through September 1993 as compared to the same period of a year earlier.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,270; Leviton Manufacturing Co., Inc., Brooklyn, NY</textblock>
    <textblock>Predominate reason for the layoff of workers was a corporate decision to transfer certain product lines from the subject firm to more modern facilities in U.S. affiliates.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,242; B-5 Welding Special Services, Seminole, TX</textblock>
    <textblock>The workers' firm does not produce an article as required for certification under section 222 of the Trade Act of 1974.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,311; The LTV Corp., Dallas, TX</textblock>
    <textblock>The workers' firm does not produce an article as required for certification under section 222 of the Trade Act of 1974.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,341: Olsten Staffing Services, Messena, NY</textblock>
    <textblock>The workers' firm does not produce an article as required for certification under section 222 of the Trade Act of 1974.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,318; National Steel Pellet Co., Keewatin, MN</textblock>
    <textblock>The investigation revealed that criterion (2) has not been met. Sales or production did not decline during the relevant period for certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,253; Plains Petroleum Operating Co., Lakewood, CO</textblock>
    <textblock>The investigation revealed that criterion (2) has not been met. Sales or production did not decline during the relevant period for certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,306; Bhalla Lighting, Inc., West Caldwell, NJ</textblock>
    <textblock>The investigation revealed that criterion (2) has not been met. Sales or production did not decline during the relevant period for certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,252; Neste Oil, Inc., Houston, TX</textblock>
    <textblock>The investigation revealed that the subject firm's parent company, Neste Oy, made the decision to divest itself of all United States oil and gas assets. These assets were managed by workers at the subject firm; when the sale of the assets was completed in mid-1993, the employees of Neste Oil, Inc., were severed from employment.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,240; The ARO Corp, Life Support Products Div., Buffalo, NY</textblock>
    <textblock>The investigation revealed that criterion (2) has not been met. Sales or production did not decline during the relevant period for certification.</textblock>
    <textblock>Affirmative Determinations for Worker Adjustment Assistance</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,272; Jo-Ann Apparel Mfg, Inc., Ebensburg, PA</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after November 16, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,192; Parsons Footwear, Parsons, WV</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after October 17, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,236; F-Bruno Faceting Corp., Union, NJ</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after November 12, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,264; Synektron, Portland, OR</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after November 16, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-28,972; AT&amp;T, Westminster, CO</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after August 9, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,332; Recycled Aluminum Metals Co., Dallesport, WA</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after December 7, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,317: Rexham Graphics, Portland, OR</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after November 30, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,208; Roseburg Forest Products Co., Sawmill</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>1, Dillard, OR</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers separated on or after September 27, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Also, pursuant to title V of the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act (Pub. L. 103-182) concerning transitional adjustment assistance hereinafter called (NAFTA-TAA) and in accordance with section 250(a) subchapter D, chapter 2, title II, of the Trade Act as amended, the Department of Labor presents summaries of determinations regarding eligibility to apply for NAFTA-TAA issued during the month of February, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order for an affirmative determination to be made and a certification of eligibility to apply for NAFTA-TAA the following group eligibility requirements of Section 250 of the Trade Act must be met:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) That a significant number or proportion of the workers in the workers' firm, or an appropriate subdivision thereof, (including workers in any agricultural firm or appropriate subdivision thereof) have become totally or partially separated from employment and either_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) That sales or production, or both, of such firm or subdivision have decreased absolutely,</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) That imports from Mexico or Canada of articles like or directly competitive with articles produced by such firm or subdivision have increased.</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) That the increase in imports contributed importantly to such workers' separations or threat of separation and to the decline in sales or production of such firm or subdivision; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) That there has been a shift in production by such workers' firm or subdivision to Mexico or Canada of articles like or directly competitive with articles which are produced by the firm or subdivision.</textblock>
    <textblock>Affirmative Determinations NAFTA-TAA</textblock>
    <textblock>NAFTA-TAA-00002; Emerson Electric Co., White Rodgers Div., Logansport, IN</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers engaged in employment related to the production of relays, contactors and solenoids at Emerson Electric Company, White Rodgers Div., Logansport, IN separated on or after December 8, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>NAFTA-TAA-00010; Steward, Inc., ICD (Integrated Components Division), East Ridge, TN</textblock>
    <textblock>A certification was issued covering all workers at Steward, Inc., ICD, in East Ridge, TN separated on or after December 8, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>I hereby certify that the aforementioned determinations were issued during the month of February, 1994. Copies of these determinations are available for inspection in room C-4318, U.S. Department of Labor, 200 Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20210 during normal business hours or will be mailed to persons who write to the above address.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Determinations Regarding Eligibility To Apply for Worker Adjustment Assistance and NAFTA Transitional Adjustment Assistance</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Marvin M. Fooks,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Trade Adjustment Assistance.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4070 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4510-30-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
