<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00128</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00079</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Garnishment of Federal Employees Wages for Payment of Debt</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF STATE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Public Notice 1949]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of State.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of State is giving notice that all requests for payments pursuant to court-ordered garnishments as authorized under section 9 of Public Law No. 103-94, Hatch Act Reform Amendments of 1993, for all employees of the Department of State shall be submitted to the Executive Director (L/EX), Office of the Legal Adviser, Department of State, room 5519A, 22nd and C Streets NW., Washington, DC 20520, (202) 647-8323. This is the same agent designated for service of garnishments under 5 CFR part 581.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Executive Director of the Office of the Legal Adviser, Department of State, is not authorized to accept requests for payments pursuant to court-ordered garnishments for employees of any other Federal agency, and any such requests submitted will be returned.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 23, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments regarding this notice should be sent to the Assistant Legal Adviser for Legislation and General Management (L/LM), Office of the Legal Adviser, Department of State, room 5425, 22nd and C Streets NW., Washington, DC 20520.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Sheila McCoy at (202) 647-7359.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Congress has authorized the garnishment of Federal civilian employees' wages for debts pursuant to section 9 of Public Law 103-94, Hatch Act Reform Amendments of 1993. The applications and orders and legal issues related thereto will be reviewed by the Office of the Legal Adviser.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Mary Beth West,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Legal Adviser for Legislation and General Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3948 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4710-08-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
