<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00097</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00052</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Extension of Public Comment Period on the Draft Pacific Coastal Barriers Study and Accompanying Maps of Areas Under Consideration for Inclusion in the Coastal Barrier Resources System</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of extension of time period for public comment.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (Service), is extending the comment period for review of the Draft Pacific Coastal Barriers Study and accompanying maps, prepared pursuant to the Coastal Barriers Improvement Act of 1990 (Act). The notice of availability for the Draft Study and maps was published on December 17, 1993. Public information meetings were held in the four affected States. Based on requests received from the public and the Governors of California, Oregon, and Washington during the initial public comment period, the Service determined an extended review period is necessary to allow interested parties additional time to submit written comments on the proposal.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be received from the appropriate Governors no later than April 25, 1994. Comments from all other interested parties should be received no later than March 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments should be addressed to the Regional Director, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, 911 NE. 11th Avenue, Portland, Oregon 97232-4181.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Paula Levin, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, 911 NE. 11th Avenue, Portland, Oregon 97232-4181, (503) 231-2068. Copies of the Draft Study and accompanying maps are available for public inspection, during normal business hours, at the locations listed under supplementary information.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Reference December 17, 1993,</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice of availability of the Draft Pacific Coastal Barriers Study and Accompanying Maps of Areas Under consideration for Inclusion in the Coastal Barriers Resources System.</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 18, 1982, President Reagan signed the Coastal Barrier Resources Act (CBRA) into law (Pub. L. 97-348). Section 4 of CBRA establishes the Coastal Barrier Resources System (System) as referred to and adopted by Congress, and sections 5 and 6 prohibit all new Federal expenditures and financial assistance within the units of that System unless specifically excepted by the Act. Coastal barrier units were designated along the Atlantic and Gulf of Mexico coasts.</textblock>
    <textblock>On November 16, 1990, President Bush signed the Coastal Barrier Improvement Act of 1990 (CBIA) into law (Pub. L. 101-591). The CBIA greatly expanded the size of the System by adding coastal barriers of the Great Lakes, as well as additional areas along the Atlantic and Gulf of Mexico coasts. The CBIA amended section 1321 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to prohibit the issuance of new Federal flood insurance within ``otherwise protected areas'' identified on the maps referred to in the CBIA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 6 of the CBIA directed the Secretary of the Interior to prepare a study which examines the need for protecting undeveloped coastal barriers along the Pacific coast of the United States and to prepare maps identifying undeveloped coastal barriers bordering the Pacific Ocean south of 49 degrees north latitude (approximately the Canada-Washington State boundary) which the Secretary and the appropriate Governor consider to be appropriate for inclusion in the System. Furthermore, the study is to examine:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The potential for loss of human life and damage to fish, wildlife, and other natural resources, and the potential for the wasteful expenditure of Federal revenues given the geologic differences of the coastal barriers along the Pacific coast as opposed to those found along the Atlantic and Gulf coasts; and</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
