<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00214</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00102</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Act limits any one award to not more than $10,000,000 for any one fiscal year. The Department is not bound by any estimates in this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Part III</textblock>
    <textblock>CFDA No. 84.203A␣Star Schools_Distance Education Projects</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose of the program:</textblock>
    <textblock>To encourage improved instruction in various subject areas for underserved populations through the use of telecommunications networks.</textblock>
    <textblock>Eligible applicants:</textblock>
    <textblock>Only eligible telecommunications partnerships may receive grants under this program. Eligible telecommunications partnerships must be organized on a statewide or multistate basis. Two types of partnerships are eligible:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A public agency or corporation established for the purposes of developing and operating telecommunications networks to enhance educational opportunities provided by educational institutions, teacher training centers, and other entities, provided that the agency or corporation represents the interests of elementary and secondary schools which are eligible for assistance under Chapter 1 of Title 1 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) A partnership which includes three or more of the following, and at least one of which shall be an agency described in (1) or (2), and which will provide a telecommunications network:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A local educational agency, which has a significant number of elementary and secondary schools which are eligible for assistance under Chapter 1 of Title 1 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 or elementary and secondary schools operated for Indian children by the Department of the Interior eligible under section 1005(d) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A State educational agency;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) An institution of higher education or a State higher education agency;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) A teacher training center or academy which_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Provides teacher preservice and inservice training; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Receives Federal financial assistance or has been approved by a State agency;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)(A) A public or private entity with experience and expertise in the planning and operation of a telecommunications network, including entities involved in telecommunications through satellite, cable, telephone, or computers; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) A public broadcasting entity with such experience; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) A public or private elementary or secondary school.</textblock>
    <textblock>Continuing eligibility:</textblock>
    <textblock>An eligible telecommunications partnership currently funded under the Star Schools Program is eligible to receive an additional grant if it demonstrates that the partnership will:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Continue to provide services in the subject areas and geographic areas in which services were provided under the previous Star Schools grant; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Use all grant funds to provide expanded services by:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Increasing the number of students, schools, or school districts served by the courses of instruction assisted under this program in the previous grant period;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Providing new courses of instruction; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Serving new populations of underserved individuals, such as children or adults who are disadvantaged, have limited-English proficiency, are disabled, are illiterate, or lack high school diplomas or their equivalent.</textblock>
    <textblock>Priorities:</textblock>
    <textblock>Under 34 CFR 75.105(c)(3), the Secretary gives an absolute preference for applications that meet one or more of the following priorities. The Secretary funds under this competition only applications that meet one or more of these absolute priorities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Absolute Priority 1_National Education Goals</textblock>
    <textblock>Projects that develop and deliver instructional programming for elementary or secondary school students, or both, that supports achievement of one or more of the National Education Goals, and that is consistent with challenging national or State content standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Absolute Priority 2_Preparation for Work</textblock>
    <textblock>Projects that develop and deliver instructional programming to enhance the workplace and literacy skills of high school students, or young adults who are not in school, or both, in order to prepare students for responsible citizenship, further learning, and productive employment, and make the school-to-work transition more successful.</textblock>
    <textblock>Absolute Priority 3_Preservice and Inservice Teacher Education</textblock>
    <textblock>Projects that develop and deliver programming for preservice teachers attending colleges and universities, or professional development for practicing teachers and other educational personnel, or both. In meeting this priority, projects must provide information about the National Education Goals, emerging national or State content standards, and ways in which standards-driven systemic reform can help ensure that all students have opportunities to reach high levels of achievement. In addition, projects must provide professional development activities that include strong academic content and subject-specific pedagogical components to help teachers provide challenging learning experiences in the core academic subjects for their students.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Part II_Fiscal Information</textblock>
    <textblock>1CFDA No. and name</textblock>
    <textblock>1Estimated available funds</textblock>
    <textblock>1Estimated range of awards</textblock>
    <textblock>1Estimated average size of awards</textblock>
    <textblock>1Estimated number of awards</textblock>
    <textblock>84.203A␣Distance Education Projects</textblock>
    <textblock>$20,096,800</textblock>
    <textblock>$1,500,000-4,000,000</textblock>
    <textblock>$2,500,000</textblock>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
    <textblock>84.203B␣Special Statewide Project</textblock>
    <textblock>4,000,000</textblock>
    <textblock>4,000,000</textblock>
    <textblock>4,000,000</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>84.203C␣Dissemination Grants</textblock>
    <textblock>1,297,200</textblock>
    <textblock>250,000-350,000</textblock>
    <textblock>300,000</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
