<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00121</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00072</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Documents Containing Reporting or Recordkeeping Requirements: Office of Management and Budget Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of the OMB review of information and collection.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The NRC has recently submitted to OMB for review the following proposal for collection of information under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. chapter 35).</textblock>
    <textblock>1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of submission:</textblock>
    <textblock>Revision.</textblock>
    <textblock>2.</textblock>
    <textblock>The title of the information collection:</textblock>
    <textblock>10 CFR Part 34, ``Licenses for Radiography and Radiation Safety Requirements for Radiographic Operations'' and NRC Form 313, Application for Material License.</textblock>
    <textblock>3.</textblock>
    <textblock>The form number, if applicable:</textblock>
    <textblock>NRC Form 313.</textblock>
    <textblock>4.</textblock>
    <textblock>How often the collection is required:</textblock>
    <textblock>On occasion. Upon submittal of an application for a materials license or renewal, decommissioning review, petition for rulemaking, status as an independent certifying organization, or upon discovery of a leaking source.</textblock>
    <textblock>5.</textblock>
    <textblock>Who will be required to report:</textblock>
    <textblock>Licenses and applicants requesting approvals for actions proposed in accordance with 10 CFR Part 34.</textblock>
    <textblock>6.</textblock>
    <textblock>An estimate of the number of responses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 34_729, NRC Form 313-700.</textblock>
    <textblock>7.</textblock>
    <textblock>An estimate of the total number of hours needed annually to complete the requirement or request:</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 34_1,530 hours for reporting (approximately 2.2 hours per response) plus an additional 64,285 hours for recordkeeping (approximately 91.8 hours per licensee); NRC Form 313_9,900 hours for 700 licensees (approximately 14 hours per response).</textblock>
    <textblock>8.</textblock>
    <textblock>An indication of whether section 3504(h), Pub. L. 96-511 applies:</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicable.</textblock>
    <textblock>9.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abstract:</textblock>
    <textblock>NRC regulation, 10 CFR part 34, specifies the information and data to be provided by applicants and licensees using byproduct material for industrial radiography. The 10 CFR part 34 is being revised in its entirety. The revision will add or modify the requirements to include mandatory certification of radiographers, additional training of radiographers' assistants, leak tests of ``S'' tubes, and specifies records to be kept at field stations, permanent installations, temporary jobsites and use or storage location exceeding 180 days. The proposed revision will require the following additional information to be reported on NRC Form 313, Application for Materials License: locations and descriptions of all field stations and permanent radiographic installations, the designation of a Radiation Safety Officer, and additional information on training and testing. This information is reviewed by NRC to ensure that the safety of radiographers and the public is protected.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the submittal may be inspected or obtained for a fee from the NRC Public Document Room, 2120 L Street, NW. (Lower Level), Washington, DC 20037.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments and questions should be directed to the OMB reviewer: Troy Hillier, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs (3150-0007 and 3150-0120), NEOB-3019, Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments can also be submitted by telephone (202) 395-3084.</textblock>
    <textblock>The NRC Clearance Officer is Brenda Jo Shelton, (301) 492-8132.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated at Bethesda, Maryland, this 14th day of February 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Arnold E. Levin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Designated Senior Official for Information Resources Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3981 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7590-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
