<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00124</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00075</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Consolidation of Region V Office With Region IV Office; Transfer of Emergency Response Functions and Responsibilities</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>General notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) is transferring the emergency response functions and responsibilities of the current Region V office in Walnut Creek, California, to the Region IV office in Arlington, Texas.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Samuel J. Collins, USNRC, Region IV, Arlington, Texas, telephone (817) 860-8183.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of this notice is to announce that the NRC is consolidating its Region V office in Walnut Creek, California, with the Region IV office in Arlington, Texas. Transition planning for this consolidation has established that, effective March 1, 1994, the emergency response functions and responsibilities of the current Region V office will transfer to the Region IV office.</textblock>
    <textblock>The NRC Incident Response Plan, as stated in NUREG-0728, Rev. 2, will remain unchanged and all response functions and responsibilities currently in place in the Region V office will be transferred to the RIV office in Arlington, Texas. Licensee notifications for emergency response purposes will be unchanged and will be sent to the NRC Headquarters Operations Officer at 301-951-0550.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sometime shortly after March 1, 1994, the actual realignment of organizational structure will occur eliminating Region V and establishing an NRC Field Office in Walnut Creek, California, as an integral part of the Region IV office in Arlington, Texas. Until the formal realignment, the lead for inspection program responsibility remains with Region V. Separate notification will be provided when Region V is abolished and the Region IV Field Office is established in Walnut Creek, California.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated at Arlington, Texas, this 14th day of February 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John M. Montgomery,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Regional Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3982 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7590-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
