<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00192</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00099</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Wednesday</textblock>
    <textblock>February 23, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part IV</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Commerce</textblock>
    <textblock>International Trade Administration</textblock>
    <textblock>North American Free Trade Agreement: Rules of Procedure for Article 1905 Special Committees; Notice</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 36␣/␣Wednesday, February 23,</textblock>
    <textblock>1994␣/␣Notices</textblock>
    <textblock>North American Free Trade Agreement: Rules of Procedure for Article 1905 Special Committees</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>International Trade Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>North American Free Trade Agreement, NAFTA Secretariat, United States Section, International Trade Administration, Department of Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Rules of Procedure for NAFTA Article 1905 Special Committees.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Canada, Mexico, and the United States have negotiated the rules of procedure for Article 1905 Special Committees. These rules apply to special committee proceedings conducted pursuant to Article 1905 of the Agreement, unless the involved Parties otherwise agree.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 1, 1994, the date of the entry into force of the North American Free Trade Agreement (``Agreement''). These Rules of Procedure shall apply to all special committee proceedings commenced on or after the effective date.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Lisa B. Koteen, Senior Attorney, Stacy J. Ettinger, Attorney-Advisor, or Terrence J. McCartin, Attorney-Advisor, Office of the Chief Counsel for Import Administration, room B-099, U.S. Department of Commerce, 14th and Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20230; telephone: (202) 482-0836, (202) 482-4618, or (202) 482-5031, respectively. For procedural matters involving cases under panel review, contact James R. Holbein, United States Secretary, NAFTA Secretariat, room 2061, U.S. Department of Commerce, 14th and Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20230; telephone: (202) 482-5438; fax: (202) 482-0148.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>Chapter Nineteen of the North American Free Trade Agreement (``Agreement'') establishes a mechanism for replacing judicial review of final antidumping and countervailing duty determinations involving imports from Canada, Mexico, or the United States with review by independent binational panels. If requested, these panels will expeditiously review final determinations to determine whether they are consistent with the antidumping or countervailing duty law of the importing country.</textblock>
    <textblock>In instances in which one of the Parties to the Agreement alleges, pursuant to Article 1905.1 of the Agreement, that the application of another Party's domestic law (a) has prevented the establishment of a panel; (b) has prevented a panel from rendering a final decision; (c) has prevented the implementation of a panel's decision or denied it binding force and effect; or (d) has resulted in a failure to provide opportunity for proper review of a final determination by a panel or a court of competent jurisdiction, that Party may request the establishment of a special committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title IV of the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act of 1993, Public Law No. 103-182, 107 Stat. 2057, amends United States law to implement Chapter Nineteen of the Agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>The</textblock>
    <textblock>Article 1905 Special Committee Rules</textblock>
    <textblock>are intended to give effect to the special committee provisions of Chapter Nineteen of the Agreement by setting forth the procedures for commencing, conducting, and completing special committee proceedings. These rules are the result of negotiations among Canada, Mexico, and the United States in compliance with the terms of the Agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>North American Free Trade Agreement</textblock>
    <textblock>Rules of Procedure for Article 1905 Special Committees</textblock>
    <textblock>Contents</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Short Title</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Statement of General Intent</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Interpretation</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Operation of the Special Committee</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
