<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00089</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00044</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Social Security Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Rescission of Social Security Acquiescence</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Social Security Administration, HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Rescission of Social Security Acquiescence Ruling 88-5(1)_</textblock>
    <textblock>McCuin</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary of Health and Human Services,</textblock>
    <textblock>817 F.2d 161 (1st Cir. 1987).</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with 20 CFR 404.985(e), 416.1485(e) and 422.406(b)(2), published January 11, 1990 (55 FR 1012), the Principal Deputy Commissioner of Social Security gives notice of the rescission of Social Security Acquiescence Ruling 88-5(1).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 23, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Darlynda Bogle, Litigation Staff, Social Security Administration, 6401 Security Blvd., Baltimore, MD 21235, (410) 965-4237.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>A Social Security Acquiescence Ruling explains how we will apply a holding in a decision of a United States Court of Appeals that we determine conflicts with our interpretation of a provision of the Social Security Act or regulations when the Government has decided not to seek further review of the case or is unsuccessful on further review.</textblock>
    <textblock>As provided by 20 CFR 404.985(e)(4) and 416.1485(e)(4), a Social Security Acquiescence Ruling may be rescinded as obsolete if we subsequently clarify, modify or revoke the regulation or ruling that was the subject of the circuit court holding for which the Acquiescence Ruling was issued.</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 27, 1988, we issued Acquiescence Ruling (AR)</textblock>
    <textblock>88-5(1) to reflect the holding in</textblock>
    <textblock>McCuin</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary of Health and Human Services,</textblock>
    <textblock>817 F.2d 161 (1st Cir. 1987), that, once the 60-day period for the Appeals Council's own-motion review had expired, the Secretary's reopening regulations (20 CFR 404.987, 404.988, 416.1487 and 416.1488)</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>allowed reopening of an Administrative Law Judge (ALJ) decision only on the claimant's motion. Accordingly, under the McCuin AR, where an ALJ's decision had become final, (</textblock>
    <textblock>i.e.,</textblock>
    <textblock>the time for requesting Appeals Council review of the decision had expired and no request for such review had been filed by the claimant and the Appeals Council had not taken own-motion review within the 60-day time limit), the Appeals Council could not reopen and revise the decision on its own initiative under the Secretary's regulations on reopening. The AR applied to cases in which the claimant resided in Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island or, for title II claims only, in Puerto Rico at the time of the ALJ decision.</textblock>
    <textblock>We indicated in the McCuin AR that the Social Security Administration (SSA) intended to clarify the reopening regulations at issue in the McCuin case through the rulemaking process, and that the AR would continue to apply until such clarification was made. On October 28, 1991, we published a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking and proposed rules (56 FR 55477) that would clarify these regulations. In this issue of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>we are now publishing final rules, which explicitly state that SSA may reopen a determination or decision that has become final either on its own initiative or at the request of an individual who was a party to the determination or decision. Accordingly, since the regulation that was the subject of the McCuin decision has now been revised, we are rescinding the McCuin AR concurrently with the publication of the revised regulations. Adjudicators of claims arising in the First Circuit (Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island or Puerto Rico) will no longer follow the AR, but will decide cases in accordance with the revised regulations on reopening</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Programs Nos. 93.802 Social Security_Disability Insurance; 93.803 Social Security_Retirement Insurance; 93.805 Social Security_Survivor's Insurance; 93.806_Special Benefits for Disabled Coal Miners; 93.807_Supplemental Security Income.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: November 4, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The court based its decision on the reopening regulations applicable to title II cases. However, since the reopening regulations applicable to title XVI cases are similar, the AR extended to both title II and title XVI cases.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Shirley S. Chater,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Commissioner of Social Security.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3959 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4190-29-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
