<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00103</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00054</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>A request extending the collection of information listed below has been submitted to the Office of Management and Budget for approval under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. Chapter 35). Copies of the proposed collection of information and related forms and explanatory material may be obtained by contacting the Bureau's clearance officer at the phone number listed below. Comments and suggestions on the requirement should be made within 30 days directly to the Bureau clearance officer and to the Office of Management and Budget, Paperwork Reduction Project (1032-0044), Washington, DC 20503, telephone 202-395-7340.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Railroad Agent's Report of Shipments of Minerals and Mineral Products.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB Approval Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>1032-0044.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abstract:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bureau's work of collecting and compiling mineral data is supervised by persons who have scientific and practical knowledge of the subject and a personal acquaintance with both the producing and consuming establishments. These personnel use Form 6-1998-Q, Railroad Agent's Report of Shipments of Minerals and Products, to obtain general information on mines not presently on the Bureau's mailing lists. If the information obtained from Form 6-1198-Q indicates that the mine is currently producing a mineral for which the Bureau collects data, the company operating the mine is added to the appropriate survey frame and mailed the corresponding collection.</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau form number:</textblock>
    <textblock>6-1198-Q.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency:</textblock>
    <textblock>Quarterly.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Railroad agents handling mineral products.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual responses:</textblock>
    <textblock>18.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual burden hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>36.</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau clearance officer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Alice J. Wissman (202) 501-9569.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Mines</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Information Collection Submitted to the Office of Management and Budget for Review Under the Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Hermann Enzer,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Bureau of Mines.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3952 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-53-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
