<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00230</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00104</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Implementation of the second concept would be coordinated through the national Operation</textblock>
    <textblock>Lifesaver headquarters office located in Alexandria, Virginia. This second concept would</textblock>
    <textblock>facilitate individual recruitment of National Service volunteers at the local level and would</textblock>
    <textblock>provide participants with opportunities to provide service to their local communities and states</textblock>
    <textblock>and to participate in the development of viable transportation safety programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>2.4.2␣Goals and Priorities</textblock>
    <textblock>This program addresses the following national priorities:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Education_Participants will be exposed to a variety of project specific tasks</textblock>
    <textblock>and general job skills that could prepare participants for future employment</textblock>
    <textblock>opportunities.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Public Safety_Operation Lifesaver assists in promoting public awareness of the</textblock>
    <textblock>dangers associated with rail crossings, trespassing on railroad properties, and</textblock>
    <textblock>improper use of motor vehicles around rail facilities. Further, it will bring the</textblock>
    <textblock>audiences into contact with local police and other law enforcement agencies,</textblock>
    <textblock>which will open the lines of communication and create opportunities for</textblock>
    <textblock>cooperation.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Human Needs_This Program will stimulate awareness of rail and highway</textblock>
    <textblock>safety-related problems within local and State communities and bring people</textblock>
    <textblock>together to address them. The programs will also provide safety training to a</textblock>
    <textblock>wide audience, ranging in age from pre-schoolers to senior citizens.</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Environment_Operation Lifesaver has been successful in reducing community</textblock>
    <textblock>environmental hazards associated with rail crossings.</textblock>
    <textblock>2.4.3␣ Anticipated Outcomes and Results</textblock>
    <textblock>a. The utilization of a community service organization would result in benefits to</textblock>
    <textblock>the local communities and provide needed public education in the area of rail</textblock>
    <textblock>safety to the specifically targeted audiences and the general public. As past</textblock>
    <textblock>records have shown, there should be a downward trend in accidents, injuries,</textblock>
    <textblock>and trespasser violations in conjunction with the Operation Lifesaver Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>The statistics developed would be readily available for program evaluation, cost</textblock>
    <textblock>analysis, and community acceptance and adoption.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. The hiring and placement of assistant administrative coordinators throughout the</textblock>
    <textblock>Operation Lifesaver system would result in better coordination of the program</textblock>
    <textblock>with railroad companies, law enforcement agencies, local and state governments,</textblock>
    <textblock>the various informational media and the general population. The opportunity to</textblock>
    <textblock>function within an established program would enhance the job skills and</textblock>
    <textblock>personal marketability for the participants for future endeavors.</textblock>
    <textblock>Both concepts will expose the participants to the opportunity to perform community service, and</textblock>
    <textblock>enhance the development of personal qualities, educational values and positive work ethics.</textblock>
    <textblock>2.4.4␣Funding</textblock>
    <textblock>DOT intends to apply for funding for program costs, including living allowances, educational</textblock>
    <textblock>awards, health insurance, and child care costs, from the National Service Corporation. A</textblock>
    <textblock>budgetary review is ongoing at this time to seek other sources of funding within DOT. The</textblock>
    <textblock>National and Community Service Act will be an item in the Fiscal Year 1996 budget submission</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Federal Railroad Administration, and it is anticipated that direct funding for national</textblock>
    <textblock>service involvement in the Operation Lifesaver program may be available from DOT in future</textblock>
    <textblock>years.</textblock>
    <textblock>2.4.5␣DOT Agency Involvement and Expertise Available</textblock>
    <textblock>The Operation Lifesaver and adjunct trespasser programs are addressed by several of the DOT</textblock>
    <textblock>modal administrations, specifically the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) and the Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Highway Administration (FHWA).</textblock>
    <textblock>2.4.6␣DOT Contacts</textblock>
    <textblock>Gordon J. Smith, Federal Railroad Administration, Office of Administration, (202) 366-0589, FAX (202) 366-7439</textblock>
    <textblock>Bruce George, Highway Rail Crossing and Trespasser Division, Federal Railroad Administration, (202) 366-0533</textblock>
    <textblock>Mailing Address: Room 8232, 400 7th St. SW., Washington DC 20590</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
