<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-1-00040</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Extension of Compliance Date for Installation of Digital Flight Data Recorders on Stage 2 Airplanes</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 121</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 27532; Notice No. 94-4]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 2120-AF34</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>agency:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of proposed rulemaking (NPRM).</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>summary:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice proposes to change the final compliance date for installing improved (11-parameter digital) flight data recorders from May 26, 1994, to the next heavy maintenance check, but no later than May 26, 1995, in Stage 2 airplanes subject to the rules requiring a transition to an all Stage 3 fleet. This change would allow carriers more time to take actions necessary to retrofit Stage 2 airplanes, and would make the flight data recorder replacement rule more compatible with the noise transition requirements without having a significant impact on safety.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>dates:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received by March 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>addresses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this notice should be mailed, in triplicate to: Federal Aviation Administration, Office of Chief Counsel, Attention: Rules Docket (AGC-200), Docket No. 27532, 800 Independence Avenue, Washington, DC 20591. Comments delivered must be marked Docket No. 27532. Comments may be examined in room 915G weekdays, except on Federal holidays, between 8:30 a.m. and 5 p.m.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>for further information contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Gary E. Davis, Project Development Branch, AFS-240, Air Transportation Division, Flight Standards Service, Federal Aviation Administration, 800 Independence Avenue SW., Washington, DC 20591, telephone (202) 267-8096.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments Invited</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to participate in the making of the proposed rule by submitting such written data, views, or arguments as they may desire. Comments relating to the environmental, energy, federalism, or economic impact that might result from adopting the proposal in this notice are also invited. Substantive comments should be accompanied by cost estimates. Comments should identify the regulatory docket or notice number and should be submitted in triplicate to the Rules Docket address specified above. All comments received on or before the closing date for comments specified will be considered by the Administrator before taking action on this proposed rulemaking. The proposal contained in this notice may be changed in light of comments received. All comments received will be available, both before and after the closing date for comments, in the Rules Docket for examination by interested persons. A report summarizing each substantive public contact with Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) personnel concerned with this rulemaking will be filed in the docket. Commenters wishing the FAA to acknowledge receipt of their comments submitted in response to this notice must include a pre-addressed, stamped postcard on which the following statement is made: ``Comments to Docket No. 27532.'' The postcard will be date stamped and mailed to the commenter.</textblock>
    <textblock>Availability of NPRM's</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person may obtain a copy of this NPRM by submitting a request to the Federal Aviation Administration, Office of Public Affairs, Attention: Public Inquiry Center, APA-430, 800 Independence Avenue SW., Washington, DC 20591, or by calling (202) 267-3484. Communications must identify the notice number of this NPRM.</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons interested in being placed on the mailing list for future NPRM's should request from the above office a copy of Advisory Circular No. 11-2A, Notice of Proposed Rulemaking Distribution System, which describes the application procedure.</textblock>
    <textblock>History</textblock>
    <textblock>On March 25, 1987, the FAA promulgated a final rule that requires operators, by May 26, 1994, to install improved (11-parameter digital) flight data recorders on all airplanes type certificated on or before September 30, 1969, and operated under part 121 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (52 FR 9622). The final rule, ยง121.343(c), was issued in response to a recommendation from the National Transportation Safety Board that was based on accident/incident files for January 1983 to February 1986 that revealed a high failure rate for metal foil flight recorders. The data revealed that 37 recorders (48 percent) had one or more malfunctioning parameters preceding the accident or incident, preventing the recording or readout of pertinent data.</textblock>
    <textblock>Air Transport Association's Petition for Exemption</textblock>
    <textblock>In August 1991, the Air Transport Association (ATA) petitioned the FAA for an exemption from ยง121.343(c). The ATA stated that the compliance date for the digital flight data recorder (DFDR) retrofit was inappropriate when considering the schedule for either retrofitting airplanes with noise abatement equipment or retiring airplanes in order to comply with the Stage 3 transition mandated in September 1991 (56 FR 48628, September 25, 1991). The FAA denied the ATA exemption request, stating that the Stage 3 transition rule did not mandate the retirement of any Stage 2 airplanes. The FAA pointed out that noise abatement equipment was expected to be available for virtually the entire active fleet.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
