<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00041</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00031</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[OPP-50770; FRL-4639-2]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Issuance of Experimental Use Permits</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA has granted experimental use permits to the following applicants. These permits are in accordance with, and subject to, the</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions of 40 CFR part l72, which defines EPA procedures with respect to the use of pesticides for experimental use purposes.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>By mail: Registration Division (7505C), Office of Pesticide Programs, Environmental Protection Agency, 401 M St., SW., Washington, DC 20460.</textblock>
    <textblock>In person or by telephone: Contact the product manager at the</textblock>
    <textblock>following address at the office location or telephone number cited in each</textblock>
    <textblock>experimental use permit: 1921 Jefferson Davis Highway, Arlington, VA.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA has issued the following experimental use permits:</textblock>
    <textblock>4581-EUP-41</textblock>
    <textblock>. Issuance. Elf Atochem North America, Inc., Agrichemicals Division, 3 Parkway, Rm. 619, Philadelphia, PA 19102. This experimental use permit allows the use of 100 pounds of the herbicide mono(N,N-dimethylalkylamine) salt of endothall on 74.25 acres of cotton to evaluate the control of desiccation and defoliation. The program is authorized only in the State of Texas. The experimental use permit is effective from June 17, 1993 to June 17, 1994. This permit is issued with the limitation that all crops are destroyed or used for research purposes only. (Joanne Miller, PM 23, Rm. 237, CM #2, (703-305-7830)).</textblock>
    <textblock>34147-EUP-3</textblock>
    <textblock>. Renewal. Hoechst-Roussel Agri-Vet Company, Route 202-206, P.O. Box 2500, Sommerville, NJ 08876-1258. This experimental use permit allows the use of 800 pounds of the insecticide (1R,3R)-3-(2,2-dibromovinyl)-2,2-dimethylcyclopropanecarboxylic acid (s)-alpha-cyano-3-phenoxybenzyl ester on 4,000 acres of cotton to evaluate the control of various cotton insects. The program is authorized only in the States of Alabama, Arkansas, California, Georgia, Louisiana, Mississippi, New Mexico, North Carolina, Oklahoma, South Carolina, Tennessee, and Texas. The experimental use permit is effective from June 1, 1993 to June 1, 1994. A temporary tolerance for residues of the active ingredient in or on cotton has been established. (Susan Lewis, PM 21, Rm. 227, CM #2, (703-305-5663)).</textblock>
    <textblock>524-EUP-75.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issuance. Monsanto Agricultural Company, 800 North Lindbergh Blvd., St. Louis, MO 63167. This experimental use permit allows the use of 1,633.5 pounds (810.0 pounds on citrus and 823.5 pounds on cotton each year) of the herbicide 3-pyridinecarboxylic acid, 2-(difluoromethyl)-5-(4,5-dihydro-2-thiazolyl)-4-(2-methylpropyl)-6-(trifluoromethyl)-, methyl ester on 3,615 acres per year of citrus and cotton to evaluate the control of various weeds. The program is authorized only in the States of Alabama, Arizona, Arkansas, California, Florida, Georgia, Louisiana, Mississippi, North Carolina, and Texas. The experimental use permit is effective from July 27, 1993 to July 27, 1995. Temporary tolerances for residues of the active ingredient in or on citrus, cotton forage, and cotton seed have been established. (Joanne Miller, PM 23, Rm. 237, CM #2, (703-305-7830)).</textblock>
    <textblock>65626-EUP-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issuance. Mycotech Corporation, 630 Utah Ave., P.O. Box 4113, Butte, MT 59702. This experimental use permit allows the use of 600 pounds of the microbial insecticide</textblock>
    <textblock>Beauvaria bassiana</textblock>
    <textblock>- Mycotech grasshopper strain on 3,390 acres of rangeland to evaluate the control of grasshoppers and mormon crickets. The program is authorized only in the States of Idaho, Montana, Nebraska, North Dakota, South Dakota, and Wyoming. The experimental use permit is effective from June 25, 1993 to July 15, 1994. A temporary exemption from the requirement of a tolerance for residues of the active ingredient in or on rangeland has been established. (Phil Hutton, PM 18, Rm. 213, CM #2, (703-305-7690)).</textblock>
    <textblock>45639-EUP-49</textblock>
    <textblock>. Issuance. Nor-Am Chemical Company, Little Falls Centre One, 2711 Centerville, Rd., Wilmington, DE 19808. This experimental use permit allows the use of 525 pounds of the herbicides diuron and thidiazuron on 3,500 acres of cotton to be evaluated as a pre-harvest aid through defoliation. The program is authorized only in the States of Arizona, California, and Texas. The experimental use permit is effective from August 12, 1993 to August 12, 1994. Permanent tolerances for residues of the active ingredients in or on cotton have been established (40 CFR 180.106 and 180.403). (Joanne Miller, PM 23, Rm. 237, CM #2, (703-305-7830))</textblock>
    <textblock>58998-EUP-8</textblock>
    <textblock>. Extension. Novo Nordisk Bioindustrials, Inc., 33 Turner Road, Danbury, CT 06813. This experimental use permit allows the use of 44 pounds of the microbial insecticide</textblock>
    <textblock>Bacillus thuringiensis</textblock>
    <textblock>subspecies</textblock>
    <textblock>israelensis</textblock>
    <textblock>on 453 acres of catch basins, clean water, curb gutters in residential areas, ditches, flood water, polluted waters, ponds, rivers, salt marshes, storm water retention areas, streams, and tidal water. The program is authorized only in the States of California, Delaware, Florida, Michigan, Minnesota, New York, Pennsylvania, South Carolina, Tennessee, Texas, and Utah. The experimental use permit is effective from July 6, 1993 to January 31, 1994. (Phil Hutton, PM 18, Rm. 213, CM #2, (703-305-7690))</textblock>
    <textblock>66204-EUP-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issuance. Sylvan Foods, Inc., One Moonlight Dr., Worthington, PA 16262. This experimental use permit allows the use of 14 pounds of the</textblock>
    <textblock>pseudomonas fluorescens</textblock>
    <textblock>strain NCIB 12089 on 13 acres of mushrooms to evaluate the control of bacterial blotch. The program is authorized only in the State of Pennsylvania. The experimental use permit is effective from June 15, 1993 to June 30, 1994. A temporary exemption from the requirement of a tolerance for residues of the active ingredient in or on mushrooms has been established. (Susan Lewis, PM 21, Rm. 227, CM #2, (703-305-5663))</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons wishing to review these experimental use permits are referred to the designated product managers. Inquires concerning these permits should be directed to the persons cited above. It is suggested that interested persons call before visiting the EPA office, so that the appropriate file may be made available for inspection purposes from 8 a.m. to 4 p.m., Monday through</textblock>
    <textblock>Friday, excluding legal holidays.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority</textblock>
    <textblock>: 7 U.S.C. 136.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental protection, Experimental use permits.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Stephen L. Johnson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Registration Division, Office of Pesticide Programs.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3762 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
