<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-0-00044</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-0-00019</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>This action has been classified as a Table 2 action by the Regional Administrator under the procedures published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on January 19, 1989 (54 FR 2214-2225). On January 6, 1989, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) waived Table 2 and 3 SIP revisions (54 FR 2222) from the requirements of section 3 of Executive Order 12291 for two years. EPA has submitted a request for a permanent waiver for Table 2 and Table 3 SIP revisions. OMB has agreed to continue the waiver until such time as it rules on EPA's request. This request continues in effect under Executive Order 12866 which superseded Executive Order 12291 on September 30, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Nothing in this action shall be construed as permitting or allowing or establishing a precedent for any future request for a revision to any state implementation plan. Each request for revision to the state implementation plan shall be considered separately in light of specific technical, economic, and environmental factors and in relation to relevant statutory and regulatory requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the Regulatory Flexibility Act, 5 U.S.C. 600</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.,</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA must prepare a regulatory flexibility analysis assessing the impact of any proposed or final rule on small entities. 5 U.S.C. 603 and 604. Alternatively, EPA may certify that the rule will not have a significant impact on a substantial number of small entities. Small entities include small businesses, small not-for-profit enterprises, and government entities with jurisdiction over populations of less than 50,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>By this action, EPA is approving a state program created for the purpose of assisting small businesses in complying with existing statutory and regulatory requirements. The program being approved does not impose any new regulatory burden on small businesses; it is a program under which small businesses may elect to take advantage of assistance provided by the state. Therefore, because the EPA's approval of this program does not impose any new regulatory requirements on small businesses, I certify that it does not have a significant economic impact on any small entities affected.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 40 CFR Part 52</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental protection, Air pollution control, Incorporation by reference, Intergovernmental relations, Small business stationary source technical and environmental assistance program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Patrick M. Tobin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Administrator.</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 52 of chapter I, title 40,</textblock>
    <textblock>Code of Federal Regulations,</textblock>
    <textblock>is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 52_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 52 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>42.U.S.C. 7401-7671q.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart K_Florida</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 52.520, is amended by adding paragraph (c) (80) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§52.520</textblock>
    <textblock>Identification of plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(80) The Florida Department of Environmental Regulation has submitted revisions to chapter 403.0852 of the Florida Statute on February 24, 1993. These revisions address the requirements of section 507 of title V of the CAA and establish the Small Business Stationary Source Technical and Environmental Assistance Program (PROGRAM).</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Incorporation by reference.</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Florida Statute 403.031(20), 403.0852(1), (2), (3), (4), 403.0872(10)(b), 403.0873, 403.0851, approved on April 8, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Additional information_None.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3944 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
