<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00241</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00104</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Appendix A_Application Form for Proposals for the Department of Transportation National and Community Service Program</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposals for the DOT National and Community Service Program should contain all of the</textblock>
    <textblock>following information and should be submitted in the following format. DOT may need to seek</textblock>
    <textblock>additional information from applicants as a result of changes in the proposed regulations issued</textblock>
    <textblock>by the National Service Corporation or to more fully clarify and define specific proposals.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications should be double sided, double spaced, and printed in a font size not smaller than</textblock>
    <textblock>12 points. One unbound copy of the proposal with original signatures suitable for reproduction,</textblock>
    <textblock>plus two bound copies, should be submitted. All pages should be numbered and the specific</textblock>
    <textblock>DOT Program or Programs to be addressed should be identified at the top of each page. All</textblock>
    <textblock>documentation, attachments, or other information pertinent to the application should be included</textblock>
    <textblock>in a single submission, forwarded directly to the address listed below. Proposals should be</textblock>
    <textblock>submitted to:</textblock>
    <textblock>Brenda L. Harris</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Transportation</textblock>
    <textblock>400 7th Street SW., room 9410</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20590</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposals must be received by DOT no later than March 23, 1994, 4</textblock>
    <textblock>p.m. EST.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Title page</textblock>
    <textblock>(to be completed on the attached form identified as ``Attachment 1''), along with</textblock>
    <textblock>a Table of Contents for the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Application summary page</textblock>
    <textblock>, providing a one page overview of the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Identification of which of the five DOT Programs the applicant intends to</textblock>
    <textblock>implement.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. The specific needs to be met, particularly as they relate to the national priorities</textblock>
    <textblock>identified for the individual DOT Program(s).</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Key elements of the program design.</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Recruitment goals, including the percentage of participants (if any) to be drawn</textblock>
    <textblock>from the national recruitment system established by the National Service</textblock>
    <textblock>Corporation.</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Description of the administering organization and identification of primary</textblock>
    <textblock>program partners.</textblock>
    <textblock>3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Program mission statement and annual objectives</textblock>
    <textblock>(to be completed on the attached</textblock>
    <textblock>form identified as ``Attachment 2''). The National Service Corporation has identified</textblock>
    <textblock>three goals of National Service:</textblock>
    <textblock>a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Community service.</textblock>
    <textblock>Meeting community needs by getting things done through direct and</textblock>
    <textblock>demonstrable service in education, public safety, human needs, and the</textblock>
    <textblock>environment.</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Participant development.</textblock>
    <textblock>Positively impacting participants by developing leadership skills, fostering</textblock>
    <textblock>active, productive citizenship, and enhancing educational opportunities.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
