<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-0-00062</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-0-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>13. Section 393.67 is amended by adding a new paragraph (a)(6) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§393.67</textblock>
    <textblock>Liquid fuel tanks.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Private motor carrier of passengers. Motor carriers engaged in the private transportation of passengers may continue to operate a commercial motor vehicle which was not subject to this section or 49 CFR 571.301 at the time of its manufacture, provided the fuel tank of such vehicle is maintained to the original manufacturer's standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 395_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>16. The authority citation for part 395 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>49 U.S.C. 3102; 49 U.S.C. app. 2505; and 49 CFR 1.48.</textblock>
    <textblock>17. In §395.8, paragraph (a) introductory text is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§395.8</textblock>
    <textblock>Driver's record of duty status.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Except for a private motor carrier of passengers (nonbusiness), every motor carrier shall require every driver used by the motor carrier to record his/her duty status for each 24 hour period using the methods prescribed in either paragraphs (a)(1) or (2) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 396_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>18. The authority citation for part 396 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>49 U.S.C. app. 2509; 49 U.S.C. 3102; 49 CFR 1.48.</textblock>
    <textblock>19. In §396.3, the introductory text of paragraph (b) is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§396.3</textblock>
    <textblock>Inspection, repair, and maintenance.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Required records</textblock>
    <textblock>_For vehicles controlled for 30 consecutive days or more, except for a private motor carrier of passengers (nonbusiness), the motor carriers shall maintain, or cause to be maintained, the following record for each vehicle:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>20. In §396.11, paragraph (d) is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§396.11</textblock>
    <textblock>Driver vehicle inspection report(s).</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Exemption. The rules in this section shall not apply to a private motor carrier of passengers (nonbusiness) operations, driveaway-towaway operations as specified in §396.15, or to any motor carrier operating only one (1) motor vehicle.</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3951 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-22-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
