<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-1-00077</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-1-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>King and Tanner Crab Fisheries of the Bering Sea and Aleutian Islands</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>50 CFR Part 671</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[I.D. 021494A]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability of an amendment to a fishery management plan; request for comments.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>NMFS issues this notice that the North Pacific Fishery Management Council (Council) has submitted Amendment 2 to the Fishery Management Plan (FMP) for the Commercial King and Tanner Crab Fisheries of the Bering Sea/Aleutian Islands (BSAI) for Secretarial review and is requesting comments from the public. Copies of the amendment may be obtained from the Council (see</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on the FMP amendment should be submitted on or before April 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on the FMP amendment should be submitted to Ronald J. Berg, Chief, Fisheries Management Division, Alaska Region, NMFS, P.O. Box 21668, Juneau, Alaska 99802 (Attn: Lori Gravel), or delivered to the Federal Building, 709 West 9th Street, Juneau, Alaska.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of Amendment 2 and the environmental assessment (EA) and economic analysis prepared for the amendment are available from the North Pacific Fishery Management Council, P.O. Box 103136, Anchorage, AK 99510 (907-271-2809).</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Kim J. Spitler, Fisheries Management Division, Alaska Region, NMFS, at 907-586-7228.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act (Magnuson Act) requires that each Regional Fishery Management Council submit any FMP or FMP amendment it prepares to the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) for review and approval, disapproval, or partial disapproval. The Magnuson Act also requires that the Secretary, upon receiving an FMP or amendment, immediately publish a notice that the FMP or amendment is available for public review and comment. The Secretary will consider the public comments received during the comment period in determining whether to approve the FMP or amendment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendment 2 would establish the Norton Sound Section of the Northern District of the king crab fishery as a superexclusive registration area. The operator of any vessel registered and participating in this fishery would not be able to register that vessel and participate in other BSAI king crab fisheries. A proposed rule has been submitted that would remove existing regulations, which supersede State of Alaska regulations that established Norton Sound as a superexclusive registration area in the exclusive economic zone of the BSAI.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 50 CFR Part 671</textblock>
    <textblock>Fisheries, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 1801,</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard H. Schaefer,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director of Office of Fisheries,</textblock>
    <textblock>Conservation and Management,</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3932 Filed 2-16-94; 5:12 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
