<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00231</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00104</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>2.5␣Hazardous Materials Transportation Emergency Preparedness Assistance</textblock>
    <textblock>2.5.1␣Description of Program</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Background.</textblock>
    <textblock>The DOT Research and Special Programs Administration, Office of Hazardous Materials Safety</textblock>
    <textblock>(OHMS), currently carries out a national safety program to protect against the risks to life,</textblock>
    <textblock>health, property, and the environment inherent in the transportation of hazardous materials by</textblock>
    <textblock>water, air, highway and railroad. OHMS plans, implements, and manages hazardous materials</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory, enforcement, and outreach programs, and administers a user fee funded grant</textblock>
    <textblock>program to States and Indian tribes for planning and training for hazardous materials</textblock>
    <textblock>emergencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>The number and type of entities regulated by OHMS have increased dramatically since 1990,</textblock>
    <textblock>when the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act (HMTA) was amended. Prior to 1990, the</textblock>
    <textblock>office had jurisdiction over approximately 40,000 hazardous materials shippers and carriers. In</textblock>
    <textblock>the future, the inclusion of intrastate shippers and carriers will bring an additional 110,000 newly</textblock>
    <textblock>regulated shippers and carriers mandated by the HMTA amendment under the Hazardous</textblock>
    <textblock>Materials Regulations (HMR).</textblock>
    <textblock>Certain shippers and carriers are required to register with the Department and pay an annual fee.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Hazardous Materials Registration Program, which began in September 1992, funds</textblock>
    <textblock>emergency preparedness grants to States and Indian tribes for training and preparing to respond</textblock>
    <textblock>to hazardous materials emergencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>The HMTA Grant Program was presented to Congress in 1990 during the legislative process</textblock>
    <textblock>reauthorizing the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act of 1974. Grant funds were first</textblock>
    <textblock>distributed in Fiscal Year 1993. The HMTA grant program is carefully crafted to build upon</textblock>
    <textblock>existing programs and relationships. It has increased the emphasis on improving the capability</textblock>
    <textblock>of communities to plan for the full range of transportation related hazardous materials risks they</textblock>
    <textblock>face.</textblock>
    <textblock>Forty-seven States are participating in the HMTA grant program_an overwhelming first year</textblock>
    <textblock>response. Fifty-eight grants, totaling approximately $8.4 million, were given to States, Tribes,</textblock>
    <textblock>and Territories in the first grant budget period. 180,000 emergency responders will be trained</textblock>
    <textblock>with HMTA grant funds in the first year of the program; 81% of these responders are either</textblock>
    <textblock>paid or volunteer firefighters.</textblock>
    <textblock>The existing grant process begins with each participating State's Governor determining which</textblock>
    <textblock>agency within the State receives the HMTA grant. The selected agency distributes funds in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with HMTA grant rules and required certifications, ensuring the assistance is</textblock>
    <textblock>provided to intended recipients. The grant distribution system allows each State's Governor to</textblock>
    <textblock>make decisions on funding based on local factors, and allows DOT to leverage resources,</textblock>
    <textblock>thereby operating the HMTA grant program efficiently. The HMTA grant distribution system</textblock>
    <textblock>is lean, and gives exceptionally responsive service to State grantees.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. National Service Corps.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the OHMS's ``Hazardous Materials Transportation Emergency Preparedness Assistance''</textblock>
    <textblock>Program, national service funding will be used to employ national service participants as</textblock>
    <textblock>assistants to the State Emergency Response Commission (SERC), Local Emergency Planning</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee (LEPC), and State Emergency Management Agency levels. This Program will</textblock>
    <textblock>reinforce the Nation's Hazardous Materials Transportation Emergency Response/State</textblock>
    <textblock>Emergency Response structure, one of the objectives of the existing HMTA grant program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Local SERC/LEPC/emergency management national service participants may serve as assistants</textblock>
    <textblock>to prepare local emergency plans, perform hazardous materials commodity flow studies, and</textblock>
    <textblock>coordinate exercise of plans. These jobs, requiring little previous experience, could be learned</textblock>
    <textblock>mainly through on-the-job training.</textblock>
    <textblock>Use of national service funds to increase the effectiveness of the nationally recognized HMTA</textblock>
    <textblock>grant program would not only help the nation and localities, but also give national service</textblock>
    <textblock>participants experience in, and access to, an industry which is experiencing growth. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Emergency Planning and Community Right-to-Know Act of 1986, a reaction in part to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Bhopal, India tragedy, created SERCs and LEPCs to plan for emergency response, including</textblock>
    <textblock>feedback and coordination from broadly based local groups; many responsibilities were levied</textblock>
    <textblock>on states and localities with little funding. This program can provide assistance not previously</textblock>
    <textblock>available. Similarly, state emergency management agencies need assistance with hazardous</textblock>
    <textblock>materials planning and training grants.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is proposed that national service participants be involved as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. A day in the life of a national service participant might include assignment</textblock>
    <textblock>to an LEPC. For this participant the day might include working under the</textblock>
    <textblock>LEPC chairperson's supervision to gather data at the state police inspection</textblock>
    <textblock>point for a commodity flow study. The participant might use the data while</textblock>
    <textblock>interacting with LEPC members at an evening meeting. As a result of the</textblock>
    <textblock>meeting the LEPC might modify their emergency plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. At other times the participant might distribute material safety data sheets to</textblock>
    <textblock>the public, conduct community outreach meetings, or receive notification of a</textblock>
    <textblock>hazardous materials release and provide support for the SERC/LEPC or the</textblock>
    <textblock>community. At a state emergency information center, the participant might</textblock>
    <textblock>assist the watch officer in preparing and distributing the daily situation report.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Daily activities provide on-the-job training. For example, data may have</textblock>
    <textblock>indicated heavy transport of gasoline indicating the need for training in response</textblock>
    <textblock>to tanker incidents. The participant learns from experience the interaction</textblock>
    <textblock>between data, planning, and training. The participant might also be mentored</textblock>
    <textblock>by the members of the LEPC, the response community, or the trucking industry.</textblock>
    <textblock>In this way, the public good is served and the participant receives valuable</textblock>
    <textblock>training.</textblock>
    <textblock>2.5.2␣Goals and Priorities</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed program meets all criteria for funding under the President's National Service</textblock>
    <textblock>program; it improves public safety and health, guards the environment, and educates program</textblock>
    <textblock>participants. The program addresses national service priorities while at the same time provides</textblock>
    <textblock>an opportunity for public service and giving participants training that may enable them to gain</textblock>
    <textblock>employment later. It specifically addresses the following national priorities:</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
