<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-1-00065</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-1-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>§101-26.502</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Government National Credit Card.</textblock>
    <textblock>A waiver has been issued by the Government Printing Office to GSA for the procurement of the printing of Standard Form 149, U.S. Government National Credit Card.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Paragraph (c) of §101-26.408-4 is redesignated as §101-26.503 and revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§101-26.503</textblock>
    <textblock>Multiple award schedule purchases made by GSA supply distribution facilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>GSA supply distribution facilities are responsible for quickly and economically providing Government customers with frequently needed common-use items. Stocking a variety of commercial, high-demand items purchased from FSS multiple award schedules is an important way in which GSA supply distribution facilities meet this responsibility.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Section 101-26.507 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§101-26.507</textblock>
    <textblock>Security equipment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal agencies and other activities authorized to purchase security equipment through GSA sources shall do so in accordance with provisions of this §101-26.507. Under section 201 of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 (40 U.S.C. 481), the Administrator of GSA has determined that fixed-price contractors and lower tier subcontractors who are required to protect and maintain custody of security classified records and information may purchase security equipment from GSA sources. Delivery orders for security equipment submitted by such contractors and lower tier subcontractors shall contain a statement that the security equipment is needed for housing Government security classified information and that the purchase of such equipment is required to comply with the security provision of a Government contract. In the event of any inconsistency between the terms and conditions of the delivery order and those of the Federal Supply Schedule contract, the latter shall govern. Security equipment shall be used as prescribed by the cognizant security office.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Section 101-26.507-3 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§101-26.507-3</textblock>
    <textblock>Purchase of security equipment from Federal Supply Schedules.</textblock>
    <textblock>To ensure that a readily available source exists to meet the unforeseen demands for security equipment, Federal Supply Schedule contracts have been established to satisfy requirements that are not appropriate for consolidated procurement and do not exceed the maximum order limitations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 15, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Nicholas M. Economou,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, FSS Acquisition Management Center (FCO).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3709 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6820-61-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
