<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00013</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[I.D. 020894A]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Marine Mammals</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), NOAA, Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Receipt of application for a permit to take marine mammals for the purposes of scientific research and to enhance the survival of a species (P772</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>65).</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the Southwest Fisheries Science Center, National Marine Fisheries Service, P.O. Box 271, La Jolla, California 92038-0271, has applied in due form for a permit to take Hawaiian monk seals (</textblock>
    <textblock>Monachus schauinslandi</textblock>
    <textblock>) for purposes of scientific research and to enhance the survival of the species.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments must be received on or before March 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The application and related documents are available for review upon written request or by appointment in the following office(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>Permits Division, Office of Protected Resources, NMFS, 1315 East-West Highway, room 13130, Silver Spring, MD 20910 (301/713-2289);</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, Southwest Region, NMFS, 501 West Ocean Boulevard, suite 4200, Long Beach, CA 90802, (310/980-4016); and</textblock>
    <textblock>Marine Mammal Coordinator, Pacific Area Office, NMFS, 2570 Dole Street, room 106, Honolulu, HI 96822</textblock>
    <textblock>(808/955-8831).</textblock>
    <textblock>Written data or views, or requests for a public hearing on this request, should be submitted to the Director, Office of Protected Resources, NMFS, NOAA, U.S. Department of Commerce, 1315 East-West Highway, Room 13130, Silver Spring, MD 20910, within 30 days of the publication of this notice. Those individuals requesting a hearing should set forth the specific reasons why a hearing on this particular request would be appropriate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Concurrent with the publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, the Secretary of Commerce is forwarding copies of this application to the Marine Mammal Commission and its Committee of Scientific Advisors.</textblock>
  </address>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The subject permit is requested under the authority of the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972, as amended (16 U.S.C. 1361</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.), the Regulations Governing the Taking and Importing of Marine Mammals (50 CFR part 216), the Endangered Species Act of 1973, as amended (16 U.S.C. 1531</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.), and the regulations governing the taking, importing, and exporting of endangered fish and wildlife (50 CFR part 222).</textblock>
    <textblock>The applicant proposes to conduct several research/enhancement activities on Hawaiian monk seals (</textblock>
    <textblock>Monachus schauinslandi</textblock>
    <textblock>). The various activities requested are primarily those which have been authorized in the past under the applicant's previous permits (e.g., Permit Nos. 657, 729, and 778). These activities include the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Possible inadvertent harassment (multiple times annually) of up to the entire population of Hawaiian monk seals (approximately 1500) incurred during census activities; (2) mass mortality response activities, including (a) sacrifice of up to 10 moribund pups,</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) collection of samples from up to 20 diseased seals,</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) collection of samples from up to 10 apparently healthy seals (and possible biopsy of up to 5 of these 10),</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) sacrifice of up to 6 apparently normal males,</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) experimental treatment and or removal from the affected island of up to 10 diseased seals, and (f) treatment and/or removal of up to 100 additional seals; (3) collection for rehabilitation and release to the wild of up to 70 immature seals; (4) tagging and marking of up to 1000 pups and juveniles; (5) instrumentation (satellite/VHF transmitters, and time-depth recorders (TDRs)) of up to 25 seals;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) bleach marking of up to 1500 seals; and (7) stomach lavage of up to 40 seals. Additionally, the applicant is requesting authorization for the accidental mortality of some of these animals.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William W. Fox, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Protected Resources, National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3966 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
