<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00109</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00060</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Determinations</textblock>
    <textblock>On the basis of the record</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>developed in the subject investigations, the Commission unanimously determines, pursuant to section 733(a) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (19 U.S.C. 1673b(a)), that there is a reasonable indication that an industry in the United States is materially injured by reason of imports from Brazil, India, Italy, Japan, and Spain of stainless steel bar, provided for in subheadings 7222.10.00, 7222.20.00, and 7222.30.00 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, that are alleged to be sold in the United States at less than fair value (LTFV).</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 30, 1993, a petition was filed with the Commission and the Department of Commerce by Al Tech Specialty Steel Corp., Dunkirk, NY; Carpenter Technology Corp., Reading, PA; Republic Engineered Steels, Inc., Massillon, OH; Slater Steels Corp., Fort Wayne, IN; Talley Metals Technology, Inc., Hartsville, SC; and the United Steelworkers of America, AFL-CIO/CLC, alleging that an industry in the United States is materially injured or threatened with material injury by reason of LTFV imports of stainless steel bar from Brazil, India, Italy, Japan, and Spain. Accordingly, effective December 30, 1993, the Commission instituted antidumping investigations Nos. 731-TA-678 through 682 (Preliminary).</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of the institution of the Commission's investigations and of a public conference to be held in connection therewith was given by posting copies of the notice in the Office of the Secretary, U.S. International Trade Commission, Washington, DC, and by publishing the notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of January 7, 1994 (59 FR 1027). The conference was held in Washington, DC, on January 20, 1994, and all persons who requested the opportunity were permitted to appear in person or by counsel.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission transmitted its determinations in these investigations to the Secretary of Commerce on February 14, 1994. The views of the Commission are contained in USITC Publication 2734 (February 1994), entitled ``Stainless Steel Bar from Brazil, India, Italy, Japan, and Spain: Investigations Nos. 731-TA-678 through 682 (Preliminary).''</textblock>
    <textblock>By order of the Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued: February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Investigations Nos. 731-TA-678 through 682 (Preliminary)]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Stainless Steel Bar From Brazil, India, Italy, Japan, and Spain</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The record is defined in sec. 207.2(f) of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (19 CFR 207.2(f)).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The imported stainless steel bar covered by these investigations comprises articles of stainless steel in straight lengths that have been either hot-rolled, forged, turned, cold-drawn, cold-rolled, or otherwise cold-finished, or ground, having a uniform solid cross section along their whole length in the shape of circles, segments of circles, ovals, rectangles (including squares), triangles, hexagons, octagons, or other convex polygons. Except as specified above, the term does not include stainless steel semifinished products, cut-to-length flat-rolled products (i.e., cut-to-length rolled products which if less than 4.75 mm in thickness have a width measuring at least 10 times the thickness, or if 4.75 mm or more in thickness having a width which exceeds 150 mm and measures at least twice the thickness), wire (i.e., cold-formed products in coils, of any uniform solid cross section along their whole length, which do not conform to the definition of flat-rolled products), and angles, shapes, or sections. Stainless steel bar includes cold-finished stainless steel bars that are turned or ground in straight lengths, whether produced from hot-rolled bar or from straightened and cut rod or wire, and reinforcing bars that have indentations, ribs, grooves, or other deformations produced during the rolling process.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna R. Koehnke,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3991 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7020-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
