<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00036</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00026</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 16, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that a Staff Panel shall be convened in accordance with the Commission order</textblock>
    <textblock>in the above-captioned docket to allow opportunity for written comments and for the oral presentation of views, data, and arguments regarding the fair and equitable rates to be established for system-wide transportation service under section 311 of the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978 on Transok, Inc.'s system. The Staff Panel will not be a judicial or evidentiary-type hearing and there will be no cross examination of persons presenting statements. Members participating on the Staff Panel before whom the presentations are made may ask questions. If time permits, Staff Panel members may also ask such relevant questions as are submitted to them by participants. Other procedural rules relating to the panel will be announced at the time the proceeding commences.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Staff Panel will be held on Tuesday, April 26, 1994, at 10 a.m. in a room to be designated at the offices of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE, Washington, DC 20426.</textblock>
    <textblock>The parties also agreed to certain filing dates prior to the Staff Panel proceeding to assist the Panel in developing a record. Those dates are as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 23, 1994: Transok files written presentation.</textblock>
    <textblock>March 4, 1994: Intervenor discovery request.</textblock>
    <textblock>March 14, 1994: Transok response to discovery.</textblock>
    <textblock>March 29, 1994: Intervenor files written presentation.</textblock>
    <textblock>April 5, 1994: Transok discovery request.</textblock>
    <textblock>April 18, 1994: Intervenor response to discovery.</textblock>
    <textblock>April 26, 1994: Staff Panel.</textblock>
    <textblock>Attendance is open to all interested parties and staff. Any questions regarding these proceedings should be directed to Mark Hegerle at (202) 208-0927.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. PR93-4-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Transok, Inc.; Staff Panel</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See Transok, Inc., 62 FERC ¶␣61,291 (1993).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4019 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
