<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00107</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00058</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Investigation No. 337-TA-360]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Initial Determination Terminating Respondent on the Basis of Settlement Agreement</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. International Trade Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the Commission has received an initial determination from the presiding administrative law judge in the above captioned investigation terminating the following respondent on the basis of a settlement agreement: Total Technologies.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the Matter of: Certain Devices for Connecting Computers via Telephone lines.</textblock>
  </action>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This investigation is being conducted pursuant to section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (19 U.S.C. 1337). Under the Commission's rules, the presiding officer's initial determination will become the determination of the Commission thirty (30) days after the date of its service upon the parties, unless the Commission orders review of the initial determination. The initial determination in this matter was served upon parties on February 16, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the initial determination, the settlement agreement, and all other nonconfidential documents filed in connection with this investigation are available for inspection during official business hours (8:45 a.m. to 5:15 p.m.) in the Office of the Secretary, U.S. International Trade Commission, 500 E Street, SW., Washington, DC</textblock>
    <textblock>20436, telephone (202) 205-2000. Hearing impaired individuals are advised that information on this matter can be obtained by contacting the Commission's TDD terminal on (202) 205-1810.</textblock>
    <textblock>WRITTEN COMMENTS:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons may file written comments with the Commission concerning termination of the aforementioned respondents. The original and 14 copies of all such documents must be filed with the Secretary to the Commission, 500 E Street, SW., Washington, DC 20436, no later than 10 days after publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. Any person desiring to submit a document (or portions thereof) to the Commission in confidence must request confidential treatment. Such requests should be directed to the Secretary to the Commission and must include a full statement of the reasons why confidential treatment should be granted.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission will either accept the submission in confidence or return it.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ruby J. Dionne, Office of the Secretary, U.S. International Trade Commission, Telephone (202) 205-1802.</textblock>
    <textblock>By order of the Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued: February 16, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna R. Koehnke,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3990 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7020-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
