<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00078</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00039</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Dkt. 9251]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Synchronal Corporation, et al.; Proposed Consent Agreement With Analysis To Aid Public Comment</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>agency:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Trade Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed consent agreement.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>summary:</textblock>
    <textblock>In settlement of alleged violations of federal law prohibiting unfair acts and practices and unfair methods of competition, this consent agreement, accepted subject to final Commission approval, would prohibit, among other things, Thomas L. Fenton, a former officer of Synchronal Corporation, from disseminating a purported baldness cure infomerical, for a product called Omexin; from misrepresenting that any commercial is an independent program; and from making unsubstantiated claims for any food, drug or device in the future.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>dates:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before April 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>addresses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be directed to: FTC/Office of the Secretary, room 159, 6th St. and Pa. Ave., NW., Washington, DC 20580.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>for further information contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Lisa Kopchik, FTC/S-4002, Washington, DC 20580. (202) 326-3139.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>supplementary information:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 6(f) of the Federal Trade Commission Act, 38 Stat. 721, 15 U.S.C. 46 and ยง3.25(f) of the Commission's Rules of Practice (16 CFR 3.25(f)), notice is hereby given that the following consent agreement containing a consent order to cease and desist, having been filed with and accepted, subject to final approval, by the Commission, has been placed on the public record for a period of sixty (60) days. Public comment is invited. Such comments or views will be considered by the Commission and will be available for inspection and copying at its principal office in accordance with ยง4.9(b)(6)(ii) of the Commission's Rules of Practice (16 CFR 4.9(b)(6)(ii)).</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
