<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00022</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00019</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Floodplain Statement of Findings for Proposed Sampling at Solid Waste Management Units 94 and 95 at the Paducah Gaseous Diffusion Plant, Paducah, KY</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Energy (DOE).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Floodplain Statement of Findings.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a Floodplain Statement of Findings for the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>sampling at solid waste management units (SWMUs) 94 and 95.</textblock>
    <textblock>DOE proposes to conduct a Resource Conservation and Recovery Act Facility Investigation (RFI) at SWMUs 94 and 95 at the Paducah Gaseous Diffusion Plant (PGDP) that would involve the collection of surface water, ground water, sediment, and soil samples at these SWMUs. Some sampling is proposed to occur in the floodplains of two creeks near PGDP in McCracken County, Kentucky. DOE prepared a floodplain assessment describing the effects, alternatives, and measures designed to avoid or minimize potential harm to or within the affected floodplains. DOE will endeavor to allow 15 days of public review after publication of the statement of findings before implementing the proposed action.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information on the proposed action (including maps of potentially disturbed floodplain areas) is available from:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Robert C. Sleeman, Director, Environmental Restoration Division, Oak Ridge Operations Office, U.S. Department of Energy, P.O. Box 2001, Oak Ridge, Tennessee 37831-8541, (615) 576-0715, (615) 576-6074 (Fax).</textblock>
    <textblock>Further information on general DOE floodplain/wetlands environmental review requirements is available from:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Carol M. Borgstrom, Director, Office of NEPA Oversight, (EH-25), U.S. Department of Energy, 1000 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20585, (202) 586-4600 or (800) 472-2756.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a Floodplain Statement of Findings for the proposed RFI sampling at SWMUs 94 and 95 prepared in accordance with 10 CFR part 1022. A Notice of Floodplain/Wetland Involvement for Environmental Restoration and Waste Management Activities at PGDP was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on October 5, 1993, at 58 FR 51812, and a floodplain assessment has been prepared; no wetland will be involved in the proposed action. DOE is proposing to collect surface water, ground water, sediment, and soil samples to define the nature and extent of contamination in these media at two SWMUs on the site of the former Kentucky Ordnance Works near PGDP in McCracken County, Kentucky.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ground-water wells and deep soil borings would be placed within the 100-year floodplain of an unnamed tributary to Big Bayou Creek at SWMU 94 and within the 100-year floodplain of Big Bayou Creek at SWMU 95 to determine if the floodplains have been contaminated from past releases from the two SWMUs. Sampling would allow DOE to define the nature and extent of potential contamination in floodplain media. Two alternatives were considered_the no action alternative and an alternative that included performing the activities outside of the floodplain. Neither of these alternatives would provide the necessary characterization information and, therefore, are unacceptable alternatives. The proposed action does conform to applicable State floodplain protection standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Minor temporary impacts would occur from construction of temporary access roads and drilling pads for heavy equipment used to install deep soil borings and wells. Some trees would have to be cut at SWMU 95 to clear new access routes. Existing roadways and clearings would be used to the greatest extent possible to minimize new road construction. New temporary roadways and drilling pads would require small amounts of gravel and rock fill for drilling equipment.</textblock>
    <textblock>All drilling pads and most access roadways would be reclaimed and revegetated at the conclusion of the project. Some roadways would be left in place for continued access to monitoring wells. The number of trees to be cut would be kept to the minimum needed to clear access routes. Standard engineering practices would control potential soil erosion from the sites. Access road and drilling pad construction and clearing vegetation for site access would not reduce the flood storage capacity of the floodplain, interfere with stream flow, or produce hazardous flood velocities. DOE will endeavor to allow 15 days of public review after publication of the statement of findings prior to implementing the proposed action.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>James J. Fiore,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Eastern Area Programs, Office of Environmental Restoration.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4024 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
