<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-0-00011</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-0-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Establishment of Class D Airspace, Barking Sands, Kauai, HI</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 71</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Airspace Docket No. 93-AWP-17]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule; correction.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document contains a correction to the final rule published on December 10, 1993. This final rule established Class D airspace at Barking Sands Pacific Missile Range Facility (PMRF), Kekaha, Kauai, Hawaii, effective March 3, 1994. This correction to the final rule will establish the effective dates and times as continuously published in the Airport/Facility Directory, Pacific Chart Supplement. The Pacific Chart Supplement had been omitted from the original proposal.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>0901 U.T.C., March 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Gene Enstad, Airspace Specialist, System Management Branch, AWP-530, Air Traffic Division, Western-Pacific Region, Federal Aviation Administration, 15000 Aviation Boulevard, Lawndale, California 90261: telephone (310) 297-0010.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 10, 1993, the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) published a final rule that established Class D airspace at Barking Sands Pacific Missile Range Facility, Kekaha, Kauai, Hawaii (FR Vol. 58, page 64880). The description of the Class D Airspace omitted any mention of the Pacific Chart Supplement in describing the publication where the effective dates and times of the Class D airspace are published.</textblock>
    <textblock>Correction of Final Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, pursuant to the authority delegated to me, the publication on December 10, 1993 (58 FR 64880), and the description in FAA Order 7400.9A, which is incorporated by reference in 14 CFR 71.1, are corrected as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง71.1</textblock>
    <textblock>[Corrected]</textblock>
    <textblock>On page 64881, in the first column, last sentence of the description for the Class D airspace is corrected to read ``The effective date and time will thereafter be continuously published in the Airport/Facility Directory, Pacific Chart Supplement.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Lawndale on February 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard R. Lien,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Air Traffic Division, AWP-500.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4003 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
