<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00238</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00104</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>While DOT will attempt to assure that programs funded are geographically</textblock>
    <textblock>diverse, at the same time, for the first year of funding, DOT may give priority</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration to fund programs in any or all of the areas of greatest need as</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by criteria set forth in the regulations issued under the National and</textblock>
    <textblock>Community Service Trust Act (see ``Need'' in Section 4.1. ``General Criteria,''</textblock>
    <textblock>of this RFP).</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Matching Funds in Excess of Requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Priority consideration will be</textblock>
    <textblock>given to any proposals that provide funding from other sources in excess of the</textblock>
    <textblock>required match amounts (see Section 5.3, ``Matching Funds,'' in this RFP).</textblock>
    <textblock>5.</textblock>
    <textblock>Overall Compliance and Consistency</textblock>
    <textblock>with the National and Community</textblock>
    <textblock>Service Trust Act and related regulations and all other applicable laws and</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>6.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ability to Achieve Transportation-Related Goals.</textblock>
    <textblock>DOT is particularly interested in programs that will address one or more of the</textblock>
    <textblock>following transportation-related goals:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Tying America together through an effective intermodal transportation</textblock>
    <textblock>system;</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Promoting safe and secure transportation;</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Actively enhancing our environment through wise transportation decisions;</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Putting people first in our transportation system by making it relevant and</textblock>
    <textblock>accessible to users.</textblock>
    <textblock>4.3␣Priorities for Specific DOT Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>For each specific DOT Program, priority consideration will be given for proposals with the</textblock>
    <textblock>following characteristics:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Priorities for Rehabilitation, Reclamation, and Beautification of</textblock>
    <textblock>Transportation-Related Facilities Program:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Proposal's balance between work experience, basic and life skills,</textblock>
    <textblock>education, training, and support services.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Ability to adequately oversee and supervise crews of youths.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Demonstrated ability to network with other organizations and proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>coordination with and use of other available organizational resources.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Demonstration of how participation will address currently unmet needs</textblock>
    <textblock>in community.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Priorities for Transit Ambassadors Program:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Ability to deal with the elderly, disabled, and Head-Start populations;</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Ability to deal with minor emergency medical situations, or to provide</textblock>
    <textblock>training in this area;</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Knowledge of the types of transportation and the schedules available in</textblock>
    <textblock>the community, such as bus, subway, light rail, and taxis;</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Procedures for summoning (such as a two-way communication)</textblock>
    <textblock>emergency medical services and police for assistance;</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Understanding of the community lifestyles;</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Knowledge of the layout of the community being served, for example,</textblock>
    <textblock>major intersections, street lights, and traffic patterns.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
