<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-1-00021</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-1-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(1) The total pounds of milk received from each producer and the pounds of butterfat and nonfat milk solids contained in such milk;</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Section 1124.32 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§1124.32</textblock>
    <textblock>Other reports.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to the reports required pursuant to §§1124.30 and 1124.31, each handler shall report such other information as the market administrator deems necessary to verify or establish such handler's obligations under the order.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Section 1124.41 is amended by revising the second sentence of paragraph (c) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§1124.41</textblock>
    <textblock>Shrinkage.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) *␣*␣* If the operator of a plant or a commercial food processing establishment pursuant to §1124.20 purchases such milk on the basis of weights determined from its measurement at the farm, and butterfat tests and nonfat milk solids determined from farm bulk tank samples, the applicable percentage under this paragraph for the cooperative association shall be zero.</textblock>
    <textblock>10. The center heading preceding §1124.50 is revised to read</textblock>
    <textblock>``Class and Component Prices''</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>11. Section 1124.50 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§1124.50</textblock>
    <textblock>Class and component prices.</textblock>
    <textblock>The class and component prices for the month, per hundredweight or per pound, shall be as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The</textblock>
    <textblock>Class I price,</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to the provisions of</textblock>
    <textblock>§1124.52, shall be the basic formula price defined in §1124.51 for the second preceding month plus $1.90.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>The Class II price</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be computed by the Director of the Dairy Division and transmitted to the market administrator on or before the 15th day of the preceding month. The Class II price shall be the basic Class II formula price computed pursuant to §1124.51(b) for the month plus the amount that the value computed pursuant to paragraph (b)(1) of this section exceeds the value computed pursuant to paragraph (b)(2) of this section, plus any amount by which the basic Class II formula price for the second preceding month, adjusted pursuant to paragraphs (b)(1) and (b)(2) of this section, was less than the Class III price for the second preceding month:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Determine for the most recent 12-month period the simple average (rounded to the nearest cent) of the basic formula prices computed pursuant to §1124.51(a) and add 25 cents; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Determine for the same 12-month period as specified in paragraph (b)(1) of this section the simple average (rounded to the nearest cent) of the basic Class II formula prices computed pursuant to §1124.51(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The</textblock>
    <textblock>Class III price</textblock>
    <textblock>shall be the basic formula price for the month.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) The</textblock>
    <textblock>Class III-A price</textblock>
    <textblock>for the month shall be the average Western States nonfat dry milk price for the month, as reported by the Department, less 12.5 cents, times an amount computed by subtracting from 9 an amount calculated by dividing .4 by such nonfat dry milk price, plus the butterfat differential times 35 and rounded to the nearest cent.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) The</textblock>
    <textblock>skim milk price</textblock>
    <textblock>per hundredweight shall be the basic formula price for the month pursuant to §1124.51(a) less an amount computed by multiplying the butterfat differential computed pursuant to §1124.19(e) by 35.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) The</textblock>
    <textblock>butterfat price</textblock>
    <textblock>per pound shall be the total of:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The skim price computed in paragraph (e) of this section divided by 100; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The butterfat differential computed pursuant to §1124.19(e) multiplied by 10.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g) The</textblock>
    <textblock>nonfat milk solids price</textblock>
    <textblock>per pound shall be computed by subtracting the butterfat price, multiplied by 3.5, from the basic formula price and dividing the result by the average percentage of nonfat milk solids in the milk on which the basic formula price is based, as announced by the Dairy Division. The resulting price shall be rounded to the nearest whole cent.</textblock>
    <textblock>12. Section 1124.51 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§1124.51</textblock>
    <textblock>Basic formula prices.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
