<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00150</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00095</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>UNITED STATES POSTAL SERVICE BOARD OF GOVERNORS</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board of Governors of the United States Postal Service, pursuant to its Bylaws (39 CFR Section 7.5) and the Government in the Sunshine Act (5 U.S.C. Section 552b), hereby gives notice that it intends to hold a meeting at 1 p.m. on Monday, March 7, 1994, and at 8:30 a.m. on Tuesday, March 8, 1994, in Washington, DC. The March 7 meeting, at which the Board will discuss preparations for the rate case filing (See 59 FR 7300, February 14, 1994) is closed to the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>The March 8 meeting is open to the public and will be held at U.S. Postal Service Headquarters, 475 L'Enfant Plaza SW., in the Benjamin Franklin Room. The Board expects to discuss the matters stated in the agenda which is set forth below. Requests for information about the meeting should be addressed to the Secretary for the Board, David F. Harris, at (202) 268-4800.</textblock>
    <textblock>AGENDA</textblock>
    <textblock>Monday Session</textblock>
    <textblock>March 7_1 p.m. (Closed)</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Consideration of Rate Case Filing. (Messrs. Riley, Porras, Heselton, Foucheaux and Mses. Elcano and Sonnenberg)</textblock>
    <textblock>Tuesday Session</textblock>
    <textblock>March 8_8:30 a.m. (Open)</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Minutes of the Previous Meeting, February 7-8, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Remarks of the Postmaster General/Chief Executive Officer. (Marvin Runyon)</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Report on Reduction in Theft of Credit Cards. (Kenneth J. Hunter, Chief Postal Inspector)</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Briefing on Flat Sorting Machines. (William J. Dowling, Vice President, Engineering)</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Tentative Agenda for the April 4-5, 1994, meeting in Chicago, Illinois.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David F. Harris,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4150 Filed 2-18-94; 11:54 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7710-12-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
