<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00010</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-2-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Institute of Standards and Technology</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Visiting Committee on Advanced Technology; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>agency:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Institute of Standards and Technology, DOC.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of partially closed meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>summary:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the Federal Advisory Committee Act, 5 U.S.C. App. 2, notice is hereby given that the National Institute of Standards and Technology Visiting Committee on Advanced Technology will meet on Tuesday, March 8, 1994, from 8:30 a.m. to 5 p.m. The Visiting Committee on Advanced Technology is composed of nine members appointed by the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology who are eminent in such fields as business, research, new product development, engineering, labor, education, management consulting, environment, and international relations. The purpose of this meeting is to review and make recommendations regarding general policy for the Institute, its organization, its budget, and its programs within the framework of applicable national policies as set forth by the President and the Congress. Presentations will be given on the Manufacturing Extension Partnership, the Board of Assessment's report on NIST programs, the Advanced Technology Program: a progress report and industrial input and program definition, laboratory tours, and a discussion on the Institute's budget.</textblock>
    <textblock>The discussion on NIST Budget, scheduled to begin at 3:50 p.m. and end at 5 p.m. on March 8, 1994, will be closed.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>dates:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will convene March 8, 1994, at 8:30 a.m. and will adjourn at 5 p.m.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>addresses:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held in Lecture Room A, Administration Building, National Institute of Standards and Technology, Gaithersburg, Maryland.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>for further information contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dale E. Hall, Visiting Committee Executive Director, National Institute of Standards and Technology, Gaithersburg, Maryland 20899, telephone number (301) 975-2158.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>supplementary information:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Assistant Secretary for Administration, with the concurrence of the General Counsel, formally determined on February 14, 1994, that portions of the meeting of the Visiting Committee on Advanced Technology which involve examination and discussion of the budget for the Institute may be closed in accordance with section 552(b)(9)(B) of Title 5, United States Code, since the meeting is likely to disclose financial information that may be privileged or confidential.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 16, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Samuel Kramer,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4037 Filed 2-22-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
