<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940223-0-00007</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940223-0-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Airworthiness Directives: Mitsubishi Heavy Industries, Ltd., MU-2B Series Airplanes</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 39</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 92-CE-50-AD; Amendment 39-8836; AD 94-04-16]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This amendment adopts a new airworthiness directive (AD) that applies to certain Mitsubishi Heavy Industries, Ltd. (Mitsubishi), MU-2B series airplanes. This action requires reducing the maximum deflection of the elevator nose-down trim to a 1-degree to 3-degree range. Analysis of service history on the affected airplanes has revealed one accident and two incidents where the existing elevator nose-down trim deflection caused excessive control wheel force. The actions specified by this AD are intended to prevent excessive control wheel force caused by extreme elevator nose-down trim deflection, which could result in loss of control of the airplane.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective April 11, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The incorporation by reference of certain publications listed in the regulations is approved by the Director of the Federal Register as of April 11, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Service information that applies to this AD may be obtained from Mitsubishi Heavy Industries, Ltd., Nagoya Aerospace Systems, 10, Oyecho, Minato-Ku, Nagoya, Japan. This information may also be examined at the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), Central Region, Office of the Assistant Chief Counsel, room 1558, 601 E. 12th Street, Kansas City, Missouri 64106; or at the Office of the Federal Register, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., suite 700, Washington, DC.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. William Roberts, Aerospace Engineer, Los Angeles Aircraft Certification Office, FAA, 3229 E. Spring Street, Long Beach, California 90806; telephone (310) 988-5228; facsimile (310) 988-5210.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>A proposal to amend part 39 of the Federal Aviation Regulations to include an AD that would apply to certain Mitsubishi MU-2B series airplanes was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 14, 1992 (57 FR 58999). The action proposed to require reducing the maximum deflection of the elevator nose-down trim to a 1-degree to 3-degree range. The proposed action would be accomplished in accordance with Mitsubishi Service Bulletin No. 216, dated September 11, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons have been afforded an opportunity to participate in the making of this amendment. Due consideration has been given to the one comment received.</textblock>
    <textblock>The commenter supports the proposed action, but recommends that, to eliminate any applicability questions from the field, the FAA issue one AD to cover the Mitsubishi MU-2B series airplanes covered under two FAA Type Certificates: A2PC and A10SW. The FAA concurs that one AD may eliminate applicability questions from the field; however, ADs are issued against airplanes of the same type design. Since these airplanes are certificated under two separate type designs, the FAA is issuing an AD on each type design. The proposed AD is unchanged as a result of this comment.</textblock>
    <textblock>No comments were received on the FAA's determination of the cost impact on the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>After careful review, the FAA has determined that air safety and the public interest require the adoption of the rule as proposed except for minor editorial corrections. The FAA has determined that these minor corrections will not change the meaning of the AD nor add any additional burden upon the public than was already proposed.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA estimates that 252 airplanes in the U.S. registry will be affected by this AD, that it will take approximately 6 workhours per airplane to accomplish the required action, and that the average labor rate is approximately $55 an hour. Parts cost approximately $300 per airplane. Based on these figures, the total cost impact of the AD on U.S. operators is estimated to be $158,760. This figure is based on the assumption that none of the affected airplane operators have accomplished the required action.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
