<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00104</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00065</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Information Collection Under OMB Review; Voluntary Customer Surveys To Implement Executive Order 12862_Department of Veterans Affairs</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Veterans Affairs.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Veterans Affairs has submitted to OMB the following proposal for the collection of information under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. chapter 35). This document lists the following information: (1) The title of the information collection; (2) a description of the need and its use; (3) who will be required or asked to respond; (4) an estimate of the total annual reporting hours, and recordkeeping burden, if applicable; and (5) the frequency of response.</textblock>
  </action>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the proposed information collection and supporting documents may be obtained from Patti Viers, Office of Information Resources Management (723), Department of Veterans Affairs, 810 Vermont Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20420 (202) 233-3172.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments and questions about the items on the list should be directed to VA's OMB Desk Officer, Joseph Lackey, NEOB, room 3002, Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-7316. Do not send requests for benefits to this address.</textblock>
  </address>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on the information collection should be directed to the OMB Desk Officer on or before February 14, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 27, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By direction of the Secretary.</textblock>
  </date>
  <signer>
    <textblock>B. Michael Berger,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Records Management Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>New Collection</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Voluntary Customer Surveys to Implement Executive Order 12862_Department of Veterans Affairs.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Voluntary Customer Surveys will be used to implement Executive Order 12862. VA will gather the necessary information to determine the kind and quality of services VA customers want, and their level of satisfaction with existing services. The information will be used by VA to focus its planning and problem solving efforts to those service issues valued by the customer.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Individuals or households_State of local governments_Farms_Businesses or other for-profit_Federal agencies or employees_Non-profit institutions_Small businesses or organizations.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. VA estimates a total burden of 1,439,177 hours_336,252 hours in FY 1994; 491,499 hours in FY 1995; and 611,427 hours in FY 1996.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. On occasion.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2401 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8320-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
