<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00055</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In particular, the EPA has often granted requests for</textblock>
    <textblock>extensions of public comment periods in previous reviews; in</textblock>
    <textblock>order to meet the accelerated schedule for the O</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>NAAQS review, however, the EPA intends not to grant such extensions during this review. Accordingly, potential participants in the review should take note of the process outlined in this notice and be prepared to respond promptly when opportunities to comment are offered.</textblock>
    <textblock>Given the scientific and technical complexity of the issues likely to be involved in the O</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>review, the diversity of scientific opinion that has characterized previous reviews of the criteria and standards for O</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>, and the need to ensure that its ultimate decision is soundly based, the EPA cannot, of course, provide any absolute assurance that</textblock>
    <textblock>it will meet all of the interim milestone dates indicated in Table 1. Completion of the necessary steps in a timely manner is also predicated upon the availability of adequate resources during the review process. However, the Administrator has emphasized a high priority on meeting the accelerated schedule outlined in this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>To that end, the review process is well under way. The EPA initiated action to update the air quality criteria for O</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>in August 1992 (57 FR 38832). It held two peer-review workshops on draft health effects chapters of a revised Criteria Document (58 FR 35454) in July 1993. Additional workshops on draft air quality and ecological effects chapters (58 FR 48063) were held in September 1993. Since</textblock>
    <textblock>then, the EPA has discussed the schedule and process outlined in this notice with the CASAC (58 FR 59034). The EPA is also conducting exposure and risk analyses. A</textblock>
    <textblock>subcommittee of the CASAC met on December 16, 1993 to review methodologies (58 FR 63345). A further subcommittee meeting on risk analysis is planned for spring 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>1Major milestones</textblock>
    <textblock>1Tentative dates</textblock>
    <textblock>CASAC Subcommittee Meeting on Exposure Assessment Methods</textblock>
    <textblock>December 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>CASAC and Public Comment Period for Criteria Document (CD) (90 days)</textblock>
    <textblock>February to May 1994.1</textblock>
    <textblock>CASAC Subcommittee Meeting on Risk Assessment Methods</textblock>
    <textblock>March 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>CASAC Meeting on CD</textblock>
    <textblock>July 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment Period on Staff Paper (SP) (60 days)</textblock>
    <textblock>September to October 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>CASAC Meeting on SP</textblock>
    <textblock>October 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Comment Period on Revised CD and SP (90 days)</textblock>
    <textblock>Early 1995.</textblock>
    <textblock>CASAC Meeting on Revised CD and SP</textblock>
    <textblock>Mid-1995.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agency Development of Regulatory Decision/Proposal Package Draft</textblock>
    <textblock>Mid-1995 to late 1995.</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Management and Budget Review of Proposal Package</textblock>
    <textblock>Early 1996.</textblock>
    <textblock>Publication of Proposal in</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>Mid-1996.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Comment Period on Proposal (90 days)</textblock>
    <textblock>Mid-1996.</textblock>
    <textblock>CASAC Meeting to Review Proposal</textblock>
    <textblock>Late 1996.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Decisions and Final Package Draft Completed</textblock>
    <textblock>Early 1997.</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Management and Budget Review of Promulgation Package</textblock>
    <textblock>Early 1997 to mid-1997.</textblock>
    <textblock>Publication of Promulgation Notice in</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>Mid-1997.</textblock>
    <textblock>1For a notice of availability of external review draft, see 59 FR 4278, January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
