<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00046</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Libyan Sanctions Regulations; Blocking of Offshore Foreign Currency Deposits.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of Foreign Assets Control</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>31 CFR Part 550</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Foreign Assets Control, Treasury.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule; amendments.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Consistent with action by the United Nations Security Council calling upon member states to block certain financial assets of the Government of Libya, and in order further to tighten the U.S. blocking of Libyan governmental assets, the Office Foreign Assets Control is amending the Libyan Sanctions Regulations to revoke a general license that unblocked Libyan government deposits in currencies other than U.S. dollars held abroad by U.S. persons.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dennis P. Wood, Chief of Compliance (tel.: 202/622-2490), or William B. Hoffman, Chief Counsel (tel.: 202/622-2410), Office of Foreign Assets Control, Department of the Treasury, Washington, D.C. 20220.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Electronic Availability</textblock>
    <textblock>This document is available as an electronic file on</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Bulletin Board</textblock>
    <textblock>the day of publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. By modem dial 202/512-1387 or call 202/512-1530 for disks or paper copies. This file is available in Postscript, WordPerfect 5.1 and ASCII.</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>The Office of Foreign Assets Control (``FAC'') is amending the Libyan Sanctions Regulations, 31␣CFR part 550 (the ``LSR''), to revoke §550.516, which unblocked, by general license, deposits in currencies other than U.S. dollars held by U.S. persons abroad, if otherwise blocked under the LSR. FAC's amendment is consistent with action by the United Nations Security Council in Resolution 883 of November 11, 1993. The Security Council determined in that resolution that the continued failure of the Government of Libya (``GOL'') to demonstrate by concrete actions its renunciation of terrorism, and in particular the GOL's continued failure to respond fully and effectively to the requests and decisions of the Security Council in Resolutions 731 and 748, concerning the bombing of the Pan Am 103 and UTA 772 flights, constituted a threat to international peace and security. Accordingly, Resolution 883 called upon member states,</textblock>
    <textblock>inter alia</textblock>
    <textblock>, to freeze certain GOL financial assets in their territories, and to ensure that their nationals did not make such funds or any other funds or financial resources available to the GOL or any entity owned or controlled by the GOL. In light of this resolution, FAC is revoking §550.516 to eliminate an exception that had existed to the comprehensive blocking of GOL property required by Executive Order 12544 of January 8, 1986 (3 CFR, 1986 Comp., p. 183) and by the LSR.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because the LSR involve a foreign affairs function, Executive Order 12866 and the provisions of the Administrative Procedure Act, 5 U.S.C. 553, requiring notice of proposed rulemaking, opportunity for public participation, and delay in effective date, are inapplicable. Because no notice of proposed rulemaking is required for this rule, the Regulatory Flexibility Act, 5 U.S.C. 601-612, does not apply.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 31␣CFR Part 550</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedure, Banks, Banking, Blocking of assets, Exports, Foreign investment, Foreign trade, Government of Libya, Imports, Libya, Loans, Penalties, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Securities, Services, Specially designated nationals, Travel restrictions.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set forth in the preamble, 31␣CFR part 550 is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 550_LIBYAN SANCTIONS REGULATIONS</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 550 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>50 U.S.C. 1701-1706; 50 U.S.C. 1601-1651; 22 U.S.C. 287c; 49 U.S.C. App. 1514; 22 U.S.C. 2349aa-8 and 2349aa-9; 3 U.S.C. 301; E.O. 12543, 3 CFR, 1986 Comp., p. 181; E.O. 12544, 3 CFR, 1986 Comp., p. 183; E.O. 12801, 3 CFR, 1992 Comp. p. 294.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart E_Licenses, Authorizations, and Statements of Licensing Policy</textblock>
    <textblock>§550.516</textblock>
    <textblock>[Removed]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 550.516 is revoked and removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>R. Richard Newcomb,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Foreign Assets Control.</textblock>
    <textblock>Approved: January 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John P. Simpson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Assistant Secretary (Regulatory, Tariff and Trade Enforcement).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2476 Filed 1-31-94; 3:29 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4810-25-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
