<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00011</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>5. In §20.1003, the definitions of ``</textblock>
    <textblock>Member of the public</textblock>
    <textblock>,'' ``</textblock>
    <textblock>Occupational dose</textblock>
    <textblock>,'' ``</textblock>
    <textblock>Public dose</textblock>
    <textblock>,'' and ``</textblock>
    <textblock>Unrestricted area</textblock>
    <textblock>'' are revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§20.1003</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Member of the public</textblock>
    <textblock>means any individual except when that individual is receiving an occupational dose.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Occupational dose</textblock>
    <textblock>means the dose received by an individual in the course of employment in which the individual's assigned duties involve exposure to radiation and/or to radioactive material from licensed and unlicensed sources of radiation, whether in the possession of the licensee or other person. Occupational dose does not include dose received from background radiation, as a patient from medical practices, from voluntary participation in medical research programs, or as a member of the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Public dose</textblock>
    <textblock>means the dose received by a member of the public from exposure to radiation and/or radioactive material released by a licensee, or to any other source of radiation under the control of a licensee. It does not include occupational dose or doses received from background radiation, as a patient from medical practices, or from voluntary participation in medical research programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Unrestricted area</textblock>
    <textblock>means any area that is not a restricted area.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>6. In §20.1301 paragraph (b) is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§20.1301</textblock>
    <textblock>Dose limits for individual members of the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) If the licensee permits members of the public to have access to restricted areas, the limits for members of the public continue to apply to those individuals.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>7. In §20.1302 paragraph (a) is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§20.1302</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance with dose limits for individual members of the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The licensee shall make or cause to be made, as appropriate, surveys of radiation levels in unrestricted areas and radioactive materials in effluents released to unrestricted areas to demonstrate compliance with the dose limits for individual members of the public in §20.1301.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Section 20.1801 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§20.1801</textblock>
    <textblock>Security of stored material.</textblock>
    <textblock>The licensee shall secure from unauthorized removal or access licensed materials that are stored in unrestricted areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Section 20.1802 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§20.1802</textblock>
    <textblock>Control of material not in storage.</textblock>
    <textblock>The licensee shall control and maintain constant surveillance of licensed material that is in an unrestricted area and that is not in storage.</textblock>
    <textblock>10. In §20.2104 the introductory text of paragraph (a) is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§20.2104</textblock>
    <textblock>Determination of prior occupational dose.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) For each individual who is likely to receive, in a year, an occupational dose requiring monitoring pursuant to §20.1502 the licensee shall_</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>11. Section §20.2205 is added as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§20.2205</textblock>
    <textblock>Reports to individuals of exceeding dose limits.</textblock>
    <textblock>When a licensee is required, pursuant to the provisions of §§20.2203, 20.2204, or 20.2206, to report to the Commission any exposure of an identified individual worker or member of the public to radiation or radioactive material, the licensee shall also provide to the individual, a written report on his or her exposure data included therein. This report must be transmitted at a time no later than the transmittal to the Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated at Rockville, Maryland, this 19th day of January, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>James M. Taylor,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Executive Director for Operations.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2394 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7590-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
