<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00042</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(g) Geographic area of applicability;</textblock>
    <textblock>(h) Monitoring requirements and responsibilities;</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Remedial action responsibilities including funding; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(j) Provisions for protecting the mitigation bank in perpetuity.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agency participation in a wetlands mitigation banking agreement may not, in any way, restrict or limit the authorities and responsibilities of the agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. An appropriate methodology, acceptable to all signatories, should be identified and used to evaluate the success of wetland restoration and creation efforts within the mitigation bank and to identify the appropriate stage of development for issuing mitigation credits. A full range of wetland functions should be assessed. Functional evaluations of the mitigation bank should generally be conducted by a multi-disciplinary team representing involved resource and regulatory agencies and other appropriate parties. The same methodology should be used to determine the functions and values of both credits and debits. As an alternative, credits and debits can be based on acres of various types of wetlands (e.g., National Wetland Inventory classes). Final determinations regarding debits and credits will be made by the Corps, or other appropriate permitting agency, in consultation with Federal resource agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Permit applicants may draw upon the available credits of a third party mitigation bank (i.e., a bank developed and operated by an entity other than the permit applicant). The section 404 permit, however, must state explicitly that the permittee remains responsible for ensuring that the mitigation requirements are satisfied.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. To ensure legal enforceability of the mitigation conditions, use of mitigation bank credits must be conditioned in the section 404 permit by referencing the banking agreement or section 404 permit establishing the bank; however, such a provision should not limit the responsibility of the section 404 permittee for satisfying all legal requirements of the permit.</textblock>
    <textblock>Signed: August 23, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Robert H. Wayland, III,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Wetlands, Oceans, and Watersheds, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Michael L. Davis,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Army (Civil Works), Department of the Army.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Guidance Letter (RGL 93-3)</textblock>
    <textblock>RGL 93-3</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued: September 13, 1993, Expires: not applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>Subject:</textblock>
    <textblock>Rescission of Regulatory Guidance Letters (RGL) 90-5, 90-7, and 90-8</textblock>
    <textblock>1. On 25 August 1993 the final ``Excavation Rule'' was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 45008) and becomes effective on 24 September 1993. This regulation modifies the definition of ``Discharge of Dredged Material'' to address landclearing activities (see 33 CFR 323.2(d)); modifies the definitions of ``Fill Material'' and ``Discharge of Fill Material'' to address the placement of pilings (see 33 CFR 323.2(e) and (f) and 323.3(c)); and modifies the definition of ``waters of the United States'' to address prior converted cropland (see 33 CFR 328.(a)(8)).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Therefore, RGL 90-5, Subject: ``Landclearing Activities Subject to Section 404 Jurisdiction''; RGL 90-7, Subject: ``Clarification of the Phrase `Normal Circumstances' as it pertains to Cropped Wetlands''; and RGL 90-8, Subject: ``Applicability of section 404 to Pilings''; are hereby rescinded effective 24 September 1993. Furthermore, although RGL 90-5, Subject: ``Landclearing Activities Subject to section 404 Jurisdiction'' expired on 31 December 1992 it should continue to be applied until 24 September 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. In addition, RGL's 90-5, 90-7, and 90-8 as of 24 September 1993 will no longer be used for guidance since the guidance contained in those RGL's has been superseded by the regulation.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Director of Civil Works.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John P. Elmore, P.E.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Operations, Construction and Readiness Division, Directorate of Civil Works.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2429 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3710-92-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
