<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00073</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00044</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Extension of Public Comment Period for Scoping on an Environmental Impact Statement; Wild and Scenic River Study, Squirrel River, AK</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[AK-070-04-4410-02-P]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension of the public comment period for scoping on an Environmental Impact Statement (EIS); Wild and Scenic River Study, Squirrel River, Alaska.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bureau of Land Management (BLM), Kobuk District Office, Alaska, is preparing an Environmental Impact Statement for the study of the Squirrel River for possible inclusion in the national wild and scenic rivers system. The Notice of Intent to proceed with the EIS was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 29, 1993. Because of a delay for communities in northwestern Alaska receiving notice of the comment period for scoping on the EIS, the period for public comment is extended until 30 days from the publication of this Notice. These comments and others will be used in preparation of a draft EIS. An additional opportunity for public comment will be held after the draft EIS is published.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Squirrel River study was authorized by the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act of December 2, 1980 (ANILCA, Pub. L. 96-487). The Squirrel River, a tributary of the Kobuk River in northwest Alaska, was studied in 1985 by the National Park Service (NPS) for possible inclusion in the national wild and scenic river system. After publication of a draft EIS, further action by NPS was deferred for several reasons. One of these reasons included the delegation of authority to BLM to conduct wild and scenic river studies on rivers under its management.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed action in the NPS study called for designation of the federally-administered portion of the Squirrel River, plus the lower 6 miles of the river's North Fork and the lower 15 miles of the Omar River. BLM is now proceeding at the scoping level in order to obtain maximum public input on the study. Preliminary review of the draft EIS published by NPS in 1985 indicates potential issues may now include mineral development in the region, identification of transportation corridors, and subsistence lifeways in the area. Information received as a result of current scoping on this action will be used to update the NPS draft EIS and produce a new Squirrel River draft EIS.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments and requests to be placed on the mailing list will be accepted on or before March 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments and mailing requests should be sent to the District Manager, Kobuk District Office, Bureau of Land Management, 1150 University Avenue, Fairbanks, Alaska 99709-3844.</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR FURThER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Susan Will (907) 474-2338 or Curtis Wilson (907) 272-5546.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 27, 1994.</textblock>
  </address>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Helen Hankins,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Kobuk District.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2407 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-JA-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
