<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00071</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Any final decision on this proposal will take into consideration the comments and any additional information received by the Service, and such communications may lead to a final regulation that differs from this proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Endangered Species Act requires that a public hearing be held if requested within 45 days of the date of publication of a proposed rule. As indicated under the</textblock>
    <textblock>DATES</textblock>
    <textblock>section of this proposed rule, the Service intends to hold a public hearing on this proposal and will soon announce the date, time, and location in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>National Environmental Policy Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The Fish and Wildlife Service has determined that an Environmental Assessment, as defined under the authority of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, need not be prepared in connection with regulations adopted pursuant to section (4)(a) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973, as amended. A notice outlining the Service's reasons for this determination was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on October 25, 1983 (48 FR 49244).</textblock>
    <textblock>Author</textblock>
    <textblock>The primary author of this proposed rule is Loren R. Hays of the Carlsbad Field Office (see</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>section).</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 50 CFR Part 17</textblock>
    <textblock>Endangered and threatened species, Exports, Imports, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, and Transportation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Regulation Promulgation</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, the Service hereby proposes to amend part 17, subchapter B of chapter I, title 50 of the Code of Federal Regulations, as set forth below:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 17_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 17 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 1361-1407; 16 U.S.C. 1531-1544; 16 U.S.C. 4201-4245; Pub. L. 99-625, 100 Stat. 3500; unless otherwise noted.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Amend §17.11(h) by revising the entry for ``Mouse, Pacific pocket'' under ``MAMMALS,'' in the List of Endangered and Threatened Wildlife, to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§17.11</textblock>
    <textblock>Endangered and threatened wildlife.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(h)␣*␣*␣*</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
