<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00054</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Incidental Take of Marine Mammals</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>50 CFR Part 228</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 930816-4016; I.D. 071993D]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 0648-AF49</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>NMFS, upon application from the U.S. Department of the Navy (Navy), issues regulations to govern the unintentional take of a small number of marine mammals incidental to a wide variety of proposed Navy projects involving the underwater detonation of conventional explosives in the offshore waters of the Outer Sea Test Range (OSTR) of the Naval Air Warfare Center (NAWC), Pt. Mugu, Ventura County, CA, over the next 5 years. Issuance of regulations governing unintentional incidental takes in connection with particular activities is required by the Marine Mammal Protection Act (MMPA) when the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary), after notice and opportunity for comment, finds as here, that such takes will have a negligible impact on the species and stocks and will not have an unmitigable adverse impact on the availability of them for subsistence uses. These regulations do not authorize the Navy's proposed activities, such authorization is provided by the National Defense Authorization Act and is not within the jurisdiction of the Secretary. Rather, these regulations authorize the unintentional incidental take of marine mammals in connection with such activities and prescribe methods of taking and other means of effecting the least practicable adverse impact on the species and its habitat, and on the availability of the species for subsistence uses.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 3, 1994 through March 3, 1999.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the Environmental Assessment and Biological Opinion may be obtained by writing to Dr. William W. Fox, Jr., Director, Office of Protected Resources, National Marine Fisheries Service, 1335 East-West Highway, Silver Spring, MD 20910, or by telephoning the contact listed below.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Kenneth R. Hollingshead, Office of Protected Resources, NMFS (301) 713-2055.</textblock>
  </further>
</doc>
