<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00148</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00069</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Part II: Budget Information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Part III: Budget Narrative.</textblock>
    <textblock>Part IV: Application Narrative.</textblock>
    <textblock>Part V: Additional Assurances and Certifications:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Estimated Public Reporting Burden.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Assurances_Non Construction Programs (Standard Form 424B).</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Certification regarding Lobbying: Debarment, Suspension, and Other Responsibility Matters; and Drug-Free Workplace Requirements (ED 80-0013) and Instructions.</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Certification regarding Debarment, Suspension, Ineligibility and Voluntary Exclusion: Lower Tier Covered Transactions (ED 80-0014, 9/90) and Instructions. (NOTE: ED 80-0014 is intended for the use of grantees and should not be transmitted to the Department.)</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Disclosure of Lobbying Activities (Standard Form LLL) (if applicable) and instructions, and Disclosure of Lobbying Activities Continuation Sheet (Standard Form LLL-A).</textblock>
    <textblock>All applicants must submit one original signed application, including ink signatures on all forms and assurances and six copies of the application. Please mark each application as original or copy.</textblock>
    <textblock>No grant may be awarded unless a complete application form has been received.</textblock>
    <textblock>Instructions for Part II_Budget Information</textblock>
    <textblock>Section A_Budget Summary by Categories</textblock>
    <textblock>1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Personnel:</textblock>
    <textblock>Show salaries to be paid to project personnel.</textblock>
    <textblock>2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Fringe Benefits:</textblock>
    <textblock>Indicate the rate and amount of fringe benefits.</textblock>
    <textblock>3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Travel:</textblock>
    <textblock>Indicate the amount requested for both inter- and intra-State travel of project staff. Include funds for three people to attend three developmental staff meetings in Washington, DC.</textblock>
    <textblock>4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Equipment:</textblock>
    <textblock>Indicate the cost of non-expendable personal property that has a useful life of more than one year and a cost of $300 or more per unit ($5,000 or more if State, Local, or Tribal Government). (Please see EDGAR 74.132)</textblock>
    <textblock>5.</textblock>
    <textblock>Supplies:</textblock>
    <textblock>Include the cost of consumable supplies and materials to be used during the project.</textblock>
    <textblock>6.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contractual:</textblock>
    <textblock>Show the amount to be used for (1) procurement contracts (except those which belong on other lines such as supplies and equipment); and (2) sub-contracts.</textblock>
    <textblock>7.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other:</textblock>
    <textblock>Indicate all direct costs not clearly covered by lines 1 through 6 above, including consultants.</textblock>
    <textblock>8.</textblock>
    <textblock>Total, Direct Costs:</textblock>
    <textblock>Show the total for lines 1 through 7.</textblock>
    <textblock>9.</textblock>
    <textblock>Indirect Costs:</textblock>
    <textblock>Indicate the rate and amount of indirect costs.</textblock>
  </text>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Marian Banfield, U.S. Department of Education, 400 Maryland Avenue, SW. (room 4517 MES), Washington, DC 20202-7327. Telephone (202) 205-8838. Individuals who use a telecommunications device for the deaf (TDD) may call the Federal Information Relay Service (FIRS) at 1-800-877-8339 between 8 a.m. and 8 p.m., Eastern time, Monday through Friday.</textblock>
    <textblock>Information about the Department's funding opportunities, including copies of application notices for discretionary grant competitions, can be viewed on the Department's electronic bulletin board (ED Board), telephone (202) 260-9950; or the Internet Gopher Server at GOPHER.ED.GOV (under Announcements, Bulletins, and Press Releases). However, the official application notice for any discretionary grant competition is the application notice published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Program Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>20 U.S.C. 2420a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard W. Riley,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of Education.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Robert B. Reich,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of Labor.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4000-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GraphicsEN03FE94.000</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GraphicsEN03FE94.001</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GraphicsEN03FE94.002</textblock>
  </import>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4000-01-C</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
