<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00012</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Alteration of Jet Routes; Correction</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 71</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Airspace Docket No. 91-ANM-16]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule; correction.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This action corrects the description of Jet Route J-54, located in vicinity of Idaho and Oregon, published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on September 10, 1993. That final rule removed Boise, ID, from the description of J-54 to improve existing air traffic control (ATC) route continuity on frequently used high altitude routes. However, during recent flight checks of J-54, it was determined that Boise, ID, should be reinstated and the jet route segment from Cherokee, WY, to Laramie, WY, should be removed due to lack of frequency protection in the extended service volume. This action reflects the restoration of Boise, ID, and the removal of the jet route segment from Cherokee, WY, to Laramie, WY, in the description of J-54.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>0701 UTC, March 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Norman W. Thomas, Airspace and Obstruction Evaluation Branch (ATP-240), Airspace-Rules and Aeronautical Information Division, Air Traffic Rules and Procedures Service, Federal Aviation Administration, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591; telephone: (202) 267-9230.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On September 10, 1993, the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) published a final rule that alters several jet routes located in Colorado, Idaho, Kansas, Nebraska, South Dakota, Utah, Wyoming, and Oregon to coincide with the scheduled opening date of the new Denver International Airport (58 FR 47633). However, during recent flight checks of jet route J-54, it was determined that Boise, ID, should be reinstated and the jet route segment from Cherokee, WY, to Laramie, WY, should be removed due to lack of frequency protection in the extended service volume. This action reflects the reinstatement of Boise, ID, and the removal of the segment from Cherokee, WY, to Laramie, WY, in the description of J-54, which becomes effective on March 9, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Correction of Final Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, pursuant to the authority delegated to me, the publication on September 10, 1993 (58 FR 47633), and the description in FAA Order 7400.9A, which is incorporated by reference in 14 CFR 71.1, are corrected as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§71.1</textblock>
    <textblock>[Corrected]</textblock>
    <textblock>On page 47634, in the second column, the description for J-54 is corrected to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>J-54␣[Corrected]</textblock>
    <textblock>From Tatoosh, WA, via Olympia, WA; Baker, OR; Boise, ID; to Pocatello, ID.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 27, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Willis C. Nelson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Manager, Airspace-Rules and Aeronautical Information Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2398 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
