<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00068</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(2) Of the essential elements for proper maintenance of the customer-owned service line, such as those listed in subpart M of this part or those listed in applicable local building codes;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Of available resources that could aid the customer in obtaining maintenance assistance, such as the gas pipeline operator, the state licensing board for plumbers and state plumbers' associations, Federal and state gas pipeline safety organizations, the local building code agencies, and appropriate leak detection, gas utility, and corrosion protection contractors;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Of any information that the operator has concerning the operation and maintenance of the customer-owned service line that could aid the customer, such as information on excavation damage prevention, local codes and standards (when applicable), and the age, location, and material of the customer-owned service line; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) The potential hazards of not maintaining the customer-owned service line, such as corrosion and gas leakage.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) An operator shall provide the notification required in paragraph (a) of this section:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Before (enter date 6 months after date of publication of final rule) for existing customers; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Before (enter date 6 months after date of publication of final rule) or within 30 days from date the gas service line is placed in service for new customers, whichever is later.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Each operator must keep a record of the written notifications made under the requirements of paragraph (a) of this section.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>George W. Tenley, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Administrator for Pipeline Safety.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2399 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-60-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
