<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00072</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00043</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>SmithKline Beecham Clinical Laboratories, 3175 Presidential Drive, Atlanta, GA 30340, 404-934-9205 (formerly: SmithKline Bio-Science Laboratories)</textblock>
    <textblock>SmithKline Beecham Clinical Laboratories, 506 E. State Parkway, Schaumburg, IL 60173, 708-885-2010 (formerly: International Toxicology Laboratories)</textblock>
    <textblock>SmithKline Beecham Clinical Laboratories, 11636 Administration Drive, St. Louis, MO 63146, 314-567-3905</textblock>
    <textblock>SmithKline Beecham Clinical Laboratories, 400 Egypt Road, Norristown, PA 19403, 800-523-5447 (formerly: SmithKline Bio-Science Laboratories)</textblock>
    <textblock>SmithKline Beecham Clinical Laboratories, 8000 Sovereign Row, Dallas, TX 75247, 214-638-1301 (formerly: SmithKline Bio-Science Laboratories)</textblock>
    <textblock>South Bend Medical Foundation, Inc., 530 N. Lafayette Boulevard, South Bend, IN 46601, 219-234-4176</textblock>
    <textblock>Southwest Laboratories, 2727 W. Baseline Road, Suite 6, Tempe, AZ 85283, 602-438-8507</textblock>
    <textblock>St. Anthony Hospital (Toxicology Laboratory), P.O. Box 205, 1000 N. Lee Street, Oklahoma City, OK 73102, 405-272-7052</textblock>
    <textblock>St. Louis University Forensic Toxicology Laboratory, 1205 Carr Lane, St. Louis, MO 63104, 314-577-8628</textblock>
    <textblock>Toxicology &amp; Drug Monitoring Laboratory, University of Missouri Hospital &amp; Clinics, 301 Business Loop 70 West, Suite 208, Columbia, MO 65203, 314-882-1273</textblock>
    <textblock>Toxicology Testing Service, Inc., 5426 N.W. 79th Avenue, Miami, FL 33166, 305-593-2260</textblock>
    <textblock>TOXWORX Laboratories, Inc., 6160 Variel Avenue, Woodland Hills, CA 91367, 818-226-4373 (formerly: Laboratory Specialists, Inc.; Abused Drug Laboratories; MedTox Bio-Analytical, a Division of MedTox Laboratories, Inc.; moved 12/21/92)</textblock>
    <textblock>UNILAB, 18408 Oxnard Street, Tarzana, CA 91356, 800-492-0800/818-343-8191</textblock>
    <textblock>(formerly: MetWest-BPL Toxicology Laboratory)</textblock>
    <textblock>The following laboratory withdrew from the Program on January 21, 1994: Resource One, Inc., Seven Pointe Circle, Greenville, SC 29615, 803-233-5639.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following laboratory withdrew from the Program on January 31, 1994: Clinical Pathology Facility, Inc., 711 Bingham Street, Pittsburgh, PA 15203, 412-488-7500.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard Kopanda,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Executive Officer, Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2383 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-20-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
