<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00057</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Navy describes in its application efforts that will be made to minimize project related impacts to marine mammals (see below_Measures to Reduce Impacts). The Navy strongly believes that impacts can be held to an acceptably low level by mandating conservative safety zones for marine mammal exclusion and by incorporating an active aerial survey monitoring effort in the program both prior to, and after, detonation of explosives. The Navy states that tests will not be conducted if marine mammals, sea turtles, fish schools, or seabirds are detected within the safety zone, or if weather and sea conditions preclude adequate aerial surveillance. Also, if post-test surveys determine that an injurious or lethal take of a marine mammal has occurred, the test procedure and the monitoring methods will be reviewed by the Navy and NMFS and appropriate changes will be made.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 14, 1993, under the National Environmental Policy Act (42 U.S.C. 4321</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.; NEPA), NMFS released for public comment an Environmental Assessment (EA) and on October 15, 1993, published proposed regulations (58 FR 53491) authorizing and governing the unintentional taking of a small number of pinnipeds and cetaceans incidental to the Navy's underwater explosives detonations program in the OSTR. Public meetings were held on November 8, 1993, in Long Beach, CA and on November 15, 1993, in Silver Spring, MD. The comment period closed on November 29, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments and Responses</textblock>
    <textblock>During the 45-day comment period, NMFS received several hundred letters and photocopied form letters from the general public, all but 4 of which were in opposition either to the detonation of explosives in the SCB or to the proposed regulations. Most of these comments did not address the contents of the Navy's application, the proposed regulations, or the EA. Instead, the commenters stated their opposition to the Navy's proposed activities because there would be a loss of marine life; because they believed aerial surveys were inadequate; and because they believed there would be an adverse impact on pregnant gray whales. In addition, NMFS received approximately 75 letters or hearing statements within the comment period that substantially discussed the issues and science upon which the proposed regulations were based.</textblock>
    <textblock>Concerns Relating to the MMPA</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>The majority of the letters received expressed opposition to the Navy's detonation of explosives off the Channel Islands and urged NMFS to deny it the authorization to conduct these tests.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Navy conducts ship shock tests under the authority of the National Defense Authorization Act. The Navy does not require NMFS authorization to conduct these tests. However, under the MMPA, the taking of marine mammals is prohibited unless authorized by exemption or permit. Since there is a possibility that marine mammals may be unintentionally taken incidental to the ship shock trials, the Navy applied to NMFS for a small take authorization under section 101(a)(5) of the MMPA. Thus, it is the taking of marine mammals incidental to the Navy's ship shock tests that NMFS is authorizing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment:</textblock>
    <textblock>One commenter believed that section 101(a) of the MMPA, under which the Navy is seeking permission for an unintentional take, is not appropriate for the Navy's purposes, as it was written to allow for indigenous groups to fish for subsistence. Others believe the MMPA is to protect marine mammals and that no takings under a LOA should be authorized.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table 2._Requested Take Under a Letter of Authorization: Estimated Maximum Annual Incidental Take of Marine Mammals Assuming Maximum Underwater Detonation Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>1Incidental take</textblock>
    <textblock>1Lethal</textblock>
    <textblock>1Injury</textblock>
    <textblock>1Harassment</textblock>
    <textblock>Pinnipeds:</textblock>
    <textblock>California Sea Lion</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>38</textblock>
    <textblock>173</textblock>
    <textblock>Harbor Seal</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>16</textblock>
    <textblock>68</textblock>
    <textblock>Northern Elephant Seal</textblock>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
    <textblock>158</textblock>
    <textblock>724</textblock>
    <textblock>Northern Fur Seal</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>13</textblock>
    <textblock>57</textblock>
    <textblock>Odontocetes:</textblock>
    <textblock>Common Dolphin</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>16</textblock>
    <textblock>67</textblock>
    <textblock>Striped Dolphin</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
    <textblock>Risso's Dolphin</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>Pacific White-Sided Dolphin</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>52</textblock>
    <textblock>236</textblock>
    <textblock>Northern Rt. Whale Dolphin</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>24</textblock>
    <textblock>108</textblock>
    <textblock>Dall's Porpoise</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
    <textblock>18</textblock>
    <textblock>Bottlenose Dolphin</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>15</textblock>
    <textblock>Killer Whale</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>Sperm Whale (e)</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
    <textblock>20</textblock>
    <textblock>Beaked Whales</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>Mysticetes:</textblock>
    <textblock>Minke Whale</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>Blue Whale (e)</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>11</textblock>
    <textblock>Fin Whale (e)</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
    <textblock>Sei Whale (e)</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>Humpback Whale (e)</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>Gray Whale</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>40</textblock>
    <textblock>Right Whale (e)</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) = endangered species.</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
