<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00019</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>II. Public Reporting Burden</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the current regulations, major non-municipal licensees file annual reports containing data on their electric generation during the prior fiscal year. If adopted, one alternative of the regulations discussed herein would eliminate that reporting burden.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Background</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission is required by section 10(e)(1) of the FPA</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>to collect annual charges from licensees for the cost of administering Part I of the FPA. Part 11 of the Commission's regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>provides the manner in which licensees are charged for such costs. Prior to the adoption of the current regulations in 1958 and 1963, administrative charges were not based on the actual costs of the government, but were in the nature of set fees that were billed for a calendar year.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the current regulations, the reimbursable costs are determined on a fiscal year basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 3401 of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1986 (OBRA)</textblock>
    <textblock>requires the Commission to recover all of its costs for the</textblock>
    <textblock>fiscal year through annual charges and fees.</textblock>
    <textblock>The annual charges assessed pursuant to OBRA are based on an estimate of the Commission's current-fiscal-year costs, with subsequent adjustments based on actual costs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to OBRA, the Commission collects annual charges to recover the costs of administering parts II and III of the FPA, as well as the costs the Commission incurs in administering the Natural Gas Act, the Natural Gas Policy Act, and the Interstate Commerce Act. In this regard, we note that section 3401(a)(2) of OBRA provides that ``[t]he provisions of this subtitle shall not affect the authority, requirements, exceptions, or limitations in sections 10(e) and 30(e) of the Federal Power Act.''</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Allocation Among Different Classes of Licensees</textblock>
    <textblock>The existing §11.1 provides three different allocation formulae for three different classes of licensees. For non-municipal licensees of projects of more than 2,000 horsepower of installed capacity, §11.1(a) sets forth an allocation formula that is based on a combination of the project's authorized installed capacity and the energy actually generated.</textblock>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
    <textblock>For municipal licensees of projects of more than 2,000 horsepower, §11.1(b) sets forth an allocation formula based solely on capacity.</textblock>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
    <textblock>For all licensees (both municipal and non-municipal) of projects of 2,000 horsepower or less of installed capacity, §11.1(c) specifies an annual charge of five cents per horsepower, with a minimum charge of $5 per year.</textblock>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission believes that the process of collecting data and assessing charges could be conducted more efficiently if the allocation were based on a single formula, and questions whether any presently-valid purpose is served by perpetuating the divergent formulae. Therefore, one alternative the Commission is considering is to use the same formula to allocate the annual charges among a single pool of licensees that includes both municipal licensees (</textblock>
    <textblock>i.e.</textblock>
    <textblock>, those who are not fully exempt from annual charges) and non-municipal licensees, as well as minor licensees and (as discussed below) exemptees. One variation of that alternative is to base that formula entirely on authorized installed capacity. Another variation would be to base the formula entirely on generation. A third alternative would be to base it on a combination of capacity and generation.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 803(e)(1).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>18 CFR part 11.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The present system of basing the annual charges on actual costs was adopted in Order No. 205, 19 F.P.C. 907 (1958) (with respect to municipal licensees only), and in Order No. 272, 30 F.P.C. 1333 (1963) (all other licensees); see also Order No. 272A, 31 F.P.C. 1555 (1964).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Pub. L. No. 99-509, Title III, Subtitle E, sec. 3401 (1986) (codified at 42 U.S.C. 7178). OBRA is implemented in Part 382 of the Commission's Regulations, 18 CFR Part 382.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See Joint Explanatory Statement of the Committee of Conference to Accompany H.R. 5300 (Conference Report), H.R. Rep. No. 1012, 99th Cong., 2d Sess. 238, reprinted in 1986 U.S.C.C.A.N. 3607, 3883.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The procedures for estimating the costs and later adjusting the assessments are described in Order No. 472, 52 FR 18201 (May 14, 1987), FERC Stats. &amp; Regs. (Regulations Preambles 1986-1990) ¶30,746 at pp. 30,612 and 30,616-17.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The capacity is currently measured in horsepower, while the generation is measured in kilowatt-hours. The allocation for pumped storage projects is based solely on capacity.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The capacity is currently measured in horsepower.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>As noted above, the present allocation formulae were adopted in Order No. 205, 19 F.P.C. 907 (1958) and Order No. 272, 30 F.P.C. 1333 (1963).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
