<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00008</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[C-508-605]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Industrial Phosphoric Acid From Israel; Final Results of Countervailing Duty Administrative Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>International Trade Administration/Import Administration, Department of Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of final results of countervailing duty administrative review.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 28, 1993, the Department of Commerce published the preliminary results of its administrative review of the countervailing duty order on industrial phosphoric acid from Israel (58 FR 57986). We have now completed the review and determine the net subsidy to be 6.98 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>ad valorem</textblock>
    <textblock>for all firms during the period January 1, 1991 through December 31, 1991.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Brian Albright or Cameron Cardozo, Office of Countervailing Compliance, International Trade Administration, U.S. Department of Commerce, Washington, DC 20230; telephone: (202) 482-2786.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 28, 1993, the Department of Commerce (the Department) published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 57986) the preliminary results of its administrative review of the countervailing duty order on industrial phosphoric acid from Israel (52 FR 31057;</textblock>
    <textblock>August 19, 1987) covering the period January 1, 1991 through December 31, 1991. The Department has now completed this administrative review in accordance with section 751 of the Tariff Act of 1930, as amended (the Act).</textblock>
    <textblock>Scope of Review</textblock>
    <textblock>Imports covered by this review are shipments of Israeli industrial phosphoric acid. During the review period, such merchandise was classifiable under item number 2809.20.00 of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Harmonized Tariff Schedule</textblock>
    <textblock>(HTS). The HTS item number is provided for convenience and Customs purposes. The written description remains dispositive.</textblock>
    <textblock>The review covers the period January 1, 1991 through December 31, 1991 and nine programs. Negev Phosphates, Ltd. (NPL), which merged with Rotem Fertilizers Ltd. on December 31, 1991 after operating independently throughout the review period, was the only known producer exporting the subject merchandise from Israel to the United States during the 1991 review period.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
