<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00018</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>COMMITTEE FOR THE IMPLEMENTATION OF TEXTILE AGREEMENTS</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Announcement of the Extension of the Bilateral Textile Agreement and Visa and Exempt Certification Arrangement Between the United States and India</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements (CITA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Announcing the extension of the bilateral textile agreement and visa and exempt certification arrangement with India.</textblock>
  </action>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Jennifer Tallarico, International Trade Specialist, Office of Textiles and Apparel, U.S. Department of Commerce, (202) 482-4212.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 11651 of March 3, 1972, as amended; section 204 of the Agricultural Act of 1956, as amended (7 U.S.C. 1854).</textblock>
    <textblock>A notice published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on January 5, 1994 (59 FR 574) announced an extension of the existing visa and exempt certification arrangement between the Governments of the United States and India through January 31, 1994. In a Memorandum of Understanding dated January 22, 1994 the two governments agreed to further amend and extend their Bilateral Cotton, Wool, Man-Made Fiber, Silk Blend and Other Vegetable Fiber Textile Agreement of February 6, 1987. The agreement and the visa and exempt certification arrangement have been extended through December 31, 1995. A directive to Customs implementing the limits for 1994 will be published shortly in a separate notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of this notice is to remind the public that the U.S. Customs Service must continue to require visas and exempt certifications, as previously published, for textiles and textile products, produced or manufactured in India and exported to the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>See 44 FR 68504, published on November 29, 1979.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rita D. Hayes,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2462 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DR-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
