<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00036</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Termination of Tenancy for Criminal Activity</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of the Assistant Secretary for Housing_Federal Housing Commissioner</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>24 CFR Parts 247, 880, 881, and 883</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. R-94-1696; FR-3472-P-01]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 2502-AG12</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the Assistant Secretary for Housing_Federal Housing Commissioner, HUD.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposed rule would provide that any criminal activity that threatens the health, safety, or right to peaceful enjoyment of the premises by other tenants; any criminal activity that threatens the health, safety, or right to peaceful enjoyment of their residences by persons residing in the immediate vicinity of the premises; or any drug-related criminal activity on or near such premises, engaged in by a tenant, any member of the tenant's household, or any guest or other person under the tenant's control would be grounds for termination of tenancy.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received by April 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to submit comments regarding this proposed rule to the Office of General Counsel, Rules Docket Clerk, room 10276, Department of Housing and Urban Development, 451 Seventh Street SW., Washington, DC 20410-0500. Facsimile (FAX) comments are not acceptable.</textblock>
    <textblock>Communications should refer to the above docket number and title. A copy of each communication submitted will be available for public inspection and copying on weekdays between 7:30 a.m. and 5:30 p.m. at the above address.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>James Tahash, Director of Planning and Procedures Division, room 6180, Department of Housing and Urban Development, 451 Seventh Street SW., Washington, DC 20410-8000; telephone, (voice) (202) 708-4162; (TDD) (202) 708-4594. (These are not toll-free numbers)</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposed rule would amend regulations for certain section 8 project-based assistance programs to provide that a section 8 family may be evicted for drug crimes or for criminal activity that threatens other residents. Eviction may be based on such criminal activity by a household member, a guest or another person under the tenant's control.</textblock>
    <textblock>For existing housing under the section 8 Loan Management Program (24 CFR part 886, subpart A) and section 8 Property Disposition Program (24 CFR part 886, subpart C), the proposed rule would implement section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (42 U.S.C. 1437f(d)(1)(B)(iii)), as amended by section 546 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act and section 145 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>At present, HUD's Multifamily Model Lease (Handbook 4350.3 Appendix 19a) contains similar provisions allowing eviction for drug-related criminal activities or criminal activity that threatens other residents.</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposed rule would revise 24 CFR parts 247, 880, 881 and 883. The proposed rule would apply to evictions under the section 8 new construction and substantial rehabilitation programs and under the section 8 Loan Management and Property Disposition Programs. This proposed rule also would cover the following subsidized projects subject to 24 CFR part 247: multifamily housing projects that receive the benefit of subsidy in the form of below-market interest rates under sections 221(d)(3) and (5); interest reduction payments under section 236 of the National Housing Act, including Rental Assistance Payments (RAP); below-market interest rate direct loans under section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959; rental subsidy in the form of rent supplement payments under section 101 of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965; section 8 in connection with section 202 Loans for Housing for the Elderly or Handicapped (24 CFR part 885), the section 8 Additional Assistance Program for Projects with HUD-Insured and HUD-Held Mortgages (24 CFR part 886, subpart A) and the section 8 Housing Assistance Program for the Disposition of HUD-Owned Projects (24 CFR part 886, subpart C).</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
