<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00052</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00027</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4933-2]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Michigan; Clean Air Act Section 182(f) NO</textblock>
    <textblock>x</textblock>
    <textblock>RACT Exemption Petition</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>United States Environmental Protection Agency (USEPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The USEPA is announcing that the State of Michigan has filed a petition proposing that the southeast Michigan moderate ozone nonattainment area be exempted from the requirement to implement oxides of nitrogen (NO</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>) Reasonably Available Control Technology (RACT) controls pursuant to section 182(f) of the Clean Air Act (Act). This petition is available for public review.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Daniel Meyer, Air Toxics and Radiation Branch, Regulation Development Section (AT-18J), United States Environmental Protection Agency, Region 5, Chicago, Illinois 60604, (312) 886-9401.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On November 15, 1993 the Michigan Department of Natural Resources submitted a petition proposing that the southeast Michigan moderate ozone nonattainment area be exempted from the requirement to implement NO</textblock>
    <textblock>x</textblock>
    <textblock>RACT controls pursuant to section 182(f) of the Act. More specifically, this exemption request is being made according to provisions cited in a USEPA memorandum dated September 17, 1993 from Michael Shapiro, to the Regional Offices. The exemption request is based on monitoring data which demonstrates that the ozone standard has been attained in this nonattainment area for the past 3 years, 1991 through 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 30, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Valdas V. Adamkus,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Regional Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2442 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
