<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00063</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Gas Piping Technology Committee (GPTC) Guide for Gas Transmission and Distribution Piping Systems, Volume 1</textblock>
    <textblock>The GPTC guide contains information and methods to assist gas pipeline operators in complying with the federal pipeline safety regulations by providing ``how to'' information related to the standards. The GPTC Guide contains minimum federal safety standards together with the design recommendations, material reference, and recommended practices of the GPTC.</textblock>
    <textblock>Gas Piping Technology Committee, AGA, 1515 Wilson Boulevard,</textblock>
    <textblock>Arlington, VA 22209, (703) 841-8454</textblock>
    <textblock>The National Association of Corrosion Engineers (NACE)</textblock>
    <textblock>NACE publishes a standard recommended practice to present procedures and practices for achieving effective control of external corrosion on buried or submerged metallic piping systems. This recommended practice describes the use of electrically insulating coatings, electrical isolation, and cathodic protection as corrosion control methods. The practice also contains specific provisions for the application of cathodic protection to existing bare, existing coated, and new piping systems.</textblock>
    <textblock>National Association of Corrosion Engineers P.O. Box 218340, Houston, TX 77218-8340, (713) 492-0535</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Gas Pipeline Safety Organizations</textblock>
    <textblock>The regional offices of the Federal Office of Pipeline Safety can provide an owner of a customer-owned service line with a copy of the federal pipeline safety regulations (49 CFR part 192) that operators of service lines follow, the booklet ``Guidance Manual for Operators of Small Gas Systems,'' which provides a general overview of compliance responsibilities under federal pipeline safety regulations, and verbal information on proper maintenance for customer-owned service lines:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Pipeline Safety, Eastern Region, U.S. Department of Transportation, 400 Seventh Street SW., room 5413, Washington, DC 20590, (202) 366-4580</textblock>
    <textblock>Jurisdictional authority over the District of Columbia and the states of Connecticut, Delaware, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, Vermont, Virginia and West Virginia.</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Pipeline Safety, Southern Region, 1720 Peachtree Road NW.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Suite 426 North, Atlanta, GA 30309, (404) 347-2632</textblock>
    <textblock>Jurisdictional authority over Puerto Rico and the states of Alabama, Arkansas, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, Mississippi, North Carolina, South Carolina and Tennessee</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Pipeline Safety, Central Region, 911 Walnut Street, room 1811, Kansas City, MO 64106, (816) 426-2654</textblock>
    <textblock>Jurisdictional authority over the states of Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, Michigan, Minnesota, Missouri, Nebraska, North Dakota, Ohio, South Dakota and Wisconsin</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Pipeline Safety, Southwest Region, 2320 La Branch, room 2116, Houston, TX 77004, (713) 750-1746</textblock>
    <textblock>Jurisdictional authority over the states of Arizona, Louisiana, New Mexico, Oklahoma and Texas</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Pipeline Safety, Western Region, 555 Zang Street, 2nd floor, Lakewood, CO 80228, (303) 969-5150</textblock>
    <textblock>Jurisdictional authority over the states of Alaska, California, Colorado, Hawaii, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, Oregon, Utah, Washington and Wyoming</textblock>
    <textblock>State Pipeline Safety Organizations</textblock>
    <textblock>The following state pipeline safety organizations can provide an owner of a customer-owned service line with a copy of the federal and state pipeline safety regulations that operators of service lines follow, written or verbal information on maintenance requirements for customer-owned service lines, and regional sources of additional information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Alabama Public Service Commission, PO Box 991, Montgomery, AL 36101-0991, (205) 242-5778</textblock>
    <textblock>Arizona Corporation Commission, 1200 West Washington Street, Phoenix, AZ 85007, (602) 542-3316</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
