<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00014</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Nonprocurement Debarment and Suspension</textblock>
    <textblock>Prospective participants (as defined at 15 CFR part 26, section 105) are subject to 15 CFR Part 26, Nonprocurement Debarment and Suspension'' and the related section of the certification form prescribed above applies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Drug Free Workplace</textblock>
    <textblock>Grantees (as defined at 15 CFR part 26, section 605) are subject to 15 CFR Part 26, Subpart F, ``Governmentwide Requirements for Drug-Free Workplace (Grants)'' and the related section of the certification form prescribed above applies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Anti-Lobbying</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons (as defined at 15 CFR part 28, Section 105) are subject to the lobbying provisions of 31 U.S.C. 1352, ``Limitation on use of appropriated funds to influence certain Federal contracting and financial transactions,'' and the lobbying section of the certification form prescribed above applies to applications/bids for grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts for more than $100,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>Anti-Lobbying Disclosures</textblock>
    <textblock>Any applicant that has paid or will pay for lobbying using any funds must submit an SF-LLL, ``Disclosure of Lobbying Activities,'' as required under 15 CFR part 28, appendix B.</textblock>
    <textblock>Lower Tier Certifications</textblock>
    <textblock>Recipients shall require applications/bidders for subgrants, contracts, subcontracts, or other lower tier covered transactions at any tier under the award to submit, if applicable, a completed Form CD-512, ``Certifications Regarding Debarment, Suspension, ineligibility and Voluntary Exclusion-Lower Tier Covered Transactions and Lobbying'' and disclosure form, SF-LLL, ``Disclosure of Lobbying Activities.'' Form CD-512 is intended for the use of recipients and should not be transmitted to DOC. SF-LLL submitted by any tier recipient or subrecipient should be submitted to DOC in accordance with the instructions contained in the award document.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 26, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>11.800 Minority Business Development</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance)</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William R. Fuller,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Director, New York (Regional Office)</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2328 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 510-21-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
