<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00015</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Final Rule and Rule Amendments Concerning Composition of Various Self-Regulatory Organization Governing Boards and Major Disciplinary Committees</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>COMMODITY FUTURES TRADING COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>17 CFR Part 1</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Commodity Futures Trading Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule; correction.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document contains corrections to the final rule, which was published Tuesday, July 13, 1993, (58 FR 37644). The rule implemented the statutory directives of sections 5a, 8c, and 17 of the Commodity Exchange Act as amended by section 206 of the Futures Trading Practices Act of 1992 and established various requirements with respect to the composition of self-regulatory organization governing boards and major disciplinary committees.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Barbara Webster Black, Office of General Counsel, Commodity Futures Trading Commission, 2033 K Street, NW., Washington, DC 20581. Telephone: (202) 254-9880.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>The final rule that is the subject of this correction amended chapter I of title 17 of the Code of Federal Regulations by adding ยง1.64, Composition of various self-regulatory organization governing boards and major disciplinary committees, on the effective date.</textblock>
    <textblock>Need for Correction</textblock>
    <textblock>As published, the final rule contains a typographical error which is in need of clarification.</textblock>
    <textblock>Correction of Publication</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, the publication on July 13, 1993 of the final rule, which was the subject of FR Doc. 93-16525, is corrected as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง1.64</textblock>
    <textblock>[Corrected]</textblock>
    <textblock>On page 37654, in the second column, in ยง1.64, paragraph (b) introductory text, line six, the section designation ``5(a)(12)(A)'' is corrected to read ``5a(a)(12)(A)''.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 25, 1994, by the Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jean A. Webb,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of the Commission.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2140 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6351-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
