<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00053</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00028</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4832-9]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Change in Solicitation Procedures Under the Small Business Competitiveness Demonstration Program</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Title VII of the ``Business Opportunity Development Act of 1988'' (Pub. L. 100-656) established the Small Business Competitiveness Demonstration Program and designated ten (10) agencies, including the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), to conduct the program over a four (4) year period from January 1, 1989 to December 31, 1992. The Small Business Opportunity Enhancement Act of 1992 (Pub. L. 102-366) extended the demonstration program until September 30, 1996, and made certain changes in the procedures for operation of the demonstration program.</textblock>
    <textblock>The law designated four (4) industry groups for testing whether the competitive capabilities of the specified industry groups will enable them to compete successfully on an unrestricted basis. The four (4) industry groups are: Construction (except dredging); architectural and engineering (A&amp;E) services (including surveying and mapping); refuse systems and related services (limited to trash/garbage collection services); and non-nuclear ship repair. Under the program, when a participating agency does not meet its small business participation goal, small business set-asides must be reinstated in the particular industry group. If small business goals are achieved in subsequent quarters, the agency may cancel the set-asides and return to full and open competition. The small business goal is 40 percent of the total contract dollars awarded for construction, trash/garbage collection services, and non-nuclear ship repair and 35 percent of the total contract dollars awarded for architect-engineer services. The program reserves for emerging small businesses procurements under $25,000 for construction, trash/garbage collection services, and non-nuclear ship repair, and under $50,000 for architect-engineer services.</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice announces modifications to EPA's solicitation practices under the demonstration program based on a review of the Agency's performance during the period from July 1, 1992 to June 30, 1993. Modifications to solicitation practices are set forth in the Supplementary Information section below and apply to solicitations issued on or after the date of publication of this notice.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice is effective upon publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Edward N. Chambers at (202) 260-6028.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Construction Services in SIC Codes 1629, 1761, and 1796</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Procurements over $25,000 for these SIC codes will be set aside for small business when there is a reasonable expectation of obtaining competition from two or more small businesses. If no expectation exists, the procurements will be conducted on an unrestricted basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Architect-Engineer Services (All PSC Codes Under the Demonstration Program</textblock>
    <textblock>Procurements over $50,000 for all architect-engineer services will be set aside for small business when there is a reasonable expectation of obtaining competition from two or more small businesses. If no expectation exists, the procurements will be conducted on an unrestricted basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Betty L. Bailey,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Acquisition Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2438 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
