<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00045</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Ophthalmic and Topical Dosage Form New Animal Drugs; Neomycin, Penicillin, Polymyxin, Hydrocortisone Topical Suspension</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>21 CFR Part 524</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration, HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is amending the animal drug regulations to reflect codification of a previously approved new animal drug application (NADA) held by Upjohn Co. The NADA provides for the safe use of Forte-Topical</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>Suspension (neomycin, penicillin, polymyxin, hydrocortisone suspension) as a topical antibacterial and anti-inflammatory agent in dogs.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dianne T. McRae, Center for Veterinary Medicine (HFV-102), Food and Drug Administration, 7500 Standish Pl., Rockville, MD 20855, 301-594-1623.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Upjohn Co., Kalamazoo, MI 49001, is sponsor of NADA 65-119 which provides for the safe use of Forte-Topical</textblock>
    <textblock>®</textblock>
    <textblock>Suspension. Each milliliter contains 25 milligrams (mg) of neomycin sulfate, 10,000 international units (IU's) of penicillin G procaine, 5,000 IU's of polymyxin B sulfate, 2 mg of hydrocortisone acetate, and 1.25 mg of hydrocortisone sodium succinate for the topical treatment of dogs for summer eczema, atopic dermatitis, interdigital eczema, and otitis externa caused by bacteria susceptible to neomycin, penicillin, and polymyxin B. The product was originally approved on September 15, 1959. Accordingly, the regulations in 21 CFR 524.1484h are amended to reflect approval of the NADA.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the freedom of information provisions of 21 CFR part 20 and 21 CFR 514.11(e)(2)(i) for NADA's approved prior to July 1, 1975, a summary of safety and effectiveness data and information submitted to support approval of this application is not required.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA has determined under 21 CFR 25.24(d)(1)(i) that this action is of a type that does not individually or cumulatively have a significant effect on the human environment. Therefore, neither an environmental assessment nor an environmental impact statement is required.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 21 CFR Part 524</textblock>
    <textblock>Animal drugs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and under authority delegated to the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and redelegated to the Center for Veterinary Medicine, 21 CFR part 524 is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 524_OPHTHALMIC AND TOPICAL DOSAGE FORM NEW ANIMAL DRUGS</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for 21 CFR part 524 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 512 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. 360b).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. New §524.1484h is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§524.1484h</textblock>
    <textblock>Neomycin, penicillin, polymyxin, hydrocortisone suspension.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Specifications</textblock>
    <textblock>. Each milliliter of suspension contains 25 milligrams of neomycin sulfate equivalent to 17.5 milligrams of neomycin, 10,000 international units of penicillin G procaine, 5,000 international units of polymyxin B sulfate, 2 milligrams of hydrocortisone acetate, and 1.25 milligrams of hydrocortisone sodium succinate.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Sponsor</textblock>
    <textblock>. See 000009 in §510.600(c) of this chapter.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Special considerations</textblock>
    <textblock>. The labeling shall state: This medication contains penicillin. Allergic reactions in humans are known to occur from topical exposure to penicillin.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Conditions of use_dogs_(1) Amount</textblock>
    <textblock>. Rub a small amount into the involved area 1 to 3 times a day. After definite improvement, it may be applied once a day or every other day.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Indications for use</textblock>
    <textblock>. Treatment of summer eczema, atopic dermatitis, interdigital eczema, and otitis externa caused by bacteria susceptible to neomycin, penicillin, and polymyxin B.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Limitations</textblock>
    <textblock>. For use in dogs only. Shake drug thoroughly and clean lesion before using. If redness, irritation, or swelling persists or increases, discontinue use and reevaluate diagnosis. Federal law restricts this drug to use by or on the order of a licensed veterinarian.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 27, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Robert C. Livingston,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of New Animal Drug Evaluation, Center for Veterinary Medicine.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2400 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
