<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00044</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00019</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Gordonsville Energy, L.P.; Filing</textblock>
    <textblock>January 28, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 13, 1994, Gordonsville Energy, L.P. (Gordonsville) tendered for filing a Petition for Waiver of the Commission's regulations under the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act. Gordonsville petitions the Commission to waive the ownership requirements for qualifying cogeneration facilities as set forth in ยง292.206(b), 18 CFR 292.206(b) of the Commission's regulations implementing section 201 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978, as amended (PURPA) with respect to Gordonsville's one hundred percent (100%) ownership interest in two natural gas and oil-fired qualifying cogeneration facilities (the ``Project'') located in Gordonsville, Virginia.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, N.E., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rules 211 and 214 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (18 CFR 385.211 and 18 CFR 385.214). All such motions or protests should be filed on or before February 14, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. EL94-20-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2375 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
