<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00047</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>15. Section 232.902 would be revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§232.902</textblock>
    <textblock>Eligible project.</textblock>
    <textblock>Existing projects (with such repairs and improvements as are determined by the Commissioner to be necessary) are eligible for insurance under this subpart. The project must not require substantial rehabilitation and three years must have elapsed from the date of completion of construction or substantial rehabilitation of the project, or from the beginning of occupancy, whichever is later, to the date of application for insurance. In addition, the project must have attained sustaining occupancy (occupancy that would produce income sufficient to pay operating expenses, annual debt service and reserve fund for replacement requirements) as determined by the Commissioner, before endorsement of the project for insurance; alternatively, the mortgagor must provide an operating deficit fund at the time of endorsement for insurance, in an amount, and under an agreement, approved by the Commissioner.</textblock>
    <textblock>16. Section 232.903 would be amended by revising the first sentence in the introductory paragraph (a), the first sentence in paragraph (b), and the first sentence in the introductory paragraph (d), to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§232.903</textblock>
    <textblock>Maximum mortgage limitations.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Value limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>The mortgage shall involve a principal obligation of not in excess of eighty-five percent (85%) for a profit motivated mortgagor (ninety percent (90%) for a private nonprofit mortgagor) of the Commissioner's estimate of the value of the project, including major movable equipment to be used in its operation and any repairs and improvements. *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Debt service limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>The insured mortgage shall involve a principal obligation not in excess of the amount that could be amortized by eighty-five percent (85%) for a profit motivated mortgagor (ninety percent (90%) for a private nonprofit mortgagor) of the net projected project income available for payment of debt service.␣*␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Project to be acquired_additional limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to meeting the requirements of paragraphs (a) and (b) of this section, if the project is to be acquired by the mortgagor and the purchase price is to be financed with the insured mortgage, the maximum amount must not exceed eighty-five percent (85%) for a profit motivated mortgagor (ninety percent (90%) for a private nonprofit mortgagor) of the cost of acquisition as determined by the Commissioner.␣*␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Nicolas P. Retsinas,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary for Housing_Federal Housing Commissioner.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2466 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4210-27-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
