<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00019</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>d. Beginning on page 116 and on appropriate pages thereafter, the following table entries are corrected to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Beginning on page 122 and on appropriate pages thereafter, the following table entries are added to the end of paragraph (f) to read as follows:</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1HTSUS</textblock>
    <textblock>1Tariff shift and/or other requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>i0(t)</textblock>
    <textblock>i0Section XX: Chapters 94 through 96</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>9504.10-9506.29</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 9504.10 through 9506.29 from any other subheading, including within that group.</textblock>
    <textblock>9506.31</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 9506.31 from any other subheading, except from subheading 9506.39.</textblock>
    <textblock>9506.39-9506.99</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 9506.39 through 9506.99 from any other subheading, including within that group.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
  </table>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1HTSUS</textblock>
    <textblock>1Tariff shift and/or other requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>i0(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>i0Section I: Chapters 1 through 5</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>0305.30</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 0305.30 from any other subheading, except from fillets of heading 0304.</textblock>
    <textblock>0305.41-0305.69</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 0305.41 through 0305.69 from any other chapter.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>0403.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 0403.90 from any other chapter; or</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to sour cream, or kephir from any other product of Chapter 4.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>i0(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>i0Section IV: Chapters 16 through 24</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>2008.19-2008.99</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 2008.19 through 2008.99 from any other chapter, provided that change is not the result of mere blanching of nuts.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>2202.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 2202.90 from any other subheading, except from Chapter 4 or heading 1901, 2009, or 2106; or</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 2202.90 from Chapter 4 or heading 1901, provided that the good contains no more than 50 percent of milk solids by weight; or</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 2202.90 from heading 2009 or subheading 2106.90, provided that a single juice ingredient of foreign origin, or juice ingredients from a single foreign country constitute in single strength form no more than 60 percent by volume of the good.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>i0(h)</textblock>
    <textblock>i0Section VIII: Chapters 41 through 42</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>4101-4103</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 4101 through 4103 from any other chapter.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>(k)</textblock>
    <textblock>i0Section XI: Chapters 50 through 63</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>Notes</textblock>
    <textblock>l*␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>l(e) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) For the purposes of §102.11(b) of the General Rules, except for sets, where a good classifiable in Chapter 61 through 63 does not meet the tariff shift and/or other requirements of the heading or subheading under which it is classifiable, the country of origin of that good shall be the single country where the component which determines the classification of that good was cut or formed (e.g., knit to shape).</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>5407-5408</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 5407 through 5408 from any heading outside that group; or</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>A change from greige fabric of heading 5407 through 5408 to finished fabric of those same headings by dyeing and printing, plus two or more of the following finishing operations_bleaching, shrinking, fulling, napping, decating, permanent stiffening, weighting, permanent embossing, or moireing.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>6211.31-6211.49</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to assembled fully lined, fully padded, or fully insulated garments consisting of five or more major parts, of subheading 6211.31 through 6211.49, from either subheading 6217.90 or 6117.90, provided that no major part has been knit to shape; or</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to assembled fully lined, fully padded, or fully insulated garments consisting of five or more major parts, from unassembled parts classified in subheading 6211.31 through 6211.49 as a result of the application of GRI 2(a), provided that no major part has been knit to shape.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>i0(p)</textblock>
    <textblock>i0Section XVI: Chapters 84 through 85</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>8415.10-8415.83</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 8415.10 through 8415.83 from any subheading, including another subheading within that group, except a change within that group resulting from a simple assembly.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>8419.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 8419.90 from any other heading, except headings 7303, 7304, 7305, or 7306, unless the change from these headings involves bending to shape, and except a change from heading 8501, when resulting from a simple assembly.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>8422.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 8422.90 from any other heading, except heading 8501, when resulting from a simple assembly.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>8448.11-8448.19</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 8448.11 through 8448.19 from any other subheading, including another subheading within that group.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>8448.20-8448.59</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 8448.20 through 8448.59 from any other heading, except heading 8501, when resulting from a simple assembly.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>8473</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 8473 from any other heading, except heading 8501, when resulting from a simple assembly.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>8482.91-8482.99</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 8482.91 through 8482.99 from any other heading.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>8544.11-8544.70</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 8544.11 through 8544.70 from any other subheading, including another subheading within that group, except when resulting from a simple assembly.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>(r)</textblock>
    <textblock>i0Section XVIII: Chapters 90 through 92</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>9001.10</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 9001.10 from any other subheading, except from subheading 8544.70.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>9001.40-9001.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 9001.40 through 9001.90 from any other subheading, including another subheading within that group, except from lens blanks of heading 7014 or subheading 7015.10.</textblock>
    <textblock>9002.11-9002.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 9002.11 through 9002.90 from any other subheading, including another subheading within that group, except from subheading 9001.90 or lens blanks of heading 7014.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>9005.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 9005.90 from any other heading, except from heading 9001 or 9002.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>9013.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 9013.90 from any other subheading, except from subheading 9002.19, when resulting from a simple assembly.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>9018.11-9018.19</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 9018.11 through 9018.19 from any other subheading, including another subheading within that group, except to electro-cardiographs, or patient monitoring systems from printed circuit assemblies when resulting from a simple assembly.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>9018.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 9018.90 from any other subheading, except from either subheading 9001.90 or synthetic rubber of heading 4002, when resulting from a simple assembly; or A change to defibrillators from printed circuit assemblies, except when resulting from a simple assembly.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>9021.19</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 9021.19 from any other subheading, except from either nails of heading 7317 or screws of heading 7318, when resulting from a simple assembly.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>9032.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 9032.90 from any other subheading, except from heading 8537, when resulting from a simple assembly.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>i0(s)</textblock>
    <textblock>i0Section XIX: Chapter 93</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>9301-9304</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 9301 through 9304 from any other heading, including a heading within that group, except a change from heading 9305 when that change is pursuant to GRI 2(a).</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
  </table>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1HTSUS</textblock>
    <textblock>1Tariff shift and/or other requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>i0(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>i0Section VI: Chapters 28 through 38</textblock>
    <textblock>s</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
    <textblock>3102.29</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3102.29 from any other subheading, except from subheading 3102.21 or 3102.30.</textblock>
    <textblock>3102.30</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3102.30 from any other subheading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3102.40</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3102.40 from any other subheading, except from subheading 3102.30.</textblock>
    <textblock>3102.50</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3102.50 from any other subheading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3102.60</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3102.60 from any other subheading, except from subheading 2834.29 or 3102.30.</textblock>
    <textblock>3102.70</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3102.70 from any other subheading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3102.80</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3102.80 from any other subheading, except from subheading 3102.10 or 3102.30.</textblock>
    <textblock>3102.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3102.90 from any other subheading, except from subheading 3102.10 through 3102.80.</textblock>
    <textblock>3103.10-3103.20</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3103.10 through 3103.20 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3103.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3103.90 from any other subheading, except from subheading 3103.10 or 3103.20.</textblock>
    <textblock>3104.10-3104.30</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3104.10 through 3104.30 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3104.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3104.90 from any other subheading, except from subheading 3104.10 through 3104.30.</textblock>
    <textblock>3105.10</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3105.10 from any other chapter.</textblock>
    <textblock>3105.20</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3105.20 from any other heading, except from heading 3102 through 3104.</textblock>
    <textblock>3105.30-3105.40</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3105.30 through 3105.40 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3105.51-3105.59</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3105.51 through 3105.59 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group, except from subheading 3102.10 through 3103.90, or 3105.30 through 3105.40.</textblock>
    <textblock>3105.60</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3105.60 from any other subheading, except from heading 3103 through 3104.</textblock>
    <textblock>3105.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3105.90 from any other chapter, except from subheading 2834.21.</textblock>
    <textblock>3201.10-3202.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3201.10 through 3202.90 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3203</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3203 from any other heading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3204.11-3204.17</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3204.11 through 3204.17 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3204.19</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3204.19 from any other subheading, except from subheading 3204.11 through 3204.17.</textblock>
    <textblock>3204.20-3204.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3204.20 through 3204.90 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3205</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3205 from any other heading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3206.10-3209.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3206.10 through 3209.90 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3210</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3210 from any other heading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3211</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3211 from any other heading, except from subheading 3806.20.</textblock>
    <textblock>3212.10-3212.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3212.10 through 3212.90 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3213</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3213 from any other heading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3214.10-3214.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3214.10 through 3214.90 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group, except from subheading 3823.50.</textblock>
    <textblock>3215</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3215 from any other heading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3301.11-3301.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3301.11 through 3301.90 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3302</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3302 from any other heading, except from heading 2207, 2208, or 3301.</textblock>
    <textblock>3303</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3303 from any other heading, except from subheading 3302.90.</textblock>
    <textblock>3304.10-3307.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3304.10 through 3307.90 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3401</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3401 from any other heading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3402.11-3402.20</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3402.11 through 3402.20 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3402.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3402.90 from any other heading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3403.11-3403.19</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3403.11 through 3403.19 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group, except from heading 2710 or 2712.</textblock>
    <textblock>3403.91-3403.99</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3403.91 through 3403.99 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3404.10-3404.20</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3404.10 through 3404.20 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3404.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3404.90 from any other subheading, except from heading 1521 or subheading 2712.20 or 2712.90.</textblock>
    <textblock>3405.10-3405.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3405.10 through 3405.90 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3406-3407</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3406 through 3407 from any other heading, including any heading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3501.10-3501.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3501.10 through 3501.90 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3502.10</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3502.10 from any other subheading, except from heading 0407.</textblock>
    <textblock>3502.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3502.90 from any other subheading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3503-3504</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3503 through 3504 from any other heading, including any heading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3505.10</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3505.10 from any other subheading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3505.20</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3505.20 from any other subheading, except from heading 1108.</textblock>
    <textblock>3506.10</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3506.10 from any other subheading, except from heading 3503 or subheading 3501.90.</textblock>
    <textblock>3506.91-3506.99</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3506.91 through 3506.99 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3507</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3507 from any other heading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3601-3606</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3601 through 3606 from any other heading, including any heading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3701-3703</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3701 through 3703 from any other heading outside the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3704-3706</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3704 through 3706 from any other heading, including any heading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3707.10-3707.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3707.10 through 3707.90 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3801.10</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3801.10 from any other subheading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3801.20</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3801.20 from any other subheading, except from heading 2504 or subheading 3801.10.</textblock>
    <textblock>3801.30</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3801.30 from any other subheading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3801.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3801.90 from any other subheading, except from heading 2504.</textblock>
    <textblock>3802-3805</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3802 through 3805 from any other heading, including any heading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3806.10-3806.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3806.10 through 3806.90 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3807</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3807 from any other heading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3808.10</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3808.10 from any other subheading, except from subheading 1302.14, 2916.19 or 2917.19.</textblock>
    <textblock>3808.20-3808.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3808.20 through 3808.90 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3809.10</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3809.10 from any other subheading, except from subheading 3505.10.</textblock>
    <textblock>3809.91-3809.99</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3809.91 through 3809.99 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3810-3816</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3810 through 3816 from any other heading, including any heading within the group.</textblock>
    <textblock>3817.10-3817.20</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3817.10 through 3817.20 from any other subheading, including any subheading within the group, except from subheading 2902.90.</textblock>
    <textblock>3818</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3818 from any other heading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3819</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3819 from any other heading, except from heading 2710.</textblock>
    <textblock>3820</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3820 from any other heading, except from subheading 2905.31.</textblock>
    <textblock>3821</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3821 from any other heading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3822</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to heading 3822 from any other heading, except from subheading 3002.10, 3502.90 or heading 3504.</textblock>
    <textblock>3823.10</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3823.10 from any other subheading, except from heading 3505 or subheading 3806.10 or 3806.20, or heading 3903, 3905, 3906, 3909, 3911, or 3913.</textblock>
    <textblock>3823.20</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3823.20 from any other subheading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3823.30</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3823.30 from any other subheading, except from heading 2849.</textblock>
    <textblock>3823.40</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3823.40 from any other subheading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3823.50</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3823.50 from any other subheading, except from subheading 3214.90.</textblock>
    <textblock>3823.60</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3823.60 from any other subheading.</textblock>
    <textblock>3823.90</textblock>
    <textblock>A change to subheading 3823.90 from any other subheading, provided that no more than 60 percent by weight of the goods classified hereunder is attributable to one substance or compound.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣␣ *</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
