<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00040</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Assisted Living Facilities Under Section 232</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>24 CFR Part 232</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. R-94-1695; FR-3374-P-01]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 2502-AF89</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the Assistant Secretary for Housing_Federal Housing Commissioner, HUD.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule proposes to amend the regulations to implement statutory authority to insure assisted living facilities for the care of frail elderly persons, as authorized by section 511 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992. This proposed rule would also expand current regulations to include the refinancing of conventional (non-FHA insured) nursing homes, intermediate care facilities, assisted living facilities or board and care homes under section 223(f) of the National Housing Act, and to insure additions to existing such projects. Finally, this proposed rule would make conforming changes required by the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992, and would make minor technical changes to the regulations to remove ambiguity and reflect long-standing Departmental policy.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments due date: April 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to submit comments regarding this proposed rule to the Rules Docket Clerk, room 10276, Office of General Counsel, Department of Housing and Urban Development, 451 Seventh Street, SW., Washington, DC 20410-0500. Comments should refer to the above docket number and title. A copy of each comment submitted will be available for public inspection and copying between 7:30 a.m. and 5:30 p.m. weekdays at the above address. Facsimile (FAX) comments are not acceptable.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Linda D. Cheatham, Director, Office of Insured Multifamily Housing Development, 451 Seventh Street, SW, Washington, DC 20410-0500, telephone: (202) 708-3000; the telecommunications device for the deaf (TDD) telephone number is (202) 708-4594. (These are not toll-free numbers.)</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Background</textblock>
    <textblock>Currently, under section 232 of the National Housing Act (NHA), and the accompanying regulations at 24 CFR part 232, the Department insures mortgages for nursing homes, intermediate care facilities, and board and care homes. Section 511 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992, Public Law 102-550, approved October 28, 1992 (1992 HCD Act), amends section 232 of the NHA by authorizing FHA mortgage insurance for assisted living facilities. In compliance with section 511 of the 1992 HCD Act, this proposed rule would revise 24 CFR part 232 to make assisted living facilities for the care of the frail elderly eligible for mortgage insurance.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
