<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00056</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Implementation</textblock>
    <textblock>It is important to stress that while conducting this review, the EPA remains committed to implementing the existing O</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>NAAQS in accordance with the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990 (CAAA). During the review, the EPA will continue to work with States to implement emission control strategies required by the CAAA to meet the existing O</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>NAAQS. These efforts include State and Federal actions to reduce emissions of volatile organic compounds and nitrogen oxides, which act as precursors to O</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>formation in the troposphere. The EPA will make every effort to maintain implementation schedules consistent with requirements of the CAAA to ensure continued improvement in air quality.</textblock>
    <textblock>As part of the review, the EPA is examining the ramifications of any changes to the NAAQS on current implementation efforts. If appropriate, new implementation rules and guidelines will be considered for alternative NAAQS. The EPA also is reviewing options to ensure a smooth transition for implementation of any new O</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>NAAQS in the event a decision is made to revise the current O</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>NAAQS.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 40 CFR Part 50</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental protection, Air pollution control, Carbon monoxide, Lead, Nitrogen dioxide, Ozone, Particulate matter, Sulfur oxides.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 27, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Carol M. Browner,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2487 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
