<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00085</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00054</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 223 of the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2273) the Department of Labor herein presents summaries of determinations regarding eligibility to apply for adjustment assistance issued during the period of January, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order for an affirmative determination to be made and a certification of eligibility to apply for adjustment assistance to be issued, each of the group eligibility requirements of section 222 of the Act must be met.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) That a significant number or proportion of the workers in the workers' firm, or an appropriate subdivision thereof, have become totally or partially separated,</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) That sales or production, or both, of the firm or subdivision have decreased absolutely, and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) That increases of imports of articles like or directly competitive with articles produced by the firm or appropriate subdivision have contributed importantly to the separations, or threat thereof, and to the absolute decline in sales or production.</textblock>
    <textblock>Negative Determinations</textblock>
    <textblock>In each of the following cases the investigation revealed that criterion (3) has not been met. A survey of customers indicated that increased imports did not contribute importantly to worker separations at the firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,062; SPS Technologies, Santa Ana, CA</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,182; Fiber Material Inc., Biddeford, ME</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,116; Penick Corp., Newark, NJ</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,104; Electrode Corp., Chardon, OH</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,102; Hansome Energy Systems, Inc., Linden, NJ</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,185; Library Bureau, Inc., Herkimer, NY</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,127; Jefferson Smurfit Corp., Container Div., New Hartford, NY</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,203; Rockwell International's Space Systems Div., Seal Beach, CA</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-28,897; Moore Business Forms, Inc., Salem, OR</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,139; McCabe Group, McCabe Machine Products, Claysburg, PA</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,251; Jefferson City Zinc, Jefferson City, TN</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,221; Paris Sewing, Inc., Paris, TX</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,101; Heintz Corp., Philadelphia, PA</textblock>
    <textblock>In the following cases, the investigation revealed that the criteria for eligibility have not been met for the reasons specified.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,263; Farmland Industries, Inc., Grain Div., Enid, OK</textblock>
    <textblock>The workers' firm does not produce an article as required for certification under section 222 of the Trade Act of 1974.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,106; American Telephone &amp; Telegraph, 9595 Mansfield Rd., Shreveport, LA</textblock>
    <textblock>Sales, production and employment increased in 1992 compared with 1991.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,134; Utopia Spring Water, Houston, TX</textblock>
    <textblock>The investigation revealed that the subject firm, Utopia Spring Water, Houston, TX, was purchased by another domestic firm in the spring of 1993. When support functions were consolidated at an affiliated domestic facility the subject workers were laid off.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,256; Fruehauf Corp., Delphos Parts Plant, Delphos, OH</textblock>
    <textblock>Increased imports did not contribute importantly to worker separations at the firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,006; TRW, Inc., Defense Support Programs, Redondo Beach, CA</textblock>
    <textblock>Predominant reason for layoffs at Spacecraft Technology Div., Defense Support Program, Redondo Beach, CA was a decision by its only customer to delay the schedule and delivery of the satellites produced by the subject firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,201; Essex Specialty Products, Sayreville, NJ</textblock>
    <textblock>Essex Specialty Products, Sayreville, NJ revealed company production and sales of polyurethane and adhesives increased during 1992 compared to 1991 and increased during the first nine months of 1993 compared to the same period of 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,226; DSC Communications Corp., El Paso, TX</textblock>
    <textblock>Increased imports did not contribute importantly to worker separations at the firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,319; Koch Gathering Systems, Inc., Duncan, OK</textblock>
    <textblock>Increased imports did not contribute importantly to worker separations at the firm.</textblock>
    <textblock>TA-W-29,163; Allsteel, Inc., Aurora, IL</textblock>
    <textblock>Corporate decision was made to consolidate operations transferring production from the subject firm to another domestic facility.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Determinations Regarding Eligibility To Apply for Worker Adjustment Assistance</textblock>
  </doctitle>
</doc>
