<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00090</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00056</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with the purposes of sections 29 and 182b. of the Atomic Energy Act (42 U.S.C. 2039, 2232b), the Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards will hold a meeting on February 10-12, 1994, in room P-110, 7920 Norfolk Avenue, Bethesda, Maryland. Notice of this meeting was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 23, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thursday, February 10, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>8:30 a.m.-8:35 a.m.: Opening Remarks by ACRS Chairman</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The ACRS Chairman will make opening remarks regarding conduct of the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>8:35 a.m.-9:05 a.m.: Preparation for Meeting with the NRC Commissioners</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The Committee will discuss matters scheduled for discussion during its meeting with the NRC Commissioners.</textblock>
    <textblock>9:30 a.m.-11 a.m.: Meeting with the NRC Commissioners</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The Committee will meet with the NRC Commissioners at One White Flint North, 11555 Rockville Pike, Rockville, Maryland, to discuss matters of mutual interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>12:45 p.m.-2:15 p.m.: Advanced Light-Water Reactor Policy Issue_Source Term</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The Committee will review and comment on a draft Commission paper related to the source term to be used for Advanced Light-Water Reactors. Representatives of the NRC staff will participate.</textblock>
    <textblock>2:15 p.m.-3:45 p.m.: Protection Against Malevolent Use of Vehicles at Nuclear Power Plants</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open/Closed)_The Committee will review and comment on the proposed final rule on Protection Against Malevolent Use of Vehicles at Nuclear Power Plants, including comments by NUMARC and the associated NRC staff resolution. Representatives of the NRC staff and NUMARC will participate.</textblock>
    <textblock>A portion of this session may be closed to discuss safeguards and security information.</textblock>
    <textblock>4 p.m.-5 p.m._Proposed NRC Staff Plan to Implement the Recommendations of the PRA Working Group and the Regulatory Review Group</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The Committee will review and comment on the proposed NRC staff plan to implement the recommendations of the PRA Working Group and the PRA-related recommendations of the Regulatory Review Group. Representatives of the NRC staff will participate. Representatives of the industry will participate, as appropriate.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards; Meeting Agenda</textblock>
  </doctitle>
</doc>
