<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00069</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00043</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Current List of Laboratories Which Meet Minimum Standards To Engage in Urine Drug Testing for Federal Agencies and Laboratories That Have Withdrawn From the Program</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, HHS, (Formerly: National Institute on Drug Abuse, ADAMHA, HHS).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Health and Human Services notifies Federal agencies of the laboratories currently certified to meet standards of Subpart C of Mandatory Guidelines for Federal Workplace Drug Testing Programs (53 FR 11979, 11986). A similar notice listing all currently certified laboratories will be published during the first week of each month, and updated to include laboratories which subsequently apply for and complete the certification process. If any listed laboratory's certification is totally suspended or revoked, the laboratory will be omitted from updated lists until such time as it is restored to full certification under the Guidelines.</textblock>
    <textblock>If any laboratory has withdrawn from the National Laboratory Certification Program during the past month, it will be identified as such at the end of the current list of certified laboratories, and will be omitted from the monthly listing thereafter.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mrs. Giselle Hersh, Division of Workplace Programs, Room 13-A-54, 5600 Fishers Lane, Rockville, Maryland 20857; Tel.: (301) 443-6014.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mandatory Guidelines for Federal Workplace Drug Testing were developed in accordance with Executive Order 12564 and section 503 of Public Law 100-71. Subpart C of the Guidelines, ``Certification of Laboratories Engaged in Urine Drug Testing for Federal Agencies,'' sets strict standards which laboratories must meet in order to conduct urine drug testing for Federal agencies. To become certified an applicant laboratory must undergo three rounds of performance testing plus an on-site inspection. To maintain that certification a laboratory must participate in an every-other-month performance testing program plus periodic, on-site inspections.</textblock>
    <textblock>Laboratories which claim to be in the applicant stage of certification are not to be considered as meeting the minimum requirements expressed in the HHS Guidelines. A laboratory must have its letter of certification from SAMHSA, HHS (formerly: HHS/NIDA) which attests that it has met minimum standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with Subpart C of the Guidelines, the following laboratories meet the minimum standards set forth in the Guidelines:</textblock>
    <textblock>Aegis Analytical Laboratories, Inc., 624 Grassmere Park Road, Suite 21, Nashville, TN 37211, 615-331-5300</textblock>
    <textblock>Alabama Reference Laboratories, Inc., 543 South Hull Street, Montgomery, AL 36103, 800-541-4931/205-263-5745</textblock>
    <textblock>Allied Clinical Laboratories, 201 Plaza Boulevard, Hurst, TX 76053, 817-282-2257</textblock>
    <textblock>American Medical Laboratories, Inc., 14225 Newbrook Drive, Chantilly, VA 22021, 703-802-6900</textblock>
    <textblock>Associated Pathologists Laboratories, Inc., 4230 South Burnham Avenue, Suite 250, Las Vegas, NV 89119-5412, 702-733-7866</textblock>
    <textblock>Associated Regional and University Pathologists, Inc. (ARUP), 500 Chipeta Way, Salt Lake City, UT 84108, 801-583-2787</textblock>
    <textblock>Baptist Medical Center_Toxicology Laboratory, 9601 I-630, Exit 7, Little Rock, AR 72205-7299, 501-227-2783</textblock>
    <textblock>(formerly: Forensic Toxicology Laboratory Baptist Medical Center)</textblock>
    <textblock>Bayshore Clinical Laboratory, 4555 W. Schroeder Drive, Brown Deer, WI 53223, 414-355-4444/800-877-7016</textblock>
    <textblock>Bioran Medical Laboratory, 415 Massachusetts Avenue, Cambridge, MA 02139, 617-547-8900</textblock>
    <textblock>Cedars Medical Center, Department of Pathology, 1400 Northwest 12th Avenue, Miami, FL 33136, 305-325-5810</textblock>
    <textblock>Centinela Hospital Airport Toxicology Laboratory, 9601 S. Sepulveda Blvd., Los Angeles, CA 90045, 310-215-6020</textblock>
    <textblock>Clinical Reference Lab, 11850 West 85th Street, Lenexa, KS 66214, 800-445-6917</textblock>
    <textblock>CompuChem Laboratories, Inc., A Subsidiary of Roche Biomedical Laboratory, 3308 Chapel Hill/Nelson Hwy., Research Triangle Park, NC 27709, 919-549-8263/800-833-3984</textblock>
    <textblock>CompuChem Laboratories, Special Division, 3308 Chapel Hill/Nelson Hwy., Research Triangle Park, NC 27709, 919-549-8263</textblock>
    <textblock>Cox Medical Centers, Department of Toxicology, 1423 North Jefferson Avenue, Springfield, MO 65802, 800-876-3652/417-836-3093</textblock>
    <textblock>CPF MetPath Laboratories, 21007 Southgate Park Boulevard, Cleveland, OH 44137-3054, (Outside OH) 800-338-0166/(Inside OH) 800-362-8913 (formerly Southgate Medical Laboratory; Southgate Medical Services, Inc.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Damon/MetPath, 140 East Ryan Road, Oak Creek, WI 53154, 800-638-1100 (formerly: Damon Clinical Laboratories; Chem-Bio Corporation; CBC Clinilab)</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
