<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00078</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00049</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with Departmental policy, 28 CFR 50.7, notice is hereby given that a proposed modification to a consent decree in</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>City of Wheelwright, Kentucky and the Commonwealth of Kentucky,</textblock>
    <textblock>Civil Action No. 88-436, was lodged on December 30, 1993 with the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Kentucky. The proposed modification will make changes to Section III of the decree (Remedial Actions) by modifying the schedule of construction of an agreed upon new waste water treatment facility for the City, and add a new penalty to be paid by the City in the amount of $4,000 to cover violations of the decree from entry of the decree to the entry of the proposed modification.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Justice will receive, for a period of thirty (30) days from the date of this publication, comments relating to the proposed modification to the consent decree. Comments should be addressed to the Assistant Attorney General for the Environment and Natural Resources Division, Department of Justice, Washington, DC 20530, and should refer to</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>City of Wheelwright and the Commonwealth of Kentucky,</textblock>
    <textblock>DOJ Ref.</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>90-5-1-1-2946A. The proposed consent decree and entered consent decree may be examined at the office of the United States Attorney, 110 W. Vine St., suite 400, Lexington 40507; the Region IV Office of the Environmental Protection Agency, 345 Courtland Street, NE., Atlanta Georgia 30365; and at the Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., 4th Floor, Washington, DC 2005, (202) 624-0892. A copy of the proposed modification and the filed consent decree may be obtained in person or by mail from the Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., 4th Floor, Washington, DC 20005. In requesting a copy please refer to the referenced case and enclose a check in the amount of $7.00 (25 cents per page reproduction costs), payable to the Consent Decree Library.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Lodging of Consent Decree Pursuant to the Clean Water Act, 33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John C. Cruden,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Environmental Enforcement Section, Environment and Natural Resources Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2362 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
