<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00043</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Determination of Noncompetitive Financial Assistance; National Council on Radiation Protection and Measurements</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Energy.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of intent.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>DOE announces that pursuant to 10 CFR 600.7(b)(2)(i)(G), it intends to award a grant in the amount of $50,000 to the National Council on Radiation Protection and Measurements (NCRP) in support of scientific evaluation work in operational radiation protection, radionuclides in the environment, guidance on occupational and public exposure resulting from diagnostic nuclear medicine procedures, and practical guidance on the evaluation of human exposures to radiofrequency radiation. Pursuant to Public law 88-376, the NCRP was chartered to collect, analyze, develop, and disseminate in the public interest information and recommendations pertaining to radiation protection. The NCRP's cooperation with national and international organizations, governmental and private, ensures that the recommendations provided incorporate the latest scientific information for the protection of radiation workers and members of the general public. Under this grant award, the NCRP seeks to provide guidance and recommendations that will minimize human exposure and, thus, reduce health effects of radiation. Eligibility for this award is therefore restricted to NCRP.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>Fran Kimball, Office of Health Physics, and Industrial Hygiene, U.S. Department of Energy, Washington, DC 20585, 301-903-4691.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Oak Ridge, Tennessee on December 13, 1993.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Peter D. Dayton,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>HCA Designee, Oak Ridge Operations Office.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2446 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
