<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00077</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00048</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that a proposed Settlement and Stipulated Order in</textblock>
    <textblock>In re: Leaseway Transportation Corp., Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>No. 92 B 22373 (HS) (Bankr. S.D.N.Y.) was lodged on January 12, 1994, with the Bankruptcy Court for the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York. The proposed Settlement requires the debtor Anchor Motor Freight, Inc. (``Anchor''), as the subject of a claim filed under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (``CERCLA''), 42 U.S.C. 9601,</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>, to reimburse the United States $17,500.00 for certain costs incurred by the United States in connection with the Laskin/Polar Oil Superfund Site (the ``Laskin Site''), located in Jefferson, Ohio.</textblock>
    <textblock>Six prior consent decrees have been entered in connection with the Laskin Site. Through entry of the 1989 consent decree in</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Alvin F. Laskin, et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>, CA No. 84-2035Y (N.D. Ohio), defendants paid the United States $1.47 million as partial reimbursement for certain past costs. In 1990, the United States entered into a Remedial Design/Remedial Action consent decree with certain defendants in</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Alvin Laskin, et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>, CA No. 4:90CV0483 (N.D. Ohio), wherein 27 defendants became obligated to conduct the remedial action at the Laskin Site and pay, along with 131</textblock>
    <textblock>de minimis</textblock>
    <textblock>defendants, certain future oversight costs and approximately $1.38 million as partial reimbursement of additional United States' past costs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Through entry on August 27, 1993, of three consent decrees in</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Anchor Motor Freight</textblock>
    <textblock>, CA No. 4: 89CV1999 (N.D. Ohio), ten defendants paid the United States approximately $2.7 million as partial reimbursement for certain costs. Through entry on November 16, 1993, of the sixth consent decree for this site, five defendants in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Anchor Motor Freight</textblock>
    <textblock>case paid the United States approximately $1.4 million as partial reimbursement for certain costs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Anchor did not sign the first decree entered in connection with the Laskin/Poplar Oil Site, nor any of the consent decrees entered in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Anchor Motor Freight</textblock>
    <textblock>case. The proposed Settlement reimburses the United States for certain money expended but not reimbursed through entry of any consent decree for the Laskin/Poplar Oil site.</textblock>
    <textblock>For a period of thirty (30) days from the date of this publication, the Department of Justice will receive comments relating to the proposed consent decree. Comments should be addressed to the Assistant Attorney General, Environment and Natural Resources Division, Department of Justice, Washington, DC., 20530, and should refer to</textblock>
    <textblock>In re: Leaseway Transportation Corp., Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>and DOJ Ref. No. 90-11-3-38C.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed Settlement may be examined at the office of the United States Attorney, 100 Church Street, 19th Floor, New York, New York 10007; the Region 5 Office of U.S. EPA, 77 West Jackson Blvd., Chicago, Illinois, 60604-3590; and at the Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., Washington, DC 20005, (202) 624-0892. Copies of the proposed consent decree may be obtained in person or by mail from the Consent Decree Library. In requesting a copy of a consent decree, please identify which consent decree is sought and enclose a check in the amount of $4.25 for the consent decree (25 cents per page reproduction costs) payable to ``Consent Decree Library.''</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Lodging of Settlement and Stipulated Order Pursuant to the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John C. Cruden,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Environmental Enforcement Section, Environment and Natural Resources Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2363 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
