<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00004</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 553, it is also found and determined upon good cause that it is impracticable, unnecessary, and contrary to the public interest to give preliminary notice prior to putting this rule into effect and that good cause exists for not postponing the effective date of this action until 30 days after publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>because: (1) The Committees need to have sufficient funds to pay their expenses which are incurred on a continuous basis; (2) the 1994-95 fiscal year begins on April 1, 1994, and the marketing orders require that the rate of assessment for the fiscal year apply to all assessable limes and avocados handled during the fiscal year; (3) handlers are aware of this action which was recommended by the Committees at public meetings; and (4) this interim final rule provides a 30-day comment period, and all comments timely received will be considered prior to finalization of this action.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects</textblock>
    <textblock>7 CFR Part 911</textblock>
    <textblock>Limes, Marketing agreements, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>7 CFR Part 915</textblock>
    <textblock>Avocados, Marketing agreements, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set forth in the preamble, 7 CFR Parts 911 and 915 are amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for both 7 CFR parts 911 and 915 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>7 U.S.C. 601-674.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>These sections will not appear in the Code of Federal Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 911_LIMES GROWN IN FLORIDA</textblock>
    <textblock>2. A new ยง911.232 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง911.232</textblock>
    <textblock>Expenses and Assessment rate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Expenses of $89,697 by the Florida Lime Administrative Committee are authorized, and an assessment rate of $0.16 per bushel of assessable limes is established for the 1994-95 fiscal year ending on March 31, 1995. Unexpended funds may be carried over as a reserve.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 915_AVOCADOS GROWN IN SOUTH FLORIDA</textblock>
    <textblock>3. A new ยง915.232 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง915.232</textblock>
    <textblock>Expenses and Assessment rate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Expenses of $97,000 by the Avocado Administrative Committee are authorized, and an assessment rate of $0.16 per bushel of assessable avocados is established for the 1994-95 fiscal year ending on March 31, 1995. Unexpended funds may be carried over as a reserve.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Robert C. Keeney,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Director, Fruit and Vegetable Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2418 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
