<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00087</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-2-00055</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Documents Containing Reporting or Recordkeeping Requirements: Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of the OMB review of information collection.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The NRC has recently submitted to the OMB for review the following proposal for the collection of information under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. chapter 35).</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Type of submission, new, revision, or extension: Revision.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The title of the information collection: Reactor Operator and Senior Reactor Operator Licensing Training and Requalification Programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The form number if applicable: N/A.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. How often the collection is required: Upon request by the NRC.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Who will be required or asked to report: Power and non-power reactor licensees.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. An estimate of the number of annual responses: 8 for power reactors and 4 for non-power reactors.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. An estimate of the total number of hours needed to complete the requirement or request: 32 hours annually for power reactors (approximately 4 hours per response) and 2 hours annually for non-power reactors (approximately 0.5 hours per response). There is an overall reduction of 358 hours (3.3 hours per licensee) because licensees will no longer submit material for NRC preparation of requalification examinations.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. An indication of whether section 3504(h), Public Law 96-511 applies: Not applicable.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Abstract: The Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) is amending its regulations at 10 CFR part 55 to: (1) Delete the prerequisite for license renewal that each licensed operator pass a comprehensive requalification written examination and an operating test conducted by the NRC during the term of the operator's 6-year license, (2) require facility licensees to submit upon request copies of each annual operating test or comprehensive written examination used for operator requalification to the NRC for review, and (3) amend the ``Scope'' provisions of the regulations pertaining to operators' licenses to include facility licensees. This information is needed to monitor licensed operator performance and to support the Commission's inspection program. It is concluded that these amendments will result in a substantial increase in the overall protection of public health and safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the submittal may be inspected or obtained for a fee from the NRC Public Document Room, 2120 L Street, NW. (Lower Level), Washington, DC 20555.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments and questions should be directed to the OMB reviewer: Troy Hillier, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, (3150-0018 and 3150-0101), NEOB-3019, Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503.</textblock>
  </summary>
</doc>
