<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00012</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00003</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Federal Reserve System</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Thrift Supervision</textblock>
    <textblock>Community Reinvestment Act Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>AGENCIES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, Treasury (OCC); Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Board); Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC); Office of Thrift Supervision, Treasury (OTS).</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of the Comptroller of the Currency</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>12 CFR Part 25</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93-19]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1557-AB32</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>12 CFR Part 228</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. R-0822]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>12 CFR Part 345</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 3064-AB27</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>12 CFR Part 563e</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93-234]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1550-AA69</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Joint notice of proposed rulemaking; extension of comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Office of Thrift Supervision (the Federal financial supervisory agencies) are extending the comment period until March 24, 1994, for their joint notice of proposed rulemaking regarding their regulations concerning the Community Reinvestment Act (CRA) published on December 21, 1993.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received by March 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>OCC:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be directed to: Communications Division, Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, 250 E Street, SW., Washington, DC 20219, Attention: Docket No. 93-19. Comments will be available for public inspection and photocopying at the same location.</textblock>
    <textblock>BOARD:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be directed to: William W. Wiles, Secretary, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, Docket No. R-0822, 20th Street and Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20551. Comments addressed to Mr. Wiles may also be delivered to Room B-2222 of the Eccles Building between 8:45 a.m. and 5:15 p.m. weekdays, or to the guard station in the Eccles Building courtyard on 20th Street, NW. (between Constitution Avenue and C Street) at any time. Comments may be inspected in Room MP-500 of the Martin Building between 9 a.m. and 5 p.m. weekdays, except as provided in 12 CFR 261.8 of the Board's rules regarding the availability of information.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDIC:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be directed to: Robert E. Feldman, Acting Executive Secretary, FDIC, 550 17th Street, NW., Washington, DC 20429. They may be hand delivered to room 402, 1776 F Street, NW., Washington, DC between 8:30 a.m. and 4:30 p.m. on business days. They may be sent by facsimile transmission to (202) 898-3838. Comments will be available for public inspection at the FDIC Reading Room</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>7118 at 550 17th Street, NW., Washington, DC between 9 a.m. and 4:30 p.m. on business days.</textblock>
    <textblock>OTS:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be directed to: Director, Information Services Division, Public Affairs, Office of Thrift Supervision, 1700 G Street, NW., Washington, DC 20552, Attention: Docket No. 93-234. These submissions may be hand delivered to 1700 G Street, NW. from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. on business days; they may be sent by facsimile transmission to FAX number (202) 906-7755. Submissions must be received by 5 p.m. on the day they are due in order to be considered by the OTS. Late-filed, misaddressed, or misidentified submissions will not be considered in this rulemaking. Comments will be available for public inspection at 1700 G Street, NW., from 1 p.m. until 4 p.m. on business days. Visitors will be escorted to and from the Public Reading Room at established intervals.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>OCC:</textblock>
    <textblock>Stephen M. Cross, Deputy Comptroller for Compliance, (202) 874-5216; Matthew Roberts, Special Counsel, Chief Counsel's Office, (202) 874-5200.</textblock>
    <textblock>BOARD:</textblock>
    <textblock>Glenn E. Loney, Associate Director, Division of Consumer and Community Affairs, (202) 452-3585; Scott G. Alvarez, Associate General Counsel, Legal Division, (202) 452-3583; Leonard N. Chanin, Managing Counsel, Division of Consumer and Community Affairs, (202) 452-3667.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDIC:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bobbie Jean Norris, Deputy Director, Office of Consumer Affairs, (202) 898-6760; Valerie Thomas, Review Examiner (Compliance), Division of Supervision, (202) 898-7155; Ann Loikow, Counsel, (202) 898-3796; Sandy Comenetz, Counsel, (202) 898-3582, Regulation and Legislation Section, Legal Division.</textblock>
    <textblock>OTS:</textblock>
    <textblock>Timothy R. Burniston, Deputy Assistant Director for Policy, (202) 906-5629; Theresa A. Stark, Program Analyst, Specialized Programs, (202) 906-7054; Lewis A. Segall, Senior Attorney, Legal Policy Division, Chief Counsel's Office, (202) 906-6648.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The joint notice of proposed rulemaking was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 21, 1993 (58 FR 67466), and comments were to be received by February 22, 1994. The new deadline for submission of comments is March 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
