<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00048</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-0-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>For the reasons set out in the preamble, 38 CFR part 3 is amended as set forth below:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 3_ADJUDICATION</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart A_Pension, Compensation, and Dependency and Indemnity Compensation</textblock>
    <textblock>The authority citation for part 3, subpart A, continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>38 U.S.C. 501(a), unless otherwise noted.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. In §3.307, the heading and paragraph (a)(6) are revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§3.307</textblock>
    <textblock>Presumptive service connection for chronic, tropical or prisoner-of-war related disease, or disease associated with exposure to certain herbicide agents; wartime and service on or after January 1, 1947.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)␣*␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(6)</textblock>
    <textblock>Diseases associated with exposure to certain herbicide agents.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) For the purposes of this section, the term ``herbicide agent'' means a chemical in an herbicide used in support of the United States and allied military operations in the Republic of Vietnam during the Vietnam era, specifically: 2,4-D; 2,4,5-T and its contaminant TCDD; cacodylic acid; and picloram.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The diseases listed at §3.309(e) shall have become manifest to a degree of 10 percent or more at any time after service, except that chloracne or other acneform disease consistent with chloracne and porphyria cutanea tarda shall have become manifest to a degree of 10 percent or more within a year after the last date on which the veteran was exposed to an herbicide agent during active military, naval, or air service.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) A veteran who, during active military, naval, or air service, served in the Republic of Vietnam during the Vietnam era and has a disease listed at §3.309(e) shall be presumed to have been exposed during such service to an herbicide agent, unless there is affirmative evidence to establish that the veteran was not exposed to any such agent during that service. The last date on which such a veteran shall be presumed to have been exposed to an herbicide agent shall be the last date on which he or she served in the Republic of Vietnam during the Vietnam era. ``Service in the Republic of Vietnam'' includes service in the waters offshore and service in other locations if the conditions of service involved duty or visitation in the Republic of Vietnam.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>§3.307</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>3. In §3.307(a), the first sentence of the introductory text, remove the words ``a disease associated with service in the Republic of Vietnam'' and insert, in their place, the words ``a disease associated with exposure to certain herbicide agents''.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. In §3.309, paragraph (e) is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§3.309</textblock>
    <textblock>Disease subject to presumptive service connection.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Disease associated with exposure to certain herbicide agents.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a veteran was exposed to an herbicide agent during active military, naval, or air service, the following diseases shall be service-connected if the requirements of §3.307(a)(6) are met even though there is no record of such disease during service, provided further that the rebuttable presumption provisions of §3.307(d) are also satisfied.</textblock>
    <textblock>Chloracne or other acneform disease consistent with chloracne</textblock>
    <textblock>Hodgkin's disease</textblock>
    <textblock>Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma</textblock>
    <textblock>Porphyria cutanea tarda</textblock>
    <textblock>Soft-tissue sarcoma (other than osteosarcoma, chondrosarcoma, Kaposi's sarcoma, or mesothelioma)</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>The term ``soft-tissue sarcoma'' includes the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>Adult fibrosarcoma</textblock>
    <textblock>Dermatofibrosarcoma protuberans</textblock>
    <textblock>Malignant fibrous histiocytoma</textblock>
    <textblock>Liposarcoma</textblock>
    <textblock>Leiomyosarcoma</textblock>
    <textblock>Epithelioid leiomyosarcoma (malignant leiomyoblastoma)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rhabdomyosarcoma</textblock>
    <textblock>Ectomesenchymoma</textblock>
    <textblock>Angiosarcoma (hemangiosarcoma and lymphangiosarcoma)</textblock>
    <textblock>Proliferating (systemic) angioendotheliomatosis</textblock>
    <textblock>Malignant glomus tumor</textblock>
    <textblock>Malignant hemangiopericytoma</textblock>
    <textblock>Synovial sarcoma (malignant synovioma)</textblock>
    <textblock>Malignant giant cell tumor of tendon sheath</textblock>
    <textblock>Malignant schwannoma, including malignant schwannoma with rhabdomyoblastic differentiation (malignant Triton tumor), glandular and epithelioid malignant schwannomas</textblock>
    <textblock>Malignant mesenchymoma</textblock>
    <textblock>Malignant granular cell tumor</textblock>
    <textblock>Alveolar soft part sarcoma</textblock>
    <textblock>Epithelioid sarcoma</textblock>
    <textblock>Clear cell sarcoma of tendons and aponeuroses</textblock>
    <textblock>Extraskeletal Ewing's sarcoma</textblock>
    <textblock>Congenital and infantile fibrosarcoma</textblock>
    <textblock>Malignant ganglioneuroma</textblock>
    <textblock>§3.311a</textblock>
    <textblock>[Removed]</textblock>
    <textblock>§3.311b</textblock>
    <textblock>[Redesignated as §3.311]</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Section 3.311a is removed and §3.311b is redesignated as §3.311.</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2403 Filed 2-2-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8320-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
