<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00018</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940203-1-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Charges and Fees for Hydroelectric Projects</textblock>
    <textblock>January 26, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>18 CFR Parts 11 and 381</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. RM93-7-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of proposed rulemaking.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (Commission) is inviting comments on whether it should revise its regulations governing the assessment of annual charges for the administration of Part I of the Federal Power Act and if so, what changes might be appropriate. One alternative that the Commission is considering is to allocate the annual charges for administrative costs among a single class of licensees and exemptees, based on the respective capacity of each hydropower project as measured in kilowatts, with a minimum and maximum charge, and with the assessments to commence at the same time as the commencement of project construction. To ameliorate the potential impact on licensees and exemptees, this alternative would include a transition period of several years for phasing-in the changes. Other alternatives would include, but would not be limited to, retention of the current distinction between municipal and non-municipal licensees including retention of the different formulae by which their respective annual charges are allocated.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments are due on or before April 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>An original and 14 copies of written comments must be filed. All filings should refer to Docket No. RM93-7-000 and should be addressed to: Office of the Secretary, Federal Energy Regulatory Commission,</textblock>
    <textblock>825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Barry Smoler, Office of the General Counsel, Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20426, (202) 208-1269.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to publishing the full text of this document in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, the Commission also provides all interested persons an opportunity to inspect or copy the contents of this document during normal business hours in room 3104, 941 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission Issuance Posting System (CIPS), an electronic bulletin board service, provides access to the texts of formal documents issued by the Commission. CIPS is available at no charge to the user and may be accessed using a personal computer with a modem by dialing (202) 208-1379. To access CIPS, set your communications software to use 300, 1200, or 2400 bps, full duplex, no parity, 8 data bits, and 1 stop bit. CIPS can also be accessed at 9600 bps by dialing (202) 208-1781. The full text of this rule will be available on CIPS for 30 days from the date of issuance. The complete text on diskette in Wordperfect format may also be purchased from the Commission's copy contractor, La Dorn Systems Corporation, located in room 3104, 941 North Capitol Street NE., Washington, DC 20426.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Introduction</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (Commission) invites comments on whether it should revise its regulations governing the assessment of annual charges for the administration of Part I of the Federal Power Act (FPA),</textblock>
    <textblock>and if so, what changes might be appropriate. One alternative that the Commission is considering is to allocate the annual charges for administrative costs among a single class of licensees and exemptees, based on the respective capacity of each hydropower project as measured in kilowatts, with a minimum and maximum charge, and with the assessments to commence at the same time as the commencement of project construction. To ameliorate the potential impact on licensees and exemptees, this alternative would include a transition period of several years for phasing-in the changes. Other alternatives would include, but would not be limited to, retention of the current distinction between municipal and non-municipal licensees including retention of the different formulae by which their respective annual charges are allocated.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 792-823b.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
