<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00102</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00058</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Fresh Cut Roses From Colombia and Ecuador</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>INTERNATIONAL TRADE COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Investigations Nos. 731-TA-684-685 (Preliminary)]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>International Trade Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Institution and scheduling of preliminary antidumping investigations.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission hereby gives notice of the institution of preliminary antidumping investigations Nos. 731-TA-684-685 (Preliminary) under section 733(a) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (19 U.S.C. 1673b(a)) to determine whether there is a reasonable indication that an industry in the United States is materially injured, or is threatened with material injury, or the establishment of an industry in the United States is materially retarded, by reason of imports from Colombia and Ecuador of fresh cut roses, provided for in subheading 0603.10.60 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, that are alleged to be sold in the United States at less than fair value. The Commission must complete preliminary antidumping investigations in 45 days, or in this case by March 31, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>For further information concerning the conduct of these investigations and rules of general application, consult the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure, part 201, subparts A through E (19 CFR part 201), and part 207, subparts A and B (19 CFR part 207).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Valerie Newkirk (202-205-3190), Office of Investigations, U.S. International Trade Commission, 500 E Street SW., Washington, DC 20436. Hearing-impaired persons can obtain information on this matter by contacting the Commission's TDD terminal on 202-205-1810. Persons with mobility impairments who will need special assistance in gaining access to the Commission should contact the Office of the Secretary at 202-205-2000.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>These investigations are being instituted in response to a petition filed on February 14, 1994, by the Floral Trade Council, Haslett, MI.</textblock>
    <textblock>Participation in the Investigations and Public Service List</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons (other than petitioners) wishing to participate in the investigations as parties must file an entry of appearance with the Secretary to the Commission, as provided in §§201.11 and 207.10 of the Commission's rules, not later than seven (7) days after publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. The Secretary will prepare a public service list containing the names and addresses of all persons, or their representatives, who are parties to these investigations upon the expiration of the period for filing entries of appearance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Limited Disclosure of Business Proprietary Information (BPI) Under an Administrative Protective Order (APO) and BPI Service List</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to §207.7(a) of the Commission's rules, the Secretary will make BPI gathered in these preliminary investigations available to authorized applicants under the APO issued in the investigations, provided that the application is made not later than seven (7) days after the publication of this notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. A separate service list will be maintained by the Secretary for those parties authorized to receive BPI under the APO.</textblock>
    <textblock>Conference</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission's Director of Operations has scheduled a conference in connection with these investigations for 9:30 a.m. on March 8, 1994, at the U.S. International Trade Commission Building, 500 E Street SW., Washington, DC. Parties wishing to participate in the conference should contact Valerie Newkirk (202-205-3190) not later than March 2, 1994, to arrange for their appearance. Parties in support of the imposition of antidumping duties in these investigations and parties in opposition to the imposition of such duties will each be collectively allocated one hour within which to make an oral presentation at the conference. A nonparty who has testimony that may aid the Commission's deliberations may request permission to present a short statement at the conference.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written Submissions</textblock>
    <textblock>As provided in §§201.8 and 207.15 of the Commission's rules, any person may submit to the Commission on or before March 11, 1994, a written brief containing information and arguments pertinent to the subject matter of the investigations. Parties may file written testimony in connection with their presentation at the conference no later than three (3) days before the conference. If briefs or written testimony contain BPI, they must conform with the requirements of §§201.6, 207.3, and 207.7 of the Commission's rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with §§201.16(c) and 207.3 of the rules, each document filed by a party to the investigations must be served on all other parties to the investigations (as identified by either the public or BPI service list), and a certificate of service must be timely filed. The Secretary will not accept a document for filing without a certificate of service.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority</textblock>
    <textblock>These investigations are being conducted under authority of the Tariff Act of 1930, title VII. This notice is published pursuant to section 207.12 of the Commission's rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued: February 17, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By order of the Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna R. Koehnke,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4112 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7020-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
