<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00089</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00047</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The National Center for Environmental Health (NCEH) of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) announces the following meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorionic Villus Sampling (CVS) Meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Time and Date:</textblock>
    <textblock>8:30 a.m.-5 p.m., Friday, March 11, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>CDC, Auditorium A, 1600 Clifton Road, NE., Atlanta, Georgia 30333.</textblock>
    <textblock>Status:</textblock>
    <textblock>Open to public for observation and comment, limited only by space available.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose:</textblock>
    <textblock>CVS is an obstetrical diagnostic procedure done prenatally to detect genetic abnormalities. The safety of the procedure has been questioned since infants have been reported with birth defects (limb deficiency) after their mothers had undergone CVS. Studies have been published which both support and contradict the hypothesis that CVS has caused birth defects. CDC has recently completed a multistate study investigating the association between limb deficiency and CVS. CDC will convene this public meeting to discuss all recent studies of this issue and to receive advice from individual participants on establishing public health recommendations for CVS utilization.</textblock>
    <textblock>Matters to Be Discussed:</textblock>
    <textblock>An invited group of qualified individuals will be asked to provide comments on recent studies of limb deficiency after CVS. The risk for these birth defects will be discussed in the context of other risks, benefits, and alternatives of the procedure. A written commentary from CDC which provides recommendations for CVS utilization will also be discussed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contact Person for More Information:</textblock>
    <textblock>J. David Erickson, D.D.S., Ph.D., Chief, Birth Defects and Genetic Diseases Branch, Division of Birth Defects and Developmental Disabilities, NCEH, CDC, Mailstop F-45, 4770 Buford Highway, NE, Atlanta, Georgia 30341-3724, telephone 404/488-7160.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 17, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Chorionic Villus Sampling Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Elvin Hilyer,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Director for Policy Coordination, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4124 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4163-18-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
