<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00066</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Kentucky Permanent Regulatory Program; Bond Forfeiture, Definitions, and Inspection Frequency</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>30 CFR Part 917</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement (OSM), Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule; approval of amendment.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>OSM is announcing the approval of proposed program amendments to the Kentucky permanent regulatory program (hereinafter referred to as the Kentucky program) under the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (SMCRA). The proposed amendments include revisions to those portions of the Kentucky Administrative Regulations dealing with bond forfeiture funds, definitions of terms, and inspection frequency.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>William J. Kovacic, Director, Lexington Field Office, Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement, 2675 Regency Road, Lexington Kentucky 40503, Telephone (606) 233-2896.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Background on the Kentucky Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Submission of Amendment.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Director's Findings.</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Summary and Disposition of Comments.</textblock>
    <textblock>V. Director's Decision.</textblock>
    <textblock>VI. Procedural Determinations.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Background on the Kentucky Program</textblock>
    <textblock>On May 18, 1982, the Secretary of the Interior conditionally approved the Kentucky program. Information pertinent to the general background, revisions, modifications, and amendments to the proposed permanent program submission, as well as the Secretary's findings, the disposition of comments and a detailed explanation of the conditions of approval can be found in the May 18, 1982, Federal Register (47 FR 21404-21435). Subsequent actions concerning the conditions of approval and program amendments are identified at 30 CFR 917.11, 917.13, 917.15, 917.16, and 917.17.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Submission of Amendments</textblock>
    <textblock>By letter dated May 21, 1993, (Administrative Record No. KY-1221) Kentucky submitted proposed amendments containing additions and modifications to 405 KAR 10:050 Bond forfeiture, 405 KAR 12:001 Definitions, and 405 FAR 12:010 General provisions for inspection and enforcement.</textblock>
    <textblock>OSM announced receipt of the proposed amendments in the June 11, 1993,</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 32618), and in the same notice, opened the public comment period and provided opportunity for a public hearing on the adequacy of the proposed amendments. The comment period closed on July 12, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>On June 14, 1993 (Administrative Record No. KY-1226), Kentucky revised the proposed amendment at 405 KAR 12:001 by adding a definition of the term ``unwarranted failure to comply'', since that term is used in 405 KAR 12:020 section 8. The proposed definition is identical to the existing definition set forth in 405 KAR 7:001. Since the definition already exists as part of Kentucky's approved program, the Director determined that no purpose would be served by reopening the public comment period for the modification submitted by Kentucky on June 14, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>By letter dated October 19, 1993 (Administrative Record No. KY-1242), Kentucky submitted a proposed program amendment which was intended to replace the proposals submitted on May 21, 1993, and June 14, 1993. The regulations contained in the October 19, 1993, submission completed the Kentucky promulgation process under Kentucky Revised Statue Chapter 13A.</textblock>
    <textblock>OSM announced receipt of the October 19, 1993 proposed amendment in the November 5, 1993,</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 58997), and in the same notice, reopened the public comment period and provided opportunity for a public hearing on the adequacy of the proposed amendment. The comment period closed on November 22, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Director's Findings</textblock>
    <textblock>Set forth below, pursuant to SMCRA and the Federal regulations at 30 CFR 732.15 and 732.17 are the Director's findings concerning the proposed amendments to the Kentucky program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Revisions not specifically discussed below concern nonsubstantive wording changes, or revised cross-references and paragraph notations to reflect organizational changes resulting from this amendment.</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Revisions to Kentucky's Regulations That Are Substantively Identical to the Corresponding Federal Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>Because the above proposed revision is identical in meaning to the corresponding Federal regulation, the Director finds that Kentucky's proposed rule is no less effective than the Federal rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Revisions to Kentucky's Regulations That Are Not Substantively Identical to the Corresponding Federal Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>1. General</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1State regulations (405 KAR)</textblock>
    <textblock>1Subject</textblock>
    <textblock>1Federal counterpart (30 CFR)</textblock>
    <textblock>12:001␣Sec. 1(29)</textblock>
    <textblock>Definition of term_``unwarranted failure to comply''</textblock>
    <textblock>843.5</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
