<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00009</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Rice From Thailand; Final Results of Countervailing Duty Administrative Review</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>International Trade Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[C-549-503]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>International Trade Administration/Import Administration, Department of Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of final results of countervailing duty administrative review.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>On March 10, 1992, the Department of Commerce (the Department) published the preliminary results of its administrative review of the countervailing duty order on rice from Thailand (57 FR 8437). We have now completed that review and determine the total bounty or grant during the period January 1, 1990 through December 31, 1990 to be 0.53 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>ad valorem</textblock>
    <textblock>for all producers and exporters.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Sylvia Chadwick or Rick Herring, Office of Countervailing Compliance, International Trade Administration, U.S. Department</textblock>
    <textblock>of Commerce, Washington, DC 20230; telephone: (202) 482-2786.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On March 10, 1992, the Department published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(57 FR 8437) the preliminary results of its administrative review of the countervailing duty order on rice from Thailand (51 FR 12356; April 10, 1986). The Department has now completed that administrative review in accordance with section 751 of the Tariff Act of 1930, as amended (the Act).</textblock>
    <textblock>Since the preliminary results of review, respondent, the Royal Thai Government (RTG), filed a case brief. All comments received are addressed in this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>In response to the comments, the Department recalculated loans made under the EPC program and the ACFT program using the 1989 benchmark rate instead of the 1990 benchmark rate for short-term loans received in 1989 but repaid in 1990.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department adjusted the net benefit to the millers under the Ministry of Interior (MOI) paddy price raising program. This adjustment results in a revised benefit to the millers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because of these changes, the estimated bounty or grant of 0.69 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>ad valorem</textblock>
    <textblock>found in our preliminary results has been recalculated to 0.53 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>ad valorem</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
