<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00028</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Individual lending limit_</textblock>
    <textblock>No member bank may extend credit to any insider of the bank or insider of its affiliates in an amount that, when aggregated with the amount of all other extensions of credit by the member bank to that person and to all related interests of that person, exceeds the lending limit of the member bank specified in ยง215.2(i) of this part. This prohibition does not apply to an extension of credit by a member bank to a company of which the member bank is a subsidiary or to any other subsidiary of that company.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Aggregate lending limit</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>General limit.</textblock>
    <textblock>A member bank may not extend credit to any insider of the bank or insider of its affiliates unless the extension of credit is in an amount that, when aggregated with the amount of all outstanding extensions of credit by that bank to all such insiders, does not exceed the bank's unimpaired capital and unimpaired surplus (as defined in ยง215.2(i) of this part).</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Member banks with deposits of less than $100,000,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) A member bank with deposits of less than $100,000,000 may by an annual resolution of its board of directors increase the general limit specified in paragraph (d)(1) of this section to a level not to exceed two times the bank's unimpaired capital and unimpaired surplus, if:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) The board of directors determines that such higher limit is consistent with prudent, safe, and sound banking practices in light of the bank's experience in lending to its insiders and is necessary to attract or retain directors or to prevent restricting the availability of credit in small communities;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) The resolution sets forth the facts and reasoning on which the board of directors bases the finding, including the amount of the bank's lending to its insiders as a percentage of the bank's unimpaired capital and unimpaired surplus as of the date of the resolution;</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) The bank meets or exceeds, on a fully-phased in basis, all applicable capital requirements established by the appropriate Federal banking agency; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) The bank received a satisfactory composite rating in its most recent report of examination.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) If a member bank has adopted a resolution authorizing a higher limit pursuant to paragraph (d)(2)(i) of this section and subsequently fails to meet the requirements of paragraph (d)(2)(i)(C) or (d)(2)(i)(D) of this section, the member bank shall not extend any additional credit (including a renewal of any existing extension of credit) to any insider of the bank or its affiliates unless such extension or renewal is consistent with the general limit in paragraph (d)(1) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Exceptions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The general limit specified in paragraph (d)(1) of this section does not apply to the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Extensions of credit secured by a perfected security interest in bonds, notes, certificates of indebtedness, or Treasury bills of the United States or in other such obligations fully guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States;</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Extensions of credit to or secured by unconditional takeout commitments or guarantees of any department, agency, bureau, board, commission or establishment of the United States or any corporation wholly owned directly or indirectly by the United States;</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Extensions of credit secured by a perfected security interest in a segregated deposit account in the lending bank; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) Extensions of credit arising from the discount of negotiable or nonnegotiable installment consumer paper that is acquired from an insider and carries a full or partial recourse endorsement or guarantee by the insider, provided that:</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) The financial condition of each maker of such consumer paper is reasonably documented in the bank's files or known to its officers;</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) An officer of the bank designated for that purpose by the board of directors of the bank certifies in writing that the bank is relying primarily upon the responsibility of each maker for payment of the obligation and not upon any endorsement or guarantee by the insider; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>) The maker of the instrument is not an insider.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The exceptions in paragraphs (d)(3)(i)(A) through (d)(3)(i)(C) of this section apply only to the amounts of such extensions of credit that are secured in the manner described therein.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Overdrafts.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) No member bank may pay an overdraft of an executive officer or director of the bank</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>on an account at the bank, unless the payment of funds is made in accordance with:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) A written, preauthorized, interest-bearing extension of credit plan that specifies a method of repayment; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A written, preauthorized transfer of funds from another account of the account holder at the bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The prohibition in paragraph (e)(1) of this section does not apply to payment of inadvertent overdrafts on an account in an aggregate amount of $1,000 or less, provided:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The account is not overdrawn for more than 5 business days; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The member bank charges the executive officer or director the same fee charged any other customer of the bank in similar circumstances.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>This prohibition does not apply to the payment by a member bank of an overdraft of a principal shareholder of the member bank, unless the principal shareholder is also an executive officer or director. This prohibition also does not apply to the payment by a member bank of an overdraft of a related interest of an executive officer, director, or principal shareholder of the member bank.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
