<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Navy invites interested agencies, organizations, and</textblock>
    <textblock>the general public to submit written comments or suggestions</textblock>
    <textblock>concerning the scope of the issues to be addressed, alternatives to</textblock>
    <textblock>be analyzed, and the environmental impacts to be addressed in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Draft Environmental Impact Statement. The public also is invited</textblock>
    <textblock>to attend scoping meetings in which oral comments and suggestions</textblock>
    <textblock>will be received. Oral and written comments will be considered</textblock>
    <textblock>equally in preparation of the Environmental Impact Statement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Those not desiring to submit comments or suggestions at this time,</textblock>
    <textblock>but who would like to receive a copy of the Draft Environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>Impact Statement for review when it is issued, should write to</textblock>
    <textblock>Puget Sound Naval Shipyard at the address below. When the Draft</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Impact Statement is complete, its availability will</textblock>
    <textblock>be announced in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>and in the local news media.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public hearings will be held, and comments will be solicited on</textblock>
    <textblock>this document.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments postmarked by March 21, 1994 will be considered in</textblock>
    <textblock>preparation of the Draft Environmental Impact Statement. Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>postmarked after that date will be considered to the extent</textblock>
    <textblock>practicable. Oral and written comments will be received at public</textblock>
    <textblock>scoping meetings to be held at the locations and times indicated as</textblock>
    <textblock>follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bremerton, Washington, March 10, 1994, 7pm-10pm</textblock>
    <textblock>Best Western Bayview Inn, 5640 Kitsap Way</textblock>
    <textblock>Richland, Washington, March 11, 1994, 7pm-10pm</textblock>
    <textblock>Shiloh Inn_Rivershore, 50 Comstock</textblock>
    <textblock>Olympia, Washington, March 14, 1994, 7pm-10pm</textblock>
    <textblock>Ramada Inn_Governor House, 621 So. Capitol Way</textblock>
    <textblock>Portland, Oregon, March 15, 1994, 7pm-10pm</textblock>
    <textblock>Red Lion Inn_Jantzen Beach, 909 N. Hayden Island Dr.</textblock>
    <textblock>Portsmouth, Virginia, March 17, 1994, 7pm-10pm</textblock>
    <textblock>Holiday Inn, 8 Crawford Parkway</textblock>
    <textblock>The meetings will be chaired by a presiding officer but will not be</textblock>
    <textblock>conducted as evidentiary hearings; speakers will not be cross</textblock>
    <textblock>examined although the presiding officer, Department of the Navy,</textblock>
    <textblock>and Department of Energy representatives present may ask clarifying</textblock>
    <textblock>questions. To ensure that everyone has an adequate opportunity to</textblock>
    <textblock>speak, five minutes will be allotted for each speaker. Depending</textblock>
    <textblock>on the number of persons requesting to speak, the presiding officer</textblock>
    <textblock>may allow more time for elected officials, or speakers representing</textblock>
    <textblock>multiple parties, or organizations. Persons wishing to speak on</textblock>
    <textblock>behalf of organizations should identify the organization. Persons</textblock>
    <textblock>wishing to speak may either notify Puget Sound Naval Shipyard in</textblock>
    <textblock>writing at the address below or register at the meetings. Persons</textblock>
    <textblock>registering at the meetings will be called on to speak if time</textblock>
    <textblock>permits. Written comments also will be accepted at the meetings.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments, suggestions on the scope of the Draft</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Impact Statement, or requests to speak at the public</textblock>
    <textblock>hearings should be submitted to Mr. Robert Minnitti, Puget Sound</textblock>
    <textblock>Naval Shipyard, Bremerton, Washington 98314-5000.</textblock>
  </address>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>The United States Navy placed the world's first nuclear powered</textblock>
    <textblock>submarine, the NAUTILUS, into service in 1954. The first nuclear</textblock>
    <textblock>powered cruiser, the LONG BEACH, was commissioned in 1961. As of</textblock>
    <textblock>the end of 1993, the U.S. Navy had 106 nuclear-powered submarines</textblock>
    <textblock>and 15 nuclear-powered surface ships in operation. Today, over 40%</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Navy's principal combatants are nuclear powered.</textblock>
    <textblock>At the end of their useful lifetime, when the cost of continued</textblock>
    <textblock>operation is not justified by their military capability, or when</textblock>
    <textblock>they are no longer needed, the defueled reactor compartments from</textblock>
    <textblock>these ships require disposal. In the late 1970s and early 1980s,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Navy evaluated a number of options for disposing of the pre-LOS</textblock>
    <textblock>ANGELES class nuclear powered submarine reactor compartments as the</textblock>
    <textblock>ships were beginning to approach the end of their design life. The</textblock>
    <textblock>options examined included disposal of the reactor compartment at an</textblock>
    <textblock>existing land burial site, with the non-radioactive remainder of</textblock>
    <textblock>the submarine disposed of either by sinking at sea or by cutting up</textblock>
    <textblock>for sale as scrap metal, and disposal by sinking the entire</textblock>
    <textblock>submarine in the deep ocean. The ``no action'' alternative of long</textblock>
    <textblock>term protective storage also was examined. The Navy's 1984 Final</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Impact Statement and Record of Decision concluded</textblock>
    <textblock>that permanent disposal would be environmentally safe and feasible</textblock>
    <textblock>using either the land burial or deep ocean option. The Record of</textblock>
    <textblock>Decision issued by the Secretary of the Navy stated that ``No</textblock>
    <textblock>unacceptable environmental impacts associated with either option</textblock>
    <textblock>have been identified as a result of the analysis or through the</textblock>
    <textblock>public review process'', and that ``Based on consideration of all</textblock>
    <textblock>current factors bearing on a disposal action of this kind</textblock>
    <textblock>contemplated, the Navy has decided to proceed with disposal of the</textblock>
    <textblock>reactor compartments by land burial.'' The Navy has successfully</textblock>
    <textblock>pursued this course of action and, as of the end of 1993, has</textblock>
    <textblock>safely shipped 35 submarine reactor compartments to the Department</textblock>
    <textblock>of Energy's burial grounds at Hanford, Washington.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
