<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00165</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00096</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Department of Veterans Affairs gives notice that a meeting of the Advisory Committee on Cemeteries and Memorials, authorized by 38 U.S.C. 2401, will be held at the Excelsior Hotel</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>3 Statehouse Plaza, Little Rock, Arkansas on April 20-21, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The sessions will begin at 8:30 a.m. c.s.t. each day to conduct routine business. The meeting will be open to the public up to the seating capacity which is about 20 persons. Those wishing to attend should contact Ms. Dina Wood, Special Assistant to the Director, or Mr. Larry De Meo, Executive Assistant to the Director, National Cemetery System, [phone (202) 273-5235] not later than 12 noon, EST April 4, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any interested person may attend, appear before, or file a statement with the Committee. Individuals wishing to appear before the Committee should indicate this in a letter to the Director, National Cemetery System (40) at 810 Vermont Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20420. In any such letters, the writer must fully identify themselves and state the organization or association or person they represent. Also, to the extent practicable, letters should indicate the subject matter they want to discuss. Oral presentations should be limited to 10 minutes in duration. Those wishing to file written statements to be submitted to the Committee must also mail, or otherwise deliver, them to the Director, National Cemetery System.</textblock>
    <textblock>Letters and written statements as discussed above must be mailed or delivered in time to reach the Director, National Cemetery System, by 12 noon e.s.t. April 4, 1994. Oral statements will be heard only between 1:30 p.m. and 2 p.m. c.s.t., April 20, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 15, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By Direction of the Secretary.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Advisory Committee on Cemeteries and Memorials; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Heyward Bannister,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Committee Management Officer.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4144 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8320-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
