<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-1-00014</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-1-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Airworthiness Directives: British Aerospace, Regional Aircraft Limited, HP 137 Mk1, Jetstream Models 200, 3101, and 3201 Airplanes</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 39</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 90-CE-56-AD]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule; withdrawal.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document withdraws a notice of proposed rulemaking (NPRM) that would have applied to certain British Aerospace (BAe), Regional Aircraft Limited, HP 137 Mk1, Jetstream Models 200, 3101, and 3201 airplanes. The proposed action would have required identifying all Type ``F'' universal joints on the flap torque shaft and replacing these universal joints with Type ``M'' or Type ``MC'' universal joints. Since issuance of the NPRM, Jetstream Aircraft Ltd. has introduced improved flap torque shaft assemblies that include universal joints that are not life limited, and that incorporate the actions proposed in the referenced NPRM and required in two other existing airworthiness directives (AD's). The FAA has determined that installing these improved assemblies would incorporate the actions of the current NPRM and the requirements of the two existing AD's. The FAA is withdrawing the current NPRM and will subsequently issue another NPRM that would incorporate all the actions referenced above.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Raymond A. Stoer, Program Officer, Brussels Aircraft Certification Office, FAA, Europe, Africa, and Middle East Office, c/o American Embassy, B-1000 Brussels, Belgium; telephone (322) 513-3830; facsimile (322) 230-6899; or Mr. John P. Dow, Project Officer, Small Airplane Directorate, Airplane Certification Service, FAA, 1201 Walnut, suite 900, Kansas City, Missouri 64106; telephone (816) 426-6932; facsimile (816) 426-2169.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>A proposal to amend part 39 of the Federal Aviation Regulations to include an airworthiness directive (AD) that would apply to certain British Aerospace (BAe), Regional Aircraft Limited, HP 137 Mk1, Jetstream Models 200, 3101, and 3201 airplanes was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on March 21, 1991 (56 FR 11976). The action proposed inspecting the flap torque shaft to identify all Type ``F'' universal joints, and replacing these universal joints with Type ``M'' or Type ``MC'' universal joints. The proposed actions would be accomplished in accordance with the instructions in BAe Alert Service Bulletin (ASB) 27-A-JA 900544, which incorporates the following pages and revisions:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons have been afforded an opportunity to participate in the making of this amendment. No comments were received on the proposed rule or the FAA's determination of the cost to the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>Since issuance of the notice of proposed rulemaking (NPRM), Jetstream Aircraft Ltd. has introduced improved flap torque shaft assemblies that include universal joints that are not life limited, and that incorporate the actions proposed in the referenced NPRM and required in two other existing AD's. The FAA has determined that installing these improved assemblies would incorporate the actions proposed in the current NPRM and the requirements of the following AD's:</textblock>
    <textblock>•AD 87-04-04, Amendment 39-5529, which requires limiting the in-service life of the torque tube shaft assembly on BAe HP 137 Mk1, Jetstream Models 200, 3101, and 3201 airplanes; and</textblock>
    <textblock>•AD 89-16-02, Amendment 39-6273, which requires repetitively inspecting the universal joints and universal joint rivets on BAe HP 137 Mk1, Jetstream Models 200, 3101, and 3201 airplanes, and replacing any damaged part.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA will issue another NPRM to propose combining the universal joint inspection requirements and the flap torque shaft assembly life limit requirement of the two existing AD's, but mandate installing improved flap torque shaft assemblies as terminating action for these requirements. Since this future action will also incorporate the previously proposed actions, the FAA is withdrawing the existing NPRM.</textblock>
    <textblock>Withdrawal of this NPRM constitutes only such action, and does not preclude the agency from issuing another notice in the future, nor does it commit the agency to any course of action in the future.</textblock>
    <textblock>Since this action only withdraws an NPRM, it is neither a proposed rule nor a final rule and therefore, is not covered under Executive Order 12866, the Regulatory Flexibility Act, or DOT Regulatory Policies and Procedures (44 FR 11034, February 26, 1979).</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 14 CFR Part 39</textblock>
    <textblock>Air Transportation, Aircraft, Aviation Safety, Safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Withdrawal</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, the notice of proposed rulemaking, Docket No. 90-CE-56-AD, published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on March 21, 1991 (56 FR 11976), is withdrawn.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Kansas City, Missouri, on February 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Pages</textblock>
    <textblock>1Revision level</textblock>
    <textblock>1Date</textblock>
    <textblock>1 through 5</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>Sept. 29, 1990.</textblock>
    <textblock>6 through 9, and 11 through 29</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>June 15, 1990.</textblock>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>June 22, 1990.</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John R. Colomy,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Manager, Small Airplane Directorate, Aircraft Certification Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4125 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
