<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00028</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>AGENCIES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Navy and Department of Energy.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Department of the Navy</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Intent To Prepare an Environmental Impact Statement for Disposal of Decommissioned, Defueled Cruiser, Ohio, and Los Angeles Class Naval Reactor Plants</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Navy, with the Department of Energy as</textblock>
    <textblock>a cooperating agency, announces its intent to prepare an</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Impact Statement pursuant to the National</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.), in</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with the Council on Environmental Quality Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>for Implementing the Procedural Provisions of the National</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Policy Act (40 CFR parts 1500-1508), and to conduct</textblock>
    <textblock>a series of public scoping meetings. This Environmental Impact</textblock>
    <textblock>Statement will address final disposal of decommissioned, defueled</textblock>
    <textblock>reactor plants from cruisers and OHIO (Trident) and LOS ANGELES</textblock>
    <textblock>(SSN 688) Class submarines and will analyze the associated</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonably foreseeable environmental impacts. The disposal of</textblock>
    <textblock>future reactor compartments from vessels that have not yet been</textblock>
    <textblock>commissioned (e.g., SEAWOLF Class of submarines) will be addressed,</textblock>
    <textblock>as appropriate, in future National Environmental Policy Act</textblock>
    <textblock>documents. By participating as a cooperating agency in this</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Impact Statement, the Department of Energy expects to</textblock>
    <textblock>be able to adopt this Environmental Impact Statement, if</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriate, to fulfill its environmental review obligations under</textblock>
    <textblock>the National Environmental Policy Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the Council on Environmental Quality National</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Policy Act regulations, the Department of the Navy is</textblock>
    <textblock>preparing this Environmental Impact Statement to focus on the</textblock>
    <textblock>potential for significant environmental impacts and to consider</textblock>
    <textblock>reasonable alternatives.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because of the common design characteristics of the reactor plants</textblock>
    <textblock>and their reactor compartments, the method currently being used by</textblock>
    <textblock>Puget Sound Naval Shipyard in Bremerton, Washington to dispose of</textblock>
    <textblock>submarine reactor compartments is the preferred alternative for</textblock>
    <textblock>disposal of the defueled reactor plants from cruisers and OHIO and</textblock>
    <textblock>LOS ANGELES Class submarines. Briefly, this alternative would</textblock>
    <textblock>involve draining the piping systems, tanks, vessels, and other</textblock>
    <textblock>components to the maximum extent practical, sealing the radioactive</textblock>
    <textblock>systems, removing the reactor compartment and sealing it to provide</textblock>
    <textblock>a high integrity welded steel package. The reactor compartment</textblock>
    <textblock>package would be transported by barge out of Puget Sound through</textblock>
    <textblock>the Straits of Juan de Fuca, down the Washington coast, and up the</textblock>
    <textblock>Columbia River to the Port of Benton where it would be loaded onto</textblock>
    <textblock>an overland transporter for the short movement to the Department of</textblock>
    <textblock>Energy's low level radioactive waste burial grounds at Hanford,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington.</textblock>
    <textblock>The reactor plants contain radioactivity due to neutron irradiation</textblock>
    <textblock>of structural alloys forming the reactor plant components. The</textblock>
    <textblock>reactor compartment packages would comply with the shipping</textblock>
    <textblock>container requirements of the Department of Transportation, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Nuclear Regulatory Commission, and the Department of Energy.</textblock>
    <textblock>Disposal of the reactor compartments would be in accordance with</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Energy requirements for low level radioactive waste</textblock>
    <textblock>disposal. Disposal of the reactor compartments would be regulated</textblock>
    <textblock>by the State of Washington due to the lead shielding contained</textblock>
    <textblock>within the reactor compartments and by the U.S. Environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>Protection Agency due to the small quantity of polychlorinated</textblock>
    <textblock>biphenyls in materials within the reactor compartment such as</textblock>
    <textblock>insulation, electrical cables, and rubber parts.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Navy also will evaluate in detail a ``no action'' alternative.</textblock>
    <textblock>In this alternative, the defueled ships would be maintained in</textblock>
    <textblock>waterborne protective storage for an indefinite period of time at</textblock>
    <textblock>the inactive ships facilities at Puget Sound Naval Shipyard and</textblock>
    <textblock>Norfolk Naval Shipyard.</textblock>
    <textblock>Several other alternatives will be examined. These alternatives</textblock>
    <textblock>include sea disposal, land disposal at other sites, land disposal</textblock>
    <textblock>or reuse of subdivided portions of the reactor plant, and above</textblock>
    <textblock>ground storage or disposal.</textblock>
  </summary>
</doc>
