<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00084</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00045</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The organizations listed in this notice have applied under ยง225.23(a)(2) or (f) of the Board's Regulation Y (12 CFR 225.23(a)(2) or (f)) for the Board's approval under section 4(c)(8) of the Bank Holding Company Act (12 U.S.C. 1843(c)(8)) and ยง225.21(a) of Regulation Y (12 CFR 225.21(a)) to acquire or control voting securities or assets of a company engaged in a nonbanking activity that is listed in ยง225.25 of Regulation Y as closely related to banking and permissible for bank holding companies. Unless otherwise noted, such activities will be conducted throughout the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each application is available for immediate inspection at the Federal Reserve Bank indicated. Once the application has been accepted for processing, it will also be available for inspection at the offices of the Board of Governors. Interested persons may express their views in writing on the question whether consummation of the proposal can ``reasonably be expected to produce benefits to the public, such as greater convenience, increased competition, or gains in efficiency, that outweigh possible adverse effects, such as undue concentration of resources, decreased or unfair competition, conflicts of interests, or unsound banking practices.'' Any request for a hearing on this question must be accompanied by a statement of the reasons a written presentation would not suffice in lieu of a hearing, identifying specifically any questions of fact that are in dispute, summarizing the evidence that would be presented at a hearing, and indicating how the party commenting would be aggrieved by approval of the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Unless otherwise noted, comments regarding each of these applications must be received at the Reserve Bank indicated for the application or the offices of the Board of Governors not later than March 18, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Federal Reserve Bank of New York</textblock>
    <textblock>(William L. Rutledge, Vice President) 33 Liberty Street, New York, New York 10045:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. J.P. Morgan &amp; Company, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>, New York, New York; to acquire J.P. Morgan Delaware Trust Company, Wilmington, Delaware, and thereby engage in activities that may be carried on by a trust company, including those of a fiduciary, investment management, agency and securities safekeeping nature pursuant to  225.25(b)(3) of the Board's Regulation Y.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta</textblock>
    <textblock>(Zane R. Kelley, Vice President) 104 Marietta Street, N.W., Atlanta, Georgia 30303:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Compass Bancshares, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Birmingham, Alabama; to acquire certain branches of Anchor Savings Bank, FSB, Hewlett, New York, located in Callahan, Florida; Jacksonville, Florida; and St. Augustine, Florida, and thereby engage in operating a saving bank pursuant to ยง225.25(b)(9) of the Board's Regulation Y.</textblock>
    <textblock>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, February 16, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>J.P. Morgan &amp; Company, Inc., et al.; Acquisitions of Companies Engaged in Permissible Nonbanking Activities</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jennifer J. Johnson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Secretary of the Board.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4118 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6210-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
