<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00054</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00034</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 17, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 14, 1994, Williston Basin Interstate Pipeline Company (Williston Basin), tendered for filing as part of its FERC Gas Tariff, Second Revised Volume No. 1, the following revised tariff sheet:</textblock>
    <textblock>Second Revised Volume No. 1</textblock>
    <textblock>Substitute Original Sheet No. 322A</textblock>
    <textblock>Williston Basin states that it submitted this tariff sheet as a substitute for Original Sheet No. 322A submitted in this proceeding on January 31, 1994 so as to include additional language to address the derivation of the projected system average cost of gas referenced in Section 38 of the General Terms and Conditions of Williston Basin's FERC Gas Tariff, Second Revised Volume No. 1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to protest said filing should file a protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rule 211 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (18 CFR 385.211). All such protests should be filed on or before February 25, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make the protestants parties to the proceeding. Copies of the filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. TM94-3-49-002]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Williston Basin Interstate Pipeline Co.; Notice of Compliance Tariff Filing</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4174 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
