<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00082</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00043</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The notificants listed below have applied under the Change in Bank Control Act (12 U.S.C. 1817(j)) and  225.41 of the Board's Regulation Y (12 CFR 225.41) to acquire a bank or bank holding company. The factors that are considered in acting on the notices are set forth in paragraph 7 of the Act (12 U.S.C. 1817(j)(7)).</textblock>
    <textblock>The notices are available for immediate inspection at the Federal Reserve Bank indicated. Once the notices have been accepted for processing, they will also be available for inspection at the offices of the Board of Governors. Interested persons may express their views in writing to the Reserve Bank indicated for that notice or to the offices of the Board of Governors. Comments must be received not later than March 15, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta</textblock>
    <textblock>(Zane R. Kelley, Vice President) 104 Marietta Street, N.W., Atlanta, Georgia 30303:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. William Robert Collins</textblock>
    <textblock>, Huntsville, Alabama; to retain 11.9 percent of the voting shares of BancAlabama, Inc., Huntsville, Alabama, for a total of 14.3 percent and thereby indirectly acquire BankAlabama_Huntsville, Huntsville, Alabama.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco</textblock>
    <textblock>(Kenneth R. Binning, Director, Bank Holding Company) 101 Market Street, San Francisco, California 94105:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Benjamin Namatinia</textblock>
    <textblock>, Portland, Oregon; to acquire an additional 7.39 percent of the voting shares of Cowlitz Bancorporation, Longview, Washington, for a total of 25.38 percent, and thereby indirectly acquire The Cowlitz Bank, Longview, Washington.</textblock>
    <textblock>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, February 16, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>William Robert Collins, et al.; Change in Bank Control Notices; Acquisitions of Shares of Banks or Bank Holding Companies</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jennifer J. Johnson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Secretary of the Board.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4116 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6210-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
