<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00030</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Today the Navy faces the necessity of downsizing the fleet to an</textblock>
    <textblock>extent that was not envisioned before the end of the Cold War.</textblock>
    <textblock>Over the next few years a number of major surface combatants,</textblock>
    <textblock>including nuclear powered cruisers, will be removed from service.</textblock>
    <textblock>Some LOS ANGELES Class submarines are scheduled for removal from</textblock>
    <textblock>service. Eventually, the Navy will also need to decommission OHIO</textblock>
    <textblock>Class submarines. These classes of nuclear powered ships were not</textblock>
    <textblock>considered in the 1984 Environmental Impact Statement. The total</textblock>
    <textblock>number of cruiser, OHIO, and LOS ANGELES Class reactor compartments</textblock>
    <textblock>is approximately 100. The purpose of this Environmental Impact</textblock>
    <textblock>Statement will be to assess the potential environmental impact of</textblock>
    <textblock>disposing of defueled reactor compartments from nuclear powered</textblock>
    <textblock>cruisers and the LOS ANGELES and OHIO Class submarines.</textblock>
    <textblock>Preliminary Description of Alternatives</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Preferred Alternative</textblock>
    <textblock>Because of the common design characteristics of the reactor plants</textblock>
    <textblock>and their reactor compartments, the method currently being used by</textblock>
    <textblock>Puget Sound Naval Shipyard in Bremerton, Washington to dispose of</textblock>
    <textblock>submarine reactor compartments is the preferred alternative for</textblock>
    <textblock>disposal of the defueled cruiser, OHIO and LOS ANGELES Class</textblock>
    <textblock>reactor plants. Briefly, this alternative would involve draining</textblock>
    <textblock>the piping systems, tanks, vessels, and other components to the</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum extent practical, sealing the radioactive systems, removing</textblock>
    <textblock>the reactor compartment and sealing it to provide a high integrity</textblock>
    <textblock>welded steel package, and transporting the package first by barge</textblock>
    <textblock>up the Columbia River and then a short distance over land to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Energy's low level radioactive waste burial grounds</textblock>
    <textblock>at Hanford, Washington. The reactor compartment packages would be</textblock>
    <textblock>placed in a trench, backfilled with earth, and covered by an</textblock>
    <textblock>engineered cap to minimize future water infiltration.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
