<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00039</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00019</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 17, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 14, 1994, Carnegie Natural Gas Company (Carnegie), tendered for filing as part of its FERC Gas Tariff, Third Revised Volume No. 1, the following tariff sheets to become effective October 1, 1993:</textblock>
    <textblock>First Revised Sheet No. 140A</textblock>
    <textblock>Third Revised Sheet No. 141</textblock>
    <textblock>Carnegie states that it is filing the above tariff sheet in compliance with the Commission's Order in Docket No. RP94-102-000, dated January 28, 1994, which required Carnegie to revise section 32.1 of the General Terms and Conditions of its FERC Gas Tariff to provide for the passthrough of any refunds related to amounts recovered under section 32.1 or section 26 of its superseded tariff regardless of when such refunds are received.</textblock>
    <textblock>Carnegie states that copies of the filing were served on all parties to the above-captioned proceedings.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to protest said filing should file a protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with ยง385.211 of the Commission's Rules and Regulations. All such protests should be filed on or before February 25, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection in the public reference room.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. RP94-102-001]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Carnegie Natural Gas Co.; Proposed Changes in FERC Gas Tariff</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4167 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
