<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00092</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00050</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 94N-0005]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Ciba-Geigy Corp.; Filing of Food Additive Petition</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration, HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is announcing that Ciba-Geigy Corp. has filed a petition proposing that the food additive regulations be amended to provide for the safe use of oxidized bis(hydrogenated tallow alkyl)amines as a process stabilizer for polypropylene intended for use in contact with food.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments on the petitioner's environmental assessment by March 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Submit written comments to the Dockets Management Branch (HFA-305), Food and Drug Administration, rm. 1-23, 12420 Parklawn Dr., Rockville, MD 20857.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Daniel N. Harrison, Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition (HFS-216), Food and Drug Administration, 200 C St. SW., Washington, DC 20204-0002, 202-254-9500.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (sec. 409(b)(5) (21 U.S.C. 348(b)(5))), notice is given that a food additive petition (FAP 4B4410) has been filed by Ciba-Geigy Corp., Seven Skyline Dr., Hawthorne, NY 10532. The petition proposes that the food additive regulations in ยง178.2010</textblock>
    <textblock>Antioxidants and/or stabilizers for polymers</textblock>
    <textblock>(21 CFR 178.2010) be amended to provide for the safe use of oxidized bis(hydrogenated tallow alkyl)amines (CAS Reg. No. 143925-92-2) as a process stabilizer for polypropylene intended for use in contact with food.</textblock>
    <textblock>The potential environmental impact of this action is being reviewed. To encourage public participation consistent with regulations promulgated under the National Environmental Policy Act (40 CFR 1501.4(b)), the agency is placing the environmental assessment submitted with the petition that is the subject of this notice on public display at the Dockets Management Branch (address above) for public review and comment. Interested persons may, on or before March 28, 1994, submit to the Dockets Management Branch (address above) written comments. Two copies of any comments are to be submitted, except that individuals may submit one copy. Comments are to be identified with the docket number found in brackets in the heading of this document. Received comments may be seen in the office above between 9 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through Friday. FDA will also place on public display any amendments to, or comments on, the petitioner's environmental assessment without further announcement in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. If, based on its review, the agency finds that an environmental impact statement is not required and this petition results in a regulation, the notice of availability of the agency's finding of no significant impact and the evidence supporting that finding will be published with the regulation in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>in accordance with 21 CFR 25.40(c).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Janice F. Oliver,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4080 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
