<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00135</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00084</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Application of Destination Sun Airways for Transfer of Certificate Authority Under Section 401(H)</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of the Secretary</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Transportation.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of order to show cause (Order 94-2-31),</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket 47807.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Transportation is directing all interested persons to show cause why it should not issue an order finding Conquest Sun Airlines, Inc., fit, willing, and able and transfer and reissue to it the certificate of public convenience and necessity to engage in interstate and overseas scheduled air transportation of persons, property, and mail issued to Sun Express Group, Inc. d/b/a Destination Sun Airways by Order 92-4-13.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons wishing to file objections should do so no later than February 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Objections and answers to objections should be filed in Docket 47807 and addressed to the Documentary Services Division (C-55, room 4107), U.S. Department of Transportation, 400 Seventh Street, SW., Washington, DC 20590 and should be served upon the parties listed in Attachment A to the order.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. John E. Harman, Office of Aviation Analysis (P-52, room 6401), U.S. Department of Transportation, 400 Seventh Street, SW., Washington, DC 20590, (202) 366-9721.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Patrick V. Murphy,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Assistant Secretary for Policy and International Affairs.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4319 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-62-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
