<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In several sections of the regulations affected by this amendment, Kentucky is proposing to revise the use of the terms ``permittee'', ``operator'', and ``person'' in order to achieve consistency in the use of the terms and to more clearly identify the entities that are intended to be subject to the particular statutory requirements involved. The Director finds that the proposed revisions add clarity to Kentucky's rules and are no less effective than the Federal regulations as listed below.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. 405 KAR 12:001 Definitions for 405 KAR Chapter 12</textblock>
    <textblock>Kentucky proposes to add a definition of ``willfully and willful violation'' which is identical to the definition currently found in Kentucky's program at 405 KAR 7:001, 8:001 and 10:001, and which was approved by the Director on October 1, 1992 (57 FR 45297). The Director finds that this definition was previously approved in other sections of the Kentucky program and the proposal to add it to 405 KAR Chapter 12 will not render Kentucky's regulations less effective than the Federal program.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. 405 KAR 12:010 General Provisions for Inspection and Enforcement</textblock>
    <textblock>Kentucky proposes to revise its regulations governing frequency of inspections set forth at 405 KAR 12:010 section 3(5) (a) by providing an exception to the monthly partial inspection requirement where the cabinet has received notice of temporary cessation of operations. As proposed for revision, if the cabinet has received notice of temporary cessation, the partial inspections shall continue until the cabinet determines that the permit area is sufficiently stable to insure that the quarterly complete inspections required by 405 KAR 12:010 section 3(5)(b) will provide adequate inspection of the permit area. The Federal rule at 30 CFR 840.11(a) provides for ``partial inspections of each inactive surface coal mining and reclamation operation .␣.␣. as are necessary to ensure effective enforcement of the approved State program.'' 30 CFR 840.11(f) (1) includes as an inactive surface coal mining and reclamation operation one for which the regulatory authority has received written notice of temporary cessation of mining. The Director finds that the proposed rule represents reasonable exercise of Kentucky's discretion under 30 CFR 840.11(a) and is no less effective than the Federal counterparts at 30 CFR 840.11 (a) and (f).</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Revisions to Kentucky's Regulations With No Corresponding Federal Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>1. General</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Kentucky proposes to revise the introductory material at 405 KAR 10:050 and 405 KAR 12:010 to include appropriate statutory and regulatory citations relating to the materials covered by the respective regulations. The Director finds that the inclusion of this material is not inconsistent with any requirements of SMCRA or the Federal regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. In proposed revisions to the Necessity and Function sections of 405 KAR 10:050, 12:001 and 12:010, as well as 405 KAR 10:050 section 1(1) and 405 KAR 12:010 section 4(3), Kentucky refers to</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative regulations,</textblock>
    <textblock>rather than just</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>as currently expressed in those provisions. The Director finds that the proposed revisions add appropriate clarity to the State's program and do not adversely affect any requirement of SMCRA or the Federal regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Kentucky proposes to revise the Necessity and Function section of 405 KAR 10:050 by adding the following clarifying sentence:</textblock>
    <textblock>This administrative regulation establishes criteria under which unused forfeited bond funds shall be returned to the person from whom they were collected.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Director finds that this proposed addition will not render Kentucky's program inconsistent with any provisions of the Federal program.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1State regulations proposed for revision</textblock>
    <textblock>1Federal regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>405 KAR 10:050␣Section 2(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>30 CFR 800.50(d) (1)</textblock>
    <textblock>405 KAR 12:010␣Necessity and Function</textblock>
    <textblock>30 CFR 840.11(e) (2)</textblock>
    <textblock>405 KAR 12:010␣Section 3(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>30 CFR 840.12(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>405 KAR 12:010␣Section 3(5) (a)</textblock>
    <textblock>30 CFR 840.11(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>405 KAR 12:010␣Section 3(5) (b)</textblock>
    <textblock>30 CFR 840.11(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>405 KAR 12:010␣Section 4(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>30 CFR 840.14(c) (1)</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
