<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00105</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00061</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Petitions for Modification</textblock>
    <textblock>The following parties have filed petitions to modify the application of mandatory safety standards under section 101(c) of the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977.</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Energy West Mining Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. M-94-15-C]</textblock>
    <textblock>Energy West Mining Company, P.O. Box 310, Huntington, Utah 84528 has filed a petition to modify the application of 30 CFR 75.1002 (location of trolley wires, trolley feeder wires, high-voltage cables and transformers) to its Deer Creek Mine (I.D. No. 42-00121); its Cottonwood Mine (I.D. No. 42-01944); and its Trail Mountain Mine (I.D. No. 42-01211) all located in Emery County, Utah. The petitioner proposes to use high-voltage (2400 volts) cable to power longwall equipment. The petitioner asserts that the proposed alternate method would provide at least the same measure of protection as would the mandatory standard.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Andalex Resources, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. M-94-16-C]</textblock>
    <textblock>Andalex Resources, Inc., P.O. Box 902, Price, Utah 84501 has filed a petition to modify the application of 30 CFR 75.1002</textblock>
    <textblock>(location of trolley wires, trolley feeder wires, high-voltage cables and transformers) to its Pinnacle Mine (I.D. No. 42-01474); and its Aberdeen Mine (I.D. No. 42-02028) both located in Carbon County, Utah. The petitioner proposes to use high-voltage (2400 volts) equipment in the last open crosscut at the longwall sections. The petitioner states that application of the standard would result in a diminution of safety to the miners. In addition, the petitioner asserts that the proposed alternate method would provide at least the same measure of protection as would the mandatory standard.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. De'Lyn, Ltd.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. M-94-17-C]</textblock>
    <textblock>De'Lyn, Ltd., Drawer 907, Skelton, West Virginia 25919 has filed a petition to modify the application of 30 CFR 75.364(b)(2) (weekly examination) to its Mine No. 7 (I.D. No. 46-07162) located in Boone County, West Virginia. Due to deteriorating roof conditions in the 2nd Left Mains air course, the area cannot be traveled safely. The petitioner proposes to establish monitoring stations at spad</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>2872 in entry</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>1 outby the affected area and at</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>3024 inby the affected area to measure the quantity and direction of the air flow; to post a marker indicating the proper direction of the air flow; and to record the results of air readings and examinations in a record book accessible to all interested parties. The petitioner asserts that the proposed alternative method would provide at least the same measure of protection as would the mandatory standard.</textblock>
    <textblock>Request for Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons interested in these petitions may furnish written comments. These comments must be filed with the Office of</textblock>
    <textblock>Standards, Regulations and Variances, Mine Safety and Health</textblock>
    <textblock>Administration, Room 627, 4015 Wilson Boulevard, Arlington,</textblock>
    <textblock>Virginia 22203. All comments must be postmarked or received in that office on or before March 28, 1994. Copies of these petitions are available for inspection at that address.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF LABOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Mine Safety and Health Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Patricia W. Silvey,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Standards, Regulations and Variances.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4177 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4510-43-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
