<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00055</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00035</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Energy Information Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Agency Information Collections Under Review by the Office of Management and Budget</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Energy Information Administration, Energy.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of request submitted for review by the Office of Management and Budget.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Energy Information Administration (EIA) has submitted the energy information collection(s) listed at the end of this notice to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for review under provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (Pub. L. No. 96-511, 44 U.S.C. 3501</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.). The listing does not include collections of information contained in new or revised regulations which are to be submitted under section 3504(h) of the Paperwork Reduction Act, nor management and procurement assistance requirements collected by the Department of Energy (DOE).</textblock>
    <textblock>Each entry contains the following information: (1) The sponsor of the collection; (2) Collection number(s); (3) Current OMB docket number (if applicable); (4) Collection title; (5) Type of request, e.g., new, revision, extension, or reinstatement; (6) Frequency of collection; (7) Response obligation, i.e., mandatory, voluntary, or required to obtain or retain benefit; (8) Affected public; (9) An estimate of the number of respondents per report period; (10) An estimate of the number of responses per respondent annually; (11) An estimate of the average hours per response; (12) The estimated total annual respondent burden; and (13) A brief abstract describing the proposed collection and the respondents.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be filed by March 28, 1994. If you anticipate that you will be submitting comments but find it difficult to do so within the time allowed by this notice, you should advise the OMB DOE Desk Officer listed below of your intention to do so, as soon as possible. The Desk Officer may be telephoned at (202) 395-3084. (Also, please notify the EIA contact listed below.)</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Address comments to the Department of Energy Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, Office of Management and Budget, 726 Jackson Place NW., Washington, DC 20503. (Comments should also be addressed to the Office of Statistical Standards at the address below.)</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION AND COPIES OF RELEVANT MATERIALS CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Jay Casselberry, Office of Statistical Standards, (EI-73), Forrestal Building, U.S. Department of Energy, Washington, DC 20585. Mr. Casselberry may be telephoned at (202) 254-5348.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The energy information collection submitted to OMB for review was:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Energy Information Administration.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. EIA-885.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. N.A.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Propane Provider Fleet Survey.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. New.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Triennially.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Mandatory.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Businesses or other for-profit.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. 135 respondents.</textblock>
    <textblock>10. .33 responses.</textblock>
    <textblock>11. 1.28 hours per response.</textblock>
    <textblock>12. 58 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>13. Form EIA-885 will be used to collect data on the fleet and fleet vehicles belonging to propane suppliers. Data will be published along with data obtained from other alternative fuel provider sources. Respondents are companies who conduct deliveries (residential and commercial) of propane.</textblock>
    <textblock>Statutory Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 2(a) of the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980, (Pub. L. No. 96-511), which amended Chapter 35 of Title 44 of the United States Code (See 44 U.S.C. 3506 (a) and (c)(1)).</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, February 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Yvonne M. Bishop,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Statistical Standards, Energy Information Administration.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4182 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
