<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00074</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Partial Revocation of Executive Order Dated December 12, 1917, and Secretarial Order Dated December 12, 1917; Oregon</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>43 CFR Public Land Order 7029</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[OR-943-4210-06; GP4-038; OR-19014, OR-19115]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Public land order.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This order revokes an Executive order and a Secretarial order insofar as they affect a 0.28 acre parcel of land withdrawn for the Bureau of Land Management's Powersite Reserve No. 661 and Waterpower Designation No. 14. This action will open 0.28 acre to such forms of disposition as may by law be made of Revested Oregon and California Railroad Grand Lands. The revocation is needed to permit disposal of the land through sale. The land has been and will remain open to mining and mineral leasing.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Donna Kauffman, BLM Oregon/Washington State Office, P.O. Box 2965, Portland, Oregon 97208-2965, 503-280-7162.</textblock>
    <textblock>By virtue of the authority vested in the Secretary of the Interior by Section 204 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, 43 U.S.C. 1714 (1988), it is ordered as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The Executive Order dated December 12, 1917, which established Powersite Reserve No. 661, and the Secretarial Order dated December 12, 1917, which established Waterproof Designation No. 14, are hereby revoked insofar as they affect the following described land:</textblock>
    <textblock>Willamette Meridian</textblock>
    <textblock>Revested Oregon and California Railroad Grant Lands</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 21 S., R. 1 W.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 35, lot 2.</textblock>
    <textblock>The area described contains 0.28 acre in Lane County.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. At 8:30 a.m. on March 28, 1994, the land described above will be opened to such forms of disposition as may by law be made of Revested Oregon and California Railroad Grant Lands, subject to valid existing rights, the provisions of existing withdrawals, other segregations of record, and the requirements of applicable law. All valid applications received at or prior to 8:30 a.m. on March 28, 1994, shall be considered as simultaneously filed at that time. Those received thereafter shall be considered in the order of filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Bob Armstrong,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary of the Interior.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4094 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-33-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
