<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00039</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Adoption of the Amendment</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, pursuant to the authority delegated to me by the Administrator, the Federal Aviation Administration amends 14 CFR part 39 of the Federal Aviation Regulations as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 39_AIRWORTHINESS DIRECTIVES</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 39 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>49 U.S.C. App. 1354(a), 1421 and 1423; 49 U.S.C. 106(g); and 14 CFR 11.89.</textblock>
    <textblock>§39.13</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 39.13 is amended by adding the following new AD to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>94-04-17␣Twin Commander Aircraft Corporation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendment 39-8837; Docket No. 92-CE-59-AD.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicability:</textblock>
    <textblock>Models 500, 500A, 500B, 500S, 500U, 520, 560, 560A, 560E, 560F, 680, 680E, 680F, 680FL, 680FL(P), 680FP, 680T, 680V, 680W, 681, 685, 690, 690A, 690B, 690C, 690D, 695, 695A, 695B, and 720 airplanes (all serial numbers), certificated in any category:</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance:</textblock>
    <textblock>Required within the next 50 hours time-in-service after the effective date of this AD, unless already accomplished.</textblock>
    <textblock>To prevent flap system failure caused by cable fatigue, which could result in loss of control of the airplane, accomplish the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Accomplish the following inspections and parts replacements (where applicable) of the flap system in accordance with the Accomplishment Instructions section of Twin Commander Service Bulletin (SB) No. 210, dated February 1, 1991.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Rub each flap system cable over its length using a soft cotton cloth. Where the cotton snags, visually inspect the cable for broken wires. Prior to further flight, replace any cable having a broken wire.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Inspect the slave pulley groove width. If the groove is too narrow as specified in Part I, paragraph C, of the Accomplishment Instructions section of Twin Commander SB No. 210, prior to further flight, replace the slave pulley and slave pulley cable.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Visually inspect the flap system for pulleys with worn cable clips or rubbing against the upper or lower support brackets. Prior to further flight, replace any damaged pulleys, brackets, or clips.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Replace the master pulley and the master pulley cable with new parts of improved design in accordance with the Accomplishment Instructions section of Twin Commander SB No. 210, dated February 1, 1991. The applicable master pulley and master cable pulley part numbers are referenced in Table I of Twin Commander SB No. 210.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Special flight permits may be issued in accordance with 14 CFR 21.197 and 21.199 to operate the airplane to a location where the requirements of this AD can be accomplished.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) An alternative method of compliance or adjustment of the compliance time that provides an equivalent level of safety may be approved by the Manager, Seattle Aircraft Certification Office (ACO), FAA, Northwest Mountain Region, 1601 Lind Avenue SW., Renton, Washington 98055-4056. The request shall be forwarded through an appropriate FAA Maintenance Inspector, who may add comments and then send it to the Manager, Seattle ACO, FAA, Northwest Mountain Region.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information concerning the existence of approved alternative methods of compliance with this AD, if any, may be obtained from the Seattle ACO, FAA, Northwest Mountain Region.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) The inspection and replacement required by this AD shall be done in accordance with Twin Commander Service Bulletin No. 210, dated February 1, 1991. This incorporation by reference was approved by the Director of the Federal Register in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552(a) and 1 CFR part 51. Copies may be obtained from the Twin Commander Aircraft Corporation, 19003 59th Drive, NE., Arlington, Washington 98223. Copies may be inspected at the FAA, Central Region, Office of the Assistant Chief Counsel, room 1558, 601 E. 12th Street, Kansas City, Missouri, or at the Office of the Federal Register, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., suite 700, Washington, DC.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) This amendment (39-8837) becomes effective on April 15, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Kansas City, Missouri, on February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Barry D. Clements,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Small Airplane Directorate, Aircraft Certification Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4127 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
