<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00059</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00038</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Changes to the Hotel and Motel Fire Safety Act National Master List</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>United States Fire Administration, FEMA.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA or Agency) gives notice of additions and corrections/changes to, and deletions from, the national master list of places of public accommodations which meet the fire prevention and control guidelines under the Hotel and Motel Fire Safety Act.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on the master list are invited and may be addressed to the Rules Docket Clerk, Federal Emergency Management Agency, 500 C Street, SW., room 840, Washington, DC 20472, (fax) (202) 646-4536. To be added to the National Master List, or to make any other change to the list, see Supplementary Information below.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>John Ottoson, Fire Management Programs Branch, United States Fire Administration, Federal Emergency Management Agency, National Emergency Training Center, 16825 South Seton Avenue, Emmitsburg, MD 21727, (301) 447-1272.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Acting under the Hotel and Motel Fire Safety Act of 1990, 15 U.S.C. 2201 note, the United States Fire Administration has worked with each State to compile a national master list of all of the places of public accommodation affecting commerce located in each State that meet the requirements of the guidelines under the Act. FEMA published the national master list in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on Tuesday, November 29, 1993, 58 FR 62718, and published changes approximately monthly since then.</textblock>
    <textblock>Parties wishing to be added to the National Master List, or to make any other change, should contact the State office or official responsible for compiling listings of properties which comply with the Hotel and Motel Fire Safety Act. A list of State contacts was published in 58 FR 17020 on March 31, 1993. If the published list is unavailable to you, the State Fire Marshal's office can direct you to the appropriate office. Periodically FEMA will update and redistribute the national master list to incorporate additions and corrections/changes to the list, and deletions from the list, that are received from the State offices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each update contains or may contain three categories: ``Additions;'' ``Corrections/changes;'' and ``Deletions.'' For the purposes of the updates, the three categories mean and include the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>``Additions'' are either names of properties submitted by a State but inadvertently omitted from the initial master list or names of properties submitted by a State after publication of the initial master list; ``Corrections/changes'' are corrections to property names, addresses or telephone numbers previously published or changes to previously published information directed by the State, such as changes of address or telephone numbers, or spelling corrections; and</textblock>
    <textblock>``Deletions'' are entries previously submitted by a State and published in the national master list or an update to the national master list, but subsequently removed from the list at the direction of the State.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the national master list and its updates may be obtained by writing to the Government Printing Office, Superintendent of Documents, Washington, DC 20402-9325. When requesting copies please refer to stock number 069-001-00049-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>The update to the national master list follows below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 17, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John P. Carey,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>General Counsel.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
