<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00097</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00055</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[NV-930-4210-05; N-33727]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Termination of Recreation and Public Purposes Classification and Opening Order; Nevada</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Land Management, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice terminates Recreation and Public Purposes classification, N-33727 in its entirety and opens the land to appropriation under the public land laws and the general mining laws.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>Termination of the classification is effective with the publication of this document. The land will be open to entry at 10 a.m. on March 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mary Clark, BLM Nevada State Office, 850 Harvard Way, P.O. Box 12000, Reno, NV 89520, (702) 785-6530.</textblock>
  </further>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In 1983, in response to an application from the City of Elko for a sewage treatment facility, the lands described in this notice were classified as suitable for lease with an option to purchase pursuant to the Recreation and Public Purposes Act, as amended (43 U.S.C. 869, 869-1 to 869-4). Disposal of these lands for a sewage treatment facility is no longer authorized under the Recreation and Public Purposes Act. Therefore, pursuant to section 7 of the Taylor Grazing Act (48 Stat. 1272) and the authority delegated by Appendix 1 of Bureau of Land Management Manual 1203, Recreation and Public Purposes classification N-33727 is hereby terminated in its entirety:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mount Diablo Meridian, Nevada</textblock>
    <textblock>T. 34 N., R. 55 E.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 28, SW1/4NE1/4, S1/2NW1/4, SW1/4, W1/2W1/2SE1/4;</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 29, lots 1-4, inclusive SE1/4NE1/4, SE1/2SW1/4, SE1/4;</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 32, NE1/4NW1/4NW1/4, S1/2NW1/4NW1/4, SW1/4NW1/4,W1/2SE1/4;</textblock>
    <textblock>The area described contains approximately 847.82 acres in Elko County, Nevada.</textblock>
    <textblock>At 10 a.m. on March 28, 1994, the land will be open to the operation of the public land laws, subject to valid existing rights, existing classifications and withdrawals, pending lawsuits, and requirements of applicable law. All valid applications received prior to or at 10 a.m. on March 28, 1994 will be considered as simultaneously filed. All other applications received will be considered in the order of filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>At 10 a.m. on March 28, 1994, the land will also be open to the operation of the mining laws. Appropriation of land under the general mining laws prior to the date and time of restoration is unauthorized. Any such attempted appropriation, including attempted adverse possession under 30 U.S.C. 38, shall vest no rights against the United States. Acts required to establish a location and to initiate a right of possession are governed by State law where not in conflict with Federal law. The Bureau of Land Management will not intervene in disputes between rival locators over possessory rights since Congress has provided for such determinations in local courts. The land remains open to the mineral leasing and material sale laws.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Robert G. Steele,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy State Director, Operations.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4092 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-HC-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
