<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00019</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Avesta Sheffield_Clarification to determine whether stainless steel ``hot bands'' are within the scope of the order.</textblock>
    <textblock>Country: Germany</textblock>
    <textblock>A-428-801: Antifriction Bearings (other than Tapered Roller Bearings) and Parts Thereof</textblock>
    <textblock>SKF_Clarification to determine whether certain textile machinery components are within the scope of the order.</textblock>
    <textblock>A-428-801: Consolidated Saw Mill International (CSMI) Inc._Clarification to determine whether certain Cambio bearings contained in its sawmill debarker are within the scope of the order.</textblock>
    <textblock>Country: Brazil</textblock>
    <textblock>A-351-603: Brass Sheet and Strip</textblock>
    <textblock>Eluma International Inc._Clarification to determine whether brass circles are within the scope of the order.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pending Anticircumvention Inquiry Requests As of October 1, 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>Country: Mexico</textblock>
    <textblock>A-201-806: Steel Wire Rope</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee of Domestic Steel Wire Rope and Specialty Cable Manufacturers_Anticircumvention inquiry to determine whether a producer of steel wire rope in Mexico is circumventing the antidumping order by importing steel wire strand into the United States where it is wound into steel wire rope.</textblock>
    <textblock>Country: Japan</textblock>
    <textblock>A-588-807: Industrial Belts and Components</textblock>
    <textblock>BRECOFLEX Corp._Anticircumvention inquiry to determine whether the order is being circumvented by the processing of Japanese belting into belts in Mexico before importation into the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>Country: Japan</textblock>
    <textblock>A-588-818: Personal Word Processors</textblock>
    <textblock>Smith Corona Corporation_Anticircumvention inquiry to determine whether the order is being circumvented by the importation, completion and assembly of personal word processor parts and components by Brother Industries (USA), Inc., in the United States.</textblock>
    <textblock>Country: People's Republic of China</textblock>
    <textblock>A-570-814: Butt-Weld Pipe Fittings</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Fittings Group_Anticircumvention inquiry to determine whether the order is being circumvented by adding value in Thailand (modifying pipe fittings to ``finished'' from ``unfinished'' status) after importation from the People's Republic of China.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested parties are invited to comment on the accuracy of the list of pending scope clarification requests. Any comments should be submitted to the Assistant Secretary for Import Administration, International Trade Administration, room B-099, U.S. Department of Commerce, 14th Street and Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20230.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 12, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Joseph A. Spetrini,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Assistant Secretary for Compliance.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4196 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DS-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
