<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00062</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Written comments responding to the notice were received,</textblock>
    <textblock>and a public hearing was held on April 5, 1993. After</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration of all written and oral comments regarding the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed amendments, those amendments are adopted as revised</textblock>
    <textblock>by this Treasury decision.</textblock>
    <textblock>Explanation of Provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>Changes Made by the Final Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations generally describe an</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative error and omission and include illustrative</textblock>
    <textblock>examples. Commentators have requested that the final</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations include an ``accounting error'' as an</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative error or omission. The Service and the</textblock>
    <textblock>Treasury Department are concerned that the term ``accounting</textblock>
    <textblock>error'' is too vague. However, in order to address the</textblock>
    <textblock>commentators' concerns, the final regulations clarify that</textblock>
    <textblock>an administrative error or omission includes an error in</textblock>
    <textblock>tracking the housing credit dollar amount an Agency has</textblock>
    <textblock>allocated (or that remains to be allocated) in a calendar</textblock>
    <textblock>year. For example, assume an Agency, believing that it has</textblock>
    <textblock>$100 of credit remaining in its credit ceiling for the</textblock>
    <textblock>current calendar year, allocates $100 to a project and</textblock>
    <textblock>agrees to allocate an additional $30 from the next calendar</textblock>
    <textblock>year's credit ceiling. Later, in the current calendar year,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Agency discovers that it failed to include in its credit</textblock>
    <textblock>ceiling for the current calendar year $50 of credits that</textblock>
    <textblock>were returned in the current calendar year. The error in</textblock>
    <textblock>tracking the $50 of credits that were returned is an</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative error or omission.</textblock>
    <textblock>One commentator asked for clarification of the correction</textblock>
    <textblock>procedure an Agency should use when correcting a document</textblock>
    <textblock>without the Secretary's prior approval. Under the final</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations, a document that corrects a document containing</textblock>
    <textblock>an error or omission that has not yet been filed with the</textblock>
    <textblock>Internal Revenue Service should be filed as the original.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a document containing an error has already been filed</textblock>
    <textblock>with the Internal Revenue Service, the Agency should refile</textblock>
    <textblock>a copy of the document containing the error that prominently</textblock>
    <textblock>and clearly notes the correction. The Agency should</textblock>
    <textblock>indicate at the top of the document(s) that the correction</textblock>
    <textblock>is being made under ยง1.42-13 of the Income Tax Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations require that an Agency obtain</textblock>
    <textblock>the prior approval of the Secretary to correct an</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative error or omission if (1) the correction is</textblock>
    <textblock>not made before the close of the calendar year of the error</textblock>
    <textblock>or omission, and (2) the correction is a numerical change to</textblock>
    <textblock>the housing credit dollar amount allocated for the building</textblock>
    <textblock>or project. One commentator suggested that an Agency should</textblock>
    <textblock>have until February 28, the date by which an Agency must</textblock>
    <textblock>file its Form 8610, to correct an administrative error or</textblock>
    <textblock>omission that changes the housing credit dollar amount</textblock>
    <textblock>allocated to a building or project without obtaining the</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary's prior approval. Another commentator made a</textblock>
    <textblock>similar suggestion solely for credits returned in the same</textblock>
    <textblock>year in which they were allocated. These suggestions have</textblock>
    <textblock>not been adopted. Section 42(h)(1) requires that an</textblock>
    <textblock>allocation for a certain calendar year be made by the close</textblock>
    <textblock>of that calendar year. Consistent with that approach, these</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations do not permit an Agency to make a post-year</textblock>
    <textblock>allocation without the Secretary's prior approval. Of</textblock>
    <textblock>course, for a correction of an administrative error or</textblock>
    <textblock>omission that an Agency cannot correct on its own, an</textblock>
    <textblock>Agency, or the Agency and the affected taxpayer, may seek</textblock>
    <textblock>the Secretary's prior approval.</textblock>
    <textblock>Special Analyses</textblock>
    <textblock>It has been determined that this Treasury Decision is not</textblock>
    <textblock>a significant regulatory action as defined in Executive</textblock>
    <textblock>Order 12866. It also has been determined that section</textblock>
    <textblock>553(b) of the Administrative Procedure Act (5 U.S.C. chapter</textblock>
    <textblock>5) and the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. chapter 6)</textblock>
    <textblock>do not apply to these regulations, and, therefore, a</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Analysis is not required. Pursuant</textblock>
    <textblock>to section 7805(f) of the Internal Revenue Code, a copy of</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed regulations was submitted to the Chief Counsel</textblock>
    <textblock>for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration for</textblock>
    <textblock>comment on its impact on small business.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
