<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00136</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00085</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Navigation Safety Advisory Council, Request for Applications</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Coast Guard</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[CGD 94-012]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Coast Guard, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The U.S. Coast Guard is seeking applicants for appointment to membership on the Navigation Safety Advisory Council (NAVSAC).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Completed applications and resumes must be received no later than March 28, 1994. Application forms may be obtained by contacting the Executive Director at the address below.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>To request an application, either call (202) 267-0415 and give your name and mailing address or write to Commandant (G-NSR-3), U.S. Coast Guard, 2100 Second Street SW., room 1420, Washington, DC 20593-0001.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>Margie G. Hegy, Executive Director, Navigation Safety Advisory Council (NAVSAC), room 1420, U.S. Coast Guard Headquarters, 2100 Second Street SW., Washington, DC 20593-0001, (202) 267-0415.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Council is a twenty-one member Federal advisory council that advises the Coast Guard on matters relating to the prevention of vessel collisions, rammings, and groundings, including, but not limited to: Inland Rules of the Road, International Rules of the Road, navigation regulations and equipment, routing measures, marine information, diving safety, and aids to navigation systems.</textblock>
    <textblock>The applications will be considered for seven (7) expiring terms. The Council consists of 21 members who have expertise, knowledge and experience in the Navigation Rules of the Road (International and Inland), aids to navigation, navigational safety equipment, vessel traffic service, and traffic separation schemes and vessel routing.</textblock>
    <textblock>To achieve the balance of membership required by the Federal Advisory Committee Act, the Coast Guard is especially interested in receiving applications from minorities and women. To assure balanced representation of subject matter expertise, members are chosen, insofar as practical, from the following groups: (1) Recognized experts and leaders in organizations having an active interest in the Rules of the Road and vessel and port safety; (2) representatives of owners and operators of vessels, professional mariners, recreational boaters, and the recreational boating industry; (3) individuals with an interest in maritime law; and (4) Federal and state officials with responsibility for vessel and port safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>The three-year membership term begins July 1, 1994, and assuming that the Council is continued beyond September 30,1995, will expire June 30, 1997. Those persons who have submitted previous applications must reapply as no applications received prior to this solicitation will be considered.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Council meets twice each year at various sites in the continental United States. Members serve without compensation from the Federal Government, although travel reimbursement and per diem may be provided.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>W.J. Ecker,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Rear Admiral, U.S. Coast Guard, Chief, Office of Navigation Safety and Waterway Services.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4207 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-14-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
