<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00031</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>§215.10</textblock>
    <textblock>Reports on credit to executive officers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each member bank shall include with (but not as part of) each report of condition (and copy thereof) filed pursuant to 12 U.S.C. 1817(a)(3) a report of all extensions of credit made by the member bank to its executive officers since the date of the bank's previous report of condition.</textblock>
    <textblock>§215.11</textblock>
    <textblock>Disclosure of credit from member banks to executive officers and principal shareholders.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the purposes of this section, the following definitions apply:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Principal shareholder of a member bank</textblock>
    <textblock>means any person</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>other than an insured bank, or a foreign bank as defined in 12 U.S.C. 3101(7), that, directly or indirectly, owns, controls, or has power to vote more than 10 percent of any class of voting securities of the member bank. The term includes a person that controls a principal shareholder (e.g., a person that controls a bank holding company). Shares of a bank (including a foreign bank), bank holding company, or other company owned or controlled by a member of an individual's immediate family are presumed to be owned or controlled by the individual for the purposes of determining principal shareholder status.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Related interest</textblock>
    <textblock>means:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Any company controlled by a person; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Any political or campaign committee the funds or services of which will benefit a person or that is controlled by a person. For the purpose of this section and subpart B of this part, a related interest does not include a bank or a foreign bank (as defined in 12 U.S.C. 3101(7)).</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Public disclosure.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Upon receipt of a written request from the public, a member bank shall make available the names of each of its executive officers and each of its principal shareholders to whom, or to whose related interests, the member bank had outstanding as of the end of the latest previous quarter of the year, an extension of credit that, when aggregated with all other outstanding extensions of credit at such time from the member bank to such person and to all related interests of such person, equaled or exceeded 5 percent of the member bank's capital and unimpaired surplus of $500,000, whichever amount is less. No disclosure under this paragraph is required if the aggregate amount of all extensions of credit outstanding at such time from the member bank to the executive officer or principal shareholder of the member bank and to all related interests of such a person does not exceed $25,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A member bank is not required to disclose the specific amounts of individual extensions of credit.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Maintaining records.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each member bank shall maintain records of all requests for the information described in paragraph (b) of this section and the disposition of such requests. These records may be disposed of after two years from the date of the request.</textblock>
    <textblock>§215.12</textblock>
    <textblock>Reporting requirement for credit secured by certain bank stock.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each executive officer or director of a member bank the shares of which are not publicly traded shall report annually to the board of directors of the member bank the outstanding amount of any credit that was extended to the executive officer or director and that is secured by shares of the member bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>§215.13</textblock>
    <textblock>Civil penalties.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any member bank, or any officer, director, employee, agent, or other person participating in the conduct of the affairs of the bank, that violates any provision of this part (other than §215.11 of this part) is subject to civil penalties as specified in section 29 of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 504).</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart B_[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>§215.21</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Section 215.21 is amended by removing ``1841(c)'' where it appears in paragraph (a) and adding in its place ``1971 and 1972'' and by removing footnote 10 and redesignating footnotes 11 and 12 as footnotes 5 and 6.</textblock>
    <textblock>§215.22</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Section 215.22 is amended by removing ``12 CFR 226.2(p)'' where it appears in paragraph (c)(1)(ii) and adding in its place ``12 CFR 226.2(a)(12)''.</textblock>
    <textblock>By order of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, February 15, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The term ``stockholder of record'' appearing in 12 U.S.C. 1972(2)(G) is synonymous with the term ``person.''</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William W. Wiles,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of the Board.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3860 Filed 2-18-94; 3:20 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6210-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
