<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-1-00008</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-1-00003</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Milk in the Southern Michigan Marketing Area; Reopened Hearing on Proposed Amendments to Tentative Marketing Agreement and Order</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>7 CFR Part 1040</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. AO-225-A45-RO1; DA-92-10]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Agricultural Marketing Service, USDA.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of public hearing on proposed rulemaking.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>A hearing held in February 1993 to consider proposals to adopt multiple component pricing for milk pooled under the Southern Michigan marketing order is being reopened to consider modifications to the pricing plan recommended for that order. Additional proposals would authorize the market administrator to adjust pool supply plant shipping requirements to reflect changes in marketing conditions. The reopened hearing will also consider a proposal to ``lock in'' to regulation under the Southern Michigan order a UHT packaging plant that otherwise may be regulated under a different Federal order each month. A request to consider the ``lock in'' proposal on an emergency basis also will be considered.</textblock>
    <textblock>The reopening was requested by cooperative associations representing most of the producers whose milk is pooled under the Southern Michigan order.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The hearing will convene at 9 a.m. local time on March 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The hearing will be held at the Radisson Hotel,</textblock>
    <textblock>11 Monroe Avenue NW., Grand Rapids, Michigan 49503,</textblock>
    <textblock>telephone (616) 242-6000.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Constance M. Brenner, Marketing Specialist, USDA/AMS/Dairy Division, Order Formulation Branch, room 2971, South Building, P.O. Box 96456, Washington, DC 20090-6456, (202) 720-7183.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This administrative action is governed by the provisions of sections 556 and 557 of title 5 of the United States Code and, therefore, is excluded from the requirements of Executive Order 12866.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given of a reopened public hearing to be held at the request of most of the producers whose milk is pooled under the Southern Michigan milk order. The reopened hearing will begin at 9 a.m. on March 1, 1994, at the Radisson Hotel, 11 Monroe Avenue NW., Grand Rapids, Michigan 49503, telephone (616) 242-6000, with respect to proposed amendments to the tentative marketing agreement and to the order regulating the handling of milk in the Southern Michigan marketing area.</textblock>
    <textblock>The hearing is called pursuant to the provisions of the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, as amended (7 U.S.C. 601-674), and the applicable rules of practice and procedure governing the formulation of marketing agreements and marketing orders (7 CFR part 900).</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the hearing is to receive evidence with respect to the economic and marketing conditions which relate to the proposed amendments, hereinafter set forth, and any appropriate modifications thereof, to the tentative marketing agreement and to the order.</textblock>
    <textblock>Evidence also will be taken to determine whether emergency marketing conditions exist that would warrant omission of a recommended decision under the rules of practice and procedure (7 CFR 900.12(d)) with respect to Proposal No. 3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Actions under the Federal milk order program are subject to the Regulatory Flexibility Act (Pub. L. 96-354). This Act seeks to ensure that, within the statutory authority of a program, the regulatory and informational requirements are tailored to the size and nature of small businesses. For the purpose of the Act, a dairy farm is a ``small business'' if it has an annual gross revenue of less than $500,000, and a dairy products manufacturer is a ``small business'' if it has fewer than 500 employees. Most parties subject to a milk order are considered as a small business. Accordingly, interested parties are invited to present evidence on the probable regulatory and informational impact of the hearing proposals on small businesses. Also, parties may suggest modifications of these proposals for the purpose of tailoring their applicability to small business.</textblock>
    <textblock>The amendments to the rules proposed herein have been reviewed under Executive Order 12778, Civil Justice Reform. They are not intended to have a retroactive effect. If adopted, the proposed amendments would not preempt any state or local laws, regulations, or policies, unless they present an irreconcilable conflict with these rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act provides that administrative proceedings must be exhausted before parties may file suit in court. Under section 608c(15)(A) of the Act, any handler subject to an order may file with the Secretary a petition stating that the order, any provision of the order, or any obligation imposed in connection with the order is not in accordance with the law and requesting a modification of an order or to be exempted from the order. A handler is afforded the opportunity for a hearing on the petition. After a hearing the Secretary would rule on the petition. The Act provides that the district court of the United States in any district in which the handler is an inhabitant, or has its principal place of business, has jurisdiction in equity to review the Secretary's ruling on the petition, provided a bill in equity is filed not later than 20 days after date of the entry of the ruling.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
