<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00125</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00081</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 15, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 19(b)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (``Act''), 15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(1), notice is hereby given that on February 14, 1994,</textblock>
    <textblock>the National Association of Securities Dealers, Inc. (``NASD'' or ``Association'') filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission (``SEC'' or ``Commission''), the proposed rule change as described in Items I, II, and III below, which Items have been prepared by the NASD. The Commission is publishing this notice to solicit comments on the proposed rule change from interested persons.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Self-Regulatory Organization's Statement of the Terms of Substance of the Proposed Rule Change</textblock>
    <textblock>Below is the text of the proposed rule change. Proposed new language is italicized; proposed deletions are in brackets.</textblock>
    <textblock>Code of Procedure</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Article II</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 10</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Acceptance, Waiver and Consent of the Respondent</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) If the Committee has reason to believe a violation has occurred and the member or associated person does not dispute the violation, the Committee may suggest that the member or associated person submit a letter containing an acceptance of a finding of violations, a waiver of all rights of appeal to the National Business Conduct Committee (and any review thereof by the Board of Governors), the Securities and Exchange Commission and the courts or to otherwise challenge or contest the validity of the Order issued if the letter is accepted, and a consent to the imposition of sanctions. The letter shall describe the act or practice engaged in or omitted; the rule, regulation or statutory provision violated; and the sanction to be imposed therefore. If the Committee then concludes that the Letter of Acceptance, Waiver and Consent is appropriate and should be accepted, it shall be submitted to the National Business Conduct Committee. If the letter is accepted by the National Business Conduct Committee or a</textblock>
    <textblock>Subcommittee designated by the National Business Conduct Committee,</textblock>
    <textblock>it shall become final and shall constitute the complaint, answer and decision in the matter. If the letter is rejected by the Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>,</textblock>
    <textblock>[or] the National Business Conduct Committee, or a</textblock>
    <textblock>Subcommittee designated by the National Business Conduct Committee,</textblock>
    <textblock>any acceptances, waivers and consents contained therein shall not be considered in any further complaint action which may be taken against the member or associated person.</textblock>
    <textblock>Minor Rule Violations Procedure</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The Letter shall be submitted to the Committee and, if accepted, the Letter shall then be submitted to the National Business Conduct Committee. If the National Business Conduct Committee or a</textblock>
    <textblock>Subcommittee designated by the National Business Conduct Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>accepts the Letter, the Corporation will report the violation to the Securities and Exchange Commission as required by the Commission pursuant to a plan approved under Rule 19d-1(c)(2) adopted under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, as amended. If the Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>,</textblock>
    <textblock>[or]</textblock>
    <textblock>the</textblock>
    <textblock>National Business Conduct Committee, or a</textblock>
    <textblock>Subcommittee designated by the National Business Conduct Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>rejects the Letter, the Committee or National Business Conduct Committee may take any other appropriate disciplinary action with respect to the violation or violations.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Settlement Procedure</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 11</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Before any such Order of Acceptance of Offer of Settlement shall become effective it must be submitted to and approved by the National Business Conduct Committee or a</textblock>
    <textblock>Subcommittee designated by the National Business Conduct Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>, which is hereby delegated authority to accept or reject an Offer of Settlement. If the National Business Conduct Committee [by a majority vote] or a</textblock>
    <textblock>Subcommittee designated by the National Business Conduct Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>approves the Committee's Order, it shall communicate its conclusion to the Committee which shall thereafter issue such Order.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Self-Regulatory Organization's Statement of the Purpose of, and Statutory Basis for, the Proposed Rule Change</textblock>
    <textblock>In its filing with the Commission, the NASD included statements concerning the purpose of and basis for the proposed rule change and discussed any comments it received on the proposed rule change. The text of these statements may be examined at the places specified in Item IV below. The NASD has prepared summaries, set forth in Sections (A), (B), and (C) below, of the most significant aspects of such statements.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Release No. 34-33627; File No. SR-NASD-93-76]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Self-Regulatory Organizations; Notice of Filing of Proposed Rule Change by National Association of Securities Dealers, Inc. to Article II, Sections 10 and 11 of the Code of Procedures Relating to the Procedures of the National Business Conduct Committee</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The NASD submitted the filing on December 16, 1993. However, on February 14, 1994, it filed an amendment to replace and supersede the original filing.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
