<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00056</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Indirect Food Additives: Adhesives and Components of Coatings</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>21 CFR Part 175</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 92F-0061]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration, HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is amending the food additive regulations to provide for the safe use of trimethylolpropane as a pigment dispersant in resinous and polymeric coatings in contact with food. This action is in response to a petition filed by SCM Chemicals.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective February 24, 1994; written objections and requests for a hearing by March 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Submit written objections to the Dockets Management Branch (HFA-305), Food and Drug Administration, rm. 1-23, 12420 Parklawn Dr., Rockville, MD 20857.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Vir Anand, Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition (HFS-216), Food and Drug Administration, 200 C St. SW., Washington, DC 20204, 202-254-9500.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>In a notice published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of April 13, 1992 (57 FR 12831), FDA announced that a food additive petition (FAP 2B4316) had been filed by SCM Chemicals, c/o 1001 G St. NW., suite 500 West, Washington, DC 20001. The petition proposed that the food additive regulations in ยง175.300</textblock>
    <textblock>Resinous and polymeric coatings</textblock>
    <textblock>(21 CFR 175.300) be amended to provide for the safe use of trimethylolpropane as a pigment dispersant in resinous and polymeric coatings in contact with food.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA has evaluated data in the petition and other relevant material. The agency concludes that the proposed use of the additive is safe and that the regulations in ยง175.300 should be amended as set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with ยง171.1(h) (21 CFR 171.1(h)), the petition and the documents that FDA considered and relied upon in reaching its decision to approve the petition are available for inspection at the Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition by appointment with the information contact person listed above. As provided in 21 CFR 171.1(h), the agency will delete from the documents any materials that are not available for public disclosure before making the documents available for inspection.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agency has carefully considered the potential environmental effects of this action. FDA has concluded that the action will not have a significant impact on the human environment, and that an environmental impact statement is not required. The agency's finding of no significant impact and the evidence supporting that finding, contained in an environmental assessment, may be seen in the Dockets Management Branch (address above) between 9 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through Friday.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person who will be adversely affected by this regulation may at any time on or before March 28, 1994, file with the Dockets Management Branch (address above) written objections thereto. Each objection shall be separately numbered, and each numbered objection shall specify with particularity the provisions of the regulation to which objection is made and the grounds for the objection. Each numbered objection on which a hearing is requested shall specifically so state. Failure to request a hearing for any particular objection shall constitute a waiver of the right to a hearing on that objection. Each numbered objection for which a hearing is requested shall include a detailed description and analysis of the specific factual information intended to be presented in support of the objection in the event that a hearing is held. Failure to include such a description and analysis for any particular objection shall constitute a waiver of the right to a hearing on the objection. Three copies of all documents shall be submitted and shall be identified with the docket number found in brackets in the heading of this document. Any objections received in response to the regulation may be seen in the Dockets Management Branch between 9 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through Friday.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 21 CFR Part 175</textblock>
    <textblock>Adhesives, Food additives, Food packaging.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and under authority delegated to the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and redelegated to the Director, Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition, 21 CFR part 175 is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 175_INDIRECT FOOD ADDITIVES: ADHESIVES AND COMPONENTS OF COATINGS</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for 21 CFR part 175 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Secs. 201, 402, 409, 721 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. 321, 342, 348, 379e).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 175.300 is amended in paragraph (b)(3)(xxxiii) by alphabetically adding a new entry to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง175.300</textblock>
    <textblock>Resinous and polymeric coatings.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(xxxiii) Miscellaneous materials:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Trimethylolpropane (CAS Reg. No. 77-99-6). For use as a pigment dispersant at levels not to exceed 0.45 percent by weight of the pigment.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Janice F. Oliver,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4081 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
