<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00023</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>VII. Conforming Definition of ``Bank''</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart B of Regulation O partially implements the reporting requirements of title VIII of FIRA, as amended by the Garn-St. Germain Depository Institutions Act of 1982</textblock>
    <textblock>and FDICIA. 12 U.S.C. 1972(2)(G). Section 215.22 requires an executive officer or principal shareholder of a bank to report to the bank each year if the person or any related interest of the person borrowed during the prior calendar year from a correspondent bank of the bank.</textblock>
    <textblock>As originally enacted, a correspondent bank was defined in title VIII of FIRA to include a bank as defined in the Bank Holding Company Act. Title VIII was subsequently amended to include in the definition a mutual savings bank, a savings bank, and a savings association as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act. 12 U.S.C. 1971 and 1972(H). The Board proposed to amend the definition of bank in subpart B of Regulation O to conform the rule to the statutory amendments. See 58 FR 47400, September 9, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments were favorable, and the Board has adopted this provision as proposed.</textblock>
    <textblock>VIII. Technical Amendments</textblock>
    <textblock>The Board has adopted a series of technical amendments to Regulation O that are designed to make the regulation more easily understandable and somewhat shorter. The amendments include a new definition of ``affiliate,'' which makes the regulation read more clearly and allows various cross-references and footnotes to be eliminated. Because the technical amendments do not make any substantive change to the regulation, notice and comment on them was not required.</textblock>
    <textblock>IX. Final Regulatory Flexibility Act Analysis</textblock>
    <textblock>The Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. 601</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.) requires an agency to prepare a final regulatory flexibility analysis when the agency promulgates a final rule. Two of the requirements of a final regulatory flexibility analysis, a succinct statement of the need for and objectives of the rule, and a summary and assessment of issues raised by the public comments and of any changes made in the proposed rule as a result thereof (5 U.S.C. 604(b)), are contained in the summary and supplementary information above. No significant alternatives to the final rule were considered by the agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>X. Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980, 44 U.S.C. 3507, and 5 CFR 1320.130, the Board, under authority delegated by the Office of Management and Budget, has reviewed its amendments to Regulation O. The Board has determined that the revisions do not significantly increase the burden of the reporting institutions. The changes are expected to reduce regulatory burden for some banks, particularly small community banks and rural banks, but the estimated effect on aggregate burden calculations is not deemed to be significant.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 12 CFR Part 215</textblock>
    <textblock>Credit, Penalties, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set forth in the preamble, the Board is amending 12 CFR part 215 as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 215_LOANS TO EXECUTIVE OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, AND PRINCIPAL SHAREHOLDERS OF MEMBER BANKS (REGULATION O)</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 215 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>12 U.S.C. 248(i), 375a(10), 375b(9) and (10), 1817(k) and 1972(2)(G)(ii); Pub. L. 102-242, 105 Stat. 2236.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart A_Loans by Member Banks to Their Executive Officers, Directors, and Principal Shareholders</textblock>
    <textblock>2. 12 CFR part 215, subpart A, is amended by revising §§215.1 through 215.13, to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§215.1</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority, purpose, and scope.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority</textblock>
    <textblock>. This subpart is issued pursuant to sections 11(i), 22(g), and 22(h) of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 248(i), 375a, and 375b), 12 U.S.C. 1817(k), and section 306 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act of 1991 (Pub. L. 102-242, 105 Stat. 2236 (1991)).</textblock>
  </text>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>13</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Public Law 97-320, 96 Stat. 1469 (1982).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>13</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
