<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00106</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00062</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NATIONAL ARCHIVES AND RECORDS ADMINISTRATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Move of the John F. Kennedy Assassination Collection to the National Archives at College Park</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Archives and Records Administration (NARA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of closure and reopening of reference services for the John F. Kennedy assassination collection related to the move to the National Archives at College Park (Archives II).</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice provides information about the period of time that reference service on certain holdings of the National Archives will be unavailable due to the move of those holdings and the associated National Archives staff from the National Archives Building to the new Archives II facility. Additional notices will be published by NARA relating to the move of other holdings to Archives II.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order to prepare for and complete the move, reference services will be temporarily discontinued as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Requests for textual records to be reviewed in the research room will not be accepted after February 22, 1994. Requests for reproductions received after February 7, 1994, and written requests for information from the collection received after February 18, 1994, will be processed. Requests received after these cutoff dates will be returned for resubmission after April 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>All reference services will resume on April 1, 1994, at the National Archives at College Park, 8601 Adelphi Road, College Park, MD 20740-6001. Changes in the overall move schedule may require changes in these dates.</textblock>
    <textblock>Reference services for the records of the House Select Committee on Assassinations, the Senate Select Committee To Study Governmental Operations With Respect to Intelligence Activities (the Church Committee), and the House Select Committee on Intelligence (the Pike Committee) will still be available at the National Archives Building in Washington, DC. A reference set of these Congressional records will be part of the Collection at Archives II.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>For schedule updates, call the Access Staff at (202) 501-5313.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 16, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Trudy Huskamp Peterson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Archivist of the United States.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4178 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7515-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
