<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-1-00009</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-1-00003</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Interested parties who wish to introduce exhibits should provide the Presiding Officer at the hearing with 4 copies of such exhibits for the Official Record. Also, it would be helpful if additional copies are available for the use of other participants at the hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Prior documents in this proceeding:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Hearing: Issued December 3, 1992; published December 10, 1992 (57 FR 58418).</textblock>
    <textblock>Supplemental Notice of Hearing: Issued January 19, 1993; published January 29, 1993 (58 FR 6447).</textblock>
    <textblock>Recommended Decision: Issued November 29, 1993; published December 6, 1993 (58 FR 64176).</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 7 CFR Part 1040</textblock>
    <textblock>Milk marketing orders.</textblock>
    <textblock>The authority citation for 7 CFR part 1040 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Secs. 1-19, 48 Stat. 31, as amended; 7 U.S.C. 601-674.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed amendments, as set forth below, have not received the approval of the Secretary of Agriculture.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed by Michigan Milk Producers Association and Independent Cooperative Milk Producers Association:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposal No. 1</textblock>
    <textblock>Compute the same protein price for both handlers and producers on the basis of a cheese market price and a cheese yield formula, and include any residual value in the skim milk delivered by producers in the computation of the weighted average differential value.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed by Michigan Milk Producers Association:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposal No. 2</textblock>
    <textblock>Amend the pool supply plant shipping requirement provisions to allow the market administrator to adjust the shipping percentages as market conditions require.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed by White Knight Packaging Corporation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposal No. 3</textblock>
    <textblock>Include in the pool distributing plant definition a description of a plant located within the marketing area which processes at least 50 percent of its fluid milk receipts as ultra-high temperature fluid milk products for distribution in aseptic packages. A plant qualifying as a distributing plant under the new provision would be a pool plant under the Southern Michigan order regardless of its route disposition in the marketing area of any other Federal milk order.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposal No. 4</textblock>
    <textblock>Determine whether emergency marketing conditions exist that would warrant omission of a recommended decision with respect to Proposal No. 3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposal No. 5</textblock>
    <textblock>Make such changes as may be necessary to make the entire marketing agreement and order conform with any amendments thereto that may result from this hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of this notice of hearing and the order may be procured from the Market Administrator of the Southern Michigan marketing area, or from the Hearing Clerk, room 1083, South Building, United States Department of Agriculture, Washington, DC 20250, or may be inspected there.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the transcript of testimony taken at the hearing will not be available for distribution through the Hearing Clerk's Office. If you wish to purchase a copy, arrangements may be made with the reporter at the hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>From the time that a hearing notice is issued and until the issuance of a final decision in a proceeding, Department employees involved in the decisionmaking process are prohibited from discussing the merits of the hearing issues on an ex parte basis with any person having an interest in the proceeding. For this particular proceeding, the prohibition applies to employees in the following organizational units:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the Secretary of Agriculture.</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the Administrator, Agricultural Marketing Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the General Counsel.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dairy Division, Agricultural Marketing Service (Washington office only).</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the Market Administrator, Southern Michigan Marketing Area.</textblock>
    <textblock>Procedural matters are not subject to the above prohibition and may be discussed at any time.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lon Hatamiya,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4130 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
