<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00016</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-2-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Scope Rulings</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>International Trade Administration/Import Administration, Department of Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of scope rulings and anticircumvention inquiries.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Commerce (the Department) hereby publishes a list of scope rulings and anticircumvention inquiries completed between October 1, and December 31, 1993. In conjunction with this list, the Department is also publishing a list of pending requests for scope clarifications and anticircumvention inquiries. The Department intends to publish future lists within 30 days of the end of each quarter.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>David L. Guglielmi, Office of Antidumping Compliance, Import Administration, International Trade Administration, U.S. Department of Commerce, 14th Street and Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20230; telephone (202) 482-2704.</textblock>
    <textblock>Background:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Commerce regulations (19 CFR 353.29(d)(8) and 355.29(d)(8)) provide that on a quarterly basis the Secretary will publish in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>a list of scope rulings completed within the last three months.</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice lists scope rulings and anticircumvention inquiries completed between October 1, and December 31, 1993, and pending scope clarification and anticircumvention inquiry requests. The Department intends to publish in April 1994 a notice of scope rulings and anticircumvention inquiries completed between January 1, 1994, and March 31, 1994, as well as pending scope clarification and anticircumvention inquiry requests.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following lists provide the country, case reference number, requester(s), and a brief description of either the ruling or product subject to the request.</textblock>
    <textblock>Scope Rulings Completed Between October 1, 1993 and December 31, 1993:</textblock>
    <textblock>Country: Japan</textblock>
    <textblock>A-588-810: Mechanical Transfer Presses</textblock>
    <textblock>Aida Engineering, Ltd._The FMX cold forging press is within the scope of the order_11/23/93.</textblock>
    <textblock>A-588-817: Flat Panel Displays</textblock>
    <textblock>International Digital Electronics_Certain electroluminescent FPDs used in the Graphic Control Panels, models GP-410 and GP-430, are within the scope of the order; models GP-511T, GP-530T and GP-530VM terminated due to the revocation of the active-matrix FPD order_10/04/93.</textblock>
    <textblock>Country: Italy</textblock>
    <textblock>A-475-801: Antifriction Bearings (other than Tapered Roller Bearings) and Parts Thereof</textblock>
    <textblock>Fiber Services_Certain textile machinery components are outside the scope of the order_12/23/93.</textblock>
    <textblock>Anticircumvention Rulings Completed Between October 1, 1993 and December 31, 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>None.</textblock>
    <textblock>Scope Inquiries Terminated Between October 1, 1993 and</textblock>
    <textblock>December 31, 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>None</textblock>
  </further>
</doc>
