<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-1-00017</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-1-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Vessel Identification System</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Coast Guard</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>33 CFR Part 187</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[CGD 89-050]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 2115-AD35</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Coast Guard, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule; reopening of comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 5, 1993, the Coast Guard published a notice of proposed rulemaking (NPRM) regarding the establishment of a vessel identification system. The NPRM provided a 90-day comment period that closed on January 3, 1994. The Coast Guard is reopening the comment period for an additional 30 days.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before March 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments may be mailed to the Executive Secretary, Marine Safety Council (G-LRA/3406) (CGD 89-050), U.S. Coast Guard Headquarters, 2100 Second Street, SW., Washington, DC, 20593-0001, or comments may be delivered to room 3406 at the same address between the hours of 8 a.m. and 3 p.m., Monday through Friday, except Federal holidays. The telephone number is (202) 267-1477. Comments on the collection of information requirements must be mailed to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, Office of Management and Budget, 725 17th Street, NW., Washington, DC 20503, Attn: Desk Officer, U.S. Coast Guard.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Executive Secretary maintains the public docket for this notice. Comments will become part of this docket and will be available for inspection or copying at room 3406, U.S. Coast Guard Headquarters.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>LT David Fish, Office of Marine Safety, Security and Environmental Protection, Information Management Division, (202) 267-6044.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 5, 1993, the Coast Guard published an NPRM regarding the establishment of a vessel identification system (VIS) (58 FR 51920). The VIS proposal would establish a vessel identification system, as required by legislation, guidelines for State vessel titling systems, procedures for certifying compliance with those guidelines, and rules for participation in the VIS system for undocumented vessels. The Coast Guard has received a request to extend the comment period for six months. The Coast Guard has determined that in order to keep this important project moving in as timely a manner as possible, extending the comment period for six months would be inappropriate. However, the Coast Guard recognizes the value of data and information from interested parties. Therefore, the Coast Guard, in order to encourage meaningful participation by all interested parties, is reopening the comment period for an additional 30 days.</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons submitting comments should include their names and addresses, and identify this notice (CGD 89-050). All comments and attachments should be submitted in an unbound format suitable for copying and electronic filing. If not practical, a second copy of any bound materials is requested. Persons wanting acknowledgment of receipt of comments should enclose a stamped self-addressed post card or envelope.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>A.E. Henn,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Rear Admiral, U.S. Coast Guard, Chief, Office of Marine Safety, Security and Environmental Protection.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4204 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-14-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
