<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00040</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-0-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
    <textblock>Limit on Duty-Free Insular Watches in Calendar Year 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>AGENCIES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Import Administration, International Trade Administration, Department of Commerce; Office of Territorial and International Affairs, Department of the Interior.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>International Trade Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of Territorial and International Affairs</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>15 CFR Part 303</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 931090-4048]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 0625-AA06</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This action amends 15 CFR Part 303, which governs duty-exemption allocations and duty-refund entitlements for watch producers in the United States' insular possessions (the Virgin Islands, Guam and American Samoa) and the Northern Mariana Islands. The amendments establish the total quantity and territorial shares of duty-exemption for 1994 and adjust the wages considered creditable towards the production incentive certificate (PIC).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Faye Robinson, (202) 482-1660.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The insular possessions' watch industry provision in Section 110 of Public Law 97-446 (96 Stat. 2331) (1983) (19 U.S.C. 1202, note) requires the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of the Interior, acting jointly, to establish a limit on the quantity of watches and watch movements which may be entered free of duty during each calendar year. The law also requires the Secretaries to establish the shares of this limited quantity which may be entered from the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa and the Northern Mariana Islands. Regulations on the establishment of these quantities and shares are contained in §§303.3 and 303.4 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations (15 CFR 303.3 and 303.4). Section 303.6(h) gives the Secretaries authority to make the changes in §303.14.</textblock>
    <textblock>The rule also modifies §303.14(a)(1)(i) by increasing the dollar amount of wages per person that the Departments can consider in calculating the producers' allocations and PICs. The limit is raised to $35,000 in order to help attract and retain the managerial talent necessary to operate efficient watch assembly plants.</textblock>
    <textblock>We publish these revisions in proposed form on December 14, 1993 (58 FR 65294) and invited comments. We received no comments.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Departments establish for calendar year 1994 a total quantity and respective territorial shares as shown in the following table:</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the Administrative Procedure Act, 5 U.S.C. 553(d)(1), the effective date of this rule need not be delayed for 30 days because their rule relieves a restriction. The restriction is relieved by raising the amount of wages per person that the Departments can consider in calculating the producers' allocations and PICs.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule was not subject to review by the Office of Management and Budget under Executive Order 12866.</textblock>
    <textblock>This final rule does not contain policies with Federalism implications sufficient to warrant preparation of a Federalism assessment under Executive Order 12612.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the Regulatory Flexibility Act, 5 U.S.C. 601</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>., the General Counsel of the Department of Commerce has certified that this action will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities. Fewer than ten entities are directly affected by this action. The commercial benefits of the program governed by these regulations, for entities both directly and indirectly affected, are less than $10 million per year.</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>This rulemaking involves information collection activities subject to the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980, 44 U.S.C. 3501</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>., which are currently approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control numbers 0625-0040 and 0625-0134. The amendments will not increase the information burden on the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 15 CFR Part 303</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practice and procedure, American Samoa, Customs duties and inspection, Guam, Imports, Marketing quotas, Northern Mariana Islands, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Virgin Islands, Watches and jewelry.</textblock>
    <textblock>For reasons set forth above, we are amending part 303 as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 303_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 303 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Law 97-446, 96 Stat. 2331 (19 U.S.C. 1202, note); Public Law 94-241, 90 Stat. 263 (48 U.S.C. 1681, note).</textblock>
    <textblock>§303.14</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 303.14(a)(1)(i) is amended by removing ``$32,000'' and adding ``$35,000'' in its place.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Section 303.14(d)(1) is amended by removing ``Guam,'' before American Samoa.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Section 303.14(d)(2) is amended by adding ``and Guam'' after Virgin Islands and removing ``share'' and adding ``shares'' in its place.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Section 303.14(e) is amended by removing ``4,080,000'' and adding ``3,600,000'' in its place.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Virgin Islands</textblock>
    <textblock>3,600,000</textblock>
    <textblock>Guam</textblock>
    <textblock>500,000</textblock>
    <textblock>American Samoa</textblock>
    <textblock>500,000</textblock>
    <textblock>Northern Mariana Islands</textblock>
    <textblock>500,000</textblock>
    <textblock>n,s</textblock>
    <textblock>Total</textblock>
    <textblock>5,100,000</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Joseph A. Spetrini,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Assistant Secretary for Import Administration.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Leslie M. Turner,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary for Territorial and International Affairs.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4198 Filed 2-23-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DS-M and 4310-93-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
