<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940224-1-00055</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940224-1-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>For the reasons set forth in the preamble, 50 CFR part 685 is proposed to be amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 685_PELAGIC FISHERIES OF THE WESTERN PACIFIC REGION</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 685 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 1801</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. In ยง685.2, the definition of ``Pacific pelagic management unit species'' is amended by adding three new entries alphabetically to the list of species; the definition of ``protected species zone'' is amended by revising the last sentence of the definition; the definition of ``receiving vessel'' is revised; the definition of ``substantial financial investment'' is removed; and new definitions of ``Council'', ``Fisheries Management Division (FMD)'', ``Hawaii longline limited entry permit'', ``length overall or length'', ``longline fishing vessel'', ``longline general permit'', ``moratorium'', and ``receiving vessel permit'' are added in alphabetical order, to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง685.2</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Council</textblock>
    <textblock>means the Western Pacific Regional Fishery Management Council that was established under section 302 of the Magnuson Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Fisheries Management Division (FMD)</textblock>
    <textblock>means the Chief, Fisheries Management Division, Southwest Regional Office, National Marine Fisheries Service, 501 W. Ocean Boulevard, Suite 4200, Long Beach, CA 90802, or a designee.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Hawaii longline limited entry permit</textblock>
    <textblock>means the permit required by ยง685.9(a)(2) to use a vessel to fish for Pacific pelagic management unit species with longline gear in the EEZ or to land or transship longline-caught fish shoreward of the EEZ around Hawaii.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Length overall</textblock>
    <textblock>or</textblock>
    <textblock>length</textblock>
    <textblock>of a vessel means the length overall set forth in the Certificate of Documentation (CG-1270) issued by the U.S. Coast Guard for a documented vessel, or in a registration certificate issued by a state or the U.S. Coast Guard for an undocumented vessel (addresses available from 50 CFR part 611, subpart A, appendix A). For vessels that do not have the length overall stated in an official document, or for a vessel for which NMFS requests confirmation of the length overall, the length overall is the horizontal distance, rounded to the nearest foot, between the foremost part of the stern and the aftermost part of the stem, excluding bowsprits, rudders, outboard motor brackets, and similar fittings or attachments</textblock>
    <textblock>(see Figure 1 of this part).</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Longline fishing vessel</textblock>
    <textblock>means a vessel that has longline gear on board the vessel.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Longline general permit</textblock>
    <textblock>means the permit required by</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง685.9(a)(1) to use a vessel to fish for Pacific pelagic management unit species in the fishery management area excluding the EEZ around Hawaii, or to land or transship longline-caught fish shoreward of the outer boundary of the fishery management area, excluding the waters shoreward of the EEZ around Hawaii.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Moratorium</textblock>
    <textblock>means the moratorium on new entry into the Hawaii longline fishery in effect from April 23, 1991, through April 22, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
