<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00012</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 14(a)(2)(A) of Public Law 92-463, the Federal Advisory Committee Act, and in accordance with ยง101-6.1015(a) of title 41, Code of Federal Regulations, and following consultation with the Committee Management Secretariat of the General Services Administration, notice is hereby given that the Environmental Management Advisory Board has been renewed for a 2-year period beginning January 16, 1994. The Board will provide advice to the Assistant Secretary for Environmental Restoration and Waste Management.</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the Board is to provide the Assistant Secretary for Environmental Restoration and Waste Management with advice and recommendations on both the substance and the process of the Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement and other Environmental Management projects and issues, such as future land use, occupational and public health concerns and management control effectiveness, from the perspectives of affected groups and State and local Governments. Consensus recommendations to the Department of Energy from the Board on pragmatic nationwide resolution of numerous difficult issues will help achieve the Department's objective of an integrated environmental restoration program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Additionally, the renewal of the Environmental Management Advisory Board has been determined to be essential to the conduct of Department of Energy business and to be in the public interest in connection with the performance of duties imposed on the Department of Energy by law and agreement. The Board will operate in accordance with the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act, the Department of Energy Organization Act (Pub. L. 95-91), and rules and regulations issued in implementation of those Acts.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further information regarding this Advisory Board may be obtained from Rachel Murphy Samuel at (202) 586-3279.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC on January 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Renewal of Environmental Management Advisory Board</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Marcia L, Morris,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Advisory Committee Management Officer.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1607 Filed 1-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
