<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00030</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the provisions of the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended (5 U.S.C. 552a), notice is hereby given that the Department of the Interior is deleting from its inventory of Privacy Act systems of records a notice describing records maintained by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service. The systems of records notice being abolished is entitled ``Travel Records_Interior, FW-2,'' which was previously published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 6, 1983 (48 FR 54715). This system of records is no longer being maintained in the Department of the Interior.</textblock>
    <textblock>Prior to October 14, 1992, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service maintained a separate record of official employee travel for the purpose of processing travel authorizations and claims. With the establishment of the Departmentwide system of records ``Federal Financial System_Interior, OS-90'' (57 FR 47118), this system became obsolete. On December 14, 1992, the records maintained in this system were incorporated into the Federal Financial System.</textblock>
    <textblock>This change shall be effective on publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(January 26, 1994). Additional information regarding this action may be obtained from the Departmental Privacy Act Officer, Office of the Secretary, Office of Administrative Services, 1849 ``C'' Street NW., Mail Stop 5412 MIB, Washington, DC 20240, telephone (202) 208-6045.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Privacy Act of 1974_Deletion of System of Records</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Albert C. Camacho,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Administrative Services.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1638 Filed 1-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-55</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
