<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00070</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00033</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>This Notice is issued in accordance with the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act, Public Law 92-463, 5 U.S.C., Appendix I, and the Office of Management and Budget Circular A-63, Revised.</textblock>
    <textblock>The OCS Advisory Board SC will meet in plenary sessions on Wednesday, February 2, and Thursday, February 3, 1994, at the Hyatt Regency Reston, 1800 Presidents Street, Reston, Virginia 22090, telephone (703) 709-1234.</textblock>
    <textblock>The SC is an outside group of scientists which advises the Director, MMS, on the feasibility, appropriateness, and scientific value of the MMS' OCS Environmental Studies Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Below is a schedule of meetings that will occur.</textblock>
    <textblock>The SC will meet in plenary session on Wednesday, February 2, from 8:30 a.m. to noon, and in subcommittee from 1:30 p.m. to 5:30 p.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Committee will also meet in plenary session Thursday, February 3, from 8:15 a.m. to 5 p.m. Discussion will include the following subjects:</textblock>
    <textblock>•Committee Business and Resolutions</textblock>
    <textblock>•Environmental Studies Program Status Review</textblock>
    <textblock>•MMS Goals and Objectives</textblock>
    <textblock>The meetings are open to the public. Approximately 30 visitors can be accommodated on a first-come-first-served basis at the plenary session.</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the agenda may be requested from the MMS by writing Ms. Phyllis Treichel at the address below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other inquiries concerning the SC meeting should be addressed to Dr. Ken Turgeon, Executive Secretary to the Scientific Committee, Minerals Management Service, 381 Elden Street, Mail Stop 4310, Herndon, Virginia 22070. He may be reached by telephone at (703) 787-1717.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 6, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Outer Continental Shelf (OCS), Advisory Board Scientific Committee (SC); Notice of Plenary Session Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Alan D. Powers,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Director for Offshore Minerals Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1568 Filed 1-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-MR-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
