<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-1-00003</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-1-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 38 CFR Part 13</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative practices and procedures, Estates, Fraud, Handicapped, Infants and children, Investigations, Surety bonds, Trusts and trustees, Veterans.</textblock>
    <textblock>Approved: October 22, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jesse Brown,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set forth in the preamble, 38 CFR part 13 is proposed to be amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 13_VETERANS BENEFITS ADMINISTRATION, FIDUCIARY ACTIVITIES</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 13 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>72 Stat. 1114, 1232, as amended, 1237; 38 U.S.C. 501(a), 5502, 5503, 5711, unless otherwise noted.</textblock>
    <textblock>§13.59</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. In §13.59, paragraph (a), the last sentence is removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Section 13.100, paragraph (a)(1), is revised and an authority citation is added to read as follows: §13.100, paragraph (b) and its authority citation are revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§13.100</textblock>
    <textblock>Supervision of fiduciaries.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Require an accounting, formal or informal, of Department of Veterans Affairs benefits paid to the authorized payees listed under §13.55(b) (3), (4), (6), (7) or (8). Such accounting will include all information available to the fiduciary concerning the beneficiary's income and estate derived from non-Department of Veterans Affairs sources.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 38 U.S.C. 5502)</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Court-appointed fiduciaries.</textblock>
    <textblock>In court-appointed fiduciary cases, the Veterans Services Officer will take such informal action as may be necessary to assure that the needs of the beneficiary are provided for and Department of Veterans Affairs benefits are prudently administered and adequately protected. Formal or informal accountings may be required from such fiduciaries, with or without judicial proceedings. If an accounting is required such accounting will include all information requested, including all information available to the fiduciary concerning the beneficiary's income and estate derived from non-Department of Veterans Affairs sources.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Authority: 38 U.S.C. 501, 5502)</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1538 Filed 1-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8320-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
