<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00104</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00055</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Measles, Mumps, and Rubella Vaccine (MMR)</textblock>
    <textblock>What You Need to Know Before Your Child Gets the Vaccine</textblock>
    <textblock>What are Measles, Mumps, and Rubella?</textblock>
    <textblock>MMR vaccine is named for 3 diseases: Measles, Mumps, and Rubella.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each of these diseases can lead to serious problems, even death.</textblock>
    <textblock>Your child can be protected from measles, mumps, and rubella by</textblock>
    <textblock>the vaccine. These diseases are still found in our country,</textblock>
    <textblock>mostly because some people do not get the vaccines.</textblock>
    <textblock>Measles is spread easily from person to person, causing a rash,</textblock>
    <textblock>cough, and high fever. When children catch measles, some of them</textblock>
    <textblock>also get ear infections, pneumonia, diarrhea, seizures, hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>loss, or brain damage.</textblock>
    <textblock>Mumps also is easily passed from person to person. It usually</textblock>
    <textblock>causes fever, headache, and swollen glands under the jaw. It can</textblock>
    <textblock>also cause meningitis (an inflammation of the brain and spinal</textblock>
    <textblock>cord coverings), inflammation of the brain, or hearing loss. Men</textblock>
    <textblock>can get painful, swollen testicles from mumps.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rubella is also called German measles. It also passes from</textblock>
    <textblock>person to person. It causes a mild fever, swollen glands, and a</textblock>
    <textblock>rash. Sometimes it also causes arthritis (inflamed joints),</textblock>
    <textblock>especially in women. If a pregnant woman catches rubella, it is</textblock>
    <textblock>very dangerous for her unborn baby. Many women who have rubella</textblock>
    <textblock>when they are pregnant will lose their babies or have babies born</textblock>
    <textblock>with deafness, blindness, heart disease, brain damage, or other</textblock>
    <textblock>serious problems.</textblock>
    <textblock>Should Everyone Get the MMR Vaccine?</textblock>
    <textblock>Experts believe that almost all young children should get MMR.</textblock>
    <textblock>To help your doctor/nurse know what is best for your child,</textblock>
    <textblock>please answer the following questions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Please tell your doctor/nurse if the person getting the vaccine:</textblock>
    <textblock>•Has signs of illness today.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Has a parent, brother, or sister who has had seizures.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Has ever had a seizure.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Has gotten immune globulin or other blood products (such as a transfusion) during the past several months?</textblock>
    <textblock>If the answer is ``yes'' to any of these questions, your doctor/nurse</textblock>
    <textblock>might suggest getting the shot, coming back for it later, or not</textblock>
    <textblock>getting it at all.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Yes</textblock>
    <textblock>1No</textblock>
    <textblock>Is the person getting the vaccine:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Someone who had an allergic problem that required a medical visit right after MMR in the past?</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Less able than others to fight infection</textblock>
    <textblock>because of:</textblock>
    <textblock>A disease such as cancer or leukemia?</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>Special cancer treatments such as x-rays or drugs?</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>Drugs such as prednisone or other steroids?</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>An inborn or inherited disease?</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>(Children with HIV infection or AIDS</textblock>
    <textblock>should get</textblock>
    <textblock>MMR)</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Pregnant? Does she think she is pregnant or might get pregnant in the next 3 months?</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Allergic to eggs or neomycin (an antibiotic)?</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
