<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00077</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00039</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with Departmental policy, 28 CFR 50.7, notice is hereby given that a proposed consent decree in</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Lord Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>, Civil Action No. 94-4E, was lodged on January 3, 1994 with the United States District Court for the Western District of Pennsylvania. The Consent Decree requires the Lord Corporation to design and implement a groundwater treatment system for the Saegertown Industrial Area Site in Saegertown, Crawford County, Pennsylvania. The Consent Decree also requires Lord Corporation to pay a portion of the United States past and future costs associated with the Site.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Justice will receive, for a period of thirty (30) days from the date of this publication, comments relating to the proposed consent decree. Comments should be addressed to the Assistant Attorney General for the Environment and Natural Resources Division, Department of Justice, Washington, DC 20530, and should refer to</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Lord Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>, DOJ Ref.</textblock>
    <textblock>#</textblock>
    <textblock>90-11-2-870A.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed consent decree may be examined at the office of the United States Attorney, 633 Post Office &amp; Courthouse, 7th &amp; Grant Streets, Pittsburgh, PA 15219; the Region III Office of the Environmental Protection Agency, 841 Chestnut Building, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 19107; and at the Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., 4th Floor, Washington, DC 20005, (202) 624-0892. A copy of the proposed consent decree may be obtained in person or by mail from the Consent Decree Library, 1120 G Street, NW., 4th Floor, Washington, DC 20005. In requesting a copy please refer to the referenced case and enclose a check in the amount of $44.55 (25 cents per page reproduction costs), payable to the Consent Decree Library.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Lodging of Consent Decree Pursuant to the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John C. Cruden,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Environmental Enforcement Section, Environment and Natural Resources Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1629 Filed 1-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
