<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00062</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00025</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Public Law 92-463, notice is hereby given of the meeting of a review committee of the National Institute of Mental Health for February 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be open to the public as indicated below for the discussion of NIMH policy issues and will include current administrative, legislative, and program developments. Attendance by the public will be limited to space available.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be closed to the public as indicated below in accordance with the provisions set forth in sections 552b(c)(4) and 552(c)(6), title 5, U.S.C. and section 10(d) of Public Law 92-463, for the review, discussion and evaluation of individual grant applications. These applications and the discussions could reveal confidential trade secrets or commercial property such as patentable material, and personal information concerning individuals associated with the applications, the disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Joanna L. Kieffer, Committee Management Officer, National Institute of Mental Health, Parklawn Building, room 9-105, 5600 Fishers Lane, Rockville, MD 20857, Area Code 301, 443-4333, will provide a summary of the meeting and a roster of committee members.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other information pertaining to the meeting may be obtained from the contact person indicated.</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee Name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Clinical Subcommittee, Mental Health Special Projects Review Committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Phyllis L. Zusman, Parklawn Building, room 9C-18, Telephone: 301, 443-1340.</textblock>
    <textblock>Meeting Date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 4, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>Crowne Plaza Holiday Inn, 1750 Rockville Pike, Rockville, MD 20852.</textblock>
    <textblock>Open:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 4, 1994, 8:30 a.m.-9 a.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>Closed:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 4, 1994, 9 a.m._adjournment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals who plan to attend and need special assistance, such as sign language interpretation or other reasonable accommodations, should contact the contact person named above in advance of the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Program Numbers 93.126, Small Business Innovation Research; 93.176, ADAMHA Small Instrumentation Program Grants; 93.242, Mental Health Research Grants; 93.281, Mental Research Scientist Development Award and Research Scientist Development Award for Clinicians; 93.282, Mental Health Research Service Awards for Research Training; and 93.921, ADAMHA Science Education Partnership Award.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 13, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Institutes of Health</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Institute of Mental Health; Notice of Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Susan K. Feldman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Committee Management Officer, NIH.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1745 Filed 1-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4140-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
