<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00107</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00055</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>OPV.</textblock>
    <textblock>Almost all people who get OPV will not have any problems at all. Extremely rarely, a person will get polio from the first dose of vaccine and, even more rarely, from a later dose.</textblock>
    <textblock>Children who recently got OPV have the vaccine virus in their throats for a week and in their stool for a month or sometimes longer. People who have close contact (for example, kissing or changing diapers) with someone who got OPV can get infected by the virus. Extremely rarely, if they have not already gotten the vaccine against polio, they can get polio disease. If you have a</textblock>
    <textblock>child getting OPV and you never got the polio vaccine, ask your doctor/nurse about getting IPV for yourself.</textblock>
    <textblock>IPV.</textblock>
    <textblock>Inactivated polio vaccine is not known to cause any problems other than a little soreness or redness where the shot</textblock>
    <textblock>is given.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a serious or unusual problem occurs after getting any vaccine,</textblock>
    <textblock>call a doctor or get the person to a doctor right away.</textblock>
    <textblock>What is the Injury Compensation Program?</textblock>
    <textblock>The National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program is a U.S. government program that gives compensation (payment) for some persons thought to be injured by vaccines. For facts about this program, call this toll-free number: 1-800-338-2382.</textblock>
    <textblock>If you believe that the person getting the vaccine had a serious problem because of the vaccine, tell the doctor/nurse or health department. Ask him or her to report the problem on a Vaccine Adverse Event Report form. If you want to report it yourself, you can get the form by calling this toll-free number:</textblock>
    <textblock>1-800-822-7967.</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Public Health Service, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</textblock>
    <textblock>Polio 00/00/94 (Proposed)</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 300aa-26</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
