<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00085</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00047</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 14, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463, as amended), notice is hereby given that a meeting of the National Council on the Humanities will be held in Washington, DC on February 10-11, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the meeting is to advise the Chairman of the National Endowment for the Humanities with respect to policies, programs, and procedures for carrying out his functions, and to review applications for financial support and gifts offered to the Endowment and to make recommendations thereon to the Chairman.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held in the Old Post Office Building, 1100 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Washington, DC. A portion of the morning and afternoon sessions on February 10-11, 1994, will not be open to the public pursuant to subsections (c)(4), (6) and (9)(B) of section 552b of Title 5, United States Code because the Council will consider information that may disclose: Trade secrets and commercial or financial information obtained from a person and privileged or confidential; information of a personal nature the disclosure of which will constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy; and information the disclosure of which would significantly frustrate implementation of proposed agency action. I have made this determination under the authority granted me by the Chairman's Delegation of Authority dated July 19, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agenda for the sessions on February 10, 1994, will be as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>The morning session on February 11, 1994, will convene at 9 a.m., in the 1st Floor Council Room, M-09, and will be open to the public. The agenda for the morning session will be as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>(Coffee for Council Members from 8:30-9 a.m.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Minutes of the Previous Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>Reports</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Introductory Remarks</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Introduction of New Staff</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Contracts Awarded in the Previous Quarter</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Budget Report</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Legislative Report/Reauthorization</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Committee Reports on Policy and General Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Overview</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Education Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Fellowships Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Research Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Preservation and Access</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Public Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>7. State Programs and Office of Outreach</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Jefferson Lecture</textblock>
    <textblock>G. Challenge Grants: Policy Discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>The remainder of the proposed meeting will be given to the consideration of future budget requests and specific applications (closed to the public for the reasons stated above).</textblock>
    <textblock>Further information about this meeting can be obtained from Mr. David C. Fisher, Advisory Committee Management Officer, Washington, DC 20506, or call area code (202) 606-8322, TDD (202) 606-8282. Advance notice of any special needs or accommodations is appreciated.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NATIONAL FOUNDATION ON THE ARTS AND THE HUMANITIES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Council on the Humanities; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>8:30-9 a.m</textblock>
    <textblock>Coffee for Council Members (Open to the Public)</textblock>
    <textblock>_Room 527.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>i0Committee Meetings</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>i0(Open to the Public) Policy Discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>9-10 a.m</textblock>
    <textblock>Education Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>_Room M-14.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Fellowships Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>_Room 315.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>_Room 415.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Research Programs/</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Preservation and Access</textblock>
    <textblock>_Room M-07.</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>State Programs and Office of Outreach</textblock>
    <textblock>_Room 507.</textblock>
    <textblock>10 a.m. until adjourned</textblock>
    <textblock>(Closed to the Public for the reasons stated above)_Consideration of specific applications</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>i0(Closed to the Public)</textblock>
    <textblock>3 p.m. until adjourned</textblock>
    <textblock>Jefferson Lecture Committee to review Jefferson Lecture nominees</textblock>
    <textblock>_Room 430.</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David C. Fisher,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Advisory Committee Management Officer.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1586 Filed 1-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7537-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
