<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00105</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00055</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>When Should Your Child Get the MMR Vaccine?</textblock>
    <textblock>Most children should have a total of 2 MMR vaccines. They should</textblock>
    <textblock>get vaccine at:</textblock>
    <textblock>12 to 15 months of age AND</textblock>
    <textblock>when starting school OR when starting middle school or</textblock>
    <textblock>junior high school</textblock>
    <textblock>These vaccines may be given at the same time as other childhood</textblock>
    <textblock>vaccines.</textblock>
    <textblock>People who do not know if they are protected against measles,</textblock>
    <textblock>mumps, and rubella should ask their doctor/nurse about getting</textblock>
    <textblock>MMR.</textblock>
    <textblock>Are There Risks With MMR?</textblock>
    <textblock>The MMR vaccine is the best way to protect your child against</textblock>
    <textblock>these 3 serious diseases. But there are risks with any medicine,</textblock>
    <textblock>including vaccines. There is a very small chance that serious</textblock>
    <textblock>problems, even death, could occur after getting vaccines. The</textblock>
    <textblock>risk from the vaccine is much smaller than the risk from the</textblock>
    <textblock>diseases.</textblock>
    <textblock>Most people who get MMR will not have any problems at all. Some</textblock>
    <textblock>will have minor problems like: soreness, redness, or swelling</textblock>
    <textblock>where the shot is given; mild fever; rash; a little swelling of</textblock>
    <textblock>the glands in the cheeks, neck, or under the jaw. Occasionally,</textblock>
    <textblock>pain, stiffness, or swelling in the joints (arthritis) may occur,</textblock>
    <textblock>usually 1-3 weeks after getting the vaccine. The arthritis</textblock>
    <textblock>usually does not last long. Occasionally, it lasts or comes and</textblock>
    <textblock>goes for months or longer. Young women are more likely than</textblock>
    <textblock>children to have joint problems.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rarely, more serious problems may come within 3 weeks of getting</textblock>
    <textblock>MMR. Usually they do not cause lasting harm. These rare</textblock>
    <textblock>problems include: Severe allergic problems; seizures (usually</textblock>
    <textblock>caused by fever); and low number of platelets (a type of blood</textblock>
    <textblock>cells). Other rare serious problems have been seen after MMR was</textblock>
    <textblock>given, but it is not known if the vaccine caused the problems.</textblock>
    <textblock>These problems are even more rare than the ones above and include</textblock>
    <textblock>hearing loss and inflammation of the brain that could lead to</textblock>
    <textblock>lasting damage.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a serious or unusual problem occurs after getting any vaccine,</textblock>
    <textblock>call a doctor or get the person to a doctor right away.</textblock>
    <textblock>What Is the Injury Compensation Program?</textblock>
    <textblock>The National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program is a U.S.</textblock>
    <textblock>government program that gives compensation (payment) for some</textblock>
    <textblock>persons thought to be injured by vaccines. For facts about this</textblock>
    <textblock>program, call this toll-free number: 1-800-338-2382.</textblock>
    <textblock>If you believe that the person getting the vaccine had a serious</textblock>
    <textblock>problem because of the vaccine, tell the doctor/nurse or health</textblock>
    <textblock>department. Ask him or her to report the problem on a Vaccine</textblock>
    <textblock>Adverse Event Report form. If you want to report it yourself,</textblock>
    <textblock>you can get the form by calling this toll-free number:</textblock>
    <textblock>1-800-822-7967.</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services,</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Health Service,</textblock>
    <textblock>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</textblock>
    <textblock>MMR 00/00/94 (Proposed)</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 300aa-26</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
