<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00113</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00058</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Correction of Table</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice corrects a table in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>notice on the availability of draft documents proposing Ambient Water Quality Criteria for the protection of aquatic life for two chemicals which appeared at 58 FR 61910. In the table on page 61911, the column headed Proposed FW acute criterion for the entry Aniline is corrected to read 28 μg/L and the column headed Proposed FW chronic criterion for the entry Aniline is corrected to read 14 μg/L. The table as corrected is shown below:</textblock>
    <textblock>Request for Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA is soliciting comments on the proposed criteria documents and extending the comment period for an additional 60 days to March 25, 1994. If issued in final form, the proposed documents would supersede material specific to the aquatic life toxicity of these chemicals as published in any previous ambient water quality criteria documents. Specifically, Acute and Chronic Criteria for the protection of aquatic life within proposed ``Ambient Aquatic Life Water Quality Criteria for 2,4-DIMETHYLPHENOL'' would, upon finalization, supersede guidance given in the previous Ambient Water Quality Criteria for 2,4-dimethylphenol (USEPA, 1980). The proposed criteria were derived using improved procedures and additional information.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Agency is soliciting additional toxicological data on the pollutants covered by today's notice. Data suitable (as specified in the Agency's guidelines for developing aquatic life criteria) for determining the bioconcentration of Aniline in freshwater (FW) or saltwater (SW) organisms is of particular interest. The Agency is also soliciting comments on the scientific basis for the criteria values, the appropriate analytical techniques for measuring attainment of criteria, and the allowable duration and frequency for exceeding the criteria. The proposed criteria announced today, if published in final form, would serve as guidance to the States in developing water quality standards pursuant to 40 CFR part 131.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Pollutant</textblock>
    <textblock>1CWA 307(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>priority</textblock>
    <textblock>pollutant</textblock>
    <textblock>1Proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>FW acute</textblock>
    <textblock>criterion</textblock>
    <textblock>1Proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>SW acute</textblock>
    <textblock>criterion</textblock>
    <textblock>1Proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>FW chronic</textblock>
    <textblock>criterion</textblock>
    <textblock>1Proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>SW chronic</textblock>
    <textblock>criterion</textblock>
    <textblock>Aniline</textblock>
    <textblock>No</textblock>
    <textblock>28 μg/L</textblock>
    <textblock>77 μg/L</textblock>
    <textblock>14 μg/L</textblock>
    <textblock>37 μg/L</textblock>
    <textblock>2,4-Dimethylphenol</textblock>
    <textblock>Yes</textblock>
    <textblock>1,300 μg/L</textblock>
    <textblock>270 μg/L</textblock>
    <textblock>530 μg/L</textblock>
    <textblock>110 μg/L</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Martha G. Prothro,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Assistant Administrator for Water.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1623 Filed 1-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
