<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00103</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00055</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Are There Risks With DTP?</textblock>
    <textblock>The DTP vaccine is the best way to protect your child against</textblock>
    <textblock>these 3 serious diseases. But there are risks with any medicine,</textblock>
    <textblock>including vaccines. There is a very small chance that serious</textblock>
    <textblock>problems, even death, could occur after getting vaccines. The</textblock>
    <textblock>risk from the vaccine is much smaller than the risk from the</textblock>
    <textblock>diseases.</textblock>
    <textblock>About half the children who get DTP will not have any problems at</textblock>
    <textblock>all. Some will have minor problems like: soreness, redness, or</textblock>
    <textblock>swelling where the shot is given; fever; fussiness; drowsiness;</textblock>
    <textblock>less appetite. Rarely, after DTP such problems have been noted</textblock>
    <textblock>as: crying non-stop for 3 hours or more; fever of 105</textblock>
    <textblock>○F or</textblock>
    <textblock>higher; seizures (usually caused by fever); collapse or fainting.</textblock>
    <textblock>None of these problems is known to cause any lasting harm, but</textblock>
    <textblock>they are scary. Very rarely, DTP causes long seizures, decreased</textblock>
    <textblock>consciousness, or coma that does not last. Also very rarely, DT,</textblock>
    <textblock>Td, and the diphtheria-tetanus part of DTP and DTaP cause severe</textblock>
    <textblock>allergic problems or Guillain-Barré Syndrome (sudden weakness and</textblock>
    <textblock>numbness that may go on to paralysis). Lasting brain damage</textblock>
    <textblock>after DTP has not been proven. If DTP ever causes lasting brain</textblock>
    <textblock>damage, it is very rare.</textblock>
    <textblock>DTaP causes fewer of the minor problems than DTP does. Experts</textblock>
    <textblock>do not know if the rare serious problems reported after DTP</textblock>
    <textblock>happen less often after DTaP.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a serious or unusual problem occurs after getting any vaccine,</textblock>
    <textblock>call a doctor or get the person to a doctor right away.</textblock>
    <textblock>What is the Injury Compensation Program?</textblock>
    <textblock>The National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program is a U.S.</textblock>
    <textblock>government program that gives compensation (payment) for some</textblock>
    <textblock>persons thought to be injured by vaccines. For facts about this</textblock>
    <textblock>program, call this toll-free number: 1-800-338-2382.</textblock>
    <textblock>If you believe that the person getting the vaccine had a serious</textblock>
    <textblock>problem because of the vaccine, tell the doctor/nurse or health</textblock>
    <textblock>department. Ask him or her to report the problem on a Vaccine</textblock>
    <textblock>Adverse Event Report form. If you want to report it yourself,</textblock>
    <textblock>you can get the form by calling this toll-free number:</textblock>
    <textblock>1-800-822-7967.</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Public Health Service, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</textblock>
    <textblock>DTP 00/00/94 (Proposed)</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 300aa-26</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
