<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00051</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Petition of Totem Ocean Trailer Express, Inc.; Extension of Time for Replies</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice was published on January 6, 1994, 59 FR 748, of the filing of a petition by Totem Ocean Trailer Express, Inc. pursuant to 46 CFR 514.8(a), for permanent exemption of its Local Freight Tariff No. 3-C, FMC_F No. 4, ICC TOTE 201, from the electronic tariff filing requirements of the Commission's ATFI System, on the grounds that the tariff is jointly filed with the Interstate Commerce Commission and the Federal Maritime Commission, and is therefore not compatible with the ATFI filing requirements. Alternatively, petitioner seeks complete exemption from filing the tariff in paper or electronic form.</textblock>
    <textblock>Upon the request of Sea-Land Service, Inc., the Commission has now determined to extend the time provided for interested persons to reply to the petition. Replies are now due by February 17, 1994, and shall be directed to the Secretary, Federal Maritime Commission, Washington, DC 20573-0001, shall consist of an original and 15 copies, and shall be served on Counsel for petitioner, Mr. Michael D. Duppenthaler, Registered Practioner, Interstate Commerce Commission, 1100 Olive Way, suite 1150, Seattle, Washington 98101-1839.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the petition are available for examination at the Washington, DC office of the Secretary of the Commission, 800 N. Capitol Street, NW., room 1046.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL MARITIME COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Petition for Permanent Filing Exemption; Petition No. P108-93]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Petition No. P108-93</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Ronald D. Murphy,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1611 Filed 1-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6730-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
