<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00069</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940126-2-00032</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The proposal for the collection of information listed below has been submitted to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for approval under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. Chapter 35). Copies of the proposed information collection requirement and related form and explanatory material may be obtained by contacting Jeane Kalas at (303) 231-3046. Comments and suggestions on the requirement should be made directly to the Bureau Clearance Officer at the telephone number listed below, and to the OMB Paperwork Reduction Project, Washington, DC 20503, telephone (202) 395-7340.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Form MMS-4393_Request to Exceed Regulatory Allowance Limitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abstract:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Minerals Management Service (MMS) Royalty Management Program is proposing a new form to be used by royalty payors on Federal or Indian mineral leases when requesting MMS approval to exceed established transportation or processing allowance limits. The form will be included with the payor's request to exceed allowance limits in order to ensure that MMS receives the lease data required to make a decision on the request.</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau Form Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>MMS-4393.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency:</textblock>
    <textblock>Annually.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Oil and gas companies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Completion Time:</textblock>
    <textblock>Average of one-half hour.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Responses:</textblock>
    <textblock>50.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Burden Hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>25.</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau Clearance Officer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Arthur Quintana (703) 787-1101.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 13, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Minerals Management Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Information Collection Submitted to the Office of Management and Budget for Review Under the Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>James W. Shaw,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Director for Royalty Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1635 Filed 1-25-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-MR-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
