<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00103</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00079</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>TENNESSEE VALLEY AUTHORITY</textblock>
    <textblock>[Meeting No. 1464]</textblock>
  </text>
  <date>
    <textblock>TIME AND DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>10 a.m. (EST), February 23, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>PLACE:</textblock>
    <textblock>TVA Knoxville Office Complex, 400 West Summit Hill Drive, Knoxville, Tennessee.</textblock>
    <textblock>STATUS:</textblock>
    <textblock>Open.</textblock>
    <textblock>AGENDA:</textblock>
    <textblock>Approval of minutes of meeting held on January 19, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Action Items</textblock>
    <textblock>New Business</textblock>
    <textblock>C_Energy</textblock>
    <textblock>C1. Award of a 3-year Contract to Norfolk Southern Railway Company for Transportation of Coal to John Sevier Fossil Plant.</textblock>
    <textblock>C2. Contract Extension with CSX Transportation for Transportation of Coal to Kingston Fossil Plant.</textblock>
    <textblock>E_Real Property</textblock>
    <textblock>E1. Sale of Permanent and Temporary Construction Easements to the City of Tupelo Affecting Approximately 1.1 Acre of Land in Lee County, Mississippi.</textblock>
    <textblock>E2. Sale of Land at Public Auction Affecting Approximately an Acre Portion of TVA's Bowling Green, Kentucky, Customer Service Center Property in Warren County, Kentucky.</textblock>
    <textblock>E3. Sale at Public Auction of a Coal Lease Affecting Approximately 1,690 Acres of the Red Bird Coal Reserves in Clay and Leslie Counties, Kentucky.</textblock>
    <textblock>E4. Addition of Commercial Recreation to Planned Tract Allocation and Proposed 19-Year Commercial Recreation Lease Affecting Approximately 11.98 Acres of Land on Chickamauga Reservoir, Meigs County, Tennessee.</textblock>
    <textblock>E5. Sale of Noncommercial, Nonexclusive Permanent Easements to Three Individuals for Construction and Maintenance of Recreational Water-Use Facilities Affecting Approximately 0.46 Acre of Tellico Lake Shoreline, Monroe and Loudon Counties, Tennessee.</textblock>
    <textblock>F_Unclassified</textblock>
    <textblock>F1. Approval to Enter into a Contract with Stone and Webster Engineering Corporation, Subject to Satisfactory Negotiations and Final Review Prior to Execution.</textblock>
    <textblock>F2. Supplement No. 1 to Procurement Contract Nos. TV-92PGN77052E-01 and -02 with FD Engineers and Constructors, Subject to Satisfactory Negotiations and Final Review Prior to Execution.</textblock>
    <textblock>F3. Proposed TVA Policy on Contracting Decisions.</textblock>
    <textblock>F4. Proposed Policy for Utilization of Tennessee Valley Region Businesses.</textblock>
    <textblock>CONTACT PERSON FOR MORE INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ron Loving, Vice President, Governmental Relations, or a member of his staff can respond to requests for information about this meeting. Call (615) 732-6000, Knoxville, Tennessee. Information is also available at TVA's Washington Office (202) 898-2999.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 16, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Edward S. Christenbury,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>General Counsel and Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4074 Filed 2-17-94; 3:19 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8120-08-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
