<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00092</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00072</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Intent To Rule on Application To Use the Revenues From a Passenger Facility Charge (PFC) at Washington National Airport, Washington, DC</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of intent to rule on application.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA proposes to rule and invites public comment on the application to use the revenue from a PFC at Washington National Airport under the provisions of the Aviation Safety and Capacity Expansion Act of 1990 (Title IX of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990) (Pub. L. 101-508) and part 158 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (14 CFR part 158).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before March 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this application may be mailed or delivered in triplicate to the FAA at the following address: Washington Airports District Office, 101 West Broad Street, suite 300, Falls Church, Virginia 22046.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, one copy of any comments submitted to the FAA must be mailed or delivered to Mr. James A. Wilding, General Manager of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority, at the following address: Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority, 44 Canal Center Plaza, Alexandria, Virginia 22314.</textblock>
    <textblock>Air carriers and foreign air carriers may submit copies of written comments previously provided to the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority under Section 158.23 of Part 158.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Robert Mendez, Manager, Washington Airports District Office 101 West Broad Street, Suite 300 Falls Church, Virginia 22046. The application may be reviewed in person at this same</textblock>
    <textblock>location.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA proposes to rule and invites public comment on the application to use the revenues from a PFC at Washington National Airport under the provisions of the Aviation Safety and Capacity Expansion Act of 1990 (Title IX of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990) (Pub. L. 101-508) and part III 158 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (14 CFR part 158.)</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 22, 1993, the FAA determined that the application to use the revenue from a PFC submitted by The Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority was substantially complete within the requirements of ยง158.25 of part 158. The FAA will approve or disapprove the application, in whole or in part, no later than April 14, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following is a brief overview of the application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Level of the proposed PFC:</textblock>
    <textblock>$3.00</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed charge effective date:</textblock>
    <textblock>November 1, 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed charge expiration date:</textblock>
    <textblock>November 1, 2000</textblock>
    <textblock>Total estimated PFC revenue:</textblock>
    <textblock>$166,739,071</textblock>
    <textblock>Brief description of proposed project(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>_New Thirty-five Gate North Passenger Terminal Complex including Metro Station, utility relocation, connector and signage.</textblock>
    <textblock>Class or classes of air carriers which the public agency has requested not be required to collect PFCs: Part 135 On Demand Air Taxis filing FAA Form 1800-31.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person may inspect the application in person at the FAA office listed above under</textblock>
    <textblock>``FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT''</textblock>
    <textblock>and at the FAA regional Airports office located at: Fitzgerald Federal Building, John F. Kennedy International Airport, Jamaica, New York 11430.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, any person may, upon request, inspect the application, notice and other documents germane to the application in person at The Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Jamaica, New York on February 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Peter A. Nelson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Manager, Airports Division, Eastern Region.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3892 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
