<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00004</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY</textblock>
    <textblock>FEDERAL RESERVE SYSTEM</textblock>
    <textblock>FEDERAL DEPOSIT INSURANCE CORPORATION</textblock>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY</textblock>
    <textblock>Risk-Based Capital Standards; Concentration of Credit Risk and Risks of Nontraditional Activities</textblock>
    <textblock>AGENCIES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC), Treasury; Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (Board); Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC); and Office of Thrift Supervision (OTS), Treasury.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of the Comptroller of the Currency</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>12 CFR Part 3</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 94-01]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>12 CFR Part 208</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. R-0764]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>12 CFR Part 325</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 3064-AB15</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of Thrift Supervision</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>12 CFR Part 567</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93-90]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1550-AA59</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of proposed rulemaking.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The OCC, the Board, the FDIC and the OTS (collectively ``the agencies'') are issuing this proposed rule to implement the portions of section 305 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act of 1991 (FDICIA) that require the agencies to revise their risk-based capital standards for insured depository institutions to ensure that those standards take adequate account of concentration of credit risk and the risks of nontraditional activities. The intended effect of this proposed rule is to ensure that the agencies take adequate account of concentration of credit risk and the risks of nontraditional activities in assessing an institution's capital adequacy. The proposed rule amends the risk-based capital standards by explicitly identifying concentration of credit risk and certain risks arising from nontraditional activities, as well as an institution's ability to manage these risks, as important factors in assessing an institution's overall capital adequacy.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments must be received on or before March 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested parties are invited to submit written comments to any or all of the agencies. All comments will be shared among the agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>OCC:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments should be submitted to Docket No. 94-01, Communications Division, Ninth Floor, Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, 250 E Street, SW., Washington, DC 20219. Attention: Karen Carter. Comments will be available for inspection and photocopying at that address.</textblock>
    <textblock>Board:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments, which should refer to Docket No. R-0764, may be mailed to Mr. William Wiles, Secretary, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, 20th and Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20551. Comments addressed to Mr. Wiles may also be delivered to the Board's mail room between 8:45 a.m. and 5:15 p.m. and to the security control room outside of those hours. Both the mail room and control room are accessible from the courtyard entrance on 20th Street between Constitution Avenue and C Street, NW. Comments may be inspected in room B-1122 between 9 a.m. and 5 p.m., except as provided in ยง261.8 of the Board's Rules Regarding Availability of Information, 12 CFR 261.8.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDIC:</textblock>
    <textblock>Robert E. Feldman, Acting Executive Secretary, Attention: room F-402, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, 550 17th Street, NW., Washington, DC 20429. Comments may be hand-delivered to room F-400, 1776 F Street NW., Washington, DC, on business days between 8:30 a.m. and 5 p.m. (FAX number (202) 898-3838). Comments will be available for inspection and photocopying in room 7118, 550 17th Street, NW., Washington, DC 20429, between 9 a.m. and 4:30 p.m. on business days.</textblock>
  </address>
</doc>
