<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00039</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00031</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>1. The Commission has before it the following regulations for renewal of license:</textblock>
    <textblock>(Seeking renewal of the licenses of Stations KFUO/KFUO-FM)</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Pursuant to section 309(e) of the communications Act of 1934, as amended, the above application has been designated for hearing on the issues set forth below:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. To determine the extent to which the licensee of Stations KFUO/KFUO-FM complied with the affirmative action provisions specified in §73.2080(b) of the Commission's Rules, 47 CFR 73.2080.</textblock>
    <textblock>a. To determine whether the licensee of Stations KFUO/KFUO-FM made misrepresentations of fact or was lacking in candor in violation of §73.1015 of the Commission's Rules, 47 CFR 73.1015, with regard to the stations' EEO program and documents submitted in support thereof.</textblock>
    <textblock>c. To determine whether, in light of evidence adduced pursuant to the foregoing issues, a grant of the subject license renewal applications would serve the public interest, convenience and necessity.</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the complete Hearing Designation Order in this proceeding is available for inspection and copying during normal business hours in the FCC Dockets Branch (Room 32), 1919 M Street, NW., Washington, DC. The complete text may also be purchased from the Commission's duplicating contractor, International Transcription Services, Inc., 2100 M Street, NW., suite 140, Washington, DC 20037 (telephone 202-857-3800).</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Renewal Applications Designated for Hearing</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Applicant</textblock>
    <textblock>1City/State</textblock>
    <textblock>1File Nos.</textblock>
    <textblock>1MM docket No.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Lutheran Church/Missouri Synod</textblock>
    <textblock>Clayton, MO</textblock>
    <textblock>BR-890929VC</textblock>
    <textblock>BRH-890929VB</textblock>
    <textblock>94-10</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William F. Caton,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3857 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
