<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00057</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00049</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Receipt of Applications for Permit</textblock>
    <textblock>The following applicants have applied for a permit to conduct certain activities with endangered species. This notice is provided pursuant to section 10(c) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973, as amended (16 U.S.C. 1531,</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.):</textblock>
    <textblock>PRT-702631</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant: U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Regional Director, Region 1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant requests amendment to their current permit to include take activities for: Callippe silverspot butterfly (</textblock>
    <textblock>Speyeria callippe callippe</textblock>
    <textblock>), Behren's silverspot butterfly (</textblock>
    <textblock>Speyeria zerene beherensii</textblock>
    <textblock>) and Alameda whipsnake (</textblock>
    <textblock>Masicophis lateralis euryxanthus</textblock>
    <textblock>) for the purpose of scientific research and enhancement of propagation or survival, if or when they become Federally protected as endangered or threatened by the Endangered Species Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>PRT-784974</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant: Ohio State University, Columbus, OH.</textblock>
    <textblock>The applicant requests a permit to export eight captive-bred Cotton-top tamarins to (</textblock>
    <textblock>Saguinus oedipus</textblock>
    <textblock>) to Columbia, South America, for the purpose scientific research aimed at the conservation of the species.</textblock>
    <textblock>PRT-786485</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant: Dr. Charles Bechert II, Fort Lauderdale, FL.</textblock>
    <textblock>The applicant requests a permit to import the sport-hunted trophy of one male bontebok (</textblock>
    <textblock>Damaliscus dorcas dorcas</textblock>
    <textblock>) culled from the captive herd maintained by H.Z. Kock, ``Verborgenfontein'', Merriman, Republic of South Africa, for the purpose of enhancement of survival of the species.</textblock>
    <textblock>PRT-784254</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant: AAZPA SSP for Black Rhino, Brownsville, TX.</textblock>
    <textblock>The applicant requests a permit to import two captive-held Black rhinoceros (</textblock>
    <textblock>Diceros bicornis minor</textblock>
    <textblock>) from Zimbabwe to enhance the propagation or survival of the species through captive-breeding. These rhinos were wild-caught during a rhino conservation translocation operation undertaken by Zimbabwe's Department of National Parks and Wildlife.</textblock>
    <textblock>PRT-786600</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant: National Marine Fisheries Service, Southwest Region, Long Beach, CA.</textblock>
    <textblock>The applicant requests a permit to import 50 dead specimens of the following sea turtle species: green (</textblock>
    <textblock>Chelonia mydas</textblock>
    <textblock>), hawksbill (</textblock>
    <textblock>Eretmochelys imbricata</textblock>
    <textblock>), leatherback (</textblock>
    <textblock>Dermochelys coriacea</textblock>
    <textblock>), olive ridley (</textblock>
    <textblock>Lepidochelys olivacea</textblock>
    <textblock>) and loggerhead (</textblock>
    <textblock>Caretta caretta</textblock>
    <textblock>), for biometrics, necropsy, and analysis of stomach contents to enhance the propagation and survival of the species.</textblock>
    <textblock>PRT-784960</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant: Dr. Kenneth Counts, Vilonia, AR.</textblock>
    <textblock>The applicant requests a permit to purchase in interstate commerce 3 captive-bred San Francisco Garter snakes (</textblock>
    <textblock>Thamnophis sirtalis tetrataenia</textblock>
    <textblock>) from Lloyd Lemke, Visalia, California to enhance the propagation or survival of the species through captive-breeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written data or comments should be submitted to the Director, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Office of Management Authority, 4401 North Fairfax Drive, room 432, Arlington, Virginia 22203 and must be received by the Director within 30 days of the date of this publication.</textblock>
    <textblock>Documents and other information submitted with these applications are available for review,</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to the requirements of the Privacy Act and Freedom of Information Act</textblock>
    <textblock>, by any party who submits a written request for a copy of such documents to the following office within 30 days of the date of publication of this notice: U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Office of Management Authority, 4401 North Fairfax Drive, room 420(c), Arlington, Virginia 22203. Phone: (703/358-2104); FAX: (703/358-2281).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Susan Jacobsen,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Chief, Branch of Permits, Office of Management Authority.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3848 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-55-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
