<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00022</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>National Emission Standards for Hazardous Air Pollutants; Permits for Early Reductions Sources</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>40 CFR Part 63</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4837-1]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule; reopening of comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA is reopening the comment period for a proposed rule for Early Reductions Permits published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of December 29, 1993 (58 FR 68804). Several persons who intend to submit comments concerning the proposed rule for Early Reductions Permits requested additional time to prepare their responses, beyond the 30 days originally provided. In consideration of these requests, EPA is reopening the comment period in order to give all interested persons the opportunity to comment fully.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments.</textblock>
    <textblock>The comment period is reopened. Comments must be received on or before March 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. A-93-08, containing supporting information used in developing the proposed rule is available for public inspection and copying between 8:30 a.m. and 3:30 p.m., Monday through Friday, at EPA's Air Docket, room M1500, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, 401 M Street, SW., Washington, DC. A reasonable fee may be charged for copying.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. David Beck, Emission Standards Division (MD-13), U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711, telephone (919) 541-5421.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on the proposed rule were to be received on or before January 28, 1994 (a 30 day comment period). The comment period is reopened until March 3, 1994. This extension of the comment period is consistent with Executive Order 12866, which states that ``each agency should afford the public a meaningful opportunity to comment on any proposed regulation, which in most cases should include a comment period of not less than 60 days.'' Reopening the comment period until March 3, 1994 will provide the public slightly more than the suggested 60 days.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Mary D. Nichols,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Administrator for Air and Radiation.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3894 Filed 02-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
