<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4839-4]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Acid Rain Program: Public Comment Period and Proposed Retired Unit Exemptions</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of proposed retired unit exemptions.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) is issuing for comment a draft, five-year retired unit exemption to a utility unit under the Acid Rain Program regulations (40 CFR part 72).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on the retired unit exemption must be received no later than 30 days after the date of this notice or the publication date of this notice in a local newspaper.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative Records.</textblock>
    <textblock>The administrative record, except information protected as confidential, may be viewed during normal business hours at EPA Region 5, 17th floor, Ralph H. Metcalfe Federal Bldg., 77 West Jackson Blvd., Chicago, IL 60604.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Send comments, requests for public hearings, and requests to receive notice of future actions concerning the retired unit exemption to David Kee, Director, Air and Radiation Division, EPA Region 5 (A-18J), Ralph H. Metcalfe Federal Bldg., 77 West Jackson Blvd., Chicago, IL 60604.</textblock>
    <textblock>Submit all comments in duplicate and identify the unit to which the comments apply, the commenter's name, address, and telephone number, and the commenter's interest in the matter and affiliation, if any, to the owners and operators of the unit covered by the exemption. All timely comments will be considered, except those pertaining to standard provisions under 40 CFR 72.9 and issues not relevant to the exemption.</textblock>
    <textblock>Hearings.</textblock>
    <textblock>To request a public hearing, state the issues proposed to be raised in the hearing. EPA may schedule a hearing if EPA finds that it will contribute to the decisionmaking process by clarifying significant issues affecting the exemption.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Call Pat Gimino, EPA Region V, at (312) 353-8651.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA proposes to issue exemptions from the Acid Rain permit and continuous emission monitoring requirements for Breed unit 1 in Indiana. The designated representative for Breed is John McManus.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Brian McLean,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Acid Rain Division, Office of Atmospheric Programs, Office of Air and Radiation.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3883 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
