<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00034</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Medicare Program; Limits on Payment to Health Maintenance Organizations (HMOs), Competitive Medical Plans (CMPs), and Health Care Prepayment Plans (HCPPs)</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>42 CFR Part 417</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[OCC-018-P]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 0938-AF16</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Health Care Financing Administration (HCFA), HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposed rule would remove the provision (never implemented) that would have made the adjusted average per capita cost (AAPCC) the absolute limit on payment for services furnished to Medicare enrollees by an HMO or CMP with a cost contract.</textblock>
    <textblock>This change is necessary to conform our rules to the interpretation of the statute as set forth in court decisions relating to payment of reasonable costs.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule would also provide for using the AAPCC as a presumptive limit, subject to exceptions, for HMOs and CMPs with cost contracts, and for health care prepayment plans (HCPPs) that furnish inpatient hospital care as well as part B services;</textblock>
    <textblock>Eliminate the effective incentives exception that is currently available to HCPPs;</textblock>
    <textblock>Require HCPPs that do not furnish inpatient hospital services to document that their costs do not exceed what Medicare's cost would have been if the Medicare beneficiaries who received the services had not enrolled in the HCPP; and revise the rules for reporting costs.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date: We will consider comments received no later than 5 p.m. on April 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mail written comments (1 original and 3 copies) to the following address:</textblock>
    <textblock>Health Care Financing Administration, Department of Health and Human Services, Attention: OCC-018-P, P.O. Box 26688, Baltimore, MD 21207.</textblock>
    <textblock>If you prefer, you may deliver your written comments (1 original and 3 copies) to one of the following addresses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 309-G, Hubert H. Humphrey Building, 200 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20201, or</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 132, East High Rise Building, 6325 Security Boulevard, Baltimore, MD 21207.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because of staffing and resource limitations, we cannot accept comments by facsimile (FAX) transmission. In commenting, please refer to file code OCC-18-P. Comments received timely will be available for public inspection as they are received, generally beginning approximately 3 weeks after publication of a document, in room 309-G of the Department's offices at 200 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC, on Monday through Friday of each week from 8:30 a.m. to 5 p.m. (phone: (202) 690-7890).</textblock>
    <textblock>COPIES:</textblock>
    <textblock>To order copies of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>containing this document, send your request to: New Orders, Superintendent of Documents, P.O. Box 371954, Pittsburgh, PA 15250-7954. Specify the date of the issue requested and enclose a check or money order payable to the Superintendent of Documents, or enclose your Visa or Master Card number and expiration date. Credit card orders can also be placed by calling the order desk at (202) 783-3238 or by faxing to (202) 275-6802. The cost for each copy is $4.50. As an alternative, you can view and photocopy the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>document at most libraries designated as U.S. Government Depository Libraries and at many other public and academic libraries throughout the country that receive the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Jennifer Messersmith, (202) 401-2325; Alfred D'Alberto, (410) 966-7610 (For full reporting of costs).</textblock>
  </further>
</doc>
