<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00088</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00068</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Second Coast Guard District Industry Day</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Coast Guard</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[CGD02-94-010]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Coast Guard, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commander, Second Coast Guard District is sponsoring an Industry Day event in St. Louis, Missouri. This notice will advertise the event which is open to the public.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Industry Day will be held on March 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Lieutenant Charles L. McAllister or Lieutenant Patrick G. Gerrity at Commander (mpb), Second Coast Guard District, 1222 Spruce Street, room 2.102G, St. Louis, Missouri 63103-2832. The telephone number is: (314) 539-2655.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Industry Day is designed to provide an open exchange of information, ideas, and opinions on matters of mutual interest or concern to the inland marine community and the Coast Guard. Industry Day activities will be held at the Frontenac Hilton Hotel, 1335 South Lindbergh Blvd., St. Louis, Missouri. The schedule of events follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Wednesday, 9 March</textblock>
    <textblock>5-7 p.m. Registration for early arrivals.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thursday, 10 March</textblock>
    <textblock>7:30 a.m. Registration continues.</textblock>
    <textblock>8:30 a.m. General Session: Opening comments and Selected Presentations.</textblock>
    <textblock>10 a.m. Panel Discussions: Three separate small group panels will focus on the towing industry, shoreside facilities, and the small passenger industry.</textblock>
    <textblock>12 p.m. Luncheon.</textblock>
    <textblock>1:30 p.m. Panel Discussions continue.</textblock>
    <textblock>5 p.m. Industry Day concludes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Advance registration and payment of a $25.00 conference fee is required. The fee includes the cost of a luncheon and refreshments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons interested in attending Industry Day may request registration forms or additional information on the Industry Day activities and on events scheduled by other groups to coincide with Industry Day at the address provided above. Persons interested in submitting written recommendations for agenda discussion topics should mail their recommendations directly to Commander (mpb), also at the address provided above.</textblock>
    <textblock>Completed registration forms and fees should be mailed directly to the Frontenac Hilton Hotel, Attn: Reservations, c/o Laura Arbet, 1335 S. Lindbergh, St. Louis, Missouri 63131. Registration forms and fees must be received by March 7, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Paul M. Blayney,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Rear Admiral (Lower Half), United States Coast Guard, Commander, Second Coast Guard District.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3926 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-14-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
