<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00064</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00054</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Schedules Pending</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Department of Commerce, Patent and Trademark Office (N1-241-90-5). Electronic and textual records of the Automated Patent Search System.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Department of Commerce, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (N1-370-93-2). Comprehensive records schedule for the Arabian Gulf Program Office.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Department of Education, Office of Educational Research and Improvement (N1-441-94-1). Data filed relating to kindergarten, 1971-1975.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Department of Education, Routine and facilitative financial and administrative records relating to the Federal real property assistance program (N1-441-93-5).</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Department of Health and Human Service, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (N1-442-91-11). Comprehensive schedule for National Institute of Occupational Safety and Health electronic records.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Department of Health and Human Service, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. (N1-442-91-12). Comprehensive schedule of electronic records of the Center for Infectious Diseases.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Department of Health and Human Services, Public Health Service, National Institutes of Health (N1-443-93-1). Medical Staff credentials.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Department of Health, Education and Welfare, Office of the Secretary (N1-235-93-1). Completed job satisfaction surveys filled out by Departmental employees, 1971.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Department of the Interior, U.S. Geological Survey (N1-57-93-1). Hard copy seismograms.</textblock>
    <textblock>10. Department of the Interior, Bureau of Mines (N1-70-93-1). Revisions to the records schedule for the Division of Organization and Management.</textblock>
    <textblock>11. Department of Labor, Office of the Executive Secretariat (N1-174-93-3). Miscellaneous subject files, 1991-1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>12. Department of State, Bureau of Politico-Military Affairs (N1-59-94-2). Compliance tracking system used by the Office of Defense Trade Controls.</textblock>
    <textblock>13. Department of Treasury, Office of Thrift Supervision (N1-483-92-7). Records of the Controller's Division.</textblock>
    <textblock>14. Department of Treasury, Office of Thrift Supervision (N1-483-93-16). Summary reports on financial institutions.</textblock>
    <textblock>15. Department of Treasury, Office of Thrift Supervision (N1-483-93-18). Summary reports produced by the Branch Office Survey System.</textblock>
    <textblock>16. ACTION, Office of Management and Budget (N1-362-94-3). General correspondence of the Inspector General.</textblock>
    <textblock>17. Environmental Protection Agency, Office of Pesticides (N1-412-93-3). Records relating to the National Pesticides Survey.</textblock>
    <textblock>18. National Archives and Records Administration (N2-107-94-1). Routine and facilitative records accumulated by the Office of the Secretary of War.</textblock>
    <textblock>19. National Archives and Records Administration (N2-145-94-1). Routine sound recordings used for training by the Agricultural Stabilization &amp; Conservation Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>20. Peace Corps (N1-490-93-2). Volunteer training evaluation files relating to projects in El Salvador and Honduras, 1965-67.</textblock>
    <textblock>21. Securities and Exchange Commission. (N1-266-93-1). Records relating to the Study of Investment Trusts and Companies, 1935-38.</textblock>
    <textblock>22. Tennessee Valley Authority, Resource Group (N1-142-92-17. Computer cassette tapes and engineering drawings relating to the Ammonia from Coal Project.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Trudy Huskamp Peterson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Archivist of the United States.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3917 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7515-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
