<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00065</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00055</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463), as amended, notice is hereby given that a planning meeting for the Professional Theater Companies Section of the Theater Advisory Panel will be held on February 28, 1994 from 10 a.m. to 4 p.m., in room 730, at the Nancy Hanks Center, 1100 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20506.</textblock>
    <textblock>This meeting will be open to the public on a space available basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any interested person may observe meetings or portions thereof, which are open to the public, and may be permitted to participate in the discussions at the discretion of the meeting chairman and with the approval of the full-time Federal employee in attendance.</textblock>
    <textblock>If you need special accommodations due to a disability, please contact the Office of Special Constituencies, National Endowment for the Arts, 1100 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20506, 202/682-5532, TYY 202/682-5496, at least seven (7) days prior to the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further information with reference to this meeting can be obtained from Ms. Yvonne M. Sabine, Committee Management Officer, National Endowment for the Arts, Washington, DC 20506, or call 202/682-5439.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 16, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NATIONAL FOUNDATION ON THE ARTS AND THE HUMANITIES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Theater Advisory Panel; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Yvonne M. Sabine,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Panel Operations, National Endowment for the Arts.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4073 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7537-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
