<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00022</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 15, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on February 9, 1994, Algonquin Gas Transmission Company (Algonquin) tendered for filing as part of its FERC Gas Tariff, Fourth Revised Volume No. 1, the following tariff sheets:</textblock>
    <textblock>Seventh Revised Sheet No. 20A</textblock>
    <textblock>Original Sheet No. 95C</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed effective date of Sheet Nos. 20A and 95C is March 11, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Algonquin states that the purpose of this filing is to provide for the recovery of transition costs to be paid by Algonquin to Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation (Texas Eastern) pursuant to Texas Eastern's fourth direct bill of Account No. 191 purchased gas costs filed on February 9, 1994. Algonquin requests that the Commission grant any waiver of the Commission's regulations that may be necessary to permit this application to take effect as requested.</textblock>
    <textblock>Algonquin states that copies of this tariff filing were mailed to all customers of Algonquin and interested state commissions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with 18 CFR 385.214 and 385.211 of the Commission's Rules and Regulations. All such motions or protests should be filed on or before February 23, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. RP94-131-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Algonquin Gas Transmission Co.; Proposed Changes in FERC Gas Tariff</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Linwood A. Watson, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3865 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
