<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00033</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>6. In §417.452, paragraph (a) is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§417.452</textblock>
    <textblock>Liability of Medicare enrollees.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Deductibles and coinsurance</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>General rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) A Medicare enrollee of an HMO or CMP is responsible for HMO or CMP charges that represent applicable Medicare deductible and coinsurance amounts.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The amounts that the HMO or CMP charges its Medicare enrollees under paragraph (a)(1)(i) of this section may not exceed, on the average, the actuarial value of the deductibles and coinsurance for which the Medicare enrollees would be responsible if they were not enrolled in an HMO or CMP.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Special rules: Medicare enrollees of risk HMOs and CMPs.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) If a risk HMO or CMP reduces the deductible and coinsurance charges in accordance with the ``additional benefits'' option provided in §417.440(b)(4)(i), the enrollee pays less than would otherwise be required under paragraph (a)(1) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A Medicare enrollee of a risk HMO or CMP is not responsible for deductibles applicable to national coverage decision (NCD) services that the HMO or CMP is not required to furnish because they are excepted under §417.414(b)(4). The exemption applies regardless of whether the HMO or CMP furnishes the services or the enrollee obtains them from other sources.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of charge and source of payment.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The deductible and coinsurance charges imposed by an HMO or CMP may be in the form of premiums, membership fees, or per-unit or similar charges.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The deductible and coinsurance charges may be paid by the enrollee or on his or her behalf by another individual, organization, or entity.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Section 417.586 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§417.586</textblock>
    <textblock>Special rules: Payment for significant cost national coverage decision (NCD) services.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicability.</textblock>
    <textblock>This section applies to NCD services that a risk HMO or CMP is not required to furnish because they are excepted under §417.414(b)(4).</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Method of payment.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a Medicare enrollee of a risk HMO or CMP receives an NCD service specified in paragraph (a) of this section, payment for that service_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Is in addition to the per capita payments to the HMO or CMP; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Is made by the fiscal intermediary or carrier under the usual Medicare rules and methods set forth in part 405; part 410, subpart E; part 412, 413, or 415, as appropriate; and subject to the requirements of part 424 of this chapter.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Exceptions.</textblock>
    <textblock>HCFA does not make additional payments under paragraph (b) of this section if the HMO or CMP_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Is obligated to furnish the NCD service as an ``additional benefit'' under §417.592; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Furnishes the NCD service as an optional or required supplemental service paid for by the Medicare enrollee under §417.440 (b)(2) or (b)(3).</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Program No. 93.773, Medicare_Hospital Insurance; and Program No. 93.774, Medicare_Supplementary Medical Insurance Program)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: July 28, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Bruce C. Vladeck,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator, Health Care Financing Administration.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: November 3, 1993.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna E. Shalala,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3609 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4120-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
