<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-0-00035</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>5 U.S.C. 301; 10 U.S.C. 1079, 1086.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 199.2(b) is amended by adding the new definitions, ``approved teaching programs,'' ``pastoral counselors,'' ``physician in training,'' and ``teaching physician,'' by removing the definition for ``marriage and family counselor or pastoral counselor,'' by adding the definition ``marriage and family therapist, certified,'' in alphabetical order, and by revising the definitions for ``attending physician,'' and ``mental health counselor'' to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§199.2</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>Approved teaching programs.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of CHAMPUS, an approved teaching program is a program of graduate medical education which has been duly approved in its respective specialty or subspecialty by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education of the American Medical Association, by the Committee on Hospitals of the Bureau of Professional Education of the American Osteopathic Association, by the Council on Dental Education of the American Dental Association, or by the Council on Podiatry Education of the American Podiatry Association.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Attending physician.</textblock>
    <textblock>The physician who has the primary responsibility for the medical diagnosis and treatment of the patient. A consultant or an assistant surgeon, for example, would not be an attending physician. Under very extraordinary circumstances, because of the presence of complex, serious, and multiple, but unrelated, medical conditions, a patient may have more than one attending physician concurrently rendering medical treatment during a single period of time. An attending physician also may be a teaching physician.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Marriage and family therapist, certified.</textblock>
    <textblock>An extramedical individual provider who meets the requirements outlined in §199.6.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Mental health counselor.</textblock>
    <textblock>An extramedical individual provider who meets the requirements outlined in §199.6</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Pastoral counselor.</textblock>
    <textblock>An extramedical individual provider who meets the requirements outlined in §199.6.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Physician in training.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interns, residents, and fellows participating in approved postgraduate training programs and physicians who are not in approved programs but who are authorized to practice only in a hospital or other institutional provider setting, e.g., individuals with temporary or restricted licenses, or unlicensed graduates of foreign medical schools.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Teaching physician.</textblock>
    <textblock>A teaching physician is any physician whose duties include providing medical training to physicians in training within a hospital or other institutional provider setting.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Section 199.4 is amended by revising paragraphs (b)(1)(i), (c)(1)(i), (c)(3)(ix)(A), by adding a new paragraph (c)(3)(xiii) after the Note, (g)(37)(vii), and (g)(37)(viii), and by revising paragraphs (g)(1), (g)(2), and (g)(39) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§199.4</textblock>
    <textblock>Basic program benefits.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Billing practices.</textblock>
    <textblock>To be considered for benefits under §199.4(b), covered services and supplies must be provided and billed for by a hospital or other authorized institutional provider. Such billings must be fully itemized and sufficiently descriptive to permit CHAMPUS to determine whether benefits are authorized by this part. Depending on the individual circumstances, teaching physician services may be considered an institutional benefit in accordance with §199.4(b) or a professional benefit under §199.4(c). See paragraph (c)(3)(xiii) of this section for the CHAMPUS requirements regarding teaching physicians. In the case of continuous care, claims shall be submitted to the appropriate CHAMPUS fiscal intermediary at least every 30 days either by the beneficiary or sponsor or, on a participating basis, directly by the facility on behalf of the beneficiary (refer to §199.7).</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) *␣*␣*</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
