<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-0-00044</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Safety Zone Regulations; Kill Van Kull, NY and NJ</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>33 CFR Part 165</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[CGD01-94-009]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 2115-AA97</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Coast Guard, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Temporary final rule; termination.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard is canceling the temporary final rule (CGD01-93-152) that established a safety zone in the waters near Bergen Point West Reach, in the Kill Van Kull of New York and New Jersey, from 8 a.m. December 7, 1993, until 8 a.m. on March 1, 1994. This safety zone was established as part of the Kill Van Kull dredging project. On January 24, 1994, the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers certified this portion of the dredging project and notified the Coast Guard that dredging operations in this area were completed.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule is effective on January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Lieutenant Rosanne Trabocchi, Project Manager, Captain of the Port, New York, (212) 668-7933.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background and Purpose</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 7, 1993, the U.S. Coast Guard Captain of the Port, New York established a safety zone in the waters near Bergen Point West Reach in the Kill Van Kull. This safety zone was in effect from December 7, 1993, until March 1, 1994. This safety zone placed restrictions in all waters of Kill Van Kull west of the Bayonne Bridge and east of Shooters Island.</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 24, 1994, the U.S. Coast Guard Captain of the Port, New York, received written notification that the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers certified this portion of the dredging project and that the dredging operations in this area were completed. Therefore, this rule is no longer needed and is terminated. This rule cancels the safety zone in this area of the Kill Van Kull.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 33 CFR Part 165</textblock>
    <textblock>Harbors, Marine safety, Navigation (water), Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Security measures, Waterways.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>For reasons set out in the preamble, the Coast Guard amends 33 CFR part 165 as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 165_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 165 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>33 U.S.C. 1231; 50 U.S.C. 191; 33 CFR 1.05-1(g), 6.04-1, 6.04-6, and 160.5, 49 CFR 1.46.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Temporary ยง165.T01-152 is removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>T.H. Gilmour,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Captain, U.S. Coast Guard, Captain of the Port, New York.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3924 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-14-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
