<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00021</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Discussion of Proposed Amendment</textblock>
    <textblock>A Coast Guard analysis of highway traffic showed the bridge is used almost exclusively by commuter traffic (90% flow in one direction) for about an hour each morning and afternoon. The drawbridge is opened frequently due to its substandard clearance (9 feet closed), especially during the fall and spring vessel migration periods.</textblock>
    <textblock>Holding conditions for vessels near the bridge are considered adequate to allow vessels to safely wait for a bridge opening during the commuter closed periods. A review of the traffic data indicates there has been a change in the timing and density of commuter traffic which requires an earlier morning closure period. In addition, the data shows there has been a reduction in the volume of afternoon commuter traffic which would allow a change in the closure periods without requiring an increase in the length of time vessels are required to wait for an opening.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Evaluation</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposal is not considered a significant regulatory action under Executive Order 12866 and is not significant under the Department of Transportation Regulatory Policies and Procedures (44 FR 11040, February 26, 1979). The Coast Guard expects the economic impact of this proposal to be so minimal that a Regulatory Evaluation is unnecessary. We conclude this because the proposed rule exempts tugs with tows.</textblock>
    <textblock>Small Entities</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. 601</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>), the Coast Guard must consider whether this proposal, if adopted, will have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities. ``Small entities'' include independently owned and operated small businesses that are not dominant in their field and that otherwise qualify as ``small business concerns'' under section 3 of the Small Business Act (15 U.S.C. 632).</textblock>
    <textblock>Since the proposed rule exempts tugs with tows, the Coast Guard certifies under 5 U.S.C. 605(b) that this proposal, if adopted, will not have a significant impact on a substantial number of small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Collection of Information</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposal contains no collection of information requirements under the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. 3501 et seq.).</textblock>
    <textblock>Federalism</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard has analyzed this proposal under the principles and criteria contained in Executive Order 12612, and has determined that this proposal does not have sufficient federalism implications to warrant the preparation of a Federalism Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environment</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard considered the environmental impact of this proposal and concluded that, under section 2.B.2.g.(5) of Commandant Instruction M16475.1B, promulgation of operating requirements or procedures for drawbridges is categorically excluded from further environmental documentation. A Categorical Exclusion Determination is available in the docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 33 CFR Part 117</textblock>
    <textblock>Bridges.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set out in the preamble, the Coast Guard proposes to amend 33 CFR part 117 as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 117_DRAWBRIDGE OPERATION REGULATIONS</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for Part 117 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>33 U.S.C. 499; 49 CFR 1.46; 33 CFR 1.05-1(g).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 117.261 is amended by revising paragraph (k) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง117.261</textblock>
    <textblock>Atlantic Intracoastal Waterway from St. Marys River to Key Largo.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(k) State Road 402, Max Brewer bridge, mile 878.9, at Titusville. The draw shall open on signal; except that, from 6 a.m. to 7:15 a.m. and 3:15 p.m. to 4:30 p.m. Monday through Friday, except federal holidays, the draw need not open.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 26, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William P. Leahy,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Rear Admiral, U.S. Coast Guard, Commander, Seventh Coast Guard District.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3927 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-14-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
