<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-0-00040</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(B)</textblock>
    <textblock>Pastoral counselors.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the purposes of CHAMPUS, a pastoral counselor is an individual who meets the following requirements:</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) Recognized graduate professional education with the minimum of an earned master's degree from a regionally accredited educational institution in an appropriate behavioral science field, mental health discipline; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) The following experience:</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>i</textblock>
    <textblock>) Either 200 hours of approved supervision in the practice of pastoral counseling, ordinarily to be completed in a 2- to 3-year period, of which at least 100 hours must be in individual supervision. This supervision will occur preferably with more than one supervisor and should include a continuous process of supervision with at least three cases; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>ii</textblock>
    <textblock>) 1,000 hours of clinical experience in the practice of pastoral counseling under approved supervision, involving at least 50 different cases; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>iii</textblock>
    <textblock>) 150 hours of approved supervision in the practice of psychotherapy, ordinarily to be completed in a 2- to 3-year period, of which at least 50 hours must be individual supervision; plus at least 50 hours of approved individual supervision in the practice of pastoral counseling, ordinarily to be completed within a period of not less than 1 nor more than 2 years; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>iv</textblock>
    <textblock>) 750 hours of clinical experience in the practice of psychotherapy under approved supervision involving at least 30 cases; plus at least 250 hours of clinical practice in pastoral counseling under approved supervision, involving at least 20 cases; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>) Is licensed or certified to practice as a pastoral counselor by the jurisdiction where practicing (see paragraph (c)(3)(iv)(D) of this section for more specific information regarding licensure); and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>) The services of a pastoral counselor meeting the above requirements are coverable following the CHAMPUS determined allowable charge methdology, under the following specified conditions:</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>i</textblock>
    <textblock>) The CHAMPUS beneficiary must be referred for therapy by a physician; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>ii</textblock>
    <textblock>) A physician is providing ongoing oversight and supervision of the therapy being provided; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>iii</textblock>
    <textblock>) The pastoral counselor must certify on each claim for reimbursement that a written communication has been made or will be made to the referring physician of the results of the treatment. Such communication will be made at the end of the treatment, or more frequently, as required by the referring physician (refer to ยง199.7).</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
    <textblock>) Because of the similarity of the requirements for licensure, certification, experience, and education, a pastoral counselor may elect to be authorized under CHAMPUS as a certified marriage and family therapist, and as such, be subject to all previously defined criteria for the certified marriage and family therapist category, to include acceptance of the CHAMPUS determined allowable charge as payment in full, except for applicable deductibles and cost-shares (i.e., balance billing of a beneficiary above the allowable charge is prohibited; may not bill beneficiary for noncovered care). The pastoral counselor must also agree to enter into the same participation agreement as a certified marriage and family therapist with the Office of CHAMPUS within which the pastoral counselor agrees to all provisions including licensure, national association membership and conditions upon termination, outlined above for certified marriage and family therapist.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>No dual status will be recognized by the Office of CHAMPUS. Pastoral counselors must elect to become one of the categories of extramedical CHAMPUS provides specified above. Once authorized as either a pastoral counselor, or a certified marriage and family therapist, claims review and reimbursement will be in accordance with the criteria established for the elected provider category.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
