<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00013</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[I.D. 021594C]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Pacific Fishery Management Council; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of public meetings.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Pacific Fishery Management Council (Council) and its advisory entities will meet on March 7-11, 1994, at the Columbia River Red Lion, 1401 North Hayden Island Drive, Portland, OR; telephone: (503) 283-2111. The meeting will begin on March 8, at 8 a.m. in closed session (not open to the public) to discuss personnel matters and litigation. An open session will begin at 8:30 a.m. The Council meeting will then reconvene at 8 a.m. each day from March 9 through Friday, March 11. The meeting may continue each day into the evening hours if necessary to complete business.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following items are on the Council's agenda:</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Call to Order</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Opening Remarks, Introductions, Roll Call.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Remarks by Admiral John W. Lockwood, Coast Guard.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Approve Proposed Agenda.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Approve November 1993 Minutes.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Salmon Management</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Review of 1993 Fisheries and Summary of 1994 Stock Abundance Estimates.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Reports of the Klamath and Sacramento Review Groups.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Endangered Species Act Considerations for 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Report of the Working Group on Inseason.</textblock>
    <textblock>Modification of Hook-and-Release Mortality Estimates</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Preliminary Definition of 1994 Management Options.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Adopt 1994 Management Options for Analysis.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Preliminary Discussion of a Salmon Plan Amendment.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Adopt 1994 Options for Public Review.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Adopt Schedule of Hearings on 1994 Options.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Administrative and Other Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Request of the Western Pacific Fishery Management Council for Authority to Manage Pacific Ocean Pelagic Fish Resources.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Report of the Budget Committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Status of Legislation.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Appointments to Council Advisory Groups.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Work Load Priorities for 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Adopt Draft Agenda for April 1994 Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Pacific Halibut Allocation</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Report of the Scientific and Statistical Committee on Halibut Bycatch and Stock Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Status of the 1994 Catch Sharing Plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Summary of International Pacific Halibut Commission Meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Catch Sharing Plan for 1995 and Beyond.</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Groundfish Management</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Status of Federal Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Recommendations of the Groundfish Permit Review Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Status of the Proposed Fixed Gear Sablefish Individual Quota Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Data Collection Program for the Shore-based Whiting Fishery in 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Report of Industry Workshops.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Black Rockfish Management off Oregon.</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Habitat Issues</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Report of the Snake River Salmon Recovery Team.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Report of the Habitat Steering Group.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other Meetings</textblock>
    <textblock>The Scientific and Statistical Committee will meet March 7 beginning at 1 p.m. and March 8 at 8 a.m. to address scientific issues on the Council agenda.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Groundfish Permit Review Board will meet March 7 beginning at 8 a.m. to review appeals on applications for West Coast groundfish limited entry permits which were denied by NMFS.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Salmon Technical Team will meet as necessary (irregular hours) throughout the March 7-11 period to prepare impact analyses of the proposed salmon management measures for 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Salmon Advisory Subpanel will convene at 9 a.m. on March 7 and at 8 a.m. each day thereafter through March 11 to address salmon management items on the Council agenda.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Habitat Steering Group will meet from 1 p.m. to 5 p.m. on March 7 to consider activities affecting the habitat of fish stocks managed by the Council.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Budget Committee will convene at 3 p.m. on March 7 to review the status of the fiscal year 1994 Council budget and other related issues.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Enforcement Consultants will meet at 7 p.m. on March 8 to address enforcement issues related to Council agenda items.</textblock>
    <textblock>Detailed agendas for the above advisory meetings will be available after February 24, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>This meeting is physically accessible to people with disabilities. Requests for sign language interpretation or other auxiliary aids should be directed to Michelle Perry Sailer at (503) 326-6352, at least 5 days prior to the meeting date.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Lawrence D. Six, Executive Director, Pacific Fishery Management Council, 2000 SW. First Avenue, suite 420, Portland, OR; telephone (503) 326-6352.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David S. Crestin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Office of Fisheries Conservation and Management, National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3939 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
