<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00053</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00008</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>§417.801</textblock>
    <textblock>Agreements between HCFA and health care prepayment plans.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Basic requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order to participate and receive payment under the Medicare program as an HCPP, an organization must enter into a written agreement with HCFA.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Not impose any limitations on the acceptance of Medicare enrollees or beneficiaries for care and treatment that it does not impose on all other individuals;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Consider any additional requirements that HCFA finds necessary or desirable for efficient and effective program administration; and</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Document the cost of part B services as required by §417.800(c)(4).</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The HCPP is not in substantial compliance with the provisions of the agreement, applicable HCFA regulations, or applicable provisions of the Medicare law;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The HCPP undergoes a change of ownership as specified in subpart M of this part; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) An HCPP that furnishes inpatient hospital care has had a final overclaim, as determined under §417.532(b), for 2 consecutive years.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Section 417.802 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§417.802</textblock>
    <textblock>Other applicable regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>General rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>The payment rules set forth in §§417.530 through 417.550 for cost HMOs and CMPs also apply to HCPPs except as specified in paragraph (b) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Exceptions</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1) §417.532(d). HCPPs do not have the option of paying providers that furnish inpatient hospital services, SNF services, or part B services to the HCPP's Medicare enrollees. HCFA pays the providers, as indicated in §417.800(d).</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>§417.536(1).</textblock>
    <textblock>Return on equity capital of proprietary providers owned by the HCPP is not an allowable cost.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>§417.536(m).</textblock>
    <textblock>These limitations on payment do not apply to HCPPs. The limitations that do apply are set forth in this subpart.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>§417.548.</textblock>
    <textblock>The rules governing payment for provider services furnished through arrangements do not apply because HCPPs do not pay providers.</textblock>
    <textblock>(5)</textblock>
    <textblock>§417.550(b)(2).</textblock>
    <textblock>Payment of reasonable cost for independent certification of cost reports does not apply because HCPPs are not required to have their cost reports independently certified.</textblock>
    <textblock>§417.546</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>10. In §417.546, the following changes are made:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Paragraph (b) and the Editorial Note are removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. In paragraph (a), the ``(a)'' designation is removed, and the ``(1)'' and ``(2)'' designations are changed to ``(a)'' and ``(b)'', respectively.</textblock>
    <textblock>§417.560</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>11. In §417.560, the following changes are made:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Paragraph (d)(2) is removed.</textblock>
    <textblock>b. In paragraph (d)(1), the designation ``(1)'' and the clause ``Except as provided in paragraph (d)(2) of this section'' are removed, and the word ``the'', preceding ``Medicare share'' is revised to ``The''.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Program No. 93.773, Medicare_Hospital Insurance; and Program No. 93.774, Medicare_Supplementary Medical Insurance Program)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: July 28, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Bruce C. Vladeck,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator, Health Care Financing Administration.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: November 3, 1993.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna E. Shalala,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3610 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4120-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
