<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-0-00018</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-0-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>94-04-14 Twin Commander Aircraft Corporation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendment 39-8834; Docket No. 92-CE-58-AD. Supersedes AD 91-08-09, Amendment 39-6965.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicability:</textblock>
    <textblock>The following model and serial number airplanes that do not have the wing front spar lower cap replaced in accordance with the procedures of one of the three modifications specified in paragraph (b) of this AD, certificated in any category:</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance:</textblock>
    <textblock>Required within the next 90 calendar days after the effective date of this AD or within 12 calendar months after the last inspection required by AD 91-08-09, whichever occurs later, unless already accomplished, and thereafter as indicated.</textblock>
    <textblock>To prevent wing structural damage that, if not detected, could progress to the point of failure, accomplish the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>Note 1:</textblock>
    <textblock>The serial number of the Model 685 airplanes differs from that specified in Twin Commander Service Bulletin (SB) No. 208A, dated November 9, 1992. This AD takes precedence over that service information.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Ultrasonically inspect each area of the wing front spar lower cap for corrosion in accordance with the instructions in Twin Commander SB No. 208A, dated November 9, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) If no corrosion is found, reinspect within the next 36 calendar months.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) If corrosion is found that is less than 50 percent of the allowable service limits referenced in Table 1 of Twin Commander SB No. 208A, dated November 9, 1992, reinspect within the next 30 calendar months.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) If corrosion is found to be between 50 to 100 percent of the allowable service limits referenced in Table 1 of Twin Commander SB No. 208A, dated November 9, 1992, reinspect within the next 12 calendar months.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) If corrosion is found to be greater than 100 percent of the allowable service limits referenced in Table 1 of Twin Commander SB No. 208A, dated November 9, 1992, prior to further flight, replace the wing front spar lower cap in accordance with one of the replacement modifications referenced in paragraph (b) of this AD.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The repetitive inspection requirement of this AD may be eliminated by replacing the wing front lower spar cap in accordance with the instructions in one of the following, as applicable:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) For Models 685, 690, 690A, and 690B: Twin Commander Custom Kit No. CK-144, Revision A, dated November 12, 1992;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For Models 500S, 500U, 680W, 681, 680FL, and 680FL(P): Twin Commander Custom Kit No. CK-145, dated November 21, 1992; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) For Models 690, 690A, and 690B: AVIADESIGN, Inc. Supplemental Type Certificate SA5740NM.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Special flight permits may be issued in accordance with 14 CFR 21.197 and 21.199 to operate the airplane to a location where the requirements of this AD can be accomplished.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) An alternative method of compliance or adjustment of the initial and repetitive compliance times that provides an equivalent level of safety may be approved by the Manager, Seattle Aircraft Certification Office (ACO), FAA, Northwest Mountain Region, 1601 Lind Avenue SW., Renton, Washington 98055-4056. The request shall be forwarded through an appropriate FAA Maintenance Inspector, who may add comments and then send it to the Manager, Seattle ACO, FAA, Northwest Mountain Region.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note 2:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information concerning the existence of approved alternative methods of compliance with this AD, if any, may be obtained from the Seattle ACO, FAA, Northwest Mountain Region.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) The inspections required by this AD shall be done in accordance with Twin Commander Service Bulletin No. 208A, dated November 9, 1992. This incorporation by reference was approved by the Director of the Federal Register in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552(a) and 1 CFR part 51. The replacement (as applicable) required by this AD shall be done in accordance with the instructions to either Twin Commander Custom Kit No. CK-144, Revision A, dated November 12, 1992; or Twin Commander Custom Kit No. CK-145, dated August 21, 1992, whichever is applicable. This incorporation by reference was previously approved by the Director of the Federal Register in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552(a) and 1 CFR part 51 as of April 11, 1994. Copies may be obtained from Twin Commander Aircraft Corporation, 19003 59th Drive, NE., Arlington, Washington 98223. Copies may be inspected at the FAA, Central Region, Office of the Assistant Chief Counsel, room 1558, 601 E. 12th Street, Kansas City, Missouri, or at the Office of the Federal Register, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., suite 700, Washington, DC.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) This amendment (39-8834) supersedes AD 91-08-09, Amendment 39-6965.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g) This amendment (39-8834) becomes effective on April 12, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Kansas City, Missouri, on February 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Models</textblock>
    <textblock>1Serial No.</textblock>
    <textblock>500U, 680FL, 680FL(P), and 680W</textblock>
    <textblock>1731 through 1854.</textblock>
    <textblock>500S</textblock>
    <textblock>1755 through 3323.</textblock>
    <textblock>681</textblock>
    <textblock>6001 through 6072.</textblock>
    <textblock>685</textblock>
    <textblock>12000 through 12066.</textblock>
    <textblock>690, 690A, and 690B</textblock>
    <textblock>11001 through 11566.</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Barry D. Clements,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Small Airplane Directorate, Aircraft Certification Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3839 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
