<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00046</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00038</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The notificants listed below have applied under the Change in Bank Control Act (12 U.S.C. 1817(j)) and  225.41 of the Board's Regulation Y (12 CFR 225.41) to acquire a bank or bank holding company. The factors that are considered in acting on the notices are set forth in paragraph 7 of the Act (12 U.S.C. 1817(j)(7)).</textblock>
    <textblock>The notices are available for immediate inspection at the Federal Reserve Bank indicated. Once the notices have been accepted for processing, they will also be available for inspection at the offices of the Board of Governors. Interested persons may express their views in writing to the Reserve Bank indicated for that notice or to the offices of the Board of Governors. Comments must be received not later than March 14, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta</textblock>
    <textblock>(Zane R. Kelley, Vice President) 104 Marietta Street, N.W., Atlanta, Georgia 30303:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Joyce Williams Porter</textblock>
    <textblock>, Alpharetta, Georgia; to acquire an additional 14.06 percent of the voting shares of First Colony Bancshares, Inc., Atlanta, Georgia, for a total of 14.13 percent, and thereby indirectly acquire First Colony Bank, Atlanta, Georgia.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City</textblock>
    <textblock>(John E. Yorke, Senior Vice President) 925 Grand Avenue, Kansas City, Missouri 64198:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. James Levendofsky</textblock>
    <textblock>, Belleville, Kansas; to acquire an additional 18 percent of the voting shares of Peoples BanCorp of Belleville, Inc., Belleville, Kansas, for a total of 32.25 percent, and thereby indirectly acquire Peoples National Bank of Belleville, Belleville, Kansas.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. A.P. Martin and Lloyd M. Pickering, Jr.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Trustees of the A.P. Martin Trust, Okemah, Oklahoma; to acquire 37.33 percent of the voting shares of OK Bancorporation, Inc., Okemah, Oklahoma, and thereby indirectly acquire Okemah National Bank, Okemah, Oklahoma.</textblock>
    <textblock>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Joyce Williams Porter, et al.; Change in Bank Control Notices; Acquisitions of Shares of Banks or Bank Holding Companies</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jennifer J. Johnson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Secretary of the Board.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3846 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6210-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
