<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00036</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00028</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[OPPTS-44606; FRL-4760-9]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>TSCA Chemical Testing; Receipt of Test Data</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice announces the receipt of test data on isopropanol (CAS No. 67-63-0), submitted pursuant to a final test rule under the Toxic Substances Control Act (TSCA). Publication of this notice is in compliance with section 4(d) of TSCA.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Susan B. Hazen, Director, Environmental Assistance Division (7408), Office of Pollution Prevention and Toxics, Environmental Protection Agency, Rm. E-543B, 401 M St., SW., Washington, DC 20460, (202) 554-1404, TDD (202) 554-0551.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 4(d) of TSCA requires EPA to publish a notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>reporting the receipt of test data submitted pursuant to test rules promulgated under section 4(a) within 15 days after it is received.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Test Data Submissions</textblock>
    <textblock>Test data for isopropanol were submitted by the Chemical Manufacturers Association Isopropanol Panel on behalf of the test sponsors and pursuant to a test rule at 40 CFR 799.2325. They were received by EPA on January 21, 1994. The submission describes a vapor inhalation oncogenicity study in mice. This chemical is used as a solvent in consumer products and industrial products and procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA has initiated its review and evaluation process for these data submissions. At this time, the Agency is unable to provide any determination as to the completeness of the submissions.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Public Record</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA has established a public record for this TSCA section 4(d) receipt of data notice (docket number OPPTS-44606). This record includes copies of all studies reported in this notice. The record is available for inspection from 12 noon to 4 p.m., Monday through Friday, except legal holidays, in the TSCA Public Docket Office, Rm. ET-G102, 401 M St., SW., Washington, DC 20460.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 2603.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental protection, Test data.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Denise M. Keehner,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Chemical Control Division, Office of Pollution Prevention and Toxics.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3830 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
