<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00061</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Endangered and Threatened Wildlife and Plants; Notice of Public Hearing and Reopening of Public Comment Period on Proposed Threatened Status for the Flat-Tailed Horned Lizard</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>50 CFR Part 17</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1018-AC10</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule; notice of public hearing and reopening of public comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Fish and Wildlife Service (Service), under the Endangered Species Act of 1973, as amended, gives notice that a public hearing will be held on the proposed threatened status for the flat-tailed horned lizard (</textblock>
    <textblock>Phrynosoma mcallii</textblock>
    <textblock>). At the hearing, the Service will allow all interested parties to submit oral or written comments on the proposal. The public comment period is extended to provide the public with more time to comment.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>A public hearing will be held from 6 to 8 p.m. on Tuesday, March 22, 1994, in Imperial, California. The public comment period, which closed on January 28, 1994, will be reopened from February 22, 1994 until April 22, 1994. Any comments received after the closing date may not be considered in the final decision on this proposal.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The hearing will be held on Tuesday, March 22, 1994, at Imperial Valley College, 380 Ira Aten Road, Health Sciences Building Assembly Room 2131, Imperial, California.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments and materials may be submitted at the hearing or sent directly to the Field Supervisor, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, 2730 Loker Avenue West, Carlsbad, California 92008. Comments and materials received will be available for public inspection during business hours by appointment, at the above address.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Gail Kobetich, Field Supervisor, at the address listed above (telephone 619/431-9440).</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>The flat-tailed horned lizard (</textblock>
    <textblock>Phrynosoma mcallii</textblock>
    <textblock>) is a small iguanid lizard restricted to flats and valleys of the western Sonoran desert. Its maximum length, excluding the tail, is about 8 centimeters (3 inches) (Stebbins 1985). The range of the flat-tailed horned lizard includes portions of Riverside, Imperial and extreme eastern San Diego Counties, California; northeastern Baja California, Mexico; Yuma County, Arizona; and northwestern Sonora, Mexico. An estimated 34 percent of historically occupied flat-tailed horned lizard habitat has been lost. About 95 percent of remaining optimal habitat in California is threatened by one or more factors. Various human activities threaten 36 percent of the remaining habitat in Arizona. The flat-tailed horned lizard and its habitat are also being adversely affected in Mexico, but to a lesser degree. The Service published the proposed rule detailing these factors in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on November 29, 1993 (58 FR 62629).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service has scheduled a public hearing on Tuesday, March 22, 1994, in response to formal requests from the public. Those parties wishing to make a statement for the record should bring a copy of their statement to present to the Service at the start of the hearing. Oral statements may be limited in length, if the number of parties present at the hearing necessitates such a limitation. However, the length of written comments or materials presented at the hearing or mailed to the Service are not limited. Written comments will be given the same weight as oral comments. Written comments may be submitted at the hearing or mailed to the address given in the</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>section of this notice. The comment period closes on April 22, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Author</textblock>
    <textblock>The primary author of this notice is Larry Salata, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Carlsbad Field, Office, 2730 Loker Avenue West, Carlsbad, California, 92008.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority</textblock>
    <textblock>The authority for this action is the Endangered Species Act of 1973, as amended (16 U.S.C. 1361-1407; 16 U.S.C. 1531-1544; 16 U.S.C. 4201-4245; Pub. L. 99-625, 100 Stat. 3500; unless otherwise noted).</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 50 CFR Part 17</textblock>
    <textblock>Endangered and threatened species, Exports, Imports, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, and Transportation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Marvin L. Plenert,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Regional Director, Region 1, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3837 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-55-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
