<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00014</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00003</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Mergers.</textblock>
    <textblock>A continuing Federal credit union that has merged with another credit union will pay an operating fee in the following year based on the combined total assets of the merged credit union and the continuing Federal credit union as of December 31. For purposes of this requirement, a purchase and assumption transaction wherein the continuing Federal credit union purchases all or essentially all of the assets of another credit union shall be deemed a merger. Federal credit unions merging with other Federal or state credit unions will not receive a refund of the operating fee paid to the Administration in the year in which the merger took place.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 741_REQUIREMENTS FOR INSURANCE</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The authority citation for part 741 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>12 U.S.C. 1757, 1766, and 1781-1790. Section 741.11 is also authorized by 31 U.S.C. 3717.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Section 741.11 is amended by revising paragraphs (b)(1), (c), (d) and (g) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§741.11</textblock>
    <textblock>Insurance premium and one per cent deposit.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>Insurance year</textblock>
    <textblock>means the period from January 1 through December 31.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>One percent deposit.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each insured credit union shall maintain with the NCUSIF during each insurance year a deposit in an amount equaling one percent of the total of the credit union's insured shares as of the close of the preceding insurance year. The deposit shall be adjusted annually on a date to be determined by the NCUA Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Premium.</textblock>
    <textblock>Each insured credit union shall pay to the NCUSIF, on a date to be determined by the NCUA Board, an insurance premium for that insurance year in an amount equaling one twelfth of one percent of the credit union's total insured shares as of the close of the preceding insurance year.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>New charters.</textblock>
    <textblock>A newly-chartered credit union that obtains share insurance coverage from the NCUSIF during the insurance year in which it has obtained its charter shall not be required to pay an insurance premium for that insurance year. The credit union shall fund its one percent deposit on a date to be determined by the NCUA Board in the following insurance year, but shall not participate in any distribution from NCUSIF equity related to the period prior to the credit union's funding of its deposit.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3933 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7535-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
