<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-0-00005</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-0-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(i) For Models 685, 690, 690A, and 690B_Twin Commander Custom Kit 144, Revision A, dated November 12, 1992; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) For Models 690, 690A, and 690B_AVIADESIGN, Inc. Supplemental Type Certificate SA5740NM, dated July 16, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Special flight permits may be issued in accordance with 14 CFR 21.197 and 21.199 to operate the airplane to a location where the requirements of this AD can be accomplished.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) An alternative method of compliance or adjustment of the compliance time that provides an equivalent level of safety may be approved by the Manager, Seattle Aircraft Certification Office (ACO), FAA, Northwest Mountain Region, 1601 Lind Avenue SW., Renton, Washington 98055-4056. The request shall be forwarded through an appropriate FAA Maintenance Inspector, who may add comments and then send it to the Manager, Seattle ACO, FAA, Northwest Mountain Region.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note 2:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information concerning the existence of approved alternative methods of compliance with this AD, if any, may be obtained from the Seattle ACO, FAA, Northwest Mountain Region.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) The inspections required by this AD shall be done in accordance with Twin Commander Service Bulletin No. 211, Revision No. 1, dated July 7, 1992. This incorporation by reference was approved by the Director of the Federal Register in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552(a) and 1 CFR part 51. The replacement (as applicable) required by this AD shall be done in accordance with the instructions to either Twin Commander Custom Kit No. CK-144, Revision A, dated November 12, 1992; or Twin Commander Custom Kit No. CK-145, dated August 21, 1992, whichever is applicable. This incorporation by reference was previously approved as of April 11, 1994 by the Director of the Federal Register in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 552(a) and 1 CFR part 51. Copies may be obtained from Twin Commander Aircraft Corporation, 19003 59th Drive, NE, Arlington, Washington 98223. Copies may be inspected at the FAA, Central Region, Office of the Assistant Chief Counsel, Room 1558, 601 E. 12th Street, Kansas City, Missouri, or at the Office of the Federal Register, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., suite 700, Washington, DC.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) This amendment (39-8832) becomes effective on April 12, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Kansas City, Missouri, on February 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Barry D. Clements,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Manager, Small Airplane Directorate, Aircraft Certification Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3841 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
