<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00104</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00080</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Tuesday</textblock>
    <textblock>February 22, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part II</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Interior</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Indian Affairs</textblock>
    <textblock>Salinan Tribe of Monterey County, California; Receipt of Petition for Federal Acknowledgment of Existence as an Indian Tribe; Notice</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 35␣/␣Tuesday, February 22, 1994␣/␣Notices</textblock>
    <textblock>Receipt of Petition for Federal Acknowledgment of Existence as an Indian Tribe</textblock>
    <textblock>This is published in the exercise of authority delegated by the Secretary of the Interior to the Assistant Secretary_Indian Affairs by 209 DM 8.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to 25 CFR 83.8(a) (formerly 25 CFR 54.8(a)) notice is hereby given that the Salinan Tribe of Monterey County, c/o Rosie Shaffer, P.O. Box 403, King City, California 93930, has filed a petition for acknowledgment by the Secretary of the Interior that the group exists as an Indian tribe. The petition was received by the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) on November 15, 1993, and was signed by members of the group's governing body.</textblock>
    <textblock>This is a notice of receipt of petition and does not constitute notice that the petition is under active</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration. Notice of active consideration will be sent by mail to the petitioner and other interested parties at the appropriate time.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under §83.8(d) (formerly 54.8(d)) of the Federal regulations, interested parties may submit factual and/or legal arguments in support of or in opposition to the group's petition. Any information submitted will be made available on the same basis as other information in the BIA's files. Such submissions will be provided to the petitioner upon receipt by the BIA. The petitioner will be provided an opportunity to respond to such submissions prior to a final determination regarding the petitioner's status.</textblock>
    <textblock>The petition may be examined, by appointment, in the Department of the Interior, Bureau of Indian Affairs, Branch of Acknowledgment and Research, room 1362-MIB, 1849 C Street, NW., Washington, DC 20240, Phone: (202) 208-3592.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 27, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Indian Affairs</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Ada E. Deer,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary_Indian Affairs.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3936 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
