<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00057</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The ACRS Subcommittee on Planning and Procedures will hold a meeting on Wednesday, March 9, 1994, room P-422, 7920 Norfolk Avenue, Bethesda, MD.</textblock>
    <textblock>The entire meeting will be open to public attendance, with the exception of a portion that may be closed pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 552b(c) (2) and (6) to discuss organizational and personnel matters that relate solely to internal personnel rules and practices of ACRS, and matters the release of which would represent a clearly unwarranted invasion of personnel privacy.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agenda for the subject meeting shall be as follows: Wednesday, March 9, 1994_2:15 p.m. until 4:45 p.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Subcommittee will discuss proposed ACRS activities, practices and procedures for conducting the Committee business, and organizational and personnel matters relating to ACRS and its staff. The purpose of this meeting is to gather information, analyze relevant issues and facts, and to formulate proposed positions and actions, as appropriate, for deliberation by the full Committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>Oral statements may be presented by members of the public with the concurrence of the Subcommittee Chairman; written statements will be accepted and made available to the Committee. Electronic recordings will be permitted only during those portions of the meeting that are open to the public, and questions may be asked only by members of the Subcommittee, its consultants, and staff. Persons desiring to make oral statements should notify the ACRS staff member named below as far in advance as practicable so that appropriate arrangements can be made.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further information regarding topics to be discussed, the scheduling of sessions open to the public, whether the meeting has been cancelled or rescheduled, the Chairman's ruling on requests for the opportunity to present oral statements, and the time allotted therefor can be obtained by contacting the cognizant ACRS staff person, Dr. John T. Larkins (telephone 301/492-4516) between 7:30 a.m. and 4:15 p.m. (est). Persons planning to attend this meeting are urged to contact the above named individual five days before the scheduled meeting to be advised of any changes in schedule, etc., that may have occurred.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 13, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards Subcommittee Meeting on Planning and Procedures</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Sam Duraiswamy,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Nuclear Reactors Branch.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3851 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7590-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
