<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00087</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00067</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The following Applications for Certificates of Public Convenience and Necessity and Foreign Air Carrier Permits were filed under Subpart Q of the Department of Transportation's Procedural Regulations (See 14 CFR 302.1701</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>). The due date for Answers, Conforming Applications, or Motions to Modify Scope are set forth below for each application. Following the Answer period DOT may process the application by expedited procedures. Such procedures may consist of the adoption of a show-cause order, a tentative order, or in appropriate cases a final order without further proceedings.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>49409</textblock>
    <textblock>Date filed:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 9, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Due Date for Answers, Conforming Applications, or Motion to Modify Scope:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 9, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Description:</textblock>
    <textblock>Application of Evergreen International Airlines, Inc. pursuant to Section 401 of the Act and Subpart Q of the Regulations, applies for a new or amended certificate of public convenience and necessity to engage in foreign air transportation of property and mail between the U.S. and Russia and beyond to China, Hong Kong, South Korea, Singapore and Taiwan.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Applications for Certificates of Public Convenience and Necessity and Foreign Air Carrier Permits Filed Under Subpart Q During the Week Ended February 11, 1994</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Phyllis T. Kaylor,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Documentary Services Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3827 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-62-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
