<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00042</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00034</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Public Information Collection Requirements Submitted to OMB for Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) has submitted to the Office of Management and Budget the following public information collection requirements for review and clearance in accordance with the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980, 44 U.S.C. chapter 35.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this information collection must be submitted on or before April 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Direct comments regarding the burden estimate or any aspect of this information collection, including suggestions for reducing this burden, to: the FEMA Information Collections Clearance Officer at the address below; and to Gary Waxman, Office of Management and Budget, 3235 New Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-7340, within 60 days of this notice.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the above information collection request and supporting documentation can be obtained by calling or writing Muriel Anderson, FEMA Information Collections Clearance Officer, Federal Emergency Management Agency, 500 C Street SW., Washington, DC 20472, (202) 646-2624.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type:</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension of 3067-0223.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Damage Survey Report.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abstract:</textblock>
    <textblock>The information will be collected with input from State and local governments describing in detail facilities that have been damaged in a major disaster. Following a major disaster declaration by the President, the State and Disaster Recovery Manager arranges for damage surveys to be made by teams of Federal and State inspectors and a local representative. The following FEMA forms are completed and are attached as supporting justification to the applicant's project application: FEMA Form 90-91, Damage Survey Report_Data Sheet, completed for each damaged facility and for each item of emergency and permanent work identified by the local representative for each damaged facility; FEMA Form 90-3, Pumping Equipment, provides information on any damaged pumping equipment; FEMA Form 90-51, Building Survey, provides information on damage to buildings; and FEMA Form 90-53, Bridge Survey, provides information on any damage to bridges. Prior to the survey team beginning their inspections, the local representative must compile information in accordance with the checklist requirements for damage surveys in DAP 1, Public Assistance Guide for Applicants.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>State or local governments, Federal agencies or employees.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimate of Total Annual Reporting and Recordkeeping Burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>6,155 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>12,160.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Average Burden Time per Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>30 minutes each to complete FEMA Forms, and 8 hours each to compile checklist information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>On occasion.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Wesley C. Moore,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Administrative Support.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3901 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6718-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
