<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00023</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Medicare Program; Health Maintenance Organization and Competitive Medical Plan National Coverage Decisions</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Health Care Financing Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>42 CFR Part 417</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[BPD-732-P]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 0938-AF76</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Health Care Financing Administration (HCFA), HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposed rule would affect health maintenance organizations (HMOs) and competitive medical plans (CMPs) that contract with HCFA to furnish health care services to Medicare beneficiaries and to receive payment on a risk basis. These HMOs and CMPs would no longer be required to absorb the expense of furnishing a new or additional benefit if all the following conditions apply:</textblock>
    <textblock>The benefit was established by a national coverage decision (NCD);</textblock>
    <textblock>The cost of furnishing the service would be significant and was not taken into account in calculating the per capita rate to be paid by HCFA during the current calendar year;</textblock>
    <textblock>The NCD was not published until on or after the date of the announcement of the current calendar year's per capita rate of payment.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule is necessary to implement section 4204(c) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990, commonly referred to as ``OBRA '90,'' which is effective for calendar years beginning on or after January 1, 1991.</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of the amendment is to encourage HMOs and CMPs to contract on a risk basis by ensuring that the actual scope of services covered under the contract would not change significantly during the year.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments will be considered if we receive them at the appropriate address, as provided below, no later than 5 p.m. on April 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mail written comments (1 original and 3 copies) to the following address: Health Care Financing Administration,</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Health and Human Services,</textblock>
    <textblock>Attention: BPD-732-P,</textblock>
    <textblock>P.O. Box 26688,</textblock>
    <textblock>Baltimore, MD 21207.</textblock>
    <textblock>If you prefer, you may deliver your written</textblock>
    <textblock>comments to one of the following addresses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 309-G, Hubert H. Humphrey Building,</textblock>
    <textblock>200 Independence Avenue, SW.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20201, or</textblock>
    <textblock>Room 132, East High Rise Building,</textblock>
    <textblock>6325 Security Boulevard,</textblock>
    <textblock>Baltimore, MD 21207.</textblock>
  </address>
</doc>
