<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00097</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00074</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>CAG-32.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP93-56-002, RP93-86-002 and RP93-139-002, Transwestern Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-33.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP91-203-031, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-34.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP88-44-044, El Paso Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-35.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP91-104-005, RP91-106-004, RP91-109-005, RP91-215-005, RP91-217-003 and RP92-8-003, Trunkline Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-36.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. GP90-11-002, NICOR Exploration Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-37.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-38.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP90-137-013, TM93-6-49-005, RP93-175-003, RS92-13-000 Williston Basin Interstate Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-39.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP92-166-012, Panhandle Eastern Pipe Line Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-40.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-41.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. PR91-23-001, Midcoast Ventures I</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-42.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-43.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RM87-34-071, Regulation of Natural Gas Pipelines After Partial Wellhead</textblock>
    <textblock>Decontrol</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. TA91-1-21-004 and TM91-8-21-004, Columbia Gas Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RM85-1-185, Regulation of Natural Gas Pipelines After Partial Wellhead Decontrol</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP87-115-010, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-44.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP93-151-004, RS92-23-014, RP91-132-035, RP91-203-035 and RP94-39-001, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-45.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RM91-8-004, Qualifying Certain Tight Formation Gas for Tax Credits</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-46.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RS92-1-009, ANR Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-47.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RS92-63-008 and 010, Great Lakes Gas Transmission Limited Partnership</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-48.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. CP93-690-001 and CP93-697-001, High Island Offshore System</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-49.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP89-710-013, Transcontinental Gas Pipeline Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP88-171-029, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
