<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00098</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00074</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>CAG-50.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. CP92-184-006 and CP92-459-005, Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-51.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP93-707-001, Transcontinental Gas Pipe Line Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-52.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP93-541-000, Young Gas Storage Company, Ltd</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-53.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-54.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP94-68-000, Transcontinental Gas Pipeline Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-55.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP94-123-000, Questar Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-56.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-57.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP94-166-000, Viosca Knoll Gathering System</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-58.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-119-000, Texas Gas Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-59.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP92-137-011 and RP92-108-004, Transcontinental Gas Pipe Line Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-60.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RM93-4-001, Standards for Electronic Bulletin Boards Required Under Part 284 of the Commission's Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>Hydro Agenda</textblock>
    <textblock>H-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Reserved</textblock>
    <textblock>Electric Agenda</textblock>
    <textblock>E-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. TX94-3-000, Minnesota Municipal Power Agency v. Southern Minnesota Municipal Power Agency. Order on complaint under Section 211 of the Federal Power Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>E-2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. ER93-465-000 and ER93-922-000, Florida Power &amp; Light Company. Supplemental order on policy issues.</textblock>
    <textblock>Oil and Gas Agenda</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Pipeline Rate Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>PR-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RO89-2-001, Cities Service Oil and Gas Corporation. Order on reconsideration.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Restructuring Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>RS-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-10-007, CP71-273-006, RP92-134-008 and RP93-15-005, Southern Natural Gas Company. Order on rehearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>RS-2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-26-010 and 011, Koch Gateway Pipeline Company. Order on rehearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>RS-3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RS92-4-008, Colorado Interstate Gas Company. Order on compliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>RS-4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-43-011, RP93-4-014 and RS92-43-009, Mississippi River Transmission Corporation. Order on compliance and rehearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>RS-5.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-15-008, 009, 010, 011, RP93-62-008, 009 and 010, Equitrans, Inc. Order on compliance and rehearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>RS-6.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-30-006 and RS92-30-007, Carnegie Natural Gas Company. Order on compliance and rehearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>RS-7.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-5-012, 013, 014, RP90-180-023, 024, RP91-82-014, 015, RP91-161-019, 020, RP92-3-010, 011, RP93-66-003, 004, RP93-115-003 and 004, Columbia Gas Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-6-011, 012, 013, 014, RP90-170-020, 021, RP91-160-016, 017, RP92-2-010, 011, CP93-736-002 and 003, Columbia Gulf Transmission Company. Order on compliance and rehearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Pipeline Certificate Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>PC-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Reserved</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 16, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-4061 Filed 2-17-94; 3:16 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
