<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00096</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00074</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>CAG-10.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-128-000, South Georgia Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-11.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP91-106-000, RP91-109-000, RP91-215-000, RP92-8-000, RP92-49-000 and RP92-103-000, Transwestern Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-12.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP93-147-000, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-13.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-14.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP94-1-000, RP94-1-004 and RP93-161-004, Columbia Gas Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-15.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. TA92-1-63-004, TM92-5-63-002 and TQ92-7-63-002, Carnegie Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-16.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-17.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. PR91-1-001, Tejas Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-18.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. PR93-5-000, Pontchartrain Natural Gas System</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-19.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP88-44-038, El Paso Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-20.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP92-185-010, El Paso Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-21.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-22.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP94-111-000, RP94-97-000 and RS92-87-000, Transwestern Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-23.</textblock>
    <textblock>CP92-203-004, K N Wattenberg Transmission, Ltd.</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-24.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP85-39-015, Wyoming Interstate Company, Ltd</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-25.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP94-76-002, RP93-184-003 and RP93-185-003, Carnegie Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-26.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP91-41-019 and RP91-90-011, Columbia Gas Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-27.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-28.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-60-003, Transwestern Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-29.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP93-163-001, Aquila Energy Marketing Corporation v. Natural Gas Pipeline Company of America</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-30.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP93-160-001, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-31.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
