<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00043</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00035</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Public Information Collection Requirements Submitted to OMB for Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) has submitted to the Office of Management and Budget the following public information collection requirements for review and clearance in accordance with the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980, 44 U.S.C. chapter 35.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this information collection must be submitted on or before April 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Direct comments regarding the burden estimate or any aspect of this information collection, including suggestions for reducing this burden, to: FEMA Information Collections Clearance Officer at the address below; and to Gary Waxman, Office of Management and Budget, 3235 New Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-7340, within 60 days of this notice.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the above information collection request and supporting documentation can be obtained by calling or writing Muriel B. Anderson, FEMA Information Collections Clearance Officer, Federal Emergency Management Agency, 500 C Street SW., Washington, DC 20472, (202) 646-2624.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type:</textblock>
    <textblock>Reinstatement of 3067-0222.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mobile Home Assistance_Request for the Site Inspection and Landowner's Authorization/Ingress-Egress Agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abstract:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information collected to determine site feasibility for the placement of a mobile home; to obtain written permission from the property owner to allow the mobile home on his/her land; and to obtain from adjacent property owners rights of ingress/egress for movement of the mobile home to and from the land.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals or households.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimate of Total Annual Reporting and Recordkeeping Burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>333 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>1,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Average Burden Time Per Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>20 minutes.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>On occasion.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Wesley C. Moore,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Administrative Support.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3902 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6718-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
