<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00041</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00033</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT AGENCY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Public Information Collection Requirements Submitted to OMB for Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) has submitted to the Office of Management and Budget the following public information collection requirements for review and clearance in accordance with the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980, 44 U.S.C. chapter 35.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this information collection must be submitted on or before April 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Direct comments regarding the burden estimate or any aspect of this information collection, including suggestions for reducing this burden, to: the FEMA Information Collections Clearance Officer at the address below; and to Gary Waxman, Office of Management and Budget, 3235 New Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-7340, within 60 days of this notice.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the above information collection request and supporting documentation can be obtained by calling or writing Muriel B. Anderson, FEMA Information Collections Clearance Officer, Federal Emergency Management Agency, 500 C Street SW., Washington, DC 20472, (202) 646-2624.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type:</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension of 3067-0166.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Crisis Counseling Assistance and Training.</textblock>
    <textblock>Abstract:</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Law (PL) 93-288 as amended by the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, PL 100-707, authorizes the President to provide financial assistance to State and local governments for professional counseling services to victims of major disasters in order to relieve mental health problems caused or aggravated by a major disaster or its aftermath. The Department of Health and Human Services Center for Mental Health Services and FEMA monitor State Crisis Counseling and Assistance Training program's (CCP's) to ensure that the goals of the program for people affected by disasters are met, special problems in areas where technical assistance might be necessary are identified, grants are properly managed, and technical assistance and guidance are provided on mental health matters as they relate to the crisis counseling assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>FEMA provides funds in the form of a Federal grant to State or local mental health agencies or private mental health organizations designed by the Governor to provide crisis counseling services to the Presidentially declared communities. Assistance is provided under two separate programs: Immediate Services Program and Regular Program. To obtain a grant, a State agency must submit a grant application. If approved and funded, the State agency must provide progress and financial reports on a quarterly basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>State or local governments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimate of Total Annual Reporting and Recordkeeping Burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>5,272 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Immediate Services_17; Regular Program_7.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Average Burden Time Per Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Immediate Services_24 hours reporting and 48 hours recordkeeping; Regular Program_52 hours reporting and 260 hours recordkeeping.</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Other_application, final report; Quarterly, and Recordkeeping.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Wesley C. Moore,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Office of Administration Support.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3900 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6718-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
