<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00012</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-1-00003</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Organization and Operation of Federal Credit Unions and Requirements for Insurance</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NATIONAL CREDIT UNION ADMINISTRATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>12 CFR Parts 701 and 741</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Credit Union Administration (NCUA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of proposed rulemaking.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule would amend NCUA's Regulations in order to conform them to the new NCUA Fiscal and National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund (NCUSIF) Insurance year. These changes to the fiscal and insurance years were approved by the NCUA Board on November 15, 1993 and are effective January 1, 1995.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be postmarked by April 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send comments to Becky Baker, Secretary of the Board, National Credit Union Administration, 1775 Duke Street, Alexandria, Virginia 22314-3428.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Herbert S. Yolles, Controller, Office of the Controller, at the above address or telephone: (703) 518-6570 or Mary F. Rupp, Staff Attorney, Office of General Counsel, at the above address or telephone: (703) 518-6553.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The NCUA Board on November 15, 1993, voted to change NCUA's fiscal year and NCUSIF's insurance year to coincide with the calendar year effective January 1, 1995. This change requires the NCUA to amend its regulations dealing with operating fees and insurance assessments to conform to the calendar year.</textblock>
    <textblock>Currently under ยง701.6 of NCUA's Rules and Regulations, an operating fee is assessed on federal credit unions based on a fiscal year of October 1 to September 30. This section must be changed to reflect the change to the calendar year. Further, the operating fee assessed as a result of a conversion or merger will now be based on the calendar year and those sections must be changed to delete references to the former fiscal year and reflect the new calendar year. 12 CFR 701.6(b) (2) and (3). The change will result in a transition quarter that begins on October 1, 1994 and ends on December 31, 1994 for which no operating fee would be assessed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Currently under ยง741.11 of NCUA's Rules and Regulations, an insurance premium and one percent deposit are assessed for all federally insured credit unions based on an insurance year of July 1 through June 30. 12 CFR 741.11(b)(1). This definition must be amended to reflect the change to the calendar year. Further, the due dates for the deposits and premiums must be changed from January 31 to a date as set by the NCUA Board in order to coincide with the calendar year. 12 CFR 741.11 (c), (d) and (g).</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
