<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00091</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940222-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Notice of Intent To Rule on Application To Impose and Use the Revenue From a Passenger Facility Charge (PFC) at Outagamie County Airport, Appleton, WI</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of intent to rule on application.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA proposes to rule and invites public comment on the application to impose and use the revenue from a PFC at Outagamie County Airport under the provisions of the Aviation Safety and Capacity Expansion Act of 1990 (Title IX of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990) (Pub. L. 101-508) and Part 158 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (14 CFR Part 158).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before March 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this application may be mailed or delivered in triplicate to the FAA at the following address: Federal Aviation Administration, Minneapolis Airports District Office, 6020 28th Avenue South, room 102, Minneapolis, Minnesota 55450.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, one copy of any comments submitted to the FAA must be mailed or delivered to Mr. Arthur E. Borchardt, Manager of the Outagamie County Airport at the following address: Outagamie County Airport, W6390 Challenger Drive, Suite 201, Appleton, Wisconsin 54915.</textblock>
    <textblock>Air carriers and foreign air carriers may submit copies of written comments previously provided to Outagamie County under ยง158.23 of part 158.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Franklin D. Benson, Manager, Minneapolis Airports District Office, 6020 28th Avenue South, room 102, Minneapolis, Minnesota 55450, 612-725-4221. The application may be reviewed in person at this same location.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA proposes to rule and invites public comment on the application to impose and use the revenue from a PFC at the Outagamie County Airport under the provisions of the Aviation Safety and Capacity Expansion Act of 1990 (Title IX of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990) (Pub. L. 101-508) and part 158 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (14 CFR part 158).</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 27, 1994 the FAA determined that the application to impose and use the revenue from a PFC submitted by Outagamie County was substantially complete within the requirements of ยง158.25 of part 158. The FAA will approve or disapprove the application, in whole or in part, no later than April 26, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following is a brief overview of the application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Level of the proposed PFC:</textblock>
    <textblock>$3.00</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed charge effective date:</textblock>
    <textblock>June 1, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed charge expiration date:</textblock>
    <textblock>May 30, 2001</textblock>
    <textblock>Total estimated PFC revenue:</textblock>
    <textblock>$3,811,673</textblock>
    <textblock>Brief description of proposed project(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>Projects To Impose and Use a PFC</textblock>
    <textblock>Acquire Land; Install Security Fencing; Runway Signs; Terminal Building Water Line; Grove Runway 11/29; Acquire Snow Removal Equipment; Reconstruct General Aviation Apron and Taxiways ``D'' and ``G''; Expand ARFF Building; Reconstruct and Expand Terminal Apron; Prepare PFC Application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Projects Only To Impose a PFC</textblock>
    <textblock>Terminal Baggage Claim Expansion; Improve Stormwater Drainage; Emergency Generator; Reconstruct Taxiway ``B''; Acquire Land; Friction Testing Vehicle.</textblock>
    <textblock>Class or classes of air carriers which the public agency has requested not be required to collect PFCs:</textblock>
    <textblock>Not Applicable.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person may inspect the application in person at the FAA office listed above under</textblock>
    <textblock>``FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT.''</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, any person may, upon request, inspect the application, notice and other documents germane to the application in person at the Outagamie County Airport.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Des Plaines, Illinois on February 9, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Larry Ladendorf,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Manager, Airports Division, Great Lakes Region.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3891 Filed 2-18-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
