<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00184</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00104</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>a. Standing Committees_</textblock>
    <textblock>_Audit &amp; Appropriations Committee;</textblock>
    <textblock>_Operations &amp; Regulations Committee;</textblock>
    <textblock>_Provision for the Delivery of Legal Services Committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Temporary/Special Committees_</textblock>
    <textblock>_Presidential Search Committee;</textblock>
    <textblock>_Office of the Inspector General Oversight Committee;</textblock>
    <textblock>_Other.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Chairman's and Members' Reports</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Consider and Act on Operations and Regulations Committee Report</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Consider and Act on Provision for the Delivery of Legal Services Committee Report</textblock>
    <textblock>OPEN SESSION:</textblock>
    <textblock>(Continued)</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Consider and Act on Audit and Appropriations Committee Report</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Consider and Act on Proposed Fiscal Year 1994 Consolidated Operating Budget for the Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Consider and Act on Proposed Fiscal Year 1995 Consolidated Operating Budget for the Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>10. Consider and Act on Presidential Search Committee Report</textblock>
    <textblock>11. President's Report</textblock>
    <textblock>12. Inspector General's Report</textblock>
    <textblock>CLOSED SESSION:</textblock>
    <textblock>13. Approval of Minutes of Executive Session Held on January 8, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>14. Consultation by Board with the President on Internal Personnel and Operational Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>15. Consider and Act on Internal Personnel and Operational Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>16. Consultation by Board with the Inspector General on Internal Personnel, Operational and Investigative Matters</textblock>
    <textblock>17. Consider and Act on the General Counsel's Report on Pending Litigation to which the Corporation is, or May Become, a Party</textblock>
    <textblock>OPEN SESSION:</textblock>
    <textblock>(Resumed)</textblock>
    <textblock>18. Public Comment</textblock>
    <textblock>19. Consider and Act on Motion to Close Meeting of Board on January 29, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>January 29, 1994 Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>MATTERS TO BE CONSIDERED:</textblock>
    <textblock>CLOSED SESSION:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Consider, With Advisory Committee, Prospective Candidates for the Position of President of the Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>OPEN SESSION:</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Consider and Act on Other Business</textblock>
    <textblock>CONTACT PERSON FOR INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Patricia Batie (202) 336-8800.</textblock>
    <textblock>Upon request, meeting notices will be made available in alternate formats to accommodate visual and hearing impairments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals who have a disability and need an accommodation to attend the meeting may notify Patricia Batie at (202) 336-8800.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date Issued: January 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Patricia D. Batie,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Corporate Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1895 Filed 1-25-94; 2:06 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7050-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
