<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-1-00072</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>FDA believes that if the identities of reporters or patients</textblock>
    <textblock>were made public or available to third parties, health care</textblock>
    <textblock>professionals would be much more reluctant to submit voluntary</textblock>
    <textblock>adverse event reports for fear of involving themselves and their</textblock>
    <textblock>patients in litigation. It is well recognized that many</textblock>
    <textblock>physicians are concerned about the potential for involvement in</textblock>
    <textblock>litigation by their patients or third parties. In a 1992 survey</textblock>
    <textblock>of physicians regarding adverse event reporting, over 37 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>of the respondents agreed with the statement that reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>increases the risk of becoming involved in litigation; 18 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>of the respondents listed fear of becoming involved in the</textblock>
    <textblock>administrative or legal process as an important reason for not</textblock>
    <textblock>reporting adverse reactions (Ref. 7). Several other surveys</textblock>
    <textblock>have been conducted which asked physicians what factors</textblock>
    <textblock>influenced their decision not to report an adverse event (Refs. 8, 9, and 10). Between 8 and 14 percent of the respondents in</textblock>
    <textblock>the studies stated that concern over legal liability was one</textblock>
    <textblock>reason why they did not report an adverse event. Moreover, if</textblock>
    <textblock>the reporter is a health care professional, particularly a</textblock>
    <textblock>physician, the reporter may fear that disclosure of his or her</textblock>
    <textblock>identity would increase the chances that a patient's identity</textblock>
    <textblock>would be discovered, thus risking a breach of the confidential</textblock>
    <textblock>physician-patient relationship.</textblock>
    <textblock>In recent years FDA has learned of a number of product</textblock>
    <textblock>liability lawsuits in State courts in which manufacturers have</textblock>
    <textblock>been requested or ordered to provide the names of persons</textblock>
    <textblock>reporting adverse reactions to particular products. In some</textblock>
    <textblock>instances, the names of the affected patients have been</textblock>
    <textblock>requested. The manufacturers involved in these cases vigorously</textblock>
    <textblock>opposed discovery requests that sought the disclosure of patient</textblock>
    <textblock>and reporter identities. Occasionally, when the disclosure issue</textblock>
    <textblock>was being litigated, the manufacturers requested that FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>formally express its views on the disclosure of these identities</textblock>
    <textblock>and the effects such disclosure might have on the agency's</textblock>
    <textblock>postmarketing surveillance program.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA firmly believes that the success of its postmarketing</textblock>
    <textblock>surveillance efforts is dependent upon protecting the</textblock>
    <textblock>confidentiality of individuals involved in adverse experience</textblock>
    <textblock>reports. Thus, FDA took the unusual step of becoming involved</textblock>
    <textblock>in a number of these cases by filing, with the assistance of the Department of Justice, a statement of the Federal government's</textblock>
    <textblock>interest. The statement informed the courts of the potential</textblock>
    <textblock>damage the agency believes would be done to its postmarketing</textblock>
    <textblock>surveillance program and the public health if the identities of</textblock>
    <textblock>patients and reporters were released to plaintiffs in these</textblock>
    <textblock>cases. The agency believes that its efforts have contributed to</textblock>
    <textblock>continued protection of reporter and patient identities in all</textblock>
    <textblock>the cases in which FDA has participated.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. The Need for Federal Regulation</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA has determined that in order to help assure beneficial</textblock>
    <textblock>and consistent reporting of adverse events to the agency's</textblock>
    <textblock>MEDWATCH program, State and local rules that would permit or</textblock>
    <textblock>require disclosure of the identities of reporters and patients</textblock>
    <textblock>named in the reports must be clearly preempted by FDA's amended</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Laws that permit disclosure of the identities of health</textblock>
    <textblock>professional reporters or patients identified in the reports</textblock>
    <textblock>directly interfere with FDA's ability to collect information</textblock>
    <textblock>required under sections 505(k) and 519 of the act (21 U.S.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>355(k) and 360i). Section 505(k) requires manufacturers to</textblock>
    <textblock>submit information about approved drug products in order to</textblock>
    <textblock>enable FDA to monitor the safety of the product and ``facilitate a</textblock>
    <textblock>determination'' of whether the drug should be withdrawn from the</textblock>
    <textblock>market. This provision is implemented in ยง314.80 (21 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>314.80) of the FDA regulations, which establishes mandatory</textblock>
    <textblock>reporting requirements of adverse reactions for manufacturers of</textblock>
    <textblock>drugs.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
