<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-1-00074</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>IV. Legal Authority for Federal Preemption</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Principles of Preemption Law</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the Supremacy Clause of the Constitution, State law may be preempted by Federal law in a number of ways (U.S. Const., Art. VI, cl. 2.). Congress may preempt State law by so stating in express terms (</textblock>
    <textblock>Jones</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rath Packing Co.,</textblock>
    <textblock>430 U.S. 519 (1977)). Section 521 of the act contains an express preemption provision applicable to devices. Under that section, no State may establish a requirement for a device ``different from, or in addition to'' any requirement applicable to the device under the act relating to safety or effectiveness or other matter included in an applicable requirement. (See 21 CFR part 808;</textblock>
    <textblock>Commonwealth of Massachusetts</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Hayes,</textblock>
    <textblock>691 F.2d 57 (1st Cir. 1982)).</textblock>
    <textblock>Even when Congress has not expressly preempted State law, congressional intent to preempt may be inferred in several ways. Preemption may be found ``where the scheme of federal regulation is sufficiently comprehensive to make reasonable the inference that Congress `left no room' for supplementary state regulation'' (</textblock>
    <textblock>Hillsborough County</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Automated Medical Laboratories, Inc.,</textblock>
    <textblock>471 U.S. 707, 713 (1985), quoting</textblock>
    <textblock>Rice</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Santa Fe Elevator Corp.,</textblock>
    <textblock>331 U.S. 218, 230 (1947)), or where ``the federal interest is so dominant that the federal system will be assumed to preclude enforcement of state laws on the same subject'' (</textblock>
    <textblock>Rice</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Santa Fe Elevator Corp.,</textblock>
    <textblock>331 U.S. 218, 230 (1947); see</textblock>
    <textblock>Hines</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Davidowitz,</textblock>
    <textblock>312 U.S. 52 (1941)).</textblock>
    <textblock>Another way the courts infer a congressional intent to preempt is by determining that State law actually conflicts with Federal law. The conflict may be demonstrated either when ``compliance with both federal and state [law] is a physical impossibility'' (</textblock>
    <textblock>Florida Lime and Avocado Growers, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Paul,</textblock>
    <textblock>373 U.S. 132, 142-43 (1963)), or when State law ``stands as an obstacle to the accomplishment and execution of the full purpose and objectives of Congress'' (</textblock>
    <textblock>Hines</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Davidowitz,</textblock>
    <textblock>312 U.S. at 67). State law is also preempted if it interferes with the methods by which a Federal law is designed to reach its goals. (See</textblock>
    <textblock>International Paper Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ouellette,</textblock>
    <textblock>479 U.S. 481, 494 (1987);</textblock>
    <textblock>Michigan Canners &amp; Freezers Ass'n</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agricultural Marketing &amp; Bargaining Bd.,</textblock>
    <textblock>467 U.S. 461, 477 (1984).)</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition to the various ways in which preemption may result from congressional action or intent, ```a federal agency acting within the scope of its congressionally delegated authority may preempt state regulation' and hence render unenforceable state or local laws that are otherwise not inconsistent with federal law'' (</textblock>
    <textblock>City of New York</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>FCC,</textblock>
    <textblock>486 U.S. 57, 63-64 (1988), (quoting</textblock>
    <textblock>Louisiana Public Service Comm'n</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>FCC,</textblock>
    <textblock>476 U.S. 355, 368-69 (1986))). Express congressional authorization for an agency to preempt State law is not needed and ``federal regulations have no less preemptive effect than federal statutes.'' (</textblock>
    <textblock>Fidelity Federal Savings and Loan Assn</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>de la Cuesta,</textblock>
    <textblock>458 U.S. 141, 153, 154 (1982)).</textblock>
    <textblock>When an agency's intent to preempt is clearly and unambiguously stated, the Court's inquiry will be whether the preemptive action is within the scope of that agency's delegated authority (</textblock>
    <textblock>Capital Cities Cable, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Crisp,</textblock>
    <textblock>467 U.S. 691, 700 (1984);</textblock>
    <textblock>Fidelity Federal Savings,</textblock>
    <textblock>458 U.S. at 154). If the agency's choice to preempt ``represents a reasonable accommodation of conflicting policies that were committed to the agency's care by statute [the regulation will stand unless] it appears from statute or its legislative history that the accommodation is not one that Congress would have sanctioned'' (</textblock>
    <textblock>United States</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Shimer,</textblock>
    <textblock>367 U.S. 374, 383 (1961)). In</textblock>
    <textblock>Hillsborough County,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Court stated that FDA possessed the authority to promulgate regulations preempting local laws that compromise the supply of plasma and could do so (</textblock>
    <textblock>Hillsborough County,</textblock>
    <textblock>471 U.S. at 721). FDA believes it has similar authority to preempt local rules that compromise adverse reporting systems that are essential to postmarketing surveillance and protection of the public health.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Conflicts Between State Disclosure Laws and Federal Law</textblock>
    <textblock>The conflicts between State and local disclosure laws and Federal law on reporting of adverse events justify FDA's preemption of these laws. Although Congress did not expressly preempt State law in this area, the agency's action is appropriate because State and local laws significantly interfere with the methods by which the Federal law is designed to achieve its goals.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
