<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-0-00010</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-0-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Landowners may not receive payment under ECP and WRP on the same acreage. ECP payments shall be refunded, provided the ECP practice is within the required lifespan provisions, before a WRP payment will be disbursed, unless otherwise determined by the Deputy Administrator.</textblock>
    <textblock>13. Section 703.15 is amended by revising paragraphs (a), (b)(2), and (d) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง703.15</textblock>
    <textblock>Wetlands reserve plan of operations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Prior to filing an easement to enroll land in the WRP, the landowner must have obtained an ASCS approved WRPO for the land.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)(2) Specify the manner in which the farmed wetlands or prior converted croplands included in the enrolled land shall be restored, operated, and maintained to accomplish the goal of the program together with other practices which may be necessary or appropriate to accomplish the goals of the program, including, where appropriate:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) The WRPO must be signed by SCS, FWS, CD, ASCS, and the landowner before an easement is filed. If agreement between SCS and FWS at the local level is not reached within 20 calendar days of acceptance of the appraisal by the landowner, the WRPO shall be developed by the State Conservationist of SCS in consultation with FWS.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>14. Section 703.17(c) is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง703.17</textblock>
    <textblock>Transfer of land.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Any transfer of the property prior to the filing of the easement shall void any statement of intention to participate and WRP contract, unless the new owner agrees to be a party to the intention to participate or the contract within 60 calendar days of the recordation of the deed transferring the land to the new owner, or as otherwise determined by the Deputy Administrator.</textblock>
    <textblock>15. Section 703.25(c) is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง703.25</textblock>
    <textblock>Appeals.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) An appraisal and supporting documentation used by ASCS in determining property value are considered confidential information, and shall only be disclosed as determined at the sole discretion of ASCS.</textblock>
    <textblock>Signed at Washington, DC, on January 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Bruce R. Weber,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Administrator, Agricultural Stabilization</textblock>
    <textblock>and Conservation Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1683 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3410-05-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
