<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00058</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00047</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Public Law 92-463, notice is hereby given of the meeting of the AIDS Research Advisory Committee, National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, on March 1-2, 1994, in the Congressional Ballroom of the Marriott Hotel, 5151 Pooks Hill Road, Bethesda, Maryland 20814.</textblock>
    <textblock>The entire meeting will be open to the public from 8 a.m. until recess on March 1 and from 8 a.m. until adjournment on March 2. The AIDS Research Advisory Committee (ARAC) advises and makes recommendations to the Director, National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, on all aspects of research on HIV and AIDS related to the mission of the Division of AIDS (DAIDS).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Committee will provide advice on scientific priorities, policy, and program balance at the Division level. The Committee will review the progress and productivity of ongoing efforts, identify critical gaps/obstacles to progress, and provided concept clearance for proposed research initiatives. Attendance by the public will be limited to space available.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Anne P. Claysmith, Executive Secretary, AIDS Research Advisory Committee, DAIDS, NIAID, NIH, Solar Building, room 2A22, telephone (301) 496-0545, will provide a summary of the meeting and a roster of committee members upon request. Individuals who plan to attend and need special assistance, such as sign language interpretation or other reasonable accommodations, should contact Ms. Claysmith in advance of the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Program Nos. 93.855, Immunology, Allergic and Immunologic Diseases Research; 93.856, Microbiology and Infectious Diseases Research, National Institutes of Health.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Institutes of Allergy and Infectious Diseases; Meeting: AIDS Research Advisory Committee, NIAID</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Susan K. Feldman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Committee Management Officer, NIH.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1750 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4140-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
