<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-0-00030</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Airworthiness Directives; Wytwornia Sprzetu Komunikacyjnego</textblock>
    <textblock>``PZL-RZESZOW'' PZL-3S Second Series Engines</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 39</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 92-ANE-21; Amendment 39-8804; AD 94-02-06]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This amendment supersedes an existing airworthiness directive (AD), applicable to Wytwornia Sprzetu Komunikacyjnego ``PZL-RZESZOW'' PZL-3S Second Series engines, that currently requires removal from service of certain modified pistons, inspection of the propeller to engine propeller-flange attachment bolts, inspection of the engine propeller-flange retaining nut, and inspection of the rear crankshaft counterweight system. This amendment removes the repetitive inspection requirements of the existing AD, but retains the requirement to remove from service certain modified pistons. This amendment is prompted by test results that have indicated that PZL-3S Second Series engines not configured with modified pistons are not susceptible to excessive vibration. The actions specified by this AD are intended to prevent separation of the propeller and loss of the aircraft.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Robert J. Ganley, Aerospace Engineer, Engine Certification Office, FAA, Engine and Propeller Directorate, 12 New England Executive Park, Burlington, MA 01803-5299; telephone (617) 238-7138, fax (617) 238-7199.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>A proposal to amend part 39 of the Federal Aviation Regulations by superseding AD 91-18-12, Amendment 39-8120 (57 FR 5378, February 14, 1992), which is applicable to Wytwornia Sprzetu Komunikacyjnego ``PZL-RZESZOW'' PZL-3S Second Series engines, was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on January 5, 1993 (58 FR 278). That action proposed to remove the repetitive inspection requirements of the existing AD, but retain the requirements for removal from service of certain pistons that have been modified and assembled with certain compression ring, scraper ring, and oil control ring components.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons have been afforded an opportunity to participate in the making of this amendment. No comments were received on the proposal or the FAA's determination of the cost to the public. The FAA has determined that air safety and the public interest require the adoption of the rule as proposed.</textblock>
    <textblock>There are approximately 11 PZL-3S Second Series engines of the affected design in the worldwide fleet. The FAA estimates that 3 engines of the affected design are installed on aircraft of U.S. registry, that it will take approximately 5 work hours per engine to accomplish the proposed actions, and that the average labor rate is $55 per work hour. Based on these figures, the total cost impact of the AD on U.S. operators is estimated to be $825.</textblock>
    <textblock>The regulations adopted herein will not have substantial direct effects on the States, on the relationship between the national government and the States, or on the distribution of power and responsibilities among the various levels of government. Therefore, in accordance with Executive Order 12612, it is determined that this final rule does not have sufficient federalism implications to warrant the preparation of a Federalism Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons discussed above, I certify that this action (1) is not a ``significant regulatory action'' under Executive Order 12866; (2) is not a ``significant rule'' under DOT Regulatory Policies and Procedures (44 FR 11034, February 26, 1979); and (3) will not have a significant economic impact, positive or negative, on a substantial number of small entities under the criteria of the Regulatory Flexibility Act. A final evaluation has been prepared for this action and it is contained in the Rules Docket. A copy of it may be obtained from the Rules Docket at the location provided under the caption</textblock>
    <textblock>``ADDRESSES.''</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
