<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-1-00071</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>II. The Problem_Confidentiality of Reporters' Identities</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA believes that its success in encouraging health</textblock>
    <textblock>professionals to participate in the voluntary adverse event</textblock>
    <textblock>reporting system depends substantially on the guarantee of</textblock>
    <textblock>confidentiality given the identity of the reporter under FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations (§§20.111(c)(3), 314.430(e)(4), 601.51(e)(3), and</textblock>
    <textblock>803.9(b)). When FDA receives a request from the public for</textblock>
    <textblock>adverse reaction reports submitted voluntarily by health care</textblock>
    <textblock>professionals, consumers, patients, or manufacturers, FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations require public disclosure of those reports only after</textblock>
    <textblock>deletion of the following: (1) The names and any information</textblock>
    <textblock>that would identify the person using the product, and (2) the</textblock>
    <textblock>names and any information that would identify any third party</textblock>
    <textblock>involved with the report, such as a physician, hospital, or other</textblock>
    <textblock>institution (§20.111).</textblock>
    <textblock>The rationale for this policy was first articulated in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of December 24, 1974, in the preamble to FDA's</textblock>
    <textblock>public information regulations. At that time, FDA determined</textblock>
    <textblock>that without a guarantee of confidentiality, ``the possibility of</textblock>
    <textblock>persuading health professionals voluntarily to submit adverse</textblock>
    <textblock>reaction information is substantially diminished, and indeed</textblock>
    <textblock>perhaps wholly destroyed'' (39 FR 44602 at 44616).</textblock>
    <textblock>In the SMDA amendments, Congress provided some additional</textblock>
    <textblock>protection from involvement in private civil lawsuits to</textblock>
    <textblock>physicians who submit voluntary reports concerning adverse device</textblock>
    <textblock>events. Section 519(b)(3) of the act (21 U.S.C. 360i(b)(3)),</textblock>
    <textblock>added by the SMDA, provides that:</textblock>
    <textblock>[n]o report made under [the device user</textblock>
    <textblock>facility requirements] by a physician who is</textblock>
    <textblock>not required to make such a report, shall be</textblock>
    <textblock>admissible into evidence or otherwise used in</textblock>
    <textblock>any action involving private parties unless</textblock>
    <textblock>the facility, individual, or physician who</textblock>
    <textblock>made the report had knowledge of the falsity</textblock>
    <textblock>of the information contained in the report.</textblock>
    <textblock>Congress enacted this provision to encourage private physicians</textblock>
    <textblock>to notify FDA or the manufacturer of device problems (H. Rept.</textblock>
    <textblock>808, 101st Cong., 2d sess. 21 (1990)). This provision, however,</textblock>
    <textblock>may not be sufficient to prevent manufacturers from being</textblock>
    <textblock>compelled to release the reporters' or patients' identities</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to a discovery order.</textblock>
    <textblock>The policy and program considerations underlying the need to</textblock>
    <textblock>protect patient and reporter confidentiality have become even</textblock>
    <textblock>more compelling in recent years. The increase in product</textblock>
    <textblock>liability and medical malpractice litigation has heightened the</textblock>
    <textblock>reluctance of health professionals to report events observed by</textblock>
    <textblock>them if they are not given meaningful promises of</textblock>
    <textblock>confidentiality. In addition, the potential for discrimination</textblock>
    <textblock>connected with a diagnosis of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-positive status or acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS) has strengthened the commitment of health care professionals to</textblock>
    <textblock>protect patient privacy. As a direct reflection of FDA's</textblock>
    <textblock>longstanding regulations and commitment to this policy, the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency's MEDWATCH form (and its predecessors) expressly states</textblock>
    <textblock>that the information identifying the patient and reporter is held</textblock>
    <textblock>in confidence (see 58 FR 31611 through 31612, June 3, 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>However, in connection with FDA's current efforts to promote</textblock>
    <textblock>the MEDWATCH program and to increase reporting of serious adverse</textblock>
    <textblock>events, the health care community has voiced concerns about the</textblock>
    <textblock>agency's ability to safeguard confidentiality and protect the</textblock>
    <textblock>identities of the reporter and patient identified in the report,</textblock>
    <textblock>especially in situations where the report is in the possession of</textblock>
    <textblock>an individual manufacturer. Despite FDA's longstanding policy of</textblock>
    <textblock>keeping these identities confidential, the current concerns</textblock>
    <textblock>threaten to undermine the success of the voluntary reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>program.</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA published its draft uniform MEDWATCH form for reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>suspect adverse events and product problems on February 26, 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 11768). Subsequently, the agency received several</textblock>
    <textblock>comments about FDA's ability to maintain the confidentiality of</textblock>
    <textblock>patient and reporter identities: (1) When the report of an</textblock>
    <textblock>adverse event is made directly to the manufacturer or (2) when</textblock>
    <textblock>the manufacturer receives the information from FDA after a report</textblock>
    <textblock>is made to the agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>The MEDWATCH form permits individuals reporting directly to</textblock>
    <textblock>the agency to indicate that they do not want their identity</textblock>
    <textblock>disclosed to the manufacturer. However, the agency encourages</textblock>
    <textblock>reporters to allow the agency to share the reporter's identity</textblock>
    <textblock>with the manufacturer in order to help FDA and the manufacturer</textblock>
    <textblock>conduct necessary followup. Currently, State and local laws</textblock>
    <textblock>govern disclosure of information from adverse event report forms</textblock>
    <textblock>that are in the possession of manufacturers, whether the reports</textblock>
    <textblock>come directly to the manufacturer from reporters or are relayed</textblock>
    <textblock>to manufacturers by FDA. Some State and local laws allow or</textblock>
    <textblock>require disclosure of identities of reporters and patients in</textblock>
    <textblock>adverse event reports.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
