<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-1-00055</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-1-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Ohlone tiger beetle is not currently protected by any regulatory mechanism. The California Endangered Species Act does not apply to insects. The available information suggests that the species' restricted range and small population size increase the chance of extirpation resulting from stochastic (i.e., random) or localized events, such as rock slides, erosion, disease, or predation.</textblock>
    <textblock>The petition and supporting information have been reviewed by staff at the Ventura Field Office and the Portland Regional Office of the Service. The Service finds that the petition presents substantial information indicating that listing the Ohlone tiger beetle may be warranted. The Service requests any additional data, comments, and suggestions from the public, other concerned governmental agencies, the scientific community, industry, or any other interested parties concerning the status of the Ohlone tiger beetle. Of particular interest is information regarding:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The existence and status of additional populations;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Environmental factors determining distribution, including specific habitat needs;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Early life history; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The response of populations to disturbances such as fire, clearing, or mowing.</textblock>
    <textblock>This decision is based on information contained in the petition and scientific and commercial information otherwise available to the Service at this time.</textblock>
    <textblock>References Cited</textblock>
    <textblock>Freitag, R., D.H. Kavanaugh, and R. Morgan. 1993. A new species of</textblock>
    <textblock>Cicindela</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>Cicindela</textblock>
    <textblock>) (Coleoptera: Carabidae: Cicindelini) from remnant native grassland in Santa Cruz County, California. Coleopterists' Bulletin 47(2):113-120.</textblock>
    <textblock>Kaulbars, M.M., and R. Freitag. 1993. Geographical variation, classification, reconstructed phylogeny, and geographical history of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Cicindela sexguttata</textblock>
    <textblock>group (Coleoptera: Cicindelidae). The Canadian Entomologist 125(2):267-316.</textblock>
    <textblock>Knisley, C.B., T.D. Schultz, and T.H. Hasewinkel. 1990. Seasonal activity and thermoregulatory behavior of</textblock>
    <textblock>Cicindela patruela.</textblock>
    <textblock>Annals of the Entomological Society of America. Vol. 83, no. 5, pages 911-915.</textblock>
    <textblock>Lindroth, C. 1974. Handbooks for the identification of British insects; Coleoptera Carabidae. Volume IV, part 2. Royal Entomological Society of London. 148 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Author</textblock>
    <textblock>This document was prepared by Judy Hohman of the Ventura Field Office (see</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>section).</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority</textblock>
    <textblock>The authority for this action is the Endangered Species Act (16 U.S.C. 1531</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>).</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 50 CFR Part 17</textblock>
    <textblock>Endangered and threatened species, Exports, Imports, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, and Transportation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 19, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Russell D. Earnest,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Fish and Wildlife Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1703 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-55-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
