<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00002</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>ADMINISTRATIVE CONFERENCE OF THE UNITED STATES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Model Procedure and Practice Regulations</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative Conference of the United States.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Administrative Conference's Model Rules Working Group has completed a set of model procedure and practice regulations for agency adjudications.</textblock>
    <textblock>TO OBTAIN COPIES OF THE MODEL REGULATIONS CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Susan Mack, Administrative Conference of the United States, 2120 L Street NW., Washington, DC 20037, or (202) 254-7020.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Gary J. Edles or Jeffrey S. Lubbers, Administrative Conference of the United States, (202) 254-7020.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>A Working Group of the Office of the Chairman of the Administrative Conference has completed a set of model procedure and practice regulations, with related commentary, suitable for use in those agency proceedings that offer an opportunity for an oral, fact-finding hearing before an agency adjudicator, whether conducted pursuant to the Administrative Procedure Act, other statutes, or agency regulations or practice. Hearings are currently held before presiding officers at scores of federal departments and agencies. Each agency has its own set of procedure and practice rules that cover essentially the same procedural areas. To the extent that the conduct of hearings at these agencies presents similar problems, it appears useful to formulate a set of model procedure and practice rules that addresses common procedural problems. Such model regulations can be used by those agencies that are either required to establish formal procedures for new adjudicatory programs or interested in amending their existing rules in selected areas. Because each agency has its own, unique procedural needs, the model rules are not intended as a set of uniform procedures. Rather, they are designed to provide a set of recommendations that can be considered by agencies in light of their special procedural requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Jeffrey S. Lubbers, Research Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1783 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6110-01-W</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
