<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00102</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00069</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>III. Discussion and Conclusion</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission finds the proposed rule change to be consistent with the requirements of the Act and the rules and regulations thereunder applicable to a national securities exchange, and, in particular, with the requirements of sections 6(b) (5), (6) and (7) of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 6(b)(5) of the Act, requires</textblock>
    <textblock>inter alia,</textblock>
    <textblock>that, the rules of an exchange be designed to prevent fraudulent and manipulative acts and practices and to promote just and equitable principles of trade. The Commission believes that the addition of market makers to the list of persons who may have their registration summarily suspended will help to prevent fraudulent and manipulative acts by allowing the Exchange to take immediate action against a market maker who is acting unethically or in violation of Exchange rules or federal securities laws or regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 6(b)(6) of the Act provides that the rules of the Exchange should provide that exchange members and persons associated with its members be appropriately disciplined for violation of the provisions of the Act or rules and regulations thereunder or the rules of the exchange by expulsion, suspension, limitation of activities, functions, and operations, fine, censure, being suspended or barred from being associated with a member, or any other fitting sanction. The Commission believes that the summary suspension of market maker registration is an appropriate disciplinary action in cases where the market maker has acted unethically, violated Exchange Rules or the federal securities laws, since specialists and odd-lot dealers are already subject to such action and there is no reason to distinguish among the three groups. In addition, recent experience has shown the Exchange that summary suspension authority is needed for market makers as well as for other exchange members.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 6(b)(7) of the Act provides,</textblock>
    <textblock>inter alia,</textblock>
    <textblock>that the rules of an exchange must provide a fair procedure for the disciplining of members and persons associated with members. The Commission believes that it is fair to limit the power to summarily suspend member registration to the Exchange President. The Commission agrees that, due to the serious nature of summary suspension, it is appropriate to limit summary suspension ability to a senior Exchange official. The rules also provide adequate due process to persons summarily suspended by providing the opportunity for a prompt hearing on the matter and the ability to appeal any action taken to the Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is therefore ordered,</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to section 19(b)(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Act, that the proposed rule change (SR-CHX-93-17) be, and hereby is approved.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Commission, by the Division of Market Regulation, pursuant to delegated authority.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78f(b) (5), (6) and (7) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>11</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See note 8 and accompanying text.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>11</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>12</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(2) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>12</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>13</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 200.30-3(a)(12) (1992).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>13</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1674 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
