<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00019</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Public Information Collection Requirement Submitted to OMB for Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Defense has submitted to OMB for clearance, the following proposal for collection of information under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C., Chapter 35).</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>Vocational/Technical (VOTEC) Market Analysis Surveys</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Request:</textblock>
    <textblock>New collection</textblock>
    <textblock>Number of Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>21,000</textblock>
    <textblock>Responses Per Respondent:</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Responses:</textblock>
    <textblock>21,000</textblock>
    <textblock>Average Burden Per Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>40.7 minutes</textblock>
    <textblock>Annual Burden Hours:</textblock>
    <textblock>14,250</textblock>
    <textblock>Needs and Uses:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Army is investigating the feasibility of filling part of its training requirements from vocational graduate resources. If the Army can recruit applicants who are already trained in specific career areas, it can save training resources and provide units with trained soldiers faster. This study investigates the propensity of vocational students to enlist, as well as the incentives required to induce them to enlist.</textblock>
    <textblock>Affected Public:</textblock>
    <textblock>Businesses of other for-profit, Small businesses or organizations</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency:</textblock>
    <textblock>One time</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondent's Obligation:</textblock>
    <textblock>Voluntary</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB Desk Officer: Mr. Edward C. Springer.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments and recommendations on the proposed information collection should be sent to Mr. Springer at the Office of Management and Budget, Desk Officer for DoD, Room 3235, New Executive Office Building, Washington, DC 20503</textblock>
    <textblock>DOD Clearance Officer:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. William P. Pearce. Written requests for copies of the information collection proposal should be sent to Mr. Pearce, WHS/DIOR, 1215 Jefferson Davis Highway, Suite 1204, Arlington, VA 22202-4302</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </action>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Patricia L. Toppings,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Alternate OSD Federal Register Liaison Officer, Department of Defense.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1761 Filed 1-27-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 5000-04-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
