<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00010</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[A-588-091]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Large Electric Motors From Japan; Amendment to Notice of Intent To Revoke Antidumping Duty Order</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>International Trade Administration/Import Administration, Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendment to notice of intent to revoke antidumping duty order.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Commerce is correcting its December 27, 1993 notice of intent to revoke the antidumping duty order on large electric motors from Japan.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 27, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Elisabeth Urfer or Maureen Flannery, Office of Antidumping Compliance, International Trade Administration, U.S. Department of Commerce, Washington, DC 20230, telephone: (202) 482-4733.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 27, 1993, the Department of Commerce (the Department) published a notice of intent to revoke the antidumping duty order on large electric motors from Japan. Two clerical errors appeared in that notice with regard to the deadline for filing objections to the revocation of this order. As a result, the Department is making amendments to that notice. The second paragraph of the summary section is being amended to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Domestic interested parties who object to this revocation must submit their comments in writing no later than thirty days from January 27, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The first paragraph of the section titled ``opportunity to object'' is being amended to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>No later than thirty days from January 27, 1994, domestic interested parties as defined in ยง353.2(k) (3), (4), (5), and (6) of the Department's regulations may object to the Department's intent to revoke this antidumping duty order.</textblock>
    <textblock>The third paragraph of the section titled ``opportunity to object'' is being amended to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>No interested parties requested an administrative review in accordance with the Department's notice of opportunity to request administrative review by the end of the anniversary month. If domestic interested parties do not object to the Department's intent to revoke within thirty days from January 27, 1994, we shall conclude that the order is no longer of interest to interested parties and shall proceed with revocation.</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice is in accordance with 19 CFR 353.25(d).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Roland L. MacDonald,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary for Compliance.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1778 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DS-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
