<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-0-00039</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-0-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>North Carolina; Final Authorization of Revisions to State Hazardous Waste Management Program</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>40 CFR Part 271</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4829-8]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Immediate final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>North Carolina has applied for final authorization of revisions to its hazardous waste program under the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act (RCRA). North Carolina's revisions consist of the provisions contained in rules promulgated between July 1, 1990, and June 30, 1991, otherwise known as RCRA Cluster I. These requirements are listed in Section B of this document. The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) has reviewed North Carolina's application(s) and has made a decision, subject to public review and comment, that the North Carolina hazardous waste program revisions satisfy all of the requirements necessary to qualify for final authorization. Thus, EPA intends to approve North Carolina's hazardous waste program revisions. North Carolina's applications for program revisions are available for public review and comment.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final authorization for North Carolina's program revisions shall be effective March 28, 1994, unless EPA publishes a prior Federal Register action withdrawing this immediate final rule. All comments on North Carolina's program revision applications must be received by the close of business, February 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of North Carolina's program revision applications are available during normal business hours at the following addresses for inspection and copying: North Carolina Department of Environment, Health, and Natural Resources, Hazardous Waste Branch, P.O. Box 27687, Raleigh, North Carolina 27611-7687; U.S. EPA Region IV, Library, 345 Courtland Street, NE., Atlanta, Georgia 30365; (404) 347-4216. Written comments should be sent to Al Hanke at the address listed below.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Al Hanke, Chief, State Programs Section, Waste Programs Branch, Waste Management Division, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, 345 Courtland Street, NE., Atlanta, Georgia 30365; (404) 347-2234.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Background</textblock>
    <textblock>States with final authorization under section 3006(b) of the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act (``RCRA'' or ``the Act''), 42 U.S.C. 6926(b), have a continuing obligation to maintain a hazardous waste program that is equivalent to, consistent with, and no less stringent than the Federal hazardous waste program. In addition, as an interim measure, the Hazardous and Solid Waste Amendments of 1984 (Pub. L. 98-616, November 8, 1984, hereinafter ``HSWA'') allows States to revise their programs to become substantially equivalent instead of equivalent to RCRA requirements promulgated under HSWA authority. States exercising the latter option receive ``interim authorization'' for the HSWA requirements under section 3006(g) of RCRA, 42 U.S.C. 6926(g), and later apply for final authorization for the HSWA requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Revisions to State hazardous waste programs are necessary when Federal or State statutory or regulatory authority is modified or when certain other changes occur. Most commonly, State program revisions are necessitated by changes to EPA's regulations in 40 CFR parts 124, 260 through 268, and 270.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. North Carolina</textblock>
    <textblock>North Carolina initially received final authorization for its base RCRA program effective on December 31, 1984, (49 FR 48694). North Carolina most recently received final</textblock>
    <textblock>authorization effective February 16, 1993, for Non-HSWA Cluster VI and HSWA Cluster II (54 FR 59825, December 16, 1992). On September 21, 1992, North Carolina submitted program revision application for additional program approvals. On October 20, 1993, North Carolina submitted an addendium to the September 21, 1992, program revision application. Today, North Carolina is seeking approval of its program revisions in accordance with 40 CFR 271.21(b)(3).</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA has reviewed North Carolina's applications and has made an immediate final decision that North Carolina's hazardous waste program revisions satisfy all of the requirements necessary to qualify for final authorization. Consequently, EPA intends to grant final authorization for the additional program modifications to North Carolina. The public may submit written comments on EPA's immediate final decision up until February 28, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of North Carolina's application(s) for these program revisions are available for inspection and copying at the locations indicated in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Addresses</textblock>
    <textblock>section of this document.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
