<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00091</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00066</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>OFFICE OF PERSONNEL MANAGEMENT</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Partnership Council Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Personnel Management.</textblock>
    <textblock>aCTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of meeting.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Office of Personnel Management (OPM) announces a meeting of the National Partnership Council (the Council). Notice of this meeting is required under the Federal Advisory Committee Act.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>TIME AND PLACE:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Council will meet on January 31, 1994, at 2 p.m., in the auditorium at the Office of Personnel Management, Theodore Roosevelt Building, 1900 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20415-0001. The auditorium is located on the ground level. The Council has determined that this meeting is necessary to complete its work on the development of proposals to the President by January 31, 1994, as required by section 1(b)(2) of Executive Order 12871, and is therefore being announced with less than 15 days' advance notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>TYPE OF MEETING:</textblock>
    <textblock>This meeting will be open to the public. Seating will be available on a first-come, first-served basis. Handicapped individuals wishing to attend should contact OPM to obtain appropriate accommodations.</textblock>
    <textblock>POINT OF CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Douglas K. Walker, Office of Communications, Office of Personnel Management, Theodore Roosevelt Building, 1900 E Street, NW., room 5F12, Washington, DC 20415-0001, (202) 606-1800.</textblock>
  </date>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of this meeting is to develop proposals to the President on legislative changes to the Federal Labor-Management Relations Statute that are necessary to achieve the partnership objectives outlined in the National Performance Review (NPR) report. The Council will also make proposals concerning legislation consistent with the NPR's recommendations for the creation of a flexible and responsive hiring system and the reform of the General Schedule classification system and the performance management system.</textblock>
    <textblock>PUBLIC PARTICIPATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>We invite interested persons and organizations to submit comments on the principles and features that should be embodied in any of these legislative proposals. We are especially interested in suggestions and ideas to ensure that the proposed legislation carries out the intent of the NPR, as discussed in its report. Mail or deliver your comments or recommendations to Mr. Douglas K. Walker at the address shown above. Comments should be received by January 28 in order to be considered at the January 31 meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Personnel Management.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>James B. King,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1650 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6325-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
