<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00185</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00105</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION BOARD OF DIRECTORS</textblock>
    <textblock>Presidential Search Committee Meeting</textblock>
  </text>
  <date>
    <textblock>TIME AND DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>A meeting of the Legal Services Corporation Board of Directors Presidential Search Committee will be held on January 28, 1994. The meeting will commence at 5:00 p.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>PLACE:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Legal Services Corporation, 750 1st Street, N.E., 11th Floor, The Board Room, Washington, D.C. 20002, (202) 336-8800.</textblock>
    <textblock>STATUS OF MEETING:</textblock>
    <textblock>Open,</textblock>
    <textblock>except that part of the meeting may be closed pursuant to a vote, to be solicited prior to the meeting, of a majority of the Board of Directors. Should the aforementioned majority vote to close all or a portion of the meeting be obtained, the Committee will, with its Advisory Committee, consider prospective candidates for the position of President of the Corporation. The closing will be authorized by the relevant sections of the Government in the Sunshine Act [5 U.S.C. Sections 552b(c)(2) and (6)], and the corresponding regulation of the Legal Services Corporation [45 C.F.R. Section 1622.5(a) and (e)]. The closing will be certified by the Corporation's General Counsel as authorized by the above-cited provisions of law. A copy of the General Counsel's certification will be posted for public inspection at the Corporation's headquarters, located at 750 First Street, N.E., Washington, D.C. 20002, in its eleventh floor reception area, and will otherwise be available upon request.</textblock>
    <textblock>January 28, 1994 Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>MATTERS TO BE CONSIDERED:</textblock>
    <textblock>OPEN SESSION:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Approval of Agenda</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Approval of Minutes of January 7, 1994 Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Consider and Act on Search Procedure issues</textblock>
    <textblock>CLOSED SESSION:</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Approval of Minutes of January 7, 1994 Executive Session</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Consider, With Advisory Committee, Candidates for the Position of President of the Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>OPEN SESSION:</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Consider and Act on Other Business</textblock>
    <textblock>CONTACT PERSON FOR INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Patricia D. Batie, Executive Office, (202) 336-8800.</textblock>
    <textblock>Upon request, meeting notices will be made available in alternate formats to accommodate visual and hearing impairments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals who have a disability and need an accommodation to attend the meeting may notify Patricia Batie at (202) 336-8800.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date Issued: January 25, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Patricia D. Batie,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Corporate Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1896 Filed 1-25-94; 2:05 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7050-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
