<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00153</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00089</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee Meeting on Air Carrier/General Aviation Maintenance Issues</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA is issuing this notice to advise the public of a meeting of the Federal Aviation Administration Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee to discuss air carrier/general aviation maintenance issues.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held on February 18, 1994, at 8:30 a.m. Arrange for oral presentations by February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held at the Air Transport Association of America, 1301 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., suite 1100, Washington, DC, in conference room A.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Barbara Herber, Meeting Coordinator, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591, telephone (202) 267-3493; fax number (202) 267-5075.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>Act (Pub. L. 92-463; 5 U.S.C. app. II), notice is hereby given of a meeting of the Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee to consider air carrier/general aviation maintenance issues. The meeting will be held on February 18, 1994, at ATA, 1301 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., suite 1100, Washington, DC, in conference room A. The agenda will include:</textblock>
    <textblock>•Report on the status of recommendations submitted to the FAA by the Part 65 Working Group.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Plan of action and milestones for Part 65 Phase II.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Report on the status of the Maintenance Recordkeeping draft NPRM.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Report on the status of the International Airworthiness Communications draft NPRM.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Plan of action and milestones for the Major/Minor Working Group.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Plan of action and milestones for the Parts Approval Action Team Phase III Working Group.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Discussion of future activities and other business.</textblock>
    <textblock>Attendance is open to the interested public but may be limited to the space available. The public must make arrangements on or before February 8, 1994, to present oral statements at the meeting. The public may present written statements to the executive committee at any time by providing 35 copies to the Executive Director, or by bringing the copies to him at the meeting. In addition, sign and oral interpretation can be made available at the meeting, as well as an assistive listening device, if requested 10 calendar days before the meeting. Arrangements may be made by contacting the meeting coordinator listed under the heading</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Frederick J. Leonelli,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Executive Director for Air Carrier/General Aviation Maintenance Issues, Aviation Rulemaking Advisory</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1647 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
