<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-0-00044</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-0-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Thursday</textblock>
    <textblock>January 27, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part II</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Transportation</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration</textblock>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 121, et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>Special Federal Aviation Regulations No. 36, Development of Major Repair Data; Final Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 18␣/␣Thursday, January 27, 1994␣/␣Rules and Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>14 CFR Parts 121, 127, 135, and 145</textblock>
    <textblock>Special Federal Aviation Regulation No. 36, Development of Major Repair Data</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 17551; SFAR Amendment No. 36-6]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This final rule amends and extends Special Federal Aviation Regulation (SFAR) No. 36, which provides that authorized repair station and aircraft operating certificate holders may approve aircraft products or articles for return to service after accomplishing major repairs using self-developed repair data that have not been approved by the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA). Amendments include clarification of the scope of the SFAR authorization. Extension of the regulation continues to provide, for those that qualify, an alternative from the requirement to obtain FAA approval of major repair data on a case-by-case basis, and allows additional time for the FAA to incorporate the SFAR provisions into the regulations.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective January 23, 1994 and terminates January 23, 1999.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Todd Thompson, Continued Airworthiness Staff, Aircraft Engineering Division, AIR-107, Federal Aviation Administration, 800 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC 20591, telephone: (202) 267-7218.</textblock>
  </further>
</doc>
