<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00137</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00080</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Investment Company Act Rel. No. 20030; 812-8736]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>The Alger Fund, et al.; Notice of Application</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Securities and Exchange Commission (``SEC'').</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of application for exemption under the Investment Company Act of 1940 (``Act'').</textblock>
    <textblock>APPLICANTS:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Alger Fund (the ``Fund''), any future series thereof, and any registered investment company for which Fred Alger &amp; Company, Incorporated serves in the future as principal underwriter or for which any person controlling, controlled by, or under common control with Fred Alger &amp; Company, Incorporated (within the meaning of section 2(a)(9) of the Act) may in the future serve as principal underwriter; and Fred Alger &amp; Company, Incorporated (the ``Distributor'').</textblock>
    <textblock>RELEVANT ACT SECTIONS:</textblock>
    <textblock>Order requested under section 6(c) of the Act amending previous orders that granted an exemption from sections 2(a)(32), 2(a)(35), 22(c) and 22(d) of the Act, and rule 22c-1 thereunder.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY OF APPLICATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Fund previously received exemptive orders that permit it to impose a contingent deferred sales charge (``CDSC'') on certain redemptions of shares, and waive the CDSC in certain instances. Applicants now seek to amend the prior orders to permit the Fund to waive the CDSC in connection with redemptions effected by registered investment advisers, banks and trust companies and other financial institutions exercising discretionary authority with respect to the money invested in Fund shares and on redemptions effected by registered investment advisers for their own account.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>FILING DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>The application was filed on December 21, 1993 and amended on January 21, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>HEARING OR NOTIFICATION OF HEARING:</textblock>
    <textblock>An order granting the application will be issued unless the SEC orders a hearing. Interested persons may request a hearing by writing to the SEC's Secretary and serving applicants with a copy of the request, personally or by mail. Hearing requests should be received by the SEC by 5:30 p.m. on February 15, 1994, and should be accompanied by proof of service on the applicants, in the form of an affidavit or, for lawyers, a certificate of service. Hearing requests should state the nature of the writer's interest, the reason for the request, and the issues contested. Persons who wish to be notified of a hearing may request such notification by writing to the SEC's Secretary.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretary, SEC, 450 Fifth Street NW., Washington, DC 20549. Applicants, The Alger Fund, 75 Maiden Lane, New York, New York 10038; Fred Alger &amp; Company, Incorporated, 30 Montgomery Street, Jersey City, New Jersey 07302.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Marc Duffy, Staff Attorney, at (202) 272-2511, or C. David Messman, Branch Chief, at (202) 272-3018 (Division of Investment Management, Office of Investment Company Regulation).</textblock>
  </further>
</doc>
