<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-0-00005</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-0-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>ยง7301.101</textblock>
    <textblock>General.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with 5 CFR 2635.105, the regulations in this part apply to employees of the Inter-American Foundation, with the exception of members of the Foundation's Board of Directors and Advisory Council, and supplement the Standards of Ethical Conduct for Employees of the Executive Branch contained in 5 CFR part 2635. In addition to the standards in 5 CFR part 2635, directors and other employees are subject to the executive branch financial disclosure regulations contained in 5 CFR part 2634.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Designated agency ethics official.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of this part and otherwise as required by 5 CFR 2638.202, the General Counsel of the Inter-American Foundation shall serve as the designated agency ethics official. The Deputy General Counsel shall serve as the alternate agency ethics official.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง7301.102</textblock>
    <textblock>Prior approval for outside teaching, speaking and writing.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Before engaging in outside teaching, speaking or writing, for compensation, an employee, with the exception of members of the Foundation's Board of Directors and Advisory Council, shall obtain prior written approval from the designated agency ethics official or the alternate agency ethics official.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Approval shall be granted only upon a determination that the outside teaching, speaking or writing is not expected to involve conduct prohibited by statute or Federal regulation, including 5 CFR part 2635.</textblock>
    <textblock>22 CFR CHAPTER X_INTER-AMERICAN FOUNDATION</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Part 1001 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 1001_EMPLOYEE RESPONSIBILITIES AND CONDUCT</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>5 U.S.C. 7301.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง1001.1</textblock>
    <textblock>Cross-references to employee ethical conduct standards and financial disclosure regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Directors and other employees of the Inter-American Foundation should refer to the Standards of Ethical Conduct for Employees of the Executive Branch at 5 CFR part 2635, the Inter-American Foundation regulations at 5 CFR part 7301 which supplement the executive branch standards, and the executive branch financial disclosure regulations at 5 CFR part 2634.</textblock>
  </text>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1693 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7025-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
