<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00050</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00039</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Public Law 92-463, notice is hereby given of the meeting of the Board of Scientific Counselors, DCT, National Cancer Institute, National Institutes of Health, February 14-15, 1994, Building 31C, Conference Room 6, 9000 Rockville Pike, Bethesda, Maryland 20892.</textblock>
    <textblock>This meeting will be open to the public on February 14 from 8 a.m. to approximately 5:15 p.m., and again on February 15 from approximately 11:15 a.m. until adjournment, to review program plans, concepts of contract recompetitions and budget for the DCT program. In addition, there will be scientific reviews by several programs in the Division. Attendance by the public will be limited to space available.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the provisions set forth in sec. 552b(c)(6), Title 5, U.S.C. and sec. 19(d) of Public Law 92-463, the meeting will be closed to the public on February 15 from 8 a.m. to approximately 11 a.m., for the review, discussion and evaluation of individual programs and projects conducted by the National Cancer Institute, including consideration of personnel qualifications and performance, the competence of individual investigators, and similar items, the disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Carole Frank, Committee Management Officer, National Cancer Institute, Executive Plaza North Building, room 630, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland 20892 (301-496-5708) will provide summaries of the meeting and rosters of committee members upon request.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Bruce A. Chabner, Director, Division of Cancer Treatment, National Cancer Institute, Building 31, room 3A44, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland 20892 (301-496-4291) will furnish substantive program information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals who plan to attend and need special assistance, such as sign language interpretation or other reasonable accomodations, should contact Dr. Bruce Chabner (301-496-4291) in advance of the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Program Numbers: 93.393, Cancer Cause and Prevention Research; 93.394, Cancer Detection and Diagnosis Research; 93.395, Cancer Treatment Research; 93.396, Cancer Biology Research; 93.397, Cancer Centers Support; 93.398, Cancer Research Manpower; 93.399, Cancer Control)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Institutes of Health</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Cancer Institute; Meeting (Division of Cancer Treatment Board of Scientific Counselors)</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Susan K. Feldman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Committee Management Officer, NIH.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1747 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4140-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
