<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-1-00068</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-1-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Reporting by physicians and other health care professionals</textblock>
    <textblock>of adverse experiences associated with the administration of most</textblock>
    <textblock>products is strictly voluntary. As the agency's primary source</textblock>
    <textblock>of adverse event information, this voluntary reporting system has</textblock>
    <textblock>revealed significant adverse events and drug interactions</textblock>
    <textblock>associated with products that could not be identified during the</textblock>
    <textblock>preapproval testing. There are many instances of important</textblock>
    <textblock>public health actions that have been the direct or indirect</textblock>
    <textblock>result of information provided through voluntary reporting by</textblock>
    <textblock>individual health professionals. The removal of the antibiotic</textblock>
    <textblock>temafloxacin (Omniflox) from the market, research concerning the</textblock>
    <textblock>danger of concurrent use of the antihistamine terfenadine</textblock>
    <textblock>(Seldane) when taken with either the antifungal ketoconazole or</textblock>
    <textblock>the antibiotic erythromycin, and the warning labeling requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>for latex products are just a few examples that demonstrate why</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA strongly encourages voluntary reporting by physicians and</textblock>
    <textblock>other health professionals.</textblock>
    <textblock>In a major effort to increase voluntary reporting of serious</textblock>
    <textblock>adverse events by health professionals, FDA recently announced a</textblock>
    <textblock>new reporting system called MEDWATCH. This program is designed to</textblock>
    <textblock>make it easier for health care providers to report serious</textblock>
    <textblock>adverse events and to clarify what type of information should be</textblock>
    <textblock>reported. The agency believes that preserving the</textblock>
    <textblock>confidentiality of the identities of the patient and of third</textblock>
    <textblock>parties involved with an adverse event report, such as the</textblock>
    <textblock>physician or others identified in the report, is essential to the</textblock>
    <textblock>success of the adverse event reporting system. Accordingly,</textblock>
    <textblock>although the substantive content of adverse event reports is</textblock>
    <textblock>public information under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), 5</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S.C. 552, FDA regulations have long protected the</textblock>
    <textblock>confidentiality of the patient, reporter, and institution</textblock>
    <textblock>involved in the adverse event (ยง20.111 (21 CFR 20.111)). These</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations, which have been in place since 1974, have enabled</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA to obtain voluntary reports of adverse events and to protect</textblock>
    <textblock>the confidentiality of information that could identify the</textblock>
    <textblock>patient involved.</textblock>
    <textblock>Although these regulations protect the release of</textblock>
    <textblock>confidential information by FDA, they do not protect the release</textblock>
    <textblock>of the same information contained in reports held by drug,</textblock>
    <textblock>biologic, and device manufacturers. Various State and local</textblock>
    <textblock>governments have laws, regulations, or rules that permit</textblock>
    <textblock>disclosure of this information in litigation, through discovery</textblock>
    <textblock>or otherwise. Recently, plaintiffs in several product liability</textblock>
    <textblock>and medical malpractice cases have attempted to discover the</textblock>
    <textblock>identities of reporters and patients named in adverse event</textblock>
    <textblock>reports in the possession of the product manufacturers. As</textblock>
    <textblock>discussed above, this same information is protected from public</textblock>
    <textblock>disclosure when it is contained in similar or identical reports</textblock>
    <textblock>submitted to FDA and in FDA's possession. To avoid jeopardizing</textblock>
    <textblock>the willingness of the health care community to make reports of</textblock>
    <textblock>adverse events to manufacturers and FDA, the agency believes that</textblock>
    <textblock>a similar confidentiality rule is needed to prevent disclosure or</textblock>
    <textblock>threats of disclosure of the identity of reporters or subjects of</textblock>
    <textblock>adverse event reports in the possession of manufacturers.</textblock>
    <textblock>To ensure meaningful reporting under the new MEDWATCH</textblock>
    <textblock>program, FDA believes that additional steps must be taken to</textblock>
    <textblock>safeguard the confidentiality of the identities of those involved</textblock>
    <textblock>with adverse event reports. State and local laws, regulations,</textblock>
    <textblock>or rules that permit or require the disclosure of patient and</textblock>
    <textblock>reporters' identities interfere with the agency's objective of</textblock>
    <textblock>ensuring the safety of human drugs, biologics, and devices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, FDA is proposing to amend its regulations to prohibit</textblock>
    <textblock>the disclosure of such information contained in reports held by</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA, as provided currently, and similar information held by</textblock>
    <textblock>manufacturers. The proposal also would preempt State and local</textblock>
    <textblock>laws, regulations, or rules that permit or require such</textblock>
    <textblock>disclosure. Disclosure would be permitted if both the reporter</textblock>
    <textblock>and the person identified in the report consent to disclosure or</textblock>
    <textblock>if there is a discovery order in malpractice litigation between</textblock>
    <textblock>the subject of the report and the reporter of the adverse event.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. FDA Adverse Event Reporting Programs</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Drug and Non-Vaccine Biological Products</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA receives postmarketing adverse drug reaction (ADR)</textblock>
    <textblock>reports directly from manufacturers, health professionals, and</textblock>
    <textblock>consumers. An adverse drug or biologic experience means any</textblock>
    <textblock>adverse event associated with the use of the product in humans, whether or not the event is considered related to the drug or</textblock>
    <textblock>biologic. Included are events that occur in the course of</textblock>
    <textblock>professional use, from drug overdose (whether intentional or</textblock>
    <textblock>accidental), from drug abuse, from drug withdrawal, and any</textblock>
    <textblock>failure of an expected pharmacological action (ยง314.80 (21 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>314.80(a)).</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA regulations require drug manufacturers to report to FDA</textblock>
    <textblock>serious and unexpected adverse reactions and increased frequency</textblock>
    <textblock>of serious expected reactions. These reports must be filed</textblock>
    <textblock>within a specific time after the manufacturer receives the</textblock>
    <textblock>information. Manufacturers are also required to submit periodic</textblock>
    <textblock>reports of all adverse reactions (ยง314.80). FDA has proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>similar adverse experience reporting requirements for</textblock>
    <textblock>manufacturers of licensed biological products (March 29, 1990, 55</textblock>
    <textblock>FR 11611) and expects to publish final regulations in the near</textblock>
    <textblock>future. The reporting of these adverse reactions by health</textblock>
    <textblock>professionals to either manufacturers or FDA, however, is</textblock>
    <textblock>strictly voluntary. (Health care providers are required to</textblock>
    <textblock>report certain adverse events associated with specific vaccines</textblock>
    <textblock>under the National Childhood Vaccine Injury Act. See section</textblock>
    <textblock>I.B.3 of this document.) The agency is also preparing a proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule to require adverse drug reaction reporting by manufacturers</textblock>
    <textblock>of nonprescription drug products.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
