<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00156</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00091</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>G&amp;K Automotive Conversion, Inc. of Santa Ana, California (Registered Importer No. R-90-007) has petitioned NHTSA to determine whether 1991 Mercedes-Benz 500SEL (Model ID 126.037) passenger cars are eligible for importation into the United States. The vehicle which G&amp;K believes is substantially similar is the 1991 Mercedes-Benz 420SEL, which was manufactured for importation into, and sale in the United States, and certified by its manufacturer, Daimler Benz A.G., as conforming to all applicable Federal motor vehicle safety standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>The petitioner contends that it carefully compared the 1991 model 500SEL to the 1991 model 420SEL, and found the two vehicles to be substantially similar with respect to compliance with most applicable Federal motor vehicle safety standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>G&amp;K submitted information with its petition intended to demonstrate that the 1991 model 500SEL, as originally manufactured, conforms to many Federal motor vehicle safety standards in the same manner as the 1991 model 420SEL, or is capable of being readily modified to conform to those standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Specifically, the petitioner claims that the 1991 model 500SEL is identical to the 1991 model 420SEL with respect to compliance with Standard Nos. 102</textblock>
    <textblock>Transmission Shift Lever Sequence.</textblock>
    <textblock>*␣*␣*␣, 103</textblock>
    <textblock>Defrosting and Defogging Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>104</textblock>
    <textblock>Windshield Wiping and Washing Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>105</textblock>
    <textblock>Hydraulic Brake Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>106</textblock>
    <textblock>Brake Hoses,</textblock>
    <textblock>107</textblock>
    <textblock>Reflecting Surfaces,</textblock>
    <textblock>109</textblock>
    <textblock>New Pneumatic Tires,</textblock>
    <textblock>113</textblock>
    <textblock>Hood Latch Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>116</textblock>
    <textblock>Brake Fluid,</textblock>
    <textblock>124</textblock>
    <textblock>Accelerator Control Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>201</textblock>
    <textblock>Occupant Protection in Interior Impact,</textblock>
    <textblock>202</textblock>
    <textblock>Head Restraints,</textblock>
    <textblock>204</textblock>
    <textblock>Steering Control Rearward Displacement,</textblock>
    <textblock>205</textblock>
    <textblock>Glazing Materials,</textblock>
    <textblock>207</textblock>
    <textblock>Seating Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>209</textblock>
    <textblock>Seat Belt Assemblies,</textblock>
    <textblock>210</textblock>
    <textblock>Seat Belt Assembly Anchorages,</textblock>
    <textblock>211</textblock>
    <textblock>Wheel Nuts, Wheel Discs and Hubcaps,</textblock>
    <textblock>212</textblock>
    <textblock>Windshield Retention,</textblock>
    <textblock>216</textblock>
    <textblock>Roof Crush Resistance,</textblock>
    <textblock>219</textblock>
    <textblock>Windshield Zone Intrusion,</textblock>
    <textblock>and 302</textblock>
    <textblock>Flammability of Interior Materials.</textblock>
    <textblock>Petitioner also contends that the 1991 model 500SEL is capable of being readily modified to meet the following standards, in the manner indicated:</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 101␣Controls and Displays</textblock>
    <textblock>: (a) Substitution of a lens marked ``Brake'' for a lens with an ECE symbol on the brake failure indicator lamp; (b) installation of a seat belt warning lamp that displays the seat belt symbol; (c) recalibration of the speedometer/odometer from kilometers to miles per hour.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 108␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Lamps, Reflective Devices and Associated Equipment:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Installment of U.S.- model headlamp assemblies with incorporate sealed beam headlamps and front sidemarkers; (b) installation of U.S.-model taillamp assemblies which incorporate rear sidemarkers; (c) installation of a high mounted stop lamp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 110␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Tire Selection and Rims:</textblock>
    <textblock>Installation of a tire information placard.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 111␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Rearview Mirror:</textblock>
    <textblock>Replacement of the passenger's outside rearview mirror, which is convex but does not bear the required warning statement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 114␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Theft Protection:</textblock>
    <textblock>Installation of a buzzer microswitch in the steering lock assembly, and a warning buzzer.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 115␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Vehicle Identification Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>Installation of a VIN plate that can be read from outside the left windshield pillar, and a VIN reference label on the edge of the door or latch post nearest the driver.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 118␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Power-Operated Window Systems:</textblock>
    <textblock>Rewiring of the power window system so that the window transport is inoperative when the ignition is turned off.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 206␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Door Locks and Door Retention Components:</textblock>
    <textblock>Replacement of the rear door locks with U.S.-model components.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 208␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Occupant Crash Protection:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Installation of an ignition switch-actuated seat belt warning buzzer; (b) replacement of the existing Type 1 rear seat belts with U.S. model belts equipped with retractors; (c) installation of knee bolsters to augment the vehicle's airbag-based automatic restraint system.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 214␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Side Door Strength:</textblock>
    <textblock>Installation of reinforcing beams.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 301␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Fuel System Integrity:</textblock>
    <textblock>Installation of a rollover valve in the fuel tank vent line between the fuel and the evaporative emissions collection canister.</textblock>
    <textblock>Additionally, the petitioner states that the bumpers on the 1991 model 500SEL must be reinforced to comply with the Bumper Standard found in 49 CFR part 581.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to submit comments on the petition described above. Comments should refer to the docket number and be submitted to: Docket Station, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, room 5109, 400 Seventh Street, SW., Washington, DC 20590. It is requested but not required that 10 copies be submitted.</textblock>
    <textblock>All comments received before the close of business on the closing date indicated above will be considered, and will be available for examination in the docket at the above address both before and after that date. To the extent possible, comments filed after the closing date will also be considered. Notice of final action on the petition will be published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to the authority indicated below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 1397(c)(3) (A)(i)(I) and (C)(ii); 49 CFR 593.8; delegations of authority at 49 CFR 1.50 and 501.8.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued on: January 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William A. Boehly,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Administrator for Enforcement.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1665 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-59-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
