<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00169</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00096</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Dockets No. 90-06 and 91-20 GR]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Report on Rear Hatch, Tailgate, and Back Door Opening in Crashes and Occupant Ejection Through the Back Area</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Request for comments.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice announces the publication by NHTSA of a report concerning ``Door Opening and Occupant Ejection through Rear Hatches, Tailgates, and Other Back Doors.'' This report analyzes the available data on door opening and occupant ejection from hatchback cars, stationwagons, sport utility vehicles, and light vans_vehicles frequently equipped with a rear hatch, tailgate, or other back door_that were involved in towaway crashes. This report was done as part of the agency's effort to understand the mechanisms of injury in vehicle crashes. It updates a 1990 report on ``Hatchback, Tailgate, and Back Door Opening in Crashes and Occupant Ejection through the Back Area,'' by adding four more years of the agency's detailed data on door opening and occupant ejection. The agency seeks public review and comment on this report.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be received no later than March 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons may obtain a free copy of the report by sending a self-addressed mailing label to Ms. Glorious Harris (NAD-51), National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, 400 Seventh Street SW., Washington, DC 20590. (Docket hours, 8 a.m.-4 p.m., Monday through Friday.)</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Patricia Breslin, Director, Office of Vehicle Safety Standards, Rulemaking, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, room 5320, 400 Seventh Street SW., Washington, DC 20590 (202-366-0842).</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued: January 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Barry Felrice,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Administrator for Rulemaking.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1727 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-59-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
