<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00154</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00090</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Executive Committee of the Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA is issuing this notice to advise the public of a meeting of the executive committee of the Federal Aviation Administration Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held on February 10, 1994, at 8:30 a.m. Arrange for oral presentations by February 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held at the General Aviation Manufacturers Association, 1400 K Street, NW., suite 801, Washington, DC, 8:30 a.m.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Miss Jean Casciano, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591, telephone (202) 267-9683; fax number (202) 267-5075.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463; 5 U.S.C. App. II), notice is hereby given of a meeting of the executive committee to be held on February 10, 1994, at the General Aviation Manufacturers Association, 1400 K Street, NW., suite 801, Washington. The agenda will include:</textblock>
    <textblock>•An update on the FAA/JAA Harmonization Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>•JAA membership on the Executive Committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>•A discussion of direct rulemaking for ARAC documents.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Follow-up on open action items.</textblock>
    <textblock>•A status report on working group and internal FAA procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Status reports on issues.</textblock>
    <textblock>•Other business.</textblock>
    <textblock>Attendance is open to the interested public but will be limited to the space available. The public must make arrangements by February 3, 1994, to present oral statements at the meeting. The public may present written statements to the executive committee at any time by providing 20 copies to the Executive Director, or by bringing the copies to him at the meeting. In addition, sign and oral interpretation can be made available at the meeting, as well as an assistive listening device, if requested 10 calendar days before the meeting. Arrangements may be made by contacting the person listed under the heading</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Chris A. Christie,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Executive Director, Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1648 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-30-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
