<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00202</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00112</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>29 U.S.C. 794, section 504_Rehabilitation Act of 1973, and 7 CFR part 15B (USDA implementation of the statute), prohibiting discrimination based upon physical or mental handicap in Federally assisted programs;</textblock>
    <textblock>35 U.S.C. 200</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>_Bayh-Dole Act, controlling allocation of rights to inventions made by employees of small business firms and domestic nonprofit organizations, including universities, in Federally assisted programs (implementing regulations are contained in 37 CFR part 401).</textblock>
    <textblock>Programmatic Contact</textblock>
    <textblock>For additional information on the Program, please contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. David MacKenzie or Dr. Ann Lichens-Park, Cooperative State Research Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Ag Box 2220, Washington, DC 20250-2220, Telephone: (202) 401-4892</textblock>
    <textblock>␣␣␣or</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Robert Faust, Agricultural Research Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, room 336, Building 005, BARC-West, Beltsville, MD 20705, Telephone: (301) 504-5059.</textblock>
    <textblock>How To Obtain Application Materials</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of this solicitation, the administrative provisions for the Program (7 CFR part 3415), and the Application Kit will be made available upon request. The Application Kit contains required forms, certifications, and instructions for preparing and submitting grant applications. The administrative provisions include guidelines for proposal format. Copies of this solicitation, the administrative provisions, and the Application Kit may be obtained by contacting: Proposal Services Branch, Awards Management Division, Cooperative State Research Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Ag Box 2245, Washington, DC 20250-2245, Telephone Number: (202) 401-5048</textblock>
    <textblock>Application materials may also be requested via Internet by sending a message with your name, mailing address (not e-mail) and telephone number to psb@csrs.esusda.gov which states that you wish to receive a copy of the application materials for the Fiscal Year 1994 Biotechnology Risk Assessment Research Grants Program. The materials will then be mailed to you (not e-mailed) as quickly as possible.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposal Format</textblock>
    <textblock>The format guidelines for full research proposals, found in the administrative provisions for the Program at s3415.4(d), should be followed for the preparation of proposals under the Program in fiscal year 1994 (Note that the Department elects not to solicit preproposals nor conference grant proposals in fiscal year 1994).</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance With the National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA)</textblock>
    <textblock>As outlined in 7 CFR part 3407 and 7 CFR part 520 (the CSRS and ARS regulations implementing the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969), environmental data for any proposed project is to be provided to CSRS and ARS so that CSRS and ARS may determine whether any further action is needed. The applicant shall review the following categorical exclusions and determine if the proposed project may fall within one of the categories.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Department of Agriculture Categorical Exclusions (7 CFR 1b.3)</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Policy development, planning and implementation which are related to routine activities such as personnel, organizational changes, or similar administrative functions;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Activities which deal solely with the funding of programs, such as program budget proposals, disbursements, and transfer or reprogramming of funds;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Inventories, research activities, and studies, such as resource inventories and routine data collection when such actions are clearly limited in context and intensity;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Educational and informational programs and activities;</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) Civil and criminal law enforcement and investigative activities;</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) Activities which are advisory and consultative to other agencies and public and private entities; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(vii) Activities related to trade representation and market development activities abroad.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
