<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00164</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00094</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>J.K. Motors, Inc. of Kingsville, Maryland (``J.K.'') (Registered Importer No. R-90-006) has petitioned NHTSA to determine whether 1970 Ferrari 365 GT 2+2 passenger cars are eligible for importation into the United States. The vehicle which J.K. believes is substantially similar is the 1970 Ferrari 365 GT 2+2 that was manufactured for importation into and sale in the United States and certified by its manufacturer as conforming to all applicable Federal motor vehicle safety standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>The petitioner stated that it carefully compared the non-U.S. certified version of the 1970 Ferrari 365 GT 2+2 to its U.S. certified counterpart, and found that the two vehicles are substantially similar with respect to compliance with most applicable Federal motor vehicle safety standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>J.K. submitted information with its petition intended to demonstrate that the non-U.S. certified 1970 Ferrari 365 GT 2+2, as originally manufactured, conforms to many Federal motor vehicle safety standards in the same manner as its U.S. certified counterpart, or is capable of being readily modified to conform to those standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Specifically, the petitioner claims that the non-U.S. certified 1970 Ferrari 365 GT 2+2 is identical to its U.S. certified counterpart with respect to compliance with Standard Nos. 102</textblock>
    <textblock>Transmission Shift Leave Sequence *␣*␣*, 103 Defrosting and Defogging System,</textblock>
    <textblock>104</textblock>
    <textblock>Windshield Wiping and Washing Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>105 Hydraulic Brake Systems, 106 Brake Hoses, 107</textblock>
    <textblock>Reflecting Surfaces,</textblock>
    <textblock>109</textblock>
    <textblock>New Pneumatic Tires,</textblock>
    <textblock>113</textblock>
    <textblock>Hood Latch Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>116</textblock>
    <textblock>Brake Fluid,</textblock>
    <textblock>124</textblock>
    <textblock>Accelerator Control Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>201</textblock>
    <textblock>Occupant Protection in Interior Impact,</textblock>
    <textblock>202</textblock>
    <textblock>Head Restraints,</textblock>
    <textblock>203</textblock>
    <textblock>Impact Protection for the Driver From the Steering Control System,</textblock>
    <textblock>204</textblock>
    <textblock>Steering Control Rearward Displacement,</textblock>
    <textblock>205</textblock>
    <textblock>Glazing Materials,</textblock>
    <textblock>206</textblock>
    <textblock>Door Locks and Door Retention Components,</textblock>
    <textblock>207</textblock>
    <textblock>Seating Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>209</textblock>
    <textblock>Seat Belt Assemblies,</textblock>
    <textblock>210</textblock>
    <textblock>Seat Belt Assembly Anchorages,</textblock>
    <textblock>and 211</textblock>
    <textblock>Wheel Nuts, Wheel Discs and Hubcaps.</textblock>
    <textblock>Petitioner also contends that the non-U.S. certified 1970 Ferrari 365 GT 2+2 is capable of being readily modified to meet the following standards, in he manner indicated:</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 101␣Controls and Displays:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Substitution of a lens marked ``Brake'' for a lens with an ECE symbol on the brake failure indicator lamp; (b) recalibration of the speedometer/odometer from kilometers to miles per hour.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 108␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Lamps, Reflective Devices and Associated Equipment:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Installation of U.S.-model headlamp assemblies which incorporate sealed beam headlamps and front sidemarkers; (b) installation of U.S.-model taillamp assemblies which incorporate rear sidemarkers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 110␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Tire Selection and Rims:</textblock>
    <textblock>Installation of a tire information placard.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 111␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Rearview Mirrors:</textblock>
    <textblock>Replacement of the passenger side rearview mirror, which is convex but lacks the required warning statement.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
