<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00158</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00092</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>G&amp;K Automotive Conversion, Inc. of Santa Ana, California (``G&amp;K'') (Registered Importer No. R-90-007) has petitioned NHTSA to determine whether 1989 Peugeot 405 passenger cars are eligible for importation into the United States. The vehicle which G&amp;K believes is substantially similar is the 1989 Peugeot 405 that PSA Peugeot Citroen/USTR manufactured for importation into and sale in the United States, and certified as conforming to all applicable Federal motor vehicle safety standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>The petitioner states that it carefully compared the non-U.S.-certified 1989 Peugeot 405 to its U.S.-certified counterpart, and found the two vehicles to be substantially similar with respect to compliance with most applicable Federal motor vehicle safety standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>G&amp;K submitted information with its petition intended to demonstrate that the non-U.S.-certified 1989 Peugeot 405, as originally manufactured, conforms to many Federal motor vehicle safety standards in the same manner as its U.S.-certified counterpart, or is capable of being readily modified to conform to those standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>Specifically, the petitioner claims that the non-U.S. certified 1989 Peugeot 405 is identical to the U.S-certified 1989 Peugeot 405 with respect to compliance with Standard Nos. 102</textblock>
    <textblock>Transmission Shift Lever Sequence ***,</textblock>
    <textblock>103</textblock>
    <textblock>Defrosting and Defogging Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>104</textblock>
    <textblock>Windshield Wiping and Washing Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>105</textblock>
    <textblock>Hydraulic Brake Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>106</textblock>
    <textblock>Brake Hoses,</textblock>
    <textblock>107</textblock>
    <textblock>Reflecting Surfaces,</textblock>
    <textblock>109</textblock>
    <textblock>New Pneumatic Tires,</textblock>
    <textblock>113</textblock>
    <textblock>Hood Latch Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>116</textblock>
    <textblock>Brake Fluid,</textblock>
    <textblock>124</textblock>
    <textblock>Accelerator Control Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>201</textblock>
    <textblock>Occupant Protection in Interior Impact,</textblock>
    <textblock>220</textblock>
    <textblock>Head Restraints,</textblock>
    <textblock>203</textblock>
    <textblock>Impact Protection for the Driver From the Steering Control System,</textblock>
    <textblock>204</textblock>
    <textblock>Steering Control Rearward Displacement,</textblock>
    <textblock>205</textblock>
    <textblock>Glazing Materials,</textblock>
    <textblock>206</textblock>
    <textblock>Door Locks and Door Retention Components,</textblock>
    <textblock>207</textblock>
    <textblock>Seating Systems,</textblock>
    <textblock>209</textblock>
    <textblock>Seat Belt Assemblies,</textblock>
    <textblock>210</textblock>
    <textblock>Seat Belt Assembly Anchorages,</textblock>
    <textblock>211</textblock>
    <textblock>Wheel Nuts, Wheel Discs and Hubcaps,</textblock>
    <textblock>212</textblock>
    <textblock>Windshield Retention,</textblock>
    <textblock>216</textblock>
    <textblock>Roof Crush Resistance,</textblock>
    <textblock>and 219</textblock>
    <textblock>Windshield Zone Intrusion.</textblock>
    <textblock>Petitioner also contends that the non-U.S.-certified 1989 Peugeot 405 is capable of being readily modified to meet the following standards, in the manner indicated:</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 101␣Controls and Displays:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Substitution of a lens marked ``Brake'' for a lens with an ECE symbol on the brake failure indicator lamp; (b) recalibration of the speedometer/odometer from kilometers to miles per hour.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 108␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Lamps, Reflective Devices and Associated Equipment: (a) Installation of U.S.-model headlamp assemblies which incorporate sealed beam headlamps and front sidemarkers; (b) installation of U.S.-model taillamp assemblies which incorporate rear sidemarkers; (c) installation of a high mounted stop lamp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard No. 110␣Tire Selection and Rims:</textblock>
    <textblock>Installation of a tire information placard.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
