<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-0-00008</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-0-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>§703.3</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Appraisal</textblock>
    <textblock>means the agriculture value of the easement area on an ``as is'' bases as determined by an appraiser licensed by the State in which the appraisal is made and who is also approved by ASCS.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Bid,</textblock>
    <textblock>for the 1992 Pilot Program, unless the context indicates otherwise, means the total payment requested by the owner for granting an easement.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Non-permanent easement</textblock>
    <textblock>means a temporary deed restriction that is acquired by ASCS from an eligible landowner that requires the protection and maintenance of wetland restoration on designated acreage.</textblock>
    <textblock>Participant</textblock>
    <textblock>means a landowner who has an approved contract.</textblock>
    <textblock>Permanent easement</textblock>
    <textblock>means a deed restriction that lasts through perpetuity, acquired by ASCS from an eligible landowner, and which requires the protection and maintenance of wetland restoration practices on designated acreage.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Preliminary plan</textblock>
    <textblock>means a plan jointly developed by a landowner, SCS, and FWS to provide the landowner with an estimate of the extent and cost of restoration activities, and to obtain adequate information to prioritize intentions to participate.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Substantially altered lands</textblock>
    <textblock>means lands which have not been and are not now wetlands, but with a high degree of certainty will likely develop wetland characteristics as a result of natural flooding.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Section 703.5 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§703.5</textblock>
    <textblock>Maximum acreage limitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>ASCS will attempt to enroll into the WRP during the 1991-2000 calendar years:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) A total of not less than 330,000 acres through 1995; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) A total of not less than 975,000 acres through 2000.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Section 703.7 is amended by revising paragraphs (a)(1)(i), (a)(2)(i), (a)(2)(ii), and (a)(2)(iii) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§703.7</textblock>
    <textblock>Eligible land.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)(1) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Is wetland farmed under natural conditions, a farmed wetland, prior converted cropland except that converted lands shall not be eligible for enrollment if the conversion was not commenced prior to December 23, 1985, or substantially altered land; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Have been annually planted or considered planted to an agricultural commodity in at least 1 of the 5 crop years 1986 through 1990, and have been capable of being cropped in 1992 or 1993;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) If enrolled under a CRP contract, or under a Federal or State wetland restoration program without an easement of at least 30 years, have been planted to an agricultural commodity 2 of the 5 crop years, 1981 through 1985; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Not be used as a mitigation site for Federal, State or local permit conditions or program participation requirements, or public or private mitigation banks.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>§703.8</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Section 703.8(a) is amended by revising ``Converted wetlands'' to read ``Prior converted croplands''.</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Section 703.9(b) is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§703.9</textblock>
    <textblock>Transfer of lands from the CRP to WRP.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The application for such transfer into the WRP is agreed to by ASCS. If such transfer is requested by the owner and agreed to by ASCS, then the CRP contract for the property shall be terminated or otherwise modified subject to such terms and conditions as are mutually agreed upon. Transfers from CRP to WRP after the second available WRP signup period will only be permitted if the owner agrees to refund all payments received under the CRP since the close of the second available WRP signup. Further, Emergency Wetlands Reserve Program signup periods are not considered WRP signup periods.</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Section 703.10 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§703.10</textblock>
    <textblock>Easement priority.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) ASCS shall, to the extent practicable, in determining which areas to accept, take into account the cost of restoration, the cost of acquiring the easement, and environmental benefits which would be acquired through the purchase of the easement.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) In evaluating the value of obtaining an easement, different weights may be given to the factors for determining the priority by ASCS to accomplish the goals of the WRP.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) ASCS will rank the areas offered, based on environmental benefits relative to the government expenditure using the following factors for determining the priority:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Habitat for migratory birds, threatened or endangered species, fish, and other wildlife;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Wetland functions and values;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Location significance;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Wetland management requirements;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
