<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-1-00024</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-1-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Approval and Promulgation of Implementation Plan; Illinois</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>40 CFR Part 52</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[IL12-32-6227; FRL-4829-7]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule; extension of the public comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 1, 1993, (58 FR 51279) the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) proposed rulemaking in response to an October 22, 1990, Petition for Reconsideration filed with the Administrator. This Petition requested that EPA reconsider and revise the requirements of the Chicago Federal Implementation Plan (FIP) for Ozone (which was promulgated June 29, 1990 (55 FR 26814)) as they pertain to Stepan Company's Millsdale Plant (Stepan) manufacturing facility in Elwood, Illinois.</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 2, 1993 (58 FR 63547) at the request of Stepan, EPA extended the comment period until December 16, 1993. On December 2, 1993, Stepan requested that the comment period be extended until February 15, 1994 based upon the complexity of the proposed rule and issues raised about the content of the record. At Stepan's request EPA is extending the public comment period until February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this proposal must be received by February 15, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments on this proposed action should be addressed to J. Elmer Bortzer, Chief, Regulation Development Section (AR-18J), U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region 5, Chicago, Illinois 60604. Comments should be strictly limited to the subject matter of this proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to sections 307(d)(1) (B) and (N) of the Clean Air Act (Act), 42 U.S.C. 7607(d)(1) (B) and (N), this action is subject to the procedural requirements of section 307(d). Therefore, EPA has established a public docket for this action, A-92-36, which is available for public inspection and copying between 8 a.m. and 4 p.m., Monday through Friday, at the following addresses. We recommend that you contact Randolph O. Cano before visiting the Chicago location and Jacqueline Brown before visiting the Washington, DC location. A reasonable fee may be charged for copying.</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region 5, Regulation Development Branch, 77 West Jackson Street, Chicago, Illinois 60604, (312) 886-6036.</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Docket No. A-92-36, Air Docket (LE-141), room M1500, Waterside Mall, 401 M Street, SW., Washington, DC 20460, (202) 260-7548.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Steve Rosenthal, Regulation Development Branch, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region 5, (312) 886-6052, at the Chicago address indicated above.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 13, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David A. Kee,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1732 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
