<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00025</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Niagara Mohawk Power Corp., et al.; Electric Rate and Corporate Regulation Filings</textblock>
    <textblock>January 14, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that the following filings have been made with the Commission:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Niagara Mohawk Power Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER93-313-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 10, 1994, Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation (Niagara Mohawk), tendered for filing an amendment to its Power Sales Tariff which is pending acceptance with the Commission. The Tariff provides for sales of system capacity and/or energy or resource capacity and/or energy. The proposed Tariff requires interested purchasers to enter into a Service Agreement with Niagara Mohawk before transactions may commence under this Tariff.</textblock>
    <textblock>Niagara Mohawk requests that its Tariff be accepted for filing and allowed to become effective in accordance with its terms as specified. Information filed in support of the Tariff includes cost support for Niagara Mohawk's tariff ceiling rates and pricing terms that allow for the capacity and energy changes to be pro-rated for the duration of each sale. A copy of this filing has been served upon the New York State Public Service Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 31, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. East Texas Electric Cooperative, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-891-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 6, 1994, East Texas Electric Cooperative, Inc., tendered for filing an initial proposed tariff to be designated ETEC-1. The proposed tariff shall facilitate the pooling of the purchased power resources of Sam Rayburn G&amp;T Electric Cooperative, Inc., Northeast Texas Electric Cooperative, Inc. and Tex-La Electric Cooperative of Texas, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>The initial tariff proposal is designed to capture economies of scale among the three members of ETEC in their purchased power acquisition activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the filing were served upon the public utility's customers, and the Public Utilities Commission of Texas.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 31, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. New York State Electric &amp; Gas Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-892-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 7, 1994, New York State Electric &amp; Gas Corporation (NYSEG), tendered for filing pursuant to ยง35.13 of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedures, 18 CFR 35.13 (1993), as a change in rate schedule, an agreement with Rochester Gas and Electric Corporation (RGE). The agreement supplements NYSEG Rate Schedule FERC No. 107 and provides a mechanism pursuant to which the parties can enter into separately scheduled transactions under which NYSEG will sell to RGE and RGE will purchase from NYSEG either capacity and associated energy or energy only as the parties may mutually agree.</textblock>
    <textblock>NYSEG requests that the agreement become effective on January 8, 1994, so that the parties may, if mutually agreeable, enter into separately scheduled transactions under the agreement. NYSEG has requested waiver of the notice requirements for good cause shown.</textblock>
    <textblock>NYSEG served copies of the filing upon the New York State Public Service Commission and RGE.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 31, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER93-313-000, et al.]</textblock>
  </rindock>
</doc>
