<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00051</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00040</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Public Law 92-463, notice is hereby given of the meetings of the National Center for Research Resources (NCRR) for February-March 1994. These meetings will be open to the public to discuss program planning, program accomplishments and special reports or other issues relating to committee business as indicated in the notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>These meetings will be closed to the public as indicated below in accordance with provisions set forth in secs. 552b(c)(4) and 552b(c)(6), title 5 U.S.C. and sec. 10(d) of Public Law 92-463, for the review, discussion and evaluation of individuals grant applications. These applications and the discussions could reveal confidential trade secrets or commercial property such as patentable material, and personal information concerning individuals associated with the applications, the disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Maureen Mylander, Information Officer, NCRR, Westwood Building, room 10A15, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland 20892, (301) 594-7938, will provide summaries of meetings and rosters of committee members. Other information pertaining to the meetings can be obtained from the Executive Secretary or the Scientific Review Administrator indicated. Individuals who plan to attend and need special assistance, such as sign language interpretation or other reasonable accommodations, should contact the Executive Secretary or the Scientific Review Administrator listed below, in advance of the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Name of Committee:</textblock>
    <textblock>General Clinical Research Centers Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>Scientific review administrator:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Bela J. Gulyas, National Institutes of Health, Westwood Building, room 10A16, Bethesda, MD 20892, Telephone: (301) 594-7903</textblock>
    <textblock>Dates of meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 16-18, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Place of meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>Holiday Inn, Bethesda, 8120 Wisconsin Avenue, Bethesda, MD 20814</textblock>
    <textblock>Open:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 16, 8 a.m.-9:30 a.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>Closed:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 16, 9:30 a.m. until adjournment</textblock>
    <textblock>Name of Committee:</textblock>
    <textblock>Biomedical Research Technology Review Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>Scientific review administrator:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Chhanda L. Ganguly, National Institutes of Health, Westwood Building, room 10A14, Bethesda, MD 20892, Telephone: (301) 594-7957</textblock>
    <textblock>Dates of meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 24-25, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Place of meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bethesda Ramada, 8400 Wisconsin Avenue, Bethesda, MD 20814</textblock>
    <textblock>Open:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 24, 8:30 a.m.-10 a.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>Closed:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 24, 10 a.m. until adjournment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Name of committee:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comparative Medicine Review Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>Scientific review administrator:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Bernadette Tyree, National Institutes of Health, Westwood Building, room 10A16, Bethesda, MD 20892, Telephone: (301) 594-7932</textblock>
    <textblock>Dates of meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 27-March 1, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Place of meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>One Washington Circle Hotel, One Washington Circle, NW., Washington, DC 20037</textblock>
    <textblock>Closed:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 27, 6:30 p.m. until recess</textblock>
    <textblock>Open:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 28, 8:30 a.m.-10 a.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>Closed:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 28, 10 a.m. until adjournment</textblock>
    <textblock>Name of Committee:</textblock>
    <textblock>Research Centers in Minority Institutions Review Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>Scientific review administrator:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. John Lymangrover, National Institutes of Health, Westwood Building, room 10A14, Bethesda, MD 20892, Telephone: (301) 594-7932</textblock>
    <textblock>Dates of meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 28-March 1, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Place of meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>Holiday Inn Crowne Plaza, 9000 Rockville Pike, Rockville, MD 20852</textblock>
    <textblock>Open:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 28, 8:30 a.m.-10:30 a.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>Closed:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 28, 10:30 a.m. until adjournment</textblock>
    <textblock>(Catalog of Federal Domestic Assistance Program Nos. 93.333, Clinical Research, 93.371, Biomedical Research Technology and 93.306, Laboratory Animal Sciences and Primate Research, 93.389, Research Centers in Minority Institutions, National Institutes of Health)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Institutes of Health</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Center for Research Resources; Meetings</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Susan K. Feldman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Committee Management Officer, NIH.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1754 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4140-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
