<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00063</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00052</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Investigation No. 337-TA-350]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Decision Not to Review Initial Determination Granting Joint Motion to Terminate the Investigation With Respect to Respondent Tosoh Corp. on the Basis of a License Agreement</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. International Trade Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the Matter of certain sputtered carbon coated computer disks and products containing same, including disk drives.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the U.S. International Trade Commission has determined not to review an initial determination (ID) (Order No. 79) issued on December 20, 1993, by the presiding administrative law judge (ALJ) in the above-captioned investigation granting the joint motion of complainant Harry E. Aine (``Aine'') and respondent Tosoh Corp. (``Tosoh'') to terminate the investigation as to Tosoh on the basis of a licensing agreement.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Marc A. Bernstein, Office of the General Counsel, U.S. International Trade Commission, 500 E Street, SW., Washington, DC 20436, telephone 202-205-3087.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission instituted this investigation, which concerns allegations of section 337 violations in the importation, sale for importation, and sale after importation of sputtered carbon coated computer disks and products containing such disks, including disk drives, on May 5, 1993. Complainant Aine alleges infringement of claims 23, 24, 25, 26, and 29 of U.S. Letters Patent Re 32,464.</textblock>
    <textblock>On November 17, 1993, Aine and Tosoh filed a joint motion to terminate the investigation with respect to Tosoh on the basis of a licensing agreement. The ALJ issued an ID granting the joint motion and terminating the investigation as to Tosoh. No petitions for review of the ID were filed. No agency or public comments were received.</textblock>
    <textblock>This action is taken under the authority of section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930, 19 U.S.C. 1337, and Commission interim rule 210.53, 19 CFR 210.53.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the nonconfidential version of the ID and all other nonconfidential documents filed in connection with this investigation are or will be available for inspection during official business hours (8:45 a.m. to 5:15 p.m.) in the Office of the Secretary, U.S. International Trade Commission, 500 E Street SW., Washington, DC 20436, telephone 202-205-2000. Hearing-impaired persons are advised that information on this matter can be obtained by contacting the Commission's TDD terminal on 202-205-1810.</textblock>
    <textblock>By order of the Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna R. Koehnke,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1758 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7020-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
