<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00043</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940127-2-00033</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4829-5]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Ozone Transport Commission for the Northeast United States; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The United States Environmental Protection Agency is announcing a meeting of the Ozone Transport Commission to be held on February 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>This meeting is for the Transport Commission to deal with appropriate matters within the transport region as provided for under the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990. This meeting is not subject to the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act, Public Law 92-463, as amended.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held on February 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held at: The Omni Shoreham Hotel, 2500 Calvert Street, NW., Washington, DC 20008.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Doug Gutro, State Relations Coordinator, Region I, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, John F. Kennedy Federal Building, Boston, MA 02203, (617) 666-3383.</textblock>
    <textblock>For press inquiries contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Brenda Box, Air Resources Management Division, D.C. Environmental Regulation Administration, 2100 Martin Luther King Jr. Avenue, SE., suite 404, Washington, DC 20020-5732, (202) 404-1136.</textblock>
    <textblock>For documents contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Stephanie A. Cooper, Ozone Transport Commission, 444 North Capitol Street NW., suite 604, Washington, DC 20001, (202) 508-3840.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990 contain at section 184 provisions for the ``Control of Interstate Ozone Air Pollution.'' Section 184(a) establishes an ozone transport region comprised of the States of Connecticut, Delaware, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, Vermont, parts of Virginia and the District of Columbia.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Assistant Administrator for Air and Radiation of the Environmental Protection Agency convened the first meeting of the commission in New York City on May 7, 1991. The purpose of the Transport Commission is to deal with appropriate matters within the transport region.</textblock>
    <textblock>The purpose of this notice is to announce that this Commission will meet on February 1, 1994. The meeting will be held at the address noted earlier in this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 176A(b)(2) of the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990 specifies that the meetings of Transport Commissions are not subject to the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act. This meeting will be open to the public as space permits, a time to be determined (see below).</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>Open.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agenda:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the final agenda will be available from Stephanie Cooper of the OTC office (202) 508-3840 on Wednesday, January 26, 1994. The final agenda will include the starting and adjournment times of the meeting. The purpose of the meeting is to receive reports from its committees, particularly on the Low Emission Vehicle program and control measures being studied for the November 15, 1994 State Implementation Plan revisions.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Paul Keough,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Administrator, EPA Region I.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1738 Filed 1-26-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
