<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00030</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Service Contracts</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL MARITIME COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>46 CFR Parts 514 and 581</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 92-31]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Maritime Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule; withdrawal.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Maritime Commission is discontinuing this rulemaking proceeding. An analysis of the comments received reveals no need for the Rule as proposed. The Commission will continue to address specific situations on an ad hoc basis.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>This action is effective February 2, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Robert D. Bourgoin, General Counsel, Federal Maritime Commission, 800 North Capitol Street, NW., Washington, DC 20573, (202) 523-5740.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Maritime Commission (``FMC'' or ``Commission'') initiated this proceeding by an Advance Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (``ANPR''), published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on June 8, 1992, 57 FR 24220. Following comments on the ANPR, the Commission published a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (``Proposed Rule'' or ``NPR'') in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on November 3, 1992, 57 FR 49665. The NPR stated that the Commission was proposing to amend the definition of the term ``shippers' association,''</textblock>
    <textblock>contained in its service contract and Automated Tariff Filing and Information System (``ATFI'') rules, to indicate that a group of shippers would be considered a shippers' association if it met certain requirements. In addition, the proposed definition further clarified the terms ``consolidates'' and ``nonprofit basis'' as used in the subject definition.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission received 15 comments in response to the NPR.</textblock>
    <textblock>Commenters supporting the Proposed Rule are:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Conagra, Inc.;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Household Goods Forwarders Association of America, Inc. (``HHGFAA'');</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Society of the Plastics Industry, Inc. (``SPI'');</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Cone Mills Corporation (``Cone''); and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) United States Department of Justice (``DOJ'').</textblock>
    <textblock>Commenters supporting the Proposed Rule, but suggesting clarifications are:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) American Institute for Shippers' Associations, Inc. (``AISA'');</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Fashion Accessories Shippers' Association, Inc. (``FASA'');</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) National Industrial Transportation League (``NITL''); and</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) American Import Shippers Association (``Import S.A.'').</textblock>
    <textblock>Commenters opposed to the Proposed Rule are:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Transpacific Westbound Rate Agreement (``TWRA'');</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Trans-Pacific Freight Conference of Japan and Japan-Atlantic and Gulf Freight Conference (``Japan Conferences'');</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) a group of nine conferences of ocean common carriers (``Nine Conferences'');</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Hanjin Shipping Co., Ltd. (``Hanjin'');</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) a group of 14 South/Central American and Caribbean Conferences (``South American/Caribbean Conferences'');</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) Fritz Companies, Inc. (``Fritz'').</textblock>
    <textblock>Positions of the Commenters</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Comments Supporting the Proposed Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>Cone supports the Proposed Rule because it believes it will enable Cone to move cargo to emerging countries where its volume alone is not sufficient to justify a service contract. Conagra likewise believes that the Proposed Rule will make it possible for shippers with complementary traffic to present a carrier with a more attractive traffic profile than each could present separately. It contends that to the extent such traffic can be handled more efficiently, the carrier's handling costs will be reduced. Conagra suggests that concerns about the lawfulness of the proposal are without merit and that it raises no valid antitrust concerns.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Section 3(24) of the Shipping Act of 1984 (``1984 Act''), 46 U.S.C. app. 1702(24), defines a shippers' association as:</textblock>
    <textblock>``*␣*␣*␣a group of shippers that consolidates or distributes freight on a nonprofit basis for the members of the group in order to secure carload, truckload, or other volume rates or service contracts.''</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission's present service contract and ATFI regulations simply restate the statutory definition. 46 CFR 514.2, 581.1(r).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The eight conferences originally submitting comments are: Asia North America Eastbound Rate Agreement; ``8900'' Lines; Israel Trade Conference; South Europe/USA Freight Conference; United States Atlantic and Gulf Ports/Eastern Mediterranean North African Freight Conference; United States/Southern Africa Conference; United States/East Africa Conference; and U.S. Atlantic and Gulf/Western Mediterranean Rate Agreement. After the comment period closed, the U.S. Atlantic &amp; Gulf/Australia-New Zealand Conference joined in these comments.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Venezuelan American Maritime Association; Atlantic and Gulf/West Coast South American Conference; United States/Central America Liner Association; Central America Discussion Agreement; United States Atlantic &amp; Gulf/Hispaniola Steamship Freight Association; Hispaniola Discussion Agreement; United States Atlantic Gulf/Southeastern Caribbean Steamship Freight Association; Southeastern Caribbean Discussion Agreement; Jamaica Discussion Agreement; United States/Panama Freight Association; PANAM Discussion Agreement; Puerto Rico/Caribbean Discussion Agreement; Caribbean and Central American Discussion Agreement; and Inter-American Freight Conference.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
