<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00002</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Additional Grace Period Extension for Certain Existing Agency</textblock>
    <textblock>Standards of Conduct</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>OFFICE OF GOVERNMENT ETHICS</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>5 CFR Part 2635</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RINs 3209-AA04, 3209-AA15</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Government Ethics (OGE).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule; technical amendment.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Office of Government Ethics is granting an additional</textblock>
    <textblock>grandfathering grace period extension for up to one year for</textblock>
    <textblock>certain existing executive agency standards of conduct, dealing</textblock>
    <textblock>with financial interest prohibitions and prior approval for outside</textblock>
    <textblock>employment/activities, which have been temporarily preserved. This</textblock>
    <textblock>action is necessary because many agencies have not been able to</textblock>
    <textblock>develop, with OGE concurrence, supplemental regulations for such</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions during the first one-year grace period. This additional</textblock>
    <textblock>extension will help ensure that concerned agencies have adequate</textblock>
    <textblock>time to issue successor regulatory provisions to replace the</textblock>
    <textblock>restrictions noted.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 2, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>William E. Gressman, Office of</textblock>
    <textblock>Government Ethics, telephone: 202-523-5757, FAX: 202-523-6325.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Office of Government Ethics (OGE)</textblock>
    <textblock>is granting under the executive branch standards of ethical conduct</textblock>
    <textblock>an additional extension of time for up to one year, until</textblock>
    <textblock>February 3, 1995, for certain agencies' existing conduct standards</textblock>
    <textblock>dealing with prohibited financial interests and prior approval for</textblock>
    <textblock>outside employment and activities. When OGE published its ethical</textblock>
    <textblock>conduct standards for executive branch employees in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on August 7, 1992 (as now codified at 5 CFR part 2635), it</textblock>
    <textblock>provided, by means of notes following 5 CFR 2635.403(a) and</textblock>
    <textblock>2635.803, that although most existing individual agency standards</textblock>
    <textblock>of conduct would be superseded once the executive branch-wide</textblock>
    <textblock>standards took effect on February 3, 1993, existing agency</textblock>
    <textblock>standards dealing with the two types of restrictions noted above</textblock>
    <textblock>would be preserved for one year (until February 3, 1994) or until</textblock>
    <textblock>the agency concerned issued a supplemental regulation, whichever</textblock>
    <textblock>occurred first. See 57 FR 35006-35067, as corrected at 57 FR 48557</textblock>
    <textblock>and 52583.</textblock>
    <textblock>Various executive branch departments and agencies have</textblock>
    <textblock>expressed an interest in developing supplemental regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>involving one or both of these types of provisions. Through OGE's</textblock>
    <textblock>liaison efforts, the Office of the Federal Register has assigned</textblock>
    <textblock>new chapters and parts at the end of title 5 of the Code of Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations to accommodate these agencies' future supplemental</textblock>
    <textblock>standards regulations (on these two and other appropriate subject</textblock>
    <textblock>areas), as well as any supplemental agency regulations under OGE's</textblock>
    <textblock>executive branch-wide financial disclosure provisions at 5 CFR</textblock>
    <textblock>part 2634. However, although some of the agencies have, with OGE</textblock>
    <textblock>concurrence, issued interim final or final supplemental</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations, many have not yet had the time to finalize their</textblock>
    <textblock>planned supplemental regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Office of Government Ethics has therefore determined to</textblock>
    <textblock>permit preservation of existing agency standards setting forth</textblock>
    <textblock>financial interest prohibitions and outside employment/activities</textblock>
    <textblock>prior approval requirements for up to one more year, until</textblock>
    <textblock>February 3, 1995 (or until issuance by each agency of its</textblock>
    <textblock>supplemental regulation, whichever comes first), while the</textblock>
    <textblock>concerned agencies continue to work to promulgate their new</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions in these two areas. The agencies subject to this</textblock>
    <textblock>additional grandfathering grace period extension are enumerated at</textblock>
    <textblock>new appendix A, which is being added to 5 CFR part 2635, in the</textblock>
    <textblock>order of the assignment of chapter numbers at the end of 5 CFR.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agencies not listed either have not expressed an interest in</textblock>
    <textblock>issuing supplemental agency regulations pursuant to 5 CFR 2635.105</textblock>
    <textblock>(or 5 CFR 2634.103) or have already issued final or interim final</textblock>
    <textblock>supplemental regulations. For agencies not listed in appendix A,</textblock>
    <textblock>the initial grace period for any existing standards of conduct</textblock>
    <textblock>financial interest prohibitions and prior approval for outside</textblock>
    <textblock>employment/activities expires on February 3, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative Procedure Act</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 553 (b) and (d), as Director of the Office</textblock>
    <textblock>of Government Ethics, I find good cause exists for waiving the</textblock>
    <textblock>general notice of proposed rulemaking and 30-day delay in</textblock>
    <textblock>effectiveness as to this grace period extension. The notice and</textblock>
    <textblock>delayed effective date are being waived because this rulemaking</textblock>
    <textblock>concerns a matter of agency organization, practice and procedure</textblock>
    <textblock>and because it is in the public interest that those agencies</textblock>
    <textblock>concerned have adequate time to promulgate successor provisions to</textblock>
    <textblock>their existing standards of conduct regulations in these two areas,</textblock>
    <textblock>while preserving existing restrictions in the meantime.</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 12866</textblock>
    <textblock>In promulgating this grace period extension technical</textblock>
    <textblock>amendment, the Office of Government Ethics has adhered to the</textblock>
    <textblock>regulatory philosophy and the applicable principles of regulation</textblock>
    <textblock>set forth in section 1 of Executive Order 12866, Regulatory</textblock>
    <textblock>Planning and Review. This amendment has not been reviewed by the</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Management and Budget under that Executive order, as it</textblock>
    <textblock>is not deemed ``significant'' thereunder.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
