<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00108</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>II. Diagnosis</textblock>
    <textblock>The clinical spectrum of disease due to</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>spp. is broad and ranges from asymptomatic infection to rapidly progressive pneumonia. Legionnaires' disease cannot be distinguished clinically or radiographically from pneumonia caused by other agents,361,362 and evidence of infection with other respiratory pathogens does not rule out the possibility of concomitant</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>spp. infection.</textblock>
    <textblock>363-365</textblock>
    <textblock>The diagnosis of legionellosis may be confirmed by any one of the following: Culture isolation of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>from respiratory secretions or tissues, or microscopic visualization of the bacterium in respiratory secretions or tissue by immunofluorescent microscopy; and, for legionellosis due to</textblock>
    <textblock>L. pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>serogroup 1, detection of</textblock>
    <textblock>L. pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>serogroup-1 antigens in urine by radioimmunoassay, or observation of a four-fold rise in</textblock>
    <textblock>L. pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>serogroup-1 antibody titer to "1:128 in paired acute and convalescent serum specimens by use of an indirect immunofluorescent antibody test (IFA).366 A single elevated antibody titer does not confirm a case of Legionnaires' disease because IFA titers "1:256 are found in 1-16% of healthy adults.</textblock>
    <textblock>364,367-370</textblock>
    <textblock>Because the above tests complement each other, performing each test when Legionnaires' disease is suspected increases the probability of confirming the diagnosis.371 However, because none of the laboratory tests is 100% sensitive, the diagnosis of legionellosis is not ruled out even if one or more of the tests are negative.</textblock>
    <textblock>371,372</textblock>
    <textblock>Of the available tests, the most specific is culture isolation of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>sp. from any respiratory tract specimen.</textblock>
    <textblock>373,374</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Modes of Transmission</textblock>
    <textblock>Inhalation of aerosols of water contaminated with</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>sp. is believed to be the primary mechanism of entry of these organisms into a patient's respiratory tract.336 In several hospital outbreaks, patients were considered to be infected through exposure to contaminated aerosols generated by cooling towers, showers, faucets, respiratory therapy equipment, and room-air humidifiers.</textblock>
    <textblock>227,375-382</textblock>
    <textblock>In several studies, aspiration of contaminated potable water has been proposed as the mode of transmission to certain patients.</textblock>
    <textblock>383-385</textblock>
    <textblock>Person-to-person transmission, however, has not been observed.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
