<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00140</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>383. Johnson JT, Yu VL, Best MG, et al. Nosocomial legionellosis in surgical patients with head and neck cancer: Implications for epidemiological reservoir and mode of transmission. Lancet 1985; 2:298-300.</textblock>
    <textblock>384. Marrie TJ, Haldane D, MacDonald S, et al. Control of endemic nosocomial Legionnaires' disease by using sterile potable water for high risk patients. Epidemiol Infect 1991; 107:591-605.</textblock>
    <textblock>385. Blatt SP, Parkinson MD, Pace E, et al. Nosocomial Legionnaires' disease: aspiration as a primary mode of disease acquisition. Am J Med 1993; 95:16-22.</textblock>
    <textblock>386. Fraser DW, Tsai TR, Oremstein W, et al. Legionnaires' disease: description of an epidemic of pneumonia. N Engl J Med 1977; 297:1189-1197.</textblock>
    <textblock>387. Yu VL. Routine culturing for</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>in the hospital environment may be a good idea: A three-hospital prospective study. Am J Med 1987; 294:97-99.</textblock>
    <textblock>388. Goetz A, Yu VL. Screening for nosocomial legionellosis by culture of the water supply and targeting of high-risk patients for specialized laboratory testing. Am J Infect Control 1991; 19:63-66.</textblock>
    <textblock>389. Yu VL. Nosocomial legionellosis: current epidemiologic issues. In: Remington JS, Swartz MN, eds. Current Clinical Topics in Infectious Diseases. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1986:239-253.</textblock>
    <textblock>390. Vickers RM, Yu VL, Hanna SS. Determinants of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>contamination of water distribution systems: 15-hospital prospective study. Infect Control 1987; 8:357-363.</textblock>
    <textblock>391. Tobin JO, Swann RA, Bartlett CLR. Isolation of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>from water systems: Methods and preliminary results. Br Med J 1981; 282:515-517.</textblock>
    <textblock>392. Dennis PJ, Fitzgeorge RB, Taylor JA, et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>in water plumbing systems. Lancet 1982; 1:949-951.</textblock>
    <textblock>393. Marrie TJ, Haldane D, Bezanson G, Peppard R. Each water outlet is a unique ecologic niche for</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>. Epidemiol Infect 1992; 108:261-270.</textblock>
    <textblock>394. Marrie TJ, Berzcason G, Fox J, Kuehn R, Haldane D, Birbridge S. Dynamics of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>in the potable water of one floor of a hospital. In: Barbaree JM, Breiman RF, Dufow AP, eds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>: Current status and emerging perspectives. Washington, D.C.: ASM, 1993:238-240.</textblock>
    <textblock>395. Plouffe JF, Para MF, Maher WE, Hackman B, Webster L. Subtypes of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>serogroup 1 associated with different attack rates. Lancet 1983; 2:649-650.</textblock>
    <textblock>396. Fraser DW. Sources of legionellosis. In: Thornsberry C, Balows A, Feeley JC, Jakubowski W, eds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>: Proceedings of the 2nd International Symposium. Washington, D.C.: American Society for Microbiology, 1984:277-280.</textblock>
    <textblock>397. Dourmon E, Bibb WF, Rajagopalan P, Desplaces N, McKinney RM. Monoclonal antibody reactivity as a virulence marker for</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>serogroup 1 strain. J Infect Dis 1992; 165:569-573.</textblock>
    <textblock>398. Brundrett GW. Guides on avoiding Legionnaires' disease. In:</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>and Building Services. Oxford: Butterworth Heineman, 1992:346-373.</textblock>
    <textblock>399. Kugler JW, Armitage JO, Helms CM, et al. Nosocomial Legionnaires' disease. Occurrence in recipients of bone marrow transplants. Am J Med 1983; 74:281-288.</textblock>
    <textblock>400. Department of Health. The Control of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>in Health Care Premises: A Code of Practice. London: HMSO, 1991.</textblock>
    <textblock>401. Helms CM, Massanari RM, Wenzel RP, et al. Legionnaires' disease associated with a hospital water system: A five-year progress report on continuous hyperchlorination. JAMA 1988; 259:2423-2427.</textblock>
    <textblock>402. Snyder MB, Siwicki M, Wireman J, et al. Reduction of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>through heat flushing followed by continuous supplemental chlorination of hospital hot water. J Infect Dis 1990; 162:127-132.</textblock>
    <textblock>403. Ezzeddine H, Van Ossel C, Delmee M, Wauters G.</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>spp. in a hospital hot water system: Effect of control measures. J Hosp Infect 1989; 13:121-131.</textblock>
    <textblock>404. Johnston JM, Latham RH, Meier FA, et al. Nosocomial outbreak of Legionnaires' disease: molecular epidemiology and disease control measures. Infect Control 1987; 8:53-58.</textblock>
    <textblock>405. Joly JR, McKinney RM, Tobin JO, Bibb WF, Watkins ID, Ramsay D. Development of a standardized subgrouping scheme for</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>serogroup 1 using monoclonal antibodies. J Clin Microbiol 1986; 23:768-771.</textblock>
    <textblock>406. Schoonmaker D, Helmberger T, Birkhead G. Comparison of ribotyping and restriction enzyme analysis using pulsed-field gel electrophoresis for distinguishing</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>isolates obtained during a nosocomial outbreak. J Clin Microbiol 1992; 30:1491-1498.</textblock>
    <textblock>407. Barbaree JM. Selecting a subtyping technique for use in investigations of legionellosis epidemics. In: Barbaree JM, Breiman RF, Dufow AP, eds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>: Current status and emerging perspectives. Washington, D.C.: ASM, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>408. Best M, Yu VL, Stout J, Goetz A, Muder RR, Taylor F.</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>ceae in the hospital water supply: epidemiologic link with disease and evaluation of a method for control of nosocomial Legionnaires' disease and Pittsburgh pneumonia. Lancet 1983; 2:307-310.</textblock>
    <textblock>409. Meenhorst PL, Reingold AL, Groothuis DG, et al. Water-related nosocomial pneumonia caused by</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>serogroups 1 and 10. J Infect Dis 1985; 152:356-364.</textblock>
    <textblock>410. Johnston JM, Latham RH, Meier FA, et al. Nosocomial outbreak of Legionnaires' disease: molecular epidemiology and disease control measures. Infect Control 1987; 8:53-58.</textblock>
    <textblock>411. Domingue EL, Tyndall RL, Mayberry WR, Pancorbo OC. Effects of three oxidizing biocides of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>serogroup 1. Appl Environ Microbiol 1988; 54:741-747.</textblock>
    <textblock>412. Landeen LK, Yahya MT, Gerba CP. Efficacy of copper and silver ions and reduced levels of free chlorine in inactivation of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>. Appl Environ Microbiol 1989; 55:3045-3050.</textblock>
    <textblock>413. Matulonis U, Rosenfeld CS, Shadduck RK. Prevention of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>infections in a bone marrow transplant unit: multifaceted approach to decontamination of a water system. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol 1993; 14:571-583.</textblock>
    <textblock>414. Edelstein PH, Whittaker RE, Kreiling RL, Howell CL. Efficacy of ozone in eradication of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella pneumophila</textblock>
    <textblock>from hospital fixtures. Appl Environ Microbiol 1982; 44:1330-1334.</textblock>
    <textblock>415. Wisconsin Department of Health and Social Services. Control of</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>in Cooling Towers: Summary Guidelines. Madison, WI: Wisconsin Division of Health, 1987.</textblock>
    <textblock>416. Best MG, Goetz A, Yu VL. Heat eradication measures for control of nosocomial Legionnaire's disease: Implementation, education, and cost analysis. Infect Control 1984; 12:26-30.</textblock>
    <textblock>417. Muraca PW, Yu VL, Goetz A. Disinfection of water distribution systems for</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>: a review of application procedures and methodologies. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol 1990; 11:79-88.</textblock>
    <textblock>418. Walsh TJ, Dixon DM. Nosocomial aspergillosis: environmental microbiology, hospital epidemiology, diagnosis and treatment. Eur J Epidemiol 1989; 5:131-142.</textblock>
    <textblock>419. Bodey GP, Vartivarian S. Aspergillosis. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis 1989; 8:413-437.</textblock>
    <textblock>420. Fraser DW, Ward JL, Ajello L, Plikaytis BD. Aspergillosis and other systemic mycoses: the growing problem. JAMA 1979; 242:1631-1635.</textblock>
    <textblock>421. Iwen PC, Reed EC, Armitage JO, et al. Nosocomial invasive aspergillosis in lymphoma patients treated with bone marrow or peripheral stem cell transplants. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol 1993; 14:131-139.</textblock>
    <textblock>422. Cordonnier C, Bernaudin JF, Bierling P, Huet Y, Vernant JP. Pulmonary complications occurring after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation: a study of 130 consecutive transplanted patients. Cancer 1986; 58:1047-1054.</textblock>
    <textblock>423. Klimowski LL, Rotstein C, Cummings KM. Incidence of nosocomial aspergillosis in patients with leukemia over a twenty-year period. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol 1989; 10:299-305.</textblock>
    <textblock>424. Sherertz RJ, Belani A, Kramer BS, et al. Impact of air filtration on nosocomial aspergillus infections. Unique risk of bone marrow transplant recipients. Am J Med 1987; 83:709-718.</textblock>
    <textblock>425. Rhame FS. Lessons from the Roswell Park bone marrow transplant aspergillosis outbreak. Infect Control 1985; 6:345-346.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
