<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00128</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Appendix A_Semicritical Items Used on the Respiratory Tract</textblock>
    <textblock>Air-pressure monitors</textblock>
    <textblock>Anesthesia breathing circuits including:</textblock>
    <textblock>inspiratory and expiratory tubings</textblock>
    <textblock>y connectors</textblock>
    <textblock>right-angle connectors</textblock>
    <textblock>face mask</textblock>
    <textblock>reservoir bags</textblock>
    <textblock>Breathing circuits of mechanical ventilators</textblock>
    <textblock>Bronchoscopes and their accessories</textblock>
    <textblock>CO</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>analyzers</textblock>
    <textblock>Endotracheal and endobronchial tubes</textblock>
    <textblock>Laryngoscope blades</textblock>
    <textblock>Mouthpieces and tubings of pulmonary-function testing equipment</textblock>
    <textblock>Oral and nasal airways</textblock>
    <textblock>Resuscitation bags</textblock>
    <textblock>Spirometers</textblock>
    <textblock>Suction catheters</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table</textblock>
    <textblock>3._</textblock>
    <textblock>Risk Factors and Suggested Infection Control Measures for Prevention of Nosocomial Pneumonia</textblock>
    <textblock>1Risk factors</textblock>
    <textblock>1Infection control measures suggested to prevent nosocomial pneumonia</textblock>
    <textblock>Bacterial Pneumonia:</textblock>
    <textblock>Host-Related</textblock>
    <textblock>Age (&gt;65 years)</textblock>
    <textblock>Underlying illness:</textblock>
    <textblock>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary</textblock>
    <textblock>Disease (COPD)</textblock>
    <textblock>Good chest physiotherapy: incentive spirometry; positive end expiratory pressure or continuous positive airway pressure by face mask.</textblock>
    <textblock>Immunosuppression</textblock>
    <textblock>Avoid exposure to potential nosocomial pathogens; decrease duration of immunosuppression, such as by administration of granulocyte macrophage colony stimulating factor (GMCSF).</textblock>
    <textblock>Depressed consciousness</textblock>
    <textblock>Caution on prescribing central nervous system depressants.</textblock>
    <textblock>Surgery (thoracic/abdominal)</textblock>
    <textblock>Chest physiotherapy if with COPD; proper positioning; early ambulation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Device-Related</textblock>
    <textblock>Proper cleaning, sterilization or disinfection, and handling of devices; remove devices as soon as indication for their use ceases.</textblock>
    <textblock>Endotracheal intubation and Mechanical ventilation</textblock>
    <textblock>Gentle suctioning of secretions; place patient in semirecumbent position, i.e., 30</textblock>
    <textblock>○ head-elevation; use nonalkalinizing gastric cytoprotective agent on patients at risk for stress bleeding; changing ventilator circuits not more often than every 48 hours; draining and discarding inspiratory-tubing condensate, or using heat-moisture exchanger if indicated.</textblock>
    <textblock>Nasogastric-tube (NGT) placement and Enteral feeding</textblock>
    <textblock>Use small-bore NGT; routinely verify appropriate tube placement; promptly remove NGT. Avoid large-bolus feeding; drain residual.</textblock>
    <textblock>Personnel- or Procedure-Related:</textblock>
    <textblock>Cross-contamination by hands</textblock>
    <textblock>Educate and train personnel; adequate handwashing and appropriate gloving; surveillance for cases of pneumonia, and feedback to personnel.</textblock>
    <textblock>Antibiotic administration</textblock>
    <textblock>Prudent antibiotic use, especially on high-risk intensive-care unit (ICU) patients.</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionnaires' Disease:</textblock>
    <textblock>Host-Related</textblock>
    <textblock>Immunosuppression</textblock>
    <textblock>Decrease duration of immunosuppression, such as by administration of GMCSF.</textblock>
    <textblock>Device-Related</textblock>
    <textblock>Contaminated aerosol from devices</textblock>
    <textblock>Sterilize/disinfect aerosol-producing devices before use; use only sterile water for respiratory humidifying devices; not using cool-mist room-air ``humidifiers''.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environment-Related</textblock>
    <textblock>Aerosols from contaminated water supply</textblock>
    <textblock>Hyperchlorinate or superheat hospital water system; routine maintenance of water-supply system; consider use of sterile water for drinking by immunosuppressed patients.</textblock>
    <textblock>Cooling-tower draft</textblock>
    <textblock>Proper design, placement, and maintenance of cooling towers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillosis:</textblock>
    <textblock>Host-Related</textblock>
    <textblock>Severe granulocytopenia</textblock>
    <textblock>Decrease duration of immunosuppression, such as by administration of GMCSF; consider placing severely granulocytopenic patients in protected environment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environment-Related</textblock>
    <textblock>Construction activity</textblock>
    <textblock>Remove granulocytopenic patients from vicinity of construction; if not already done, placing severely granulocytopenic patients in protected environment; mask severely granulocytopenic patients when they leave protected environment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other environmental sources of aspergilli</textblock>
    <textblock>Routine maintenance of hospital air-handling system and rooms of immunosuppressed patients.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respiratory Syncytial Virus Infection:</textblock>
    <textblock>Host-Related</textblock>
    <textblock>Age (&lt;2 years) Congenital pulmonary/cardiac disease, Immunosuppression</textblock>
    <textblock>Consider routine pre-admission screening of high-risk patients for severe RSV infection, followed by cohorting of patients and nursing personnel during hospital outbreaks of RSV infection.</textblock>
    <textblock>Personnel- or Procedure-Related</textblock>
    <textblock>Cross-contamination by hands</textblock>
    <textblock>Personnel education; handwashing; gloving; gowning; during outbreaks, use private rooms or cohort patients and nursing personnel, and limit visitors.</textblock>
    <textblock>Influenza:</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Use private room or cohort infected patients.</textblock>
    <textblock>Host-Related</textblock>
    <textblock>Age (&gt;65 years) Immunosuppression</textblock>
    <textblock>Vaccinate high-risk patients before the influenza season each year; use amantadine or rimantadine for chemoprophylaxis during an outbreak.</textblock>
    <textblock>Personnel-Related</textblock>
    <textblock>Infected personnel</textblock>
    <textblock>Vaccinate personnel caring for high-risk patients, before the influenza season each year; use amantadine or rimantadine for prophylaxis during an outbreak.</textblock>
  </table>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-18-P</textblock>
  </billing>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:graphicsEN02FE94.004</textblock>
  </import>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-18-C</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
