<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00052</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00038</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463), the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) announces the following subcommittee meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Subcommittee on Prevention and Control of Antimicrobial Resistant Microorganisms in Hospitals.</textblock>
    <textblock>Time and Date:</textblock>
    <textblock>9 a.m.-3:30 p.m., February 18, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Place:</textblock>
    <textblock>CDC, Auditorium A, 1600 Clifton Road, NE., Atlanta, Georgia 30333.</textblock>
    <textblock>Status:</textblock>
    <textblock>Open to the public, limited only by the space available.</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose:</textblock>
    <textblock>This subcommittee will review current knowledge about the epidemiology and laboratory aspects of antimicrobial resistance among nosocomial pathogens and develop an agenda for a workshop later this year to revise and/or develop recommendations to control these pathogens in acute care settings.</textblock>
    <textblock>Matters to be Discussed:</textblock>
    <textblock>The subcommittee will hold its second meeting to review current knowledge about the epidemiology and laboratory aspects of vancomycin resistance in enterococci and develop a comprehensive strategic plan to detect, prevent, and control resistant enterococci in U.S. hospitals. Agenda items are subject to change as priorities dictate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contact Person for More Information:</textblock>
    <textblock>Julia S. Garner, R.N., M.N., Nurse Consultant, Hospital Infections Program, NCID, CDC, 1600 Clifton Road, NE., Mailstop A-07, Atlanta, Georgia 30333, telephone 404/639-1552.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 27, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Hospital Infection Control Practices Advisory Committee: Subcommittee on Prevention and Control of Antimicrobial Resistant Microorganisms in Hospitals; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Elvin Hilyer,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Director for Policy Coordination, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2330 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-18-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
