<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Examples.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following examples illustrate the rules</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 1. Single stated rate paid semiannually.</textblock>
    <textblock>A debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument issued in consideration for the sale of nonpublicly</textblock>
    <textblock>traded property in a transaction that is not a potentially</textblock>
    <textblock>abusive situation calls for the payment of a principal amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>$1,000,000 at the end of a 10-year term and 20 semiannual</textblock>
    <textblock>interest payments of $60,000. Assume that the test rate of</textblock>
    <textblock>interest is 12 percent, compounded semiannually. The debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument is not subject to section 1274 because it provides for</textblock>
    <textblock>interest equal to the test rate and all interest payable on the</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument is qualified stated interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 2. Sale of farm for debt instrument with contingent</textblock>
    <textblock>interest_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Facts.</textblock>
    <textblock>On July 1, 1995, A, an individual, sells to</textblock>
    <textblock>B land used as a farm within the meaning of section 6420(c)(2).</textblock>
    <textblock>As partial consideration for the sale, B issues a debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>calling for a single $500,000 payment due in 10 years unless</textblock>
    <textblock>profits from the land in each of the 10 years preceding maturity</textblock>
    <textblock>of the debt instrument exceed a specified amount, in which case B</textblock>
    <textblock>is to make a payment of $1,200,000. The debt instrument does not</textblock>
    <textblock>provide for interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Total payments may exceed $1,000,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>Even though the</textblock>
    <textblock>total payments ultimately payable under the contract may be less</textblock>
    <textblock>than $1,000,000, at the time of the sale or exchange it cannot be</textblock>
    <textblock>determined that the sales price cannot exceed $1,000,000. Thus,</textblock>
    <textblock>the sale of the land used as a farm is not an excepted</textblock>
    <textblock>transaction described in section 1274(c)(3)(A).</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 3. Sale between related parties subject to section</textblock>
    <textblock>483(e)_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Facts.</textblock>
    <textblock>On July 1, 1995, A, an individual, sells land</textblock>
    <textblock>(not used as a farm within the meaning of section 6420(c)(2)) to</textblock>
    <textblock>A's child B for $650,000. In consideration for the sale, B</textblock>
    <textblock>issues a 10-year debt instrument to A that calls for a payment of</textblock>
    <textblock>$650,000. No other consideration is given. The debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>does not provide for interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Treatment of debt instrument.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of section</textblock>
    <textblock>483(e), the $650,000 debt instrument is treated as two separate</textblock>
    <textblock>debt instruments: a $500,000 debt instrument and a $150,000 debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument. The $500,000 debt instrument is subject to section</textblock>
    <textblock>483(e), and accordingly is covered by the exception from section</textblock>
    <textblock>1274 described in section 1274(c)(3)(F). Because the amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>the payments due as consideration for the sale exceeds $250,000,</textblock>
    <textblock>however, the $150,000 debt instrument is subject to section 1274.</textblock>
    <textblock>§1.1274-2</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue price of debt instruments to which section 1274</textblock>
    <textblock>applies.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>In general.</textblock>
    <textblock>If section 1274 applies to a debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument, section 1274 and this section determine the issue</textblock>
    <textblock>price of the debt instrument. For rules relating to the</textblock>
    <textblock>determination of the amount and timing of OID to be included in</textblock>
    <textblock>income, see section 1272 and the regulations thereunder.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue price_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Debt instruments that provide for</textblock>
    <textblock>adequate stated interest; stated principal amount.</textblock>
    <textblock>The issue</textblock>
    <textblock>price of a debt instrument that provides for adequate stated</textblock>
    <textblock>interest is the stated principal amount of the debt instrument.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of section 1274, the stated principal amount of a</textblock>
    <textblock>debt instrument is the aggregate amount of all payments due under</textblock>
    <textblock>the debt instrument, excluding any amount of stated interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under §1.1273-2(g)(2)(ii), however, the stated principal amount</textblock>
    <textblock>of a debt instrument is reduced by any payment from the buyer-</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower to the seller-lender that is designated as interest or</textblock>
    <textblock>points. See</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 2</textblock>
    <textblock>of §1.1273-2(g)(5).</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Debt instruments that do not provide for adequate stated</textblock>
    <textblock>interest; imputed principal amount.</textblock>
    <textblock>The issue price of a debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument that does not provide for adequate stated interest is</textblock>
    <textblock>the imputed principal amount of the debt instrument.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Debt instruments issued in a potentially abusive</textblock>
    <textblock>situation; fair market value.</textblock>
    <textblock>Notwithstanding paragraphs (b)(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>and (b)(2) of this section, in the case of a debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>issued in a potentially abusive situation (as defined in</textblock>
    <textblock>§1.1274-3), the issue price of the debt instrument is the fair</textblock>
    <textblock>market value of the property received in exchange for the debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument, reduced by the fair market value of any consideration</textblock>
    <textblock>other than the debt instrument issued in consideration for the</textblock>
    <textblock>sale or exchange.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Determination of whether a debt instrument provides for</textblock>
    <textblock>adequate stated interest_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>In general.</textblock>
    <textblock>A debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>provides for adequate stated interest if its stated principal</textblock>
    <textblock>amount is less than or equal to its imputed principal amount.</textblock>
    <textblock>Imputed principal amount means the sum of the present values, as</textblock>
    <textblock>of the issue date, of all payments, including payments of stated</textblock>
    <textblock>interest, due under the debt instrument (determined by using a</textblock>
    <textblock>discount rate equal to the test rate of interest as determined</textblock>
    <textblock>under §1.1274-4). If a debt instrument has a single fixed rate</textblock>
    <textblock>of interest that is paid or compounded at least annually, and</textblock>
    <textblock>that rate is equal to or greater than the test rate, the debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument has adequate stated interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Determination of present value.</textblock>
    <textblock>The present value of a</textblock>
    <textblock>payment is determined by discounting the payment from the date it</textblock>
    <textblock>becomes due to the date of the sale or exchange at the test rate</textblock>
    <textblock>of interest. To determine present value, a compounding period</textblock>
    <textblock>must be selected, and the test rate must be based on the same</textblock>
    <textblock>compounding period.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
