<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00031</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 27, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 21, 1994, Algonquin Gas Transmission Company (Algonquin) tendered for filing as part of its FERC Gas Tariff, Fourth Revised Volume No. 1, the following tariff sheet:</textblock>
    <textblock>Sub First Revised Sheet No. 98</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed effective date of the tariff sheet is November 1, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Algonquin states that the purpose of this filing is to recover stranded costs allocated to Algonquin in Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation's (Texas Eastern) filing in Docket No. RP93-204-000 dated December 30, 1993. In compliance with the October 29 Order in Docket No. RP93-204-000, Texas Eastern submitted a filing to recover stranded costs using the allocation method accepted by the Commission in the December 17 Order in Docket Nos. RS92-11-000, et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>Algonquin states that copies of this filing were served upon each affected party and interested state commissions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with §§385.214 and 385.211 of the Commission's Rules and Regulations. All such motions or protests should be filed on or before February 3, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection in the public reference room.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. RP94-115-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Algonquin Gas Transmission Co.; Proposed Changes in FERC Gas Tariff</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2308 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
