<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00042</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In response to a comment, the final regulations provide a</textblock>
    <textblock>special rule for certain variable rate debt instruments (such as</textblock>
    <textblock>auction rate or adjustable rate debt instruments) that provide</textblock>
    <textblock>for a fixed rate of interest for an initial period, followed by a</textblock>
    <textblock>period during which the interest is reset to a rate that will</textblock>
    <textblock>enable the instrument to trade at a fixed amount when the reset</textblock>
    <textblock>becomes effective. Under this special rule, the debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>is treated as maturing on the date the reset rate becomes</textblock>
    <textblock>effective and reissued on that date for the fixed amount. As a</textblock>
    <textblock>result of this rule, for example, if a debt instrument is issued</textblock>
    <textblock>at a discount (i.e., the issue price of the debt instrument is</textblock>
    <textblock>less than its par value) and is reset to par after an initial</textblock>
    <textblock>period, the discount on the instrument will be accrued entirely</textblock>
    <textblock>in the initial period rather than over the full term of the</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument.</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective Dates</textblock>
    <textblock>These regulations apply to debt instruments issued on or</textblock>
    <textblock>after April 4, 1994, and to lending transactions,</textblock>
    <textblock>sales, and exchanges that occur on or after April 4, 1994. However, ยง1.1272-3 applies to debt instruments</textblock>
    <textblock>acquired on or after April 4, 1994, and</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง1.1275-2(d)(2) applies to qualified reopenings that occur on or</textblock>
    <textblock>after March 25, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Reliance on Final Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>Except for ยง1.1272-3, taxpayers may rely on the final</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations for debt instruments issued after December 21, 1992,</textblock>
    <textblock>and for lending transactions, sales, and exchanges that occur</textblock>
    <textblock>after December 21, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority Under Section 6662</textblock>
    <textblock>Although the final regulations dispose of the underlying</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations (other than ยง1.446-2(e)(3)), the IRS will</textblock>
    <textblock>allow taxpayers to treat the proposed regulations as authority</textblock>
    <textblock>under section 6662 of the Code for debt instruments issued after</textblock>
    <textblock>December 21, 1992, and prior to April 4, 1994, and</textblock>
    <textblock>for lending transactions, sales, and exchanges that occurred</textblock>
    <textblock>after December 21, 1992, and prior to April 4, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The IRS also will allow taxpayers to treat the OID regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>that were proposed in 1986 and 1991 as authority under section</textblock>
    <textblock>6662 for debt instruments issued prior to December 22, 1992, and</textblock>
    <textblock>for lending transactions, sales, and exchanges that occurred</textblock>
    <textblock>prior to December 22, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Special Analyses</textblock>
    <textblock>It has been determined that these regulations are not major</textblock>
    <textblock>rules as defined in Executive Order 12291. Therefore, a</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Impact Analysis is not required. It also has been</textblock>
    <textblock>determined that section 553(b) of the Administrative Procedure</textblock>
    <textblock>Act (5 U.S.C. chapter 5) and the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S.C. chapter 6) do not apply to these regulations, and,</textblock>
    <textblock>therefore, a Regulatory Flexibility Analysis is not required.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 7805(f) of the Code, the notice of proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rulemaking was submitted to the Small Business Administration for</textblock>
    <textblock>comment on its impact on small business.</textblock>
    <textblock>Drafting Information</textblock>
    <textblock>The principal authors of these regulations are William E.</textblock>
    <textblock>Blanchard and Andrew C. Kittler of the Office of Assistant Chief</textblock>
    <textblock>Counsel (Financial Institutions and Products), IRS. However,</textblock>
    <textblock>other personnel from the IRS and Treasury Department participated</textblock>
    <textblock>in their development.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects</textblock>
    <textblock>26 CFR part 1</textblock>
    <textblock>Income taxes, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>26 CFR part 602</textblock>
    <textblock>Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
