<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00117</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Wash hands after contact with mucous membranes, respiratory secretions, or objects contaminated with respiratory secretions, whether or not gloves are worn. Wash hands before and after contact with a patient who has an endotracheal or tracheostomy tube in place, and before and after contact with any respiratory device that is used on the patient, whether or not gloves are worn.</textblock>
    <textblock>201,203,207,208,641,642</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Barrier Precautions</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Wear gloves for handling respiratory secretions or objects contaminated with respiratory secretions of any patient.</textblock>
    <textblock>215,216</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Change gloves and wash hands between patients; after handling respiratory secretions or objects contaminated with secretions from one patient and before contact with another patient, object, or environmental surface; and between contacts with a contaminated body site and respiratory tract of, or respiratory device on, the same patient.</textblock>
    <textblock>215,217,218</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Wear a gown when soiling with respiratory secretions from a patient is anticipated, and change the gown after such contact and before providing care to another patient.</textblock>
    <textblock>215</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Care of Patients with Tracheostomy</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Perform tracheostomy under sterile conditions.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>b. When changing a tracheostomy tube, use aseptic technique and replace the tube with one that has undergone sterilization or high-level disinfection.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Suctioning of Respiratory Tract Secretions</textblock>
    <textblock>a.</textblock>
    <textblock>NO RECOMMENDATION</textblock>
    <textblock>for wearing sterile rather than clean gloves when suctioning a patient's respiratory secretions.</textblock>
    <textblock>UNRESOLVED ISSUE</textblock>
    <textblock>b. If the open suction system is employed, use a sterile single-use catheter.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY II</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Use only sterile fluid to remove secretions from the suction catheter.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Change suction-collection tubing and canisters between patients.</textblock>
    <textblock>Category IB</textblock>
    <textblock>e.</textblock>
    <textblock>NO RECOMMENDATION</textblock>
    <textblock>for using a multi-use closed-system suction catheter in preference to a single-use open-system catheter.</textblock>
    <textblock>279-282</textblock>
    <textblock>UNRESOLVED ISSUE</textblock>
    <textblock>f.</textblock>
    <textblock>NO RECOMMENDATION</textblock>
    <textblock>for routinely using an endotracheal tube with a dorsal lumen above the endotracheal cuff, to allow drainage (by suctioning) of tracheal secretions that accumulate in the patient's subglottic area.</textblock>
    <textblock>197</textblock>
    <textblock>UNRESOLVED ISSUE</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Modifying Host Risk for Infection</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Precautions for Prevention of Endogenous Pneumonia</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Prevention of Aspiration</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Discontinue enteral-tube feeding and remove devices such as endotracheal and/or nasogastric or other enteral tubes from patients as soon as the clinical indications for these are resolved.</textblock>
    <textblock>7,34,35,80,110,173,175,176,192,643</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>b. If there is no contraindication to the maneuver, elevate at an angle of 30-45</textblock>
    <textblock>○ the head of the bed of a patient who is receiving mechanically assisted ventilation and has a nasogastric or other enteral tube in place.</textblock>
    <textblock>175,184</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Routinely verify appropriate placement of the feeding tube.</textblock>
    <textblock>175644-646</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Routinely assess the patient's intestinal motility, (e.g., by auscultating for bowel sounds and measuring residual gastric volume or abdominal girth) and adjust the rate and volume of enteral feeding to avoid regurgitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>175,188,643</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Use small-bore tubes for enteral feeding;</textblock>
    <textblock>175,176,186,644,647</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY II</textblock>
    <textblock>f. Administer enteral feeding intermittently in small quantities, rather than continuously.</textblock>
    <textblock>2T167,183,647,648</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
