<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00035</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00022</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 27, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 24, 1994 Panhandle Eastern Pipe Line Company (Panhandle) tendered for filing as part of its FERC Gas Tariff, Original Volume No. 2 revised sheets listed on Appendix A to the filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Panhandle states that such changes are made to amend Rate Schedule T-39 for the transportation of natural gas on behalf of United Cities Gas Company (United Cities) to reflect Trunkline Gas Company's and Panhandle's transportation rates as approved in Docket Nos. RP89-160-000, RP89-114-000, RP92-165-000, RS92-25-000, and RS92-22-000, et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>Panhandle respectfully requests that the Commission grant such waivers as may be necessary for the acceptance of the tariff sheets submitted herewith, to become effective on the dates shown thereon.</textblock>
    <textblock>Panhandle states that a copy of this letter and enclosures was served on United Cities and the respective state commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with §§385.211 and 385.214 of the Commission's Rules and Regulations. All such motions or protests should be filed on or before February 3, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceedings. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection in the public reference room.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. RP94-117-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Panhandle Eastern Pipe Line Co., Proposed Changes in FERC Gas Tariff</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2316 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
