<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00044</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00031</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-48324]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>AERR Co. Site, Unincorporated Jefferson County, Colorado; Notice of Proposed Administrative Settlement Pursuant to the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act, as Amended by the Superfund Amendments and Reauthorization Act</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of proposed administrative settlement; request for public comment.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 122(i) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act, 42 U.S.C. 9622(i), as amended by the Superfund Amendments and reauthorization Act (``CERCLA''), notice is hereby given of a proposed administrative settlement concerning the AERR Co. site in unincorporated Jefferson County, Colorado. The proposed administrative settlement resolves an EPA claim under section 107 of CERCLA, 42 U.S.C. 9607 against Adolph Coors Company, Ball Corporation, Continental Can Company, The Denver Post Corporation, Eastman Kodak Company, Eaton Corporation, Entrada Industries, Inc., Hewlett-Packard Company, Pease Industries, Sterling Stainless Tube Corporation, and Syntex Chemicals, Inc. The settlement requires the settling parties to pay $488,867.41 to the Hazardous Substances Superfund.</textblock>
    <textblock>For thirty (30) days following the date of publication of this notice, the Agency will receive written comments relating to the settlement. The Agency's response to any comments received will be available for public inspection at EPA Region VIII's Superfund Records Center, which is located on the 8th floor of the North Tower, at 999 18th Street, Denver, Colorado.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be submitted by March 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed administrative settlement and additional background information relating to the settlement are available for public inspection at EPA Region VIII's Superfund Records Center, at the address listed above. A copy of the proposed settlement may be obtained from Carol Pokorny (8HWM-ER), Enforcement Specialist, USEPA, 999 18th Street, suite 500, Denver, CO 80202-2466. Comments should reference the AERR CO. Site, Jefferson County, CO, EPA Docket No. CERCLA-VIII-94-04, and should be addressed to Ms. Pokorny at the address given above.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Wendy Silver, Office of Regional Counsel, (303) 294-7570.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: November 23, 1993.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Kerrigan G. Clough,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2277 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
