<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00084</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00061</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Chester, West Virginia Ordinance No. 305</textblock>
    <textblock>Regarding Transportation of Hazardous Wastes</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Highway Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Research and Special Programs Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. PDA-3(RF)]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) and Research and Special Programs Administration (RSPA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice Dismissing Application and Closing the Docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>APPLICANT:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Solid Wastes Management Association, on behalf of its Chemical Waste Transportation Institute.</textblock>
    <textblock>LOCAL LAW AFFECTED:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ordinance No. 305 of the City of Chester, West Virginia, Regarding Transportation of Hazardous Wastes.</textblock>
    <textblock>APPLICABLE FEDERAL REQUIREMENTS:</textblock>
    <textblock>Hazardous Materials Transportation Act (HMTA), 49 App. U.S.C. §1801 et seq., and the Hazardous Materials Regulations, 49 CFR Parts 171-180.</textblock>
    <textblock>MODE AFFECTED:</textblock>
    <textblock>Highway</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The application for a determination of preemption is dismissed, and this docket is closed, because Ordinance No. 305 of Chester, West Virginia never went into effect.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Frazer C. Hilder, Office of the Chief Counsel, Research and Special Programs Administration, U.S. Department of Transportation, Washington, DC 20590-0001 (Tel. No. 202-366-4400).</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>In December 1991, the National Solid Wastes Management Association, on behalf of its Chemical Waste Transportation Institute (CWTI), petitioned for an administrative determination that the HMTA preempts Chester, West Virginia Ordinance No. 305, regarding the transportation of hazardous wastes. In its application, CWTI stated that the Chester City Council had ``enacted Ordinance No. 305,'' and the copy of Ordinance No. 305 attached to CWTI's application indicated that the Ordinance had been ``Passed and Adopted'' on December 2, 1991.</textblock>
    <textblock>On April 6, 1992, FHWA and RSPA published a Public Notice and Invitation to Comment on CWTI's application. 57 FR 11654. That Notice was issued jointly by both agencies because the requirements in Ordinance No. 305 purported to affect both the highway routing of hazardous materials and other aspects of hazardous materials transportation. See 57 FR at 11655. In response to that Notice, four industry associations and more than 20 individual companies submitted comments opposing Ordinance No. 305 and supporting a finding of preemption. One party submitting comments, the Tri-State Area Transporters Association, stated that Ordinance No. 305 was originally scheduled to become effective February 1, 1992, but that in January 1992, ``Chester apparently revised the ordinance, with no effective date given.''</textblock>
    <textblock>No party, including the City of Chester, submitted comments opposing CWTI's application. CWTI submitted further comments, which it called ``rebuttal.''</textblock>
    <textblock>In a recent telephone conversation, Chester Mayor Ken Morris advised RSPA that Ordinance No. 305 was never adopted and never went into effect. Copies of a December 6, 1993 letter to Mayor Morris, confirming the substance of this telephone conversation, were sent to CWTI and each party submitting comments on CWTI's application. In a December 17, 1993 letter, CWTI advised that, based on information from its members, Ordinance No. 305 has never been enforced and that CWTI had ``no objection to DOT dismissing the Institute's petition at this time *␣*␣* without prejudice *␣*␣* ''</textblock>
    <textblock>CWTI's application is hereby dismissed, and the docket is closed. If the requirements contained in Chester, West Virginia Ordinance No. 305 are ever adopted and enforced, CWTI may again submit an application for a preemption determination.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC on January 25, 1994 .</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rodney E. Slater,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator, Federal Highway Administration.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Alan I. Roberts,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Administrator for Hazardous Materials Safety, Research and Special Programs Administration.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2285 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-60-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
