<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00072</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Restrictions on adjustments</textblock>
    <textblock>. If, due to significant</textblock>
    <textblock>restrictions on variations in a qualified floating rate or the</textblock>
    <textblock>use of certain formulae pursuant to ยง1.1275-5(b)(2) (e.g., 15</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of 1-year LIBOR, plus 800 basis points), the rate in</textblock>
    <textblock>substance resembles a fixed rate, the applicable Federal rate is</textblock>
    <textblock>determined by reference to the term of the debt instrument.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Counting of either the issue date or the maturity date.</textblock>
    <textblock>The term of a debt instrument includes either the issue date or the maturity date, but not both dates.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>Certain debt instruments that provide for principal</textblock>
    <textblock>payments uncertain as to time</textblock>
    <textblock>. If a debt instrument provides for</textblock>
    <textblock>principal payments that are fixed in total amount but uncertain</textblock>
    <textblock>as to time, the term of the instrument is determined by reference</textblock>
    <textblock>to the latest possible date on which a principal payment can be</textblock>
    <textblock>made or, in the case of an installment obligation, by reference</textblock>
    <textblock>to the longest weighted average maturity under any possible</textblock>
    <textblock>payment schedule.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Foreign currency loans</textblock>
    <textblock>. If all of the payments of a</textblock>
    <textblock>debt instrument are denominated in, or determined by reference</textblock>
    <textblock>to, a currency other than the U.S. dollar, the applicable Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>rate for the debt instrument is a foreign currency rate of</textblock>
    <textblock>interest that is analogous to the applicable Federal rate</textblock>
    <textblock>described in this section. For this purpose, an analogous rate</textblock>
    <textblock>of interest is a rate based on yields (with the appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>compounding period) of the highest grade of outstanding</textblock>
    <textblock>marketable obligations denominated in such currency (excluding</textblock>
    <textblock>any obligations that benefit from special tax exemptions or</textblock>
    <textblock>preferential tax rates not available to debt instruments</textblock>
    <textblock>generally) with due consideration given to the maturities of the</textblock>
    <textblock>obligations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Examples</textblock>
    <textblock>. The following examples illustrate the rules</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 1. Variable rate debt instrument that limits the</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of increase and decrease in the rate</textblock>
    <textblock>_(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Facts</textblock>
    <textblock>. On July</textblock>
    <textblock>1, 1996, A sells nonpublicly traded property to B in return for a</textblock>
    <textblock>5-year debt instrument that provides for interest to be paid on</textblock>
    <textblock>July 1 of each year, beginning on July 1, 1997, based on the</textblock>
    <textblock>prime rate of a local bank on that date. However, the interest</textblock>
    <textblock>rate cannot increase or decrease from one year to the next by</textblock>
    <textblock>more than .25 percentage points (25 basis points).</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Significant restriction</textblock>
    <textblock>. The debt instrument is a</textblock>
    <textblock>variable rate debt instrument (as defined in ยง1.1275-5) that</textblock>
    <textblock>provides for stated interest at a qualified floating rate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Assume that based on all the facts and circumstances, the</textblock>
    <textblock>restriction is a significant restriction on the variations in the</textblock>
    <textblock>rate of interest. Under paragraph (c)(2)(ii) of this section,</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicable Federal rate is determined by reference to the</textblock>
    <textblock>term of the debt instrument, and the applicable Federal rate is</textblock>
    <textblock>the Federal mid-term rate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 2. Installment obligation</textblock>
    <textblock>_(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Facts</textblock>
    <textblock>. On January</textblock>
    <textblock>1, 1996, A sells nonpublicly traded property to B in exchange for</textblock>
    <textblock>a debt instrument that calls for a payment of $500,000 on January</textblock>
    <textblock>1, 2001, and a payment of $1,000,000 on January 1, 2006. The</textblock>
    <textblock>debt instrument does not provide for any stated interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Determination of term</textblock>
    <textblock>. The debt instrument is an</textblock>
    <textblock>installment obligation. Under paragraph (c)(1) of this section,</textblock>
    <textblock>the term of the debt instrument is its weighted average maturity</textblock>
    <textblock>(as defined in ยง1.1273-1(e)(3)). The debt instrument's weighted</textblock>
    <textblock>average maturity is 8.33 years, which is the sum of (A) the ratio</textblock>
    <textblock>of the first payment to total payments (500,000/1,500,000),</textblock>
    <textblock>multiplied by the number of complete years from the issue date</textblock>
    <textblock>until the payment is due (5 years), and (B) the ratio of the</textblock>
    <textblock>second payment to total payments (1,000,000/1,500,000),</textblock>
    <textblock>multiplied by the number of complete years from the issue date</textblock>
    <textblock>until the second payment is due (10 years).</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicable Federal rate</textblock>
    <textblock>. Based on the calculation in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (ii) of this example, the term of the debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>is treated as 8.33 years. Consequently, the applicable Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>rate is the Federal mid-term rate.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง1.1274-5</textblock>
    <textblock>Assumptions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>In general</textblock>
    <textblock>. Section 1274 does not apply to a debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument if the debt instrument is assumed, or property is</textblock>
    <textblock>taken subject to the debt instrument, in connection with a sale</textblock>
    <textblock>or exchange of property, unless the terms of the debt instrument,</textblock>
    <textblock>as part of the sale or exchange, are modified in a manner that</textblock>
    <textblock>would constitute an exchange under section 1001.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Modifications of debt instruments</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>In general</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Except as provided in paragraph (b)(2) of this section, if a debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument is assumed, or property is taken subject to a debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument, in connection with a sale or exchange of property,</textblock>
    <textblock>the terms of the debt instrument are modified as part of the sale</textblock>
    <textblock>or exchange, and the modification triggers an exchange under</textblock>
    <textblock>section 1001, the modification is treated as a separate</textblock>
    <textblock>transaction taking place immediately before the sale or exchange</textblock>
    <textblock>and is attributed to the seller of the property. For purposes of</textblock>
    <textblock>this paragraph (b), a debt instrument is not considered to be</textblock>
    <textblock>modified as part of the sale or exchange unless the seller knew</textblock>
    <textblock>or had reason to know about the modification.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Election to treat buyer as modifying the debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>_(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>In general</textblock>
    <textblock>. Rather than having the rules in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (b)(1) of this section apply, the seller and buyer may</textblock>
    <textblock>jointly elect to treat the transaction as one in which the buyer</textblock>
    <textblock>first assumed the original (unmodified) debt instrument and then</textblock>
    <textblock>subsequently modified the debt instrument. For this purpose, the</textblock>
    <textblock>modification is treated as a separate transaction taking place</textblock>
    <textblock>immediately after the sale or exchange.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Time and manner of making the election</textblock>
    <textblock>. The buyer and</textblock>
    <textblock>seller make the election under paragraph (b)(2)(i) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section by jointly signing a statement that includes the names,</textblock>
    <textblock>addresses, and taxpayer identification numbers of the seller and</textblock>
    <textblock>buyer, and a clear indication that the election is being made</textblock>
    <textblock>under paragraph (b)(2)(i) of this section. Both the buyer and</textblock>
    <textblock>the seller must sign this statement not later than the earlier of</textblock>
    <textblock>the last day (including extensions) for filing the Federal income</textblock>
    <textblock>tax return of the buyer or seller for the taxable year in which</textblock>
    <textblock>the sale or exchange of the property occurs. The buyer and</textblock>
    <textblock>seller should attach this signed statement (or a copy thereof) to</textblock>
    <textblock>their timely filed Federal income tax returns.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
