<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00115</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>PART II. RECOMMENDATIONS FOR PREVENTION OF NOSOCOMIAL PNEUMONIA</textblock>
    <textblock>Introduction</textblock>
    <textblock>The recommendations are presented according to the etiology of the infection, in the following order: bacterial pneumonia, including Legionnaires' disease; fungal pneumonia (aspergillosis); and virus-associated pneumonia (RSV and influenza infections). Each topic is subdivided according to the following general approaches for nosocomial infection control, as applicable to the infection:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Staff education and infection surveillance;</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Interruption of transmission of microorganisms by eradicating infecting; microorganisms from their epidemiologically important reservoirs, and/or preventing person-to-person transmission; and</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Modifying host risk for infection.</textblock>
    <textblock>As in previous CDC guidelines, each recommendation is categorized on the basis of existing scientific evidence, theoretical rationale, applicability, and economic impact.</textblock>
    <textblock>213,214,605-609</textblock>
    <textblock>However, the previous CDC system of categorizing recommendations has been modified as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
    <textblock>_Strongly recommended for all hospitals and strongly supported by well-designed experimental or epidemiologic studies.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>_ Strongly recommended for all hospitals and viewed as effective by experts in the field and a consensus of HICPAC based on strong rationale and suggestive evidence, even though definitive scientific studies may not have been done.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY II</textblock>
    <textblock>_Suggested for implementation in many hospitals. Recommendations may be supported by suggestive clinical or epidemiologic studies, a strong theoretical rationale, or definitive studies applicable to some but not all hospitals.</textblock>
    <textblock>NO RECOMMENDATION; UNRESOLVED ISSUE</textblock>
    <textblock>. Practices for which insufficient evidence or consensus regarding efficacy exists.</textblock>
    <textblock>Prevention and Control of Bacterial Pneumonia</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Staff Education and Infection Surveillance</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Staff Education</textblock>
    <textblock>Educate healthcare workers regarding nosocomial bacterial pneumonias and infection control procedures to prevent their occurrence.</textblock>
    <textblock>610-613</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Surveillance</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Conduct surveillance for bacterial pneumonia in ICU patients at high-risk for nosocomial bacterial pneumonia (e.g., patients with mechanically assisted ventilation, selected postoperative patients) to determine trends and identify potential problems.</textblock>
    <textblock>7,34,35,59,60,614-616</textblock>
    <textblock>Include data regarding the causative microorganisms and their antimicrobial susceptibility patterns.</textblock>
    <textblock>2-4</textblock>
    <textblock>Express data as rates (e.g., number of infected patients or infections per 100 ICU days or per 1,000 ventilator-days) to facilitate intra- and inter-hospital comparisons.</textblock>
    <textblock>63,617-619</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Do not routinely perform surveillance cultures of patients or of equipment or devices used for respiratory therapy, pulmonary-function testing, or delivery of inhalation anesthesia.</textblock>
    <textblock>62,620,621</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
    <textblock>II. INTERRUPTION OF TRANSMISSION OF MICROORGANISMS</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Sterilization or Disinfection, and Maintenance of Equipment and Devices</textblock>
    <textblock>1. General Measures</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Thoroughly clean all equipment and devices to be sterilized or disinfected. Decontaminate equipment or device before or during cleaning if it is contaminated with blood and/or marked ``contaminated'' and received from patients who are on certain types of isolation.</textblock>
    <textblock>245,246,622</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Sterilize semicritical equipment or devices, i.e., items that touch mucous membranes (See device list, Appendix A). If sterilization is not feasible, use high-level disinfection either by wet heat pasteurization (76</textblock>
    <textblock>○C for 30 minutes), or by using liquid disinfectants approved as sterilants or disinfectants by the Environmental Protection Agency.</textblock>
    <textblock>240,242,244,246,623</textblock>
    <textblock>Follow disinfection with appropriate rinsing, drying, and packaging, taking care not to contaminate the items in the process.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Use sterile (not distilled, nonsterile), pyrogen-free water for rinsing reusable equipment and devices after they have been chemically disinfected.</textblock>
    <textblock>227,233,234,248</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Do not reprocess an equipment or device that is manufactured for single use only, unless data show that reprocessing the equipment or device poses no threat to the patient, is cost-effective, and does not change the structural integrity or function of the equipment or device.</textblock>
    <textblock>624,625</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Mechanical Ventilators, Anesthesia Machines and Circle Systems, and Pulmonary-Function Testing Equipment</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Do not routinely sterilize or disinfect the internal machinery of mechanical ventilators or anesthesia-breathing machines and their circle systems.</textblock>
    <textblock>626,627</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Do not routinely sterilize or disinfect the internal machinery of pulmonary-function testing machines between uses on different patients.</textblock>
    <textblock>628,629</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY II</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Ventilator Circuits with Humidifiers</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Do not routinely change more frequently than every 48 hours the breathing circuit, including tubing and exhalation valve, and the attached bubbling or wick humidifier of a ventilator that is in use on an individual patient.</textblock>
    <textblock>34,257,262</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
