<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00036</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Debt Instruments With Original Issue Discount; Imputed Interest</textblock>
    <textblock>on Deferred Payment Sales or Exchanges of Property</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>26 CFR Parts 1 and 602</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[TD 8517]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1545-AH46</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Internal Revenue Service (IRS), Treasury.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final regulations.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document contains final regulations relating to</textblock>
    <textblock>the tax treatment of debt instruments with original issue</textblock>
    <textblock>discount and the imputation of interest on deferred payments</textblock>
    <textblock>under certain contracts for the sale or exchange of property.</textblock>
    <textblock>The final regulations provide needed guidance to holders and</textblock>
    <textblock>issuers of debt instruments with original issue discount and to</textblock>
    <textblock>buyers and sellers of property.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The removal of §§1.163-11T, 1.1275-3T, 1.1275-6T and 1.6050H-2 is effective February 2, 1994. The remaining regulations are effective April 4, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>For dates of applicability of these regulations, see</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective Dates under</textblock>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>William E. Blanchard, 202-622-3950 (not a toll-free number), or Andrew C. Kittler, 202-622-3940</textblock>
    <textblock>(not a toll-free number).</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The collections of information contained in this final</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation have been reviewed and approved by the Office of</textblock>
    <textblock>Management and Budget in accordance with the requirements of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. 3504(h)) under control number</textblock>
    <textblock>1545-1353. The estimated annual burden per respondent varies</textblock>
    <textblock>from .3 hours to .5 hours, depending on individual circumstances,</textblock>
    <textblock>with an estimated average of .4 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>These estimates are an approximation of the average time</textblock>
    <textblock>expected to be necessary for a collection of information. They</textblock>
    <textblock>are based on such information as is available to the IRS.</textblock>
    <textblock>Individual respondents may require more or less time, depending</textblock>
    <textblock>on their particular circumstances.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments concerning the accuracy of this burden estimate and</textblock>
    <textblock>suggestions for reducing this burden should be sent to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Internal Revenue Service, Attn: IRS Reports Clearance Officer,</textblock>
    <textblock>PC:FP, Washington, DC 20224, and to the Office of Management</textblock>
    <textblock>and Budget, Attn: Desk Officer for the Department of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Treasury, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs,</textblock>
    <textblock>Washington, DC 20503.</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 22, 1992, the IRS published a notice of proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rulemaking in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(57 FR 60750) relating to</textblock>
    <textblock>original issue discount (OID) under section 163(e) and sections</textblock>
    <textblock>1271 through 1275 of the Internal Revenue Code (Code). The</textblock>
    <textblock>notice also contained proposed amendments to the regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>under sections 446 (relating to the accrual of interest), 483</textblock>
    <textblock>(relating to unstated interest), 1001 (relating to amount</textblock>
    <textblock>realized), and 1012 (relating to basis). The notice withdrew</textblock>
    <textblock>most of the proposed regulations that were previously published</textblock>
    <textblock>in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on April 8, 1986 (51 FR 12022), as</textblock>
    <textblock>amended on May 7, 1991 (56 FR 21112), and July 12, 1991 (56 FR</textblock>
    <textblock>31887).</textblock>
    <textblock>On February 16, 1993, the IRS held a public hearing on the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations. In addition, the IRS received a number of</textblock>
    <textblock>written comments on the proposed regulations. The proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations, with certain changes to respond to comments, are</textblock>
    <textblock>adopted as final regulations; to permit further comment, §1.446-2(e)(3) remains outstanding in proposed form. The changes, as</textblock>
    <textblock>well as several comments and suggestions that were not adopted in</textblock>
    <textblock>the final regulations, are discussed below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Explanation of Provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1.163-7␣Deduction for OID on Certain Debt Instruments</textblock>
    <textblock>The final regulations retain the rule of the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations that allows the issuer of a debt instrument to deduct</textblock>
    <textblock>de minimis OID using a straight line method. As requested by a</textblock>
    <textblock>commentator, the final regulations also allow the issuer the</textblock>
    <textblock>choice of deducting de minimis OID at maturity or in proportion</textblock>
    <textblock>to stated interest payments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because the proposed regulations permit flexible accrual</textblock>
    <textblock>periods, a commentator requested guidance on what accrual period</textblock>
    <textblock>controls to determine whether a debt instrument is an applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>high yield debt obligation under section 163(i). The final</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations provide that the issuer's choice of accrual periods</textblock>
    <textblock>governs for purposes of section 163(i).</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
