<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00142</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>470. Lentino JR, Rosenkranz MA, Michaels JA, et al. Nosocomial aspergillosis: a retrospective review of airborne disease secondary to road construction and contaminated air conditiners. Am J Epidemiol 1982; 116:430-437.</textblock>
    <textblock>471. Sarubbi FA, Kopf HB, Brejetta Wilson M, et al. Increased recovery of</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus flavus</textblock>
    <textblock>from respiratory specimens during hospital construction. Am Rev Respir Dis 1982; 125:33-38.</textblock>
    <textblock>472. Krasinski K, Holzman RS, Hanna B, et al. Nosocomial fungal infection during hospital renovation. Infect Control 1985; 6:278-282.</textblock>
    <textblock>473. Weems JJ, Davis BJ, Tablan OC, Kaufman L, Martone WJ. Construction activity: an independent risk factor for invasive aspergillosis and zygomycosis in patients with hematologic malignancy. Infect Control 1987; 8:71-75.</textblock>
    <textblock>474. Cage AA, Dean DC, Schimert G, Minsley N.</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus</textblock>
    <textblock>infection after cardiac surgery. Arch Surg 1970; 101:384-387.</textblock>
    <textblock>475. Streifel AJ, Stevens PP, Rhame FS. In-hospital source of airborne</textblock>
    <textblock>Penicillium</textblock>
    <textblock>spores. J Clin Microbiol 1987; 25:1-4.</textblock>
    <textblock>476. Keller NP, Cleveland TE, Bhatnagar D. Variable electrophoretic karyotypes of members of</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus flavi.</textblock>
    <textblock>Curr Genet 1992; 21:371-375.</textblock>
    <textblock>477. Denning DW, Clemons KV, Hanson LH, Stevens DA. Restriction endonuclease analysis of total cellular DNA of</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus fumigatus</textblock>
    <textblock>isolates of geographically and epidemiologically diverse origin. J Infect Dis 1990; 162:1151-1158.</textblock>
    <textblock>478. Rhame FS. Prevention of nosocomial aspergillosis. J Hosp Infect 1991; 18:466-472.</textblock>
    <textblock>479. Buckner CD, Clift RA, Sanders AJ, et al. Protective environment for marrow transplant recipients. Ann Intern Med 1978; 89:893-901.</textblock>
    <textblock>480. Murray WA, Streifel AJ, O'Dea TJ, Rhame FS. Ventilation for protection of immune compromised patients. ASHRAE Transactions 1988; 94:1185-1191.</textblock>
    <textblock>481. Streifel AJ, Vesley D. Control of airborne fungal spores in a university hospital. Environment International 1989; 12:441-444.</textblock>
    <textblock>482. Streifel AJ, Rhame FS. Hospital air filamentous fungal spore and particle counts in a specially designed hospital. Proc Indoor Air 1993; 4:161-163.</textblock>
    <textblock>483. Perry S, Penland WZ. The portable laminar flow isolator: new unit for patient protection in a germ-free environment. In: Recent Results in Cancer Research. New York: Springer-Verlag, 1970.</textblock>
    <textblock>484. Barnes RA, Rogers TR. Control of an outbreak of nosocomial aspergillosis by laminar air-flow isolation. J Hosp Infect 1989; 14:89-94.</textblock>
    <textblock>485. Levine AS, Siegel SE, Schrelber AD, et al. Protected environments and prophylactic antibiotics. N Engl J Med 1973; 288:477-483.</textblock>
    <textblock>486. ASHRAE Handbook. Heating Ventilation Air Conditioning Applications. Atlanta: ASHRAE, 1991:7.1-7.12.</textblock>
    <textblock>487. Rhame FS. Nosocomial aspergillosis: how much protection for which patients? Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol 1989; 10:296-298.</textblock>
    <textblock>488. Opal SM, Asp AA, Cannady PB, Morse PL, Burton LJ, Hammer PG. Efficacy of infection control measures during a nosocomial outbreak of disseminated aspergillosis associated with hospital construction. J Infect Dis 1986; 153:634-637.</textblock>
    <textblock>489. Welliver RC, McLaughlin S. Unique epidemiology of nosocomial infections in a children's hospital. Am J Dis Child 1984; 138:131-135.</textblock>
    <textblock>490. Valenti WM, Hall CB, Douglas RG,Jr., Menegus MA, Pincus PH. Nosocomial viral infections: I. Epidemiology and significance. Infect Control 1980; 1:33-37.</textblock>
    <textblock>491. Mintz L, Ballard RA, Sniderman SH, et al. Nosocomial respiratory syncytial virus infections in an intensive care nursery: Rapid diagnosis by direct immunofluorescence. Pediatrics 1979; 64:149-153.</textblock>
    <textblock>492. Hall CB, McBride JT, Walsh EE, et al. Aerosolized ribavirin treatment in infants with respiratory syncytial virus infection. N Engl J Med 1983; 308:1443-1447.</textblock>
    <textblock>493. Betts RF. Amantadine and rimantadine for the prevention of influenza A. Seminars Respir Infect 1989; 4:304-310.</textblock>
    <textblock>494. Rodriguez WJ, Parrott RH. Ribavirin aerosol treatment of serious respiratory syncytial virus infection in infants. Infect Dis Clin N Am 1987; 2:425.</textblock>
    <textblock>495. Krasinski K. Severe respiratory syncytial virus infection: clinical features, nosocomial acquisition and outcome. Pediatr Infect Dis 1985; 4:250-256.</textblock>
    <textblock>496. Meissner HC, Murray SA, Kiernan MA, et al. A simultaneous outbreak of respiratory syncytial virus and parainfluenza virus type 3 in a newborn nursery. J Pediatr 1984; 104:680-684.</textblock>
    <textblock>497. Hall CB, Powell KR, MacDonald NE, et al. Respiratory syncytial virus infection in children with compromised immune function. N Engl J Med 1986; 315:77-81.</textblock>
    <textblock>498. Mathur U, Bentley DW, Hall CB. Concurrent respiratory syncytial virus and influenza A infections in the institutionalized elderly and chronically ill. Ann Intern Med 1980; 93:49-52.</textblock>
    <textblock>499. MacDonald NE, Hall CB, Suffin SC, Alexon C, Harris PJ, Manning JA. Respiratory syncytial viral infection in infants with congenital heart disease. N Engl J Med 1982; 307:397-400.</textblock>
    <textblock>500. Drescher J, Zink P, Verhagen W, et al. Recent influenza virus A infections in forensic cases of sudden unexplained death. Virology 1987; 92:63-76.</textblock>
    <textblock>501. Hertz MI, Englund JA, Snover D, Bitterman PB, McGlave PB. Respiratory syncytial virus-induced acute lung injury in adult patients with bone marrow transplants: a clinical approach and review of the literature. Medicine 1989; 68:269-281.</textblock>
    <textblock>502. Baron RC, Dicker RC, Bussell KE, Herndon JL. Assessing trends in mortality in 121 U.S. cities, 1970-1979, from all causes and from pneumonia and influenza. Public Health Rep 1988; 103:120-128.</textblock>
    <textblock>503. Hall CB. The nosocomial spread of respiratory syncytial viral infections. Ann Rev Med 1983; 34:311-319.</textblock>
    <textblock>504. Finger F, Anderson LJ, Dicker RC, et al. Epidemic infections caused by respiratory syncytial virus in institutionalized young adults. J Infect Dis 1987; 155:1335-1339.</textblock>
    <textblock>505. Hall CB. Nosocomial viral infections: perennial weeds on pediatric wards. Am J Med 1981; 70:670-676.</textblock>
    <textblock>506. Hall CB, Douglas RG,Jr. Nosocomial influenza infection as a cause of intercurrent fevers in infants. Pediatrics 1975; 55:673-677.</textblock>
    <textblock>507. Glezen WP. Viral pneumonia as a cause and result of hospitalization. J Infect Dis 1983; 147:765-770.</textblock>
    <textblock>508. Wenzel RP, Deal EC, Hendley JO. Hospital-acquired viral respiratory illness on a pediatric ward. Pediatrics 1977; 60:367-371.</textblock>
    <textblock>509. Hall CB. Hospital-acquired pneumonia in children. Seminars Respir Infect 1987; 2:48-56.</textblock>
    <textblock>510. Glezen WP, Loda FA, Clyde WA,Jr., et al. Epidemiologic patterns of acute lower respiratory diseases in pediatric group practice. J Pediatr 1971; 78:397-406.</textblock>
    <textblock>511. Henderson FW, Collier AM, Clyde WA,Jr., et al. Respiratory-syncytial-virus infections, reinfections and immunity: a prospective, longitudinal study in young children. N Engl J Med 1979; 300:530-534.</textblock>
    <textblock>512. Hall WJ, Hall CB, Speers DM. Respiratory syncytial virus infection in adults: clinical, virologic, and serial pulmonary function studies. Ann Intern Med 1978; 88:203-205.</textblock>
    <textblock>513. Englund JA, Anderson LJ, Rhame FS. Nosocomial transmission of respiratory syncytial virus in immunocompromised adults. J Clin Microbiol 1991; 29:115-119.</textblock>
    <textblock>514. Falsey AR, Walsh EE, Betts RF. Serologic evidence of respiratory syncytial virus infection in nursing home patients. J Infect Dis 1990; 162:568-569.</textblock>
    <textblock>515. Hall CB, Kopelman AE, Douglas G,Jr., Griman JM, Meagher MP. Neonatal respiratory syncytial virus infection. N Engl J Med 1979; 300:393-396.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
