<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00020</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Airworthiness Directives; Airbus Industrie Model A310-200 and A310-300 Series Airplanes</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Part 39</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 93-NM-120-AD; Amendment 39-8794; AD 94-01-12]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This amendment supersedes an existing airworthiness directive (AD), applicable to all Airbus Industrie Model A310-200 and A310-300 series airplanes, that currently requires inspections and test to detect broken or missing vespel bushes in the flap universal joint assemblies, and replacement of universal joint bushes, if necessary. This amendment adds a terminating modification for the currently required inspections and tests. This amendment is prompted by the development of a modification that will improve the integrity of the flap universal joints. The actions specified by this AD are intended to prevent rupture of the flap universal joints, subsequent partial loss of lift in one wing, and reduced controllability of the airplane.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective March 4, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The incorporation by reference of Airbus Industrie Service Bulletin A310-27-2059, dated March 1, 1993, as listed in the regulations, is approved by the Director of the Federal Register as of March 4, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The incorporation by reference of Airbus Industrie Service Bulletin A310-27-2054, Revisions 2, dated November 9, 1990, as listed in the regulations, was approved previously by the Director of the Federal Register as of September 11, 1991 (56 FR 37462, August 7, 1991).</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The service information referenced in this AD may be obtained from Airbus Industrie, 1 Rond Point Maurice Bellonte, 31707 Blagnac Cedex, France. This information may be examined at the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), Transport Airplane Directorate, Rules Docket, 1601 Lind Avenue SW., Renton, Washington; or at the Office of the Federal Register, 800 North Capitol Street NW., suite 700, Washington, DC.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Stephen Slotte, Aerospace Engineer, Standardization Branch, ANM-113, FAA, Transport Airplane Directorate, 1601 Lind Avenue SW., Renton, Washington 98055-4056; telephone (206) 227-2797; fax (206) 227-1320.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>A proposal to amend part 39 of the Federal Aviation Regulations by superseding AD 91-16-05, Amendment 39-7095 (56 FR 37462, August 7, 1991), which is applicable to all Airbus Industrie Model A310-200 and A310-300 series airplanes, was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on October 6, 1993 (58 FR 52041). The action proposed to add a requirement to modify the flap universal joint assemblies. Installation of this modification would terminate the currently required inspections and tests to detect broken or missing vespel bushes in the flap universal joint assemblies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons have been afforded an opportunity to participate in the making of this amendment. Due consideration has been given to the two comments received.</textblock>
    <textblock>Both commenters support the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>After careful review of the available data, including the comments noted above the FAA has determined that air safety and the public interest require the adoption of the rule as proposed.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA estimates that 25 airplanes of U.S. registry will be affected by this AD.</textblock>
    <textblock>The inspections and tests currently required by AD 91-16-05 take approximately 5 work hours to accomplish, at an average labor cost of $55 per work hour. Based on these figures, the total cost impact on U.S. operators of the actions previously required by AD 91-16-05 is estimated to be $6,875, or $275 per airplane, per inspection and testing cycle.</textblock>
    <textblock>It will take approximately 47 work hours per airplane to accomplish the modification required by this new AD action, at an average labor rate of $55 per work hour. Required parts will cost approximately $1,000 per airplane. Based on these figures, the total additional cost impact associated with the modification requirements of this AD on U.S. operators is estimated to be $89,625, or $3,585 per airplane.</textblock>
    <textblock>The cost figures discussed above are based on assumptions that no operator has yet accomplished the requirements of this AD action.</textblock>
    <textblock>The regulations adopted herein will not have substantial direct effects on the States, on the relationship between the national government and the States, or on the distribution of power and responsibilities among the various levels of government. Therefore, in accordance with Executive Order 12612, it is determined that this final rule does not have sufficient federalism implications to warrant the preparation of a Federalism Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons discussed above, I certify that this action (1) is not a ``significant regulatory action'' under Executive Order 12866; (2) is not a ``significant rule'' under DOT Regulatory Policies and Procedures (44 FR 11034, February 26, 1979); and (3) will not have a significant economic impact, positive or negative, on a substantial number of small entities under the criteria of the Regulatory Flexibility Act. A final evaluation has been prepared for this action and it is contained in the rules Docket. A copy of it may be obtained from the Rules Docket at the location provided under the caption</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
