<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00101</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 46 CFR Part 15</textblock>
    <textblock>Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Seamen, Vessels.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set out in the preamble, the Coast Guard amends part 15 of title 46 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 15_MANNING REQUIREMENTS</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 15 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>46 U.S.C. 2103, 3703, 8101, 8502, 8901, 8902, 8903, 8904, 9102; 50 U.S.C. 198, and 49 CFR 1.46.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 15.301 is amended by adding new definitions for ``Coastwise seagoing vessel'' and ``Designated areas'' to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§15.301</textblock>
    <textblock>Definition of terms used in this part.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Coastwise seagoing vessel</textblock>
    <textblock>means a vessel that is authorized by its Certificate of Inspection to proceed beyond the Boundary Line established in part 7 of this chapter.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Designated areas</textblock>
    <textblock>means those areas within the navigable waters of the United States for which first class pilotage endorsements are issued under part 10, subpart G, of this chapter, by the Officer in Charge, Marine Inspection (OCMI). The areas for which first class pilotage endorsements are issued within a particular Marine Inspection Zone and the specific requirements for an endorsement may be obtained from the OCMI concerned.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Section 15.812 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§15.812</textblock>
    <textblock>Pilots</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Except as specified in paragraph (f) of this section, the following vessels, not sailing on register, when underway on the navigable waters of the United States, must be under the direction and control of an individual qualified to serve as pilot under paragraph (b) or (c) of this section as appropriate:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Coastwise seagoing vessels propelled by machinery and subject to inspection under 46 U.S.C. chapter 33, and tank barges subject to inspection under 46 U.S.C. chapter 37;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Vessels that are not authorized by their Certificate of Inspection to proceed beyond the Boundary Line established in part 7 of this Chapter which are in excess of 1,600 gross tons, propelled by machinery, and subject to inspection under 46 U.S.C. chapter 33; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Vessels operating on the Great Lakes that are propelled by machinery and subject to inspection under 46 U.S.C. chapter 33, or are tank barges subject to inspection under 46 U.S.C. chapter 37.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The following individuals may serve as a pilot for a vessel subject to paragraph (a) of this section, when underway on the navigable waters of the United States that are designated areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) An individual holding a valid first class pilot's license issued by the Coast Guard, operating within the restrictions of his or her license, may serve as pilot on any vessel to which this section applies.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) An individual holding a valid license issued by the Coast Guard as master or mate, employed aboard a vessel within the restrictions of his or her license, may serve as pilot on a vessel of not more than 1,600 gross tons propelled by machinery, described in paragraphs (a)(1) and (a)(3) of this section, provided he or she:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Is at least 21 years old;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Complies with the currency of knowledge provisions of §10.713 of this chapter; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Has completed a minimum of four round trips over the route to be traversed while in the wheelhouse as watchstander or observer. At least one of the round trips must be made during the hours of darkness if the route is to be traversed during darkness.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) An individual holding a valid license issued by the Coast Guard as master, mate, or operator employed aboard a vessel within the restrictions of his or her license, may serve as pilot on a tank barge or tank barges totalling not more than 10,000 gross tons, described in paragraphs (a)(1) and (a)(3) of this section, provided he or she:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Is at least 21 years old;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Complies with the currency of knowledge provisions of §10.713 of this chapter;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Has a current physical examination in accordance with the provisions of §10.709 of this chapter;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Has at least six months service in the deck department on towing vessels engaged in towing operations; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) Has completed a minimum of twelve round trips over the route to be traversed, as an observer or under instruction in the wheelhouse. At least three of the round trips must be made during the hours of darkness if the route is to be traversed during darkness.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) An individual holding a valid license issued by the Coast Guard as master, mate, or operator, employed aboard a vessel within the restrictions of his or her license, may serve as a pilot for a vessel subject to paragraph (a)(1) and (a)(2) of this section, when underway on the navigable waters of the United States that are not designated as first class pilotage areas, provided he or she:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Is at least 21 years old;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Complies with the currency of knowledge provisions of §10.713 of this chapter; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Has a current physical examination in accordance with the provisions of §10.709 of this chapter.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) In any instance when the qualifications of a person satisfying the requirements for pilotage through the provisions of this Subpart are questioned by the Coast Guard, the individual shall, within a reasonable time, provide the Coast Guard with documentation proving compliance with the applicable portion(s) of paragraphs (b) and (c) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) Federal pilotage requirements contained in the above paragraphs are summarized in two quick reference tables.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Table 15.812(e)(1) provides a guide to the pilotage requirements for inspected, self-propelled vessels.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
