<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00036</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The California red-legged frog is the largest native frog in the</textblock>
    <textblock>western United States (Wright and Wright 1949), ranging from 4 to 13</textblock>
    <textblock>centimeters (1.5 to 5.1 inches) in length (Stebbins 1985). The abdomen</textblock>
    <textblock>and hind legs of adults are red; the back is characterized by small</textblock>
    <textblock>black flecks and larger irregular dark blotches with indistinct outlines</textblock>
    <textblock>on a brown, gray, olive, or reddish background color. Dorsal spots</textblock>
    <textblock>usually have light centers (Stebbins 1985). Dorsolateral folds are</textblock>
    <textblock>prominent on the back. Larvae range from 14 to 80 millimeters (mm) (0.6</textblock>
    <textblock>to 3.1 inches) in length, and the background color of the body is dark</textblock>
    <textblock>brown and yellow with darker spots (Storer 1925).</textblock>
    <textblock>Several morphological and behavioral characteristics differentiate</textblock>
    <textblock>California red-legged frogs from northern red-legged frogs. Adult</textblock>
    <textblock>California red-legged frogs are significantly larger than northern red-</textblock>
    <textblock>legged frogs by 35 to 40 mm (1.4 to 1.6 inches) (Hayes and Miyamoto</textblock>
    <textblock>1984). Dorsal spots of northern red-legged frogs usually lack light</textblock>
    <textblock>centers common to California red-legged frogs (Stebbins 1985), but this</textblock>
    <textblock>is not a strong diagnostic character. California red-legged frogs have</textblock>
    <textblock>paired vocal sacs and call in air (Hayes and Krempels 1986), whereas</textblock>
    <textblock>northern red-legged frogs lack vocal sacs (Hayes and Krempels 1986) and</textblock>
    <textblock>call underwater (Licht 1969). Female California red-legged frogs</textblock>
    <textblock>deposit egg masses on emergent vegetation so that the egg mass floats on</textblock>
    <textblock>the surface of the water (Hayes and Miyamoto 1984). Northern red-legged</textblock>
    <textblock>frogs also attach their egg masses to emergent vegetation, but the mass</textblock>
    <textblock>is submerged (Licht 1969). California red-legged frogs breed from</textblock>
    <textblock>November to March with earlier breeding records occurring in southern</textblock>
    <textblock>localities (Storer 1925). California red-legged frogs found in coastal</textblock>
    <textblock>drainages are rarely inactive (Jennings et al. 1992), whereas those</textblock>
    <textblock>found in interior sites may hibernate (Storer 1925).</textblock>
    <textblock>The California red-legged frog occupies a fairly distinct habitat,</textblock>
    <textblock>combining both specific aquatic and riparian components (Hayes and</textblock>
    <textblock>Jennings 1988, Jennings 1988b). The adults require a dense, shrubby or</textblock>
    <textblock>emergent riparian vegetation closely associated with deep (&gt;0.7 meters)</textblock>
    <textblock>still or slow moving water (Jennings et al. 1992). The largest</textblock>
    <textblock>densities of California red-legged frogs currently are associated with</textblock>
    <textblock>deep-water pools with dense stands of overhanging willows (</textblock>
    <textblock>Salix</textblock>
    <textblock>spp.)</textblock>
    <textblock>and an intermixed fringe of cattails (</textblock>
    <textblock>Typha latifolia</textblock>
    <textblock>) (Jennings 1988b).</textblock>
    <textblock>Well-vegetated terrestrial areas within the riparian corridor may</textblock>
    <textblock>provide important sheltering habitat during winter. California red-</textblock>
    <textblock>legged frogs estivate in small mammal burrows and moist leaf litter up</textblock>
    <textblock>to 26 meters (85 feet) from water in dense riparian vegetation (Rathbun</textblock>
    <textblock>et al. 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>Egg masses that contain about 2,000 to 5,000 moderate-sized (2.0</textblock>
    <textblock>to 2.8 mm (0.08 to 0.11 inches) in diameter), dark reddish brown eggs</textblock>
    <textblock>are typically attached to vertical emergent vegetation, such as</textblock>
    <textblock>bulrushes (</textblock>
    <textblock>Scirpus</textblock>
    <textblock>spp.) or cattails (</textblock>
    <textblock>Typha</textblock>
    <textblock>spp.) (Jennings et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1992). Eggs hatch in 6 to 14 days (Jennings 1988b). The most</textblock>
    <textblock>significant mortality factor in the pre-hatching stage is water salinity</textblock>
    <textblock>(Jennings et al. 1992). One hundred percent mortality occurs in eggs</textblock>
    <textblock>exposed to salinity levels greater than 4.5 parts per thousand (Jennings</textblock>
    <textblock>and Hayes 1990). Larvae undergo metamorphosis 3.5 to 7 months after</textblock>
    <textblock>hatching (Storer 1925, Wright and Wright 1949, Jennings and Hayes 1990).</textblock>
    <textblock>Of the various life stages, larvae probably experience the highest</textblock>
    <textblock>mortality rates, with less than 1 percent of eggs laid reaching</textblock>
    <textblock>metamorphosis (Jennings et al. 1992). Sexual maturity is reached at 3</textblock>
    <textblock>to 4 years of age (Storer 1925, Jennings and Hayes 1985). California</textblock>
    <textblock>red-legged frogs may live 8 to 10 years (Jennings et al. 1992).</textblock>
    <textblock>The diet of California red-legged frogs is highly variable. Hayes</textblock>
    <textblock>and Tennant (1985) found invertebrates to be the most common food items.</textblock>
    <textblock>Vertebrates, such as Pacific tree frogs (</textblock>
    <textblock>Hyla regilla</textblock>
    <textblock>) and California</textblock>
    <textblock>mice (</textblock>
    <textblock>Peromyscus californicus</textblock>
    <textblock>), represented over half of the prey mass</textblock>
    <textblock>eaten by larger frogs (Hayes and Tennant 1985). Hayes and Tennant</textblock>
    <textblock>(1985) found juvenile frogs to be active diurnally and nocturnally,</textblock>
    <textblock>whereas adult frogs were largely nocturnal. Feeding activity probably</textblock>
    <textblock>occurs along the shoreline and on the surface of the water (Hayes and</textblock>
    <textblock>Tennant 1985). Larvae probably eat algae (Jennings et al. 1992).</textblock>
    <textblock>California red-legged frogs have sustained a 75 percent reduction</textblock>
    <textblock>in their geographic range in California as a result of several factors</textblock>
    <textblock>acting singly or in combination (Jennings et al. 1992). Habitat loss</textblock>
    <textblock>and alteration, combined with overexploitation and introduction of</textblock>
    <textblock>exotic predators, were significant factors in the California red-legged</textblock>
    <textblock>frog decline in the early to mid 1900s. California red-legged frogs</textblock>
    <textblock>were extirpated from the Central Valley probably in the 1960s.</textblock>
    <textblock>Remaining aggregations of California red-legged frogs in the Sierran</textblock>
    <textblock>foothills became fragmented and were later eliminated by reservoir</textblock>
    <textblock>construction, continued expansion of exotic predators, grazing, and</textblock>
    <textblock>drought. The pattern of disappearance of California red-legged frogs in</textblock>
    <textblock>southern California is similar to that seen in the Central Valley,</textblock>
    <textblock>except that urbanization and its associated roadway, large reservoir</textblock>
    <textblock>(exotic predators), and stream channelization projects were the primary</textblock>
    <textblock>factors causing population declines.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
