<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00022</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Imposition of Accuracy-Related Penalty</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Internal Revenue Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>26 CFR Part 1</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[TD 8519]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1545-AS25</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Internal Revenue Service (IRS), Treasury.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Temporary regulations.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>These amendments to the regulations under 26 CFR part 1</textblock>
    <textblock>provide guidance on the imposition of the accuracy-related</textblock>
    <textblock>penalty under Internal Revenue Code sections 6662 (e) and (h) and section 6664(c) for transactions between persons described in Internal Revenue Code section 482 and net section 482 transfer price adjustments. This action is necessary because of changes to the applicable tax laws made by the Omnibus</textblock>
    <textblock>Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>These regulations are effective February 2, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>These regulations apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 1993.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Thomas L. Ralph at (202) 622-3880 (not a toll-free number).</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulation is being issued without prior notice and public procedure pursuant to the Administrative Procedure Act (5 U.S.C. 553). For this reason, the collection of information contained in this regulation has been reviewed and, pending receipt and evaluation of public comments, approved by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) under control number 1545-1365. The estimated annual burden per recordkeeper varies from 5 hours to 15 hours, depending on individual circumstances, with an estimated average of 10 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>These estimates are an approximation of the average time expected to be necessary for a collection of information. They are based on such information as is available to the Internal Revenue Service. Individual recordkeepers may require greater or less time, depending on their particular circumstances.</textblock>
    <textblock>For further information concerning this collection of information, and where to submit comments on this collection of information, the accuracy of the estimated burden, and suggestions for reducing this burden, please refer to the preamble in the cross-referencing notice of proposed rulemaking published in the Proposed Rules section of this issue of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 21, 1993, the IRS published a notice of proposed rulemaking in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(58 FR 5263) that proposed amendments to the Income Tax Regulations under sections 6662 (e) and (h) and section 6664(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (Code), as amended. Those proposed regulations implemented section 11312 of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990, Public Law 101-508, 104 Stat. 1388. Comments responding to the notice of proposed rulemaking were received and a public hearing was held on May 14, 1993. Section 13236 of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993 (Pub. L. 103-66, 107 Stat. 312) further amended sections 6662 (e) and (h) of the Code. After consideration of all comments received and pursuant to the statutory changes, the IRS has withdrawn the previous proposed regulations and adopts this Treasury decision.</textblock>
    <textblock>Explanation of Provisions</textblock>
    <textblock>The principal purpose of these regulations is to set forth rules implementing the imposition of accuracy-related penalties in the context of section 482. The exceptions from the penalty imposed under section 6662(e) in the case of certain net section 482 transfer pricing adjustments are a key component of these rules are. Reflecting the amendments to the statute pursuant to section 13236 of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993, the regulations provide a two-part exception from the imposition of the penalty with respect to such adjustments, depending on whether the taxpayer used a specified or unspecified method under the regulations under section 482. If the taxpayer used a specified method, the taxpayer must have reasonably concluded, based on the available data and the potentially applicable alternative specified methods, that its application of the selected method resulted in the most accurate measure of an arm's length result. Thus, if the taxpayer reasonably concluded that a different specified method would result in a more accurate measure of an arm's length result than the selected method, the taxpayer would not satisfy the requirements of this exception. If the taxpayer used an unspecified method, the taxpayer generally must have reasonably concluded, based on the available data, that none of the specified methods was likely to achieve an arm's length result and that the method used was likely to achieve such a result.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
