<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00124</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Franzreb, K.E. 1989. Ecology and conservation of the endangered</textblock>
    <textblock>least Bell's vireo. U.S. Fish and Wildl. Serv., Biol. Rep. 89(1). 17 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Gaines, D. 1974. A new look at the nesting riparian avifauna of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Sacramento Valley, California. Western Birds 5:61-79.</textblock>
    <textblock>Gaines, D. 1977. The status of selected riparian forest birds in</textblock>
    <textblock>California. Unpubl. rep. California Department of Fish and Game, Sacramento, California. 56 + viii pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Goldwasser, S. 1978. Distribution, reproductive success and</textblock>
    <textblock>impact of nest parasitism by brown-headed cowbirds on least Bell's vireos. California Department of Fish and Game, Nongame Wildlife Investigations, Job IV-1.5.1. 27 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Goldwasser, S., D. Gaines, and S. Wilbur. 1980. The least Bell's</textblock>
    <textblock>vireo in California: A de facto endangered race. American Birds 34:742-745.</textblock>
    <textblock>Gray, M.V., and J. Greaves. 1984. Riparian forest as habitat for</textblock>
    <textblock>the least Bell's vireo. Pages 605-611</textblock>
    <textblock>in</textblock>
    <textblock>R. Warner and K. Hendrix, eds. California riparian systems: Ecology, conservation and productive management. University of California Press, Davis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Grinnell, J., and A. Miller. 1944. The distribution of the birds</textblock>
    <textblock>of California. Pacific Coast Avifauna 27. 608 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Kus, B.E., and K.L. Miner. 1987. Foraging behavior of the least</textblock>
    <textblock>Bell's vireo: Use of riparian and non-riparian habitats. Unpubl. rep. San Diego State University, San Diego, California. 22 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Newhall Land and Farming Company. 1992. Public comments</textblock>
    <textblock>submitted to the Fish and Wildlife Service on November 5, 1992, regarding the revised proposed rule to designate critical habitat for the least Bell's vireo.</textblock>
    <textblock>RECON (Regional Environmental Consultants). 1989. Comprehensive</textblock>
    <textblock>species management plan for the least Bell's vireo (</textblock>
    <textblock>Vireo bellii pusillus</textblock>
    <textblock>). Unpubl. rep. prepared for the San Diego Association of Governments, San Diego, California. Salata, L. 1983. Status of the least Bell's vireo on Camp</textblock>
    <textblock>Pendleton, California. Unpubl. rep. U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Laguna Niguel, California. 62 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Salata, L. 1987. The status of the least Bell's vireo at Camp</textblock>
    <textblock>Pendleton, California in 1987. Unpubl. rep. U.S. Marine Corps, Camp Pendleton, California. 43 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service. 1992. Economic analysis of</textblock>
    <textblock>critical habitat designation for the least Bell's vireo. Unpubl. rep. on file at U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Carlsbad, California. 115 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Wilbur, S. 1980. Status report on least Bell's vireo. Unpubl.</textblock>
    <textblock>rep. U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Portland, Oregon. 46 pp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authors</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule was prepared by Service staff from the Carlsbad Field Office, 2730 Loker Avenue West, Carlsbad, California 92008 (telephone: 619/431-9440) and the Region 1 Regional Office, 911 NE 11th Avenue, Portland, Oregon 97232-4181 (telephone: 503/231-6131).</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 50 CFR Part 17</textblock>
    <textblock>Endangered and threatened species, Exports, Imports, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Transportation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulation Promulgation</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, part 17, subchapter B of chapter I, title 50 of the Code of Federal Regulations, is amended as set forth below:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 17_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 17 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 1361-1407; 16 U.S.C. 1531-1544; 16 U.S.C. 4201-4245; Pub. L. 99-625, 100 Stat. 3500; unless otherwise noted.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
