<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00045</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Act and implementing regulations found at 50 CFR 17.21 set</textblock>
    <textblock>forth a series of general prohibitions and exceptions that apply to all</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered wildlife. With respect to the California red-legged frog,</textblock>
    <textblock>these prohibitions, in part, make it illegal for any person subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>the jurisdiction of the United States to take (including harass, harm,</textblock>
    <textblock>pursue, hunt, shoot, wound, kill, trap, capture, collect, or attempt any</textblock>
    <textblock>such conduct), import or export, transport in interstate or foreign</textblock>
    <textblock>commerce in the course of commercial activity, or sell or offer for sale</textblock>
    <textblock>in interstate or foreign commerce any listed species. It also is</textblock>
    <textblock>illegal to possess, sell, deliver, carry, transport, or ship any such</textblock>
    <textblock>wildlife that has been taken illegally. Certain exceptions apply to</textblock>
    <textblock>agents of the Service and State conservation agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Permits may be issued to carry out otherwise prohibited activities</textblock>
    <textblock>involving endangered and threatened wildlife species under certain</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances. Regulations governing permits are at 50 CFR 17.22 and</textblock>
    <textblock>17.23. Such permits are available for scientific purposes, to enhance</textblock>
    <textblock>the propagation or survival of the species, and/or for incidental take</textblock>
    <textblock>in connection with otherwise lawful activities. Requests for</textblock>
    <textblock>information on permits should be addressed to the Assistant Regional</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, Ecological Services, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, 911 NE.</textblock>
    <textblock>11th Avenue, Portland, Oregon 97232-4181 (503/231-6241; FAX 503/231-6243).</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Comments Solicited</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service intends that any final action resulting from this</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal will be as accurate and as effective as possible. Therefore,</textblock>
    <textblock>comments or suggestions from the public, other concerned governmental</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies, the scientific community, industry, or any other interested</textblock>
    <textblock>party concerning this proposed rule are hereby solicited. Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>particularly are sought concerning:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Biological, commercial trade, or other relevant data</textblock>
    <textblock>concerning any threat (or lack thereof) to the California red-legged</textblock>
    <textblock>frog;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The location of any additional populations of the California</textblock>
    <textblock>red-legged frog and the reasons why any habitat should or should not be</textblock>
    <textblock>determined to be critical habitat as provided by section 4 of the Act;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Additional information concerning the range, distribution,</textblock>
    <textblock>and population size of the California red-legged frog;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Any examples of take or vandalism of California red-legged</textblock>
    <textblock>frogs; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Current or planned activities in the subject area and their</textblock>
    <textblock>possible impacts on the California red-legged frog.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any final decision on this proposal will take into consideration</textblock>
    <textblock>the comments and any additional information received by the Service, and</textblock>
    <textblock>such communications may lead to a final regulation that differs from</textblock>
    <textblock>this proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Endangered Species Act provides for a public hearing on this</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal, if requested. Requests must be received within 45 days of the</textblock>
    <textblock>date of publication of this proposal in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. Such</textblock>
    <textblock>requests must be made in writing and addressed to the Field Supervisor</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Sacramento Field Office (see</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>section).</textblock>
    <textblock>National Environmental Policy Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The Fish and Wildlife Service has determined that an Environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>Assessment, as defined under the authority of the National Environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>Policy Act of 1969, need not be prepared in connection with regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>adopted pursuant to section 4(a) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973,</textblock>
    <textblock>as amended. A notice outlining the Service's reasons for this</textblock>
    <textblock>determination was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on October 25, 1983</textblock>
    <textblock>(48 FR 49244).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
