<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00023</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>6. Entergy Services, Inc. and</textblock>
    <textblock>Gulf States Utilities Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket Nos. EC92-21-000 and ER92-806-004]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 30, 1993, Entergy Services, Inc. tendered for filing copies of its compliance filing in the above-referenced dockets. On January 3, 1994 and January 11, 1994, Entergy Services, Inc. tendered for filing revised copies of its December 30, 1993, compliance filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 4, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. New York State Electric &amp; Gas Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-191-000 Corp.]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 28, 1993, New York State Electric &amp; Gas Corporation (NYSEG) tendered for filing an amendment to its November 29, 1993 filing in the above-referenced docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 4, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard Paragraphs</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rules 211 and 214 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (18 CFR 385.211 and 18 CFR 385.214). All such motions or protests should be filed on or before the comment date. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2292 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
