<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00025</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 27, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission's (Commission's) regulations, 18 CFR part 380 (Order No. 486, 52 FR 47897), the Office of Hydropower Licensing has reviewed the application for major new license for the Prickett Project, located on the Sturgeon River, in Baraga and Houghton counties, Michigan and has prepared a Draft Environmental Assessment (draft EA) for the project. In the draft EA, the Commission's staff has analyzed the environmental impacts of the existing project and has concluded that approval of the project, with appropriate enhancement measures, would not constitute a major federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the draft EA are available for review in the Public Reference Branch, room 3104 of the Commission's offices at 941 North Capitol Street NE., Washington, DC 20426.</textblock>
    <textblock>Please submit any comments within 45 days from the date of this notice. Comments should be addressed to Lois D. Cashell, Secretary, Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 925 North Capitol Street NE., Washington, DC 20426. Please affix Project No. 2402 to all comments. For further information, please contact CarLisa Linton, Environmental Coordinator, at (202) 219-2802.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Project No. 2402-003 Michigan]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Upper Peninsula Power Co; Availability of Draft Environmental Assessment</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2310 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
