<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00121</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>CATEGORY II</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) If</textblock>
    <textblock>Legionella</textblock>
    <textblock>sp. is detected in one or more cultures, reassess the implemented control measures, modify them accordingly, and repeat decontamination procedures. Options for repeat decontamination include the intensive use of the same technique utilized for initial decontamination, or a combination of superheating and hyperchlorination.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY II</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) Keep adequate records of all infection control measures, including maintenance procedures, and of environmental test results for cooling towers and potable-water systems.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY II</textblock>
    <textblock>Prevention and Control of Nosocomial Pulmonary Aspergillosis</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Staff Education and Infection Surveillance</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Staff Education</textblock>
    <textblock>Educate healthcare workers regarding nosocomial pulmonary aspergillosis especially in immunocompromised patients, and about infection control procedures to decrease its</textblock>
    <textblock>occurrence.</textblock>
    <textblock>611-613</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Surveillance</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Maintain a high index of suspicion for diagnosis of nosocomial pulmonary aspergillosis in high-risk patients (i.e., patients with prolonged, severe granulocytopenia [&lt;1,000 polymorphonuclear cells/mm</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>for 2 weeks or &lt;100 polymorphonuclear cells/mm</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>for 1 week]), such as organ-transplant recipients or patients with hematologic malignancies who are receiving chemotherapy.</textblock>
    <textblock>435,462,463,659</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Maintain surveillance for cases of nosocomial pulmonary aspergillosis by periodically reviewing the hospital's microbiologic, histopathologic, and postmortem data.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>3. NO RECOMMENDATION for routine, periodic culturing of the nasopharynx of high-risk patients,</textblock>
    <textblock>437,438</textblock>
    <textblock>or devices, air samples, dust, ventilation ducts, and filters in rooms occupied by high-risk patients.</textblock>
    <textblock>418,428,437,471-473</textblock>
    <textblock>UNRESOLVED ISSUE</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Interruption of Transmission of Aspergillus SPP. Spores</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Planning New Specialized-Care Units for High-Risk Patients</textblock>
    <textblock>1. When constructing new specialized-care units for high-risk patients, ensure that patient rooms have adequate capacity to minimize fungal spore counts via maintenance of (a) high-efficiency air filtration, (b) directed room airflow, (c) positive air pressure in patient's room in relation to the corridor, (d) properly sealed room, and (e) high rates of room-air changes.</textblock>
    <textblock>424,479-481,484,488,660,661</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Air Filtration</textblock>
    <textblock>Install high efficiency particulate air (HEPA) filters that are 99.97% efficient in filtering 0.3</textblock>
    <textblock>u</textblock>
    <textblock>-sized particles, at the point of use, i.e. at the room-air intake site.</textblock>
    <textblock>424,479-481,484,488,660,661</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Directed Room Airflow</textblock>
    <textblock>Place air-intake and exhaust ports such that room air comes in from one side of the room, flows across the patient's bed, and exits on the opposite side of the room. In addition, place intake and exhaust ports such that healthcare personnel entering the room to care for the patient would stand between the patient and the exhaust port.</textblock>
    <textblock>480,481</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Well-Sealed Room</textblock>
    <textblock>Construct windows, doors, and intake and exhaust ports to achieve complete sealing of the room against air leaks.</textblock>
    <textblock>480,481</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Room-Air Pressure</textblock>
    <textblock>Ensure that room-air pressure can be maintained continuously above that of corridor, e.g., as can be demonstrated by performance of the smoke-tube test, unless there are clinical-care or infection-control contraindications to do so.</textblock>
    <textblock>480,481</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) To maintain positive room-air pressure in relation to the corridor, supply room air at a rate that is 10-20% more than the rate of exhausting air from the room.</textblock>
    <textblock>480,481</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Construct rooms that have an anteroom with an independent exhaust for placement of patients at high risk of aspergillosis who also have an infection (e.g., varicella or infectious tuberculosis) requiring negative room-air pressure in relation to the corridor.</textblock>
    <textblock>480</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>e. Room-Air Changes</textblock>
    <textblock>Maintain room-air changes at "15 per hour.</textblock>
    <textblock>480,486,487</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY II</textblock>
    <textblock>2. NO RECOMMENDATION for the preferential installation of a particular system, such as one with ultra-high (100-400 per hour) air change rates, e.g., laminar airflow, over other systems that meet the conditions in II-A-1-a through II-A-1-e above.</textblock>
    <textblock>424,479-481,484,488,660,661</textblock>
    <textblock>UNRESOLVED ISSUE</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Formulate hospital policies to minimize exposures of high-risk patients to potential sources of</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus</textblock>
    <textblock>spp., such as hospital construction and renovation, cleaning activities, carpets, food, potted plants, and flower arrangements.</textblock>
    <textblock>418,437,662-664</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>4. NO RECOMMENDATION for prophylactic use of copper-8-quinolinolate biocide in fireproofing material.</textblock>
    <textblock>418,427,481,488</textblock>
    <textblock>UNRESOLVED ISSUE</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
