<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00037</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>At present, California red-legged frogs are known to occur in</textblock>
    <textblock>about 190 streams or drainages from 15 counties in central and southern</textblock>
    <textblock>California. Monterey, San Luis Obispo and Santa Barbara Counties</textblock>
    <textblock>support the greatest amount of currently occupied habitat. The most</textblock>
    <textblock>secure aggregations of California red-legged frogs are found in aquatic</textblock>
    <textblock>sites that support substantial riparian and aquatic vegetation and lack</textblock>
    <textblock>exotic predators (e.g., bullfrogs, mosquitofish, largemouth and</textblock>
    <textblock>smallmouth bass). The majority of aggregations are threatened, however,</textblock>
    <textblock>by expansion of exotic predators, proposed residential development,</textblock>
    <textblock>water storage projects, and other factors. For example, within the</textblock>
    <textblock>Central Valley hydrographic basin, only six drainages, all on the Coast</textblock>
    <textblock>range slope of the San Joaquin Valley, are known or likely to support</textblock>
    <textblock>California red-legged frogs, compared to over 60 historic locality</textblock>
    <textblock>records for this basin. Two of these drainages, known to support</textblock>
    <textblock>significant numbers of California red-legged frogs, are sites of</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed large reservoir projects. Also, in southern California,</textblock>
    <textblock>California red-legged frogs are known from only 4 locations south of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Tehachapi Mountains, compared to over 80 historic locality records for</textblock>
    <textblock>this region. Only three areas currently support more than 350 adults.</textblock>
    <textblock>Previous Federal Action</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 29, 1992, the Service received a petition from Drs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Mark R. Jennings, Marc P. Hayes, and Dan C. Holland to list the</textblock>
    <textblock>California red-legged frog (</textblock>
    <textblock>Rana aurora draytonii</textblock>
    <textblock>). The petition</textblock>
    <textblock>specified endangered or threatened status by distinct drainages</textblock>
    <textblock>(watersheds) within the range of the species. On October 5, 1992, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Service published a 90-day petition finding (57 FR 45761) that</textblock>
    <textblock>substantial information had been presented indicating the requested</textblock>
    <textblock>action may be warranted. Public comments were requested on the status</textblock>
    <textblock>of this species. The California red-legged frog had been included as a</textblock>
    <textblock>Category 1 candidate species in the Service's November 21, 1991, Animal</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Review (56 FR 58804). Category 1 candidates are species for</textblock>
    <textblock>which the Service has substantial information on biological</textblock>
    <textblock>vulnerability and threat to support proposals to list them as endangered</textblock>
    <textblock>or threatened. On July 19, 1993, the Service published a 12-month</textblock>
    <textblock>finding on the petitioned action (58 FR 38553). This finding indicated</textblock>
    <textblock>that listing of the California red-legged frog was warranted and that a</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed rule would be published promptly.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
