<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00074</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00055</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>4. Paragraphs a. and b. under Section 8 (Responsibilities) are being revised in their entirety to incorporate the new ``best practices'' approach to managing and administering service contracts.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Paragraph d. under section 8, which pertains to the Inspectors General, is being revised to ensure that any reviews are simply to ensure that agencies are in compliance with the revised Policy Letter.</textblock>
    <textblock>The guidance in section 7 which refers to the questions in the appendix A, and any resulting ``best practices'' models developed by OFPP in contract administration should not be viewed as mandatory regulatory guidance for audit purposes. We believe that agencies should use the questions as warning signals to prevent problems from occurring and the ``best practices'' models to help resolve those problems.</textblock>
    <textblock>All other provisions of the policy Letter remain unchanged.</textblock>
  </text>
  <date>
    <textblock>COMMENT DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before March 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be sent to Dr. Steven Kelman, Administrator, Office of Federal Procurement Policy, Office of Management and Budget, Old Executive Office Building, room 352, Washington, DC 20503.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Linda G. Williams, Deputy Associate Administrator, 202-395-3302.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects</textblock>
    <textblock>Government Procurement.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Steven Kelman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
