<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00116</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>b. NO RECOMMENDATION for the maximum length of time after which the breathing circuit and the attached bubbling or wick humidifier of a ventilator in use on a patient should be changed.</textblock>
    <textblock>263</textblock>
    <textblock>UNRESOLVED ISSUE</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Sterilize reusable breathing circuits and bubbling or wick humidifiers, or subject them to high-level disinfection between their uses on different patients.</textblock>
    <textblock>240,242,244,246</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>d. Periodically drain and discard any condensate that collects in the tubing of a mechanical ventilator or anesthesia machine, taking precautions not to allow condensate to drain toward the patient. Wash hands after performing the procedure or handling the fluid.</textblock>
    <textblock>256,260</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>e. NO RECOMMENDATION for placing a filter or trap at the distal end of the expiratory-phase tubing of the breathing circuit to collect condensate.</textblock>
    <textblock>231,256</textblock>
    <textblock>UNRESOLVED ISSUE</textblock>
    <textblock>f. Do not place bacterial filters between the humidifier reservoir and the inspiratory-phase tubing of the breathing circuit of a mechanical ventilator, or in the circuit of an anesthesia machine.</textblock>
    <textblock>254,627,630</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>g. Humidifier fluids.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Use sterile water to fill bubbling humidifiers.125,233,234,260</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY II</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Use sterile, distilled, or tap water to fill wick humidifiers.</textblock>
    <textblock>233,234,260</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY II</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) NO RECOMMENDATION for preferential use of a closed, continuous-feed humidification system.</textblock>
    <textblock>UNRESOLVED ISSUE</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Ventilator Circuits With Hygroscopic Condenser-Humidifiers or Heat-Moisture Exchangers</textblock>
    <textblock>a. NO RECOMMENDATION for preferential use of hygroscopic condenser-humidifier or heat-moisture exchanger rather than a heated humidifier to prevent nosocomial pneumonia.</textblock>
    <textblock>272-276</textblock>
    <textblock>UNRESOLVED ISSUE</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Change the hygroscopic condenser-humidifier or heat-moisture exchanger when evidence of gross contamination or mechanical dysfunction of the device is present.</textblock>
    <textblock>272</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Do not routinely change the breathing circuit attached to a hygroscopic condenser-humidifier or heat-moisture exchanger while it is in use on a patient.</textblock>
    <textblock>272,275</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Wall Humidifiers</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Follow manufacturers' instructions for use and maintenance of disposable wall oxygen humidifiers unless data show that the modification in their use or maintenance poses no threat to the patient and is cost effective.</textblock>
    <textblock>631-635</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Between patients, change the reservoir, tubing (including any nasal prongs), and any mask used to deliver oxygen from a wall outlet.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Small-Volume Medication Nebulizers: ``In-Line'' and Hand-Held Nebulizers</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Between treatments on the same patient, disinfect or rinse with sterile water and air-dry small-volume medication nebulizers.</textblock>
    <textblock>228,378</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Replace nebulizers between patients with those that have undergone sterilization or high-level disinfection.</textblock>
    <textblock>119,121,122,248</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Use only sterile fluids for nebulization, and dispense these fluids aseptically.</textblock>
    <textblock>223,227,233,234,248,278,378</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
    <textblock>d. If multi-dose medication vials are used, handle, dispense, and store them according to directions on the vial label or package insert.</textblock>
    <textblock>278,636,637</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Large-Volume Nebulizers and Mist Tents</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Do not use large-volume room-air humidifiers that create aerosols (e.g., by venturi principle, ultrasound, or spinning disk) and thus are really nebulizers, unless they can be sterilized or subjected to high level disinfection at least daily and filled only with sterile water.</textblock>
    <textblock>224,225,227,236,277,638</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Sterilize large-volume nebulizers that are used for inhalation therapy, e.g., for tracheostomized patients, or subject them to high-level disinfection between patients and after every 24 hours of use on the same patient.</textblock>
    <textblock>119,121,122</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Use mist-tent nebulizers and reservoirs that have undergone sterilization or high-level disinfection, and replace them between patients and after every 24 hours of use on the same patient.639</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Other Devices</textblock>
    <textblock>a. Between patients, sterilize or use high-level disinfection on respirometers, oxygen sensors, and other respiratory devices used on multiple patients.</textblock>
    <textblock>220,286</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>b. Sterilize or use high-level disinfection on hand-powered resuscitation bags (for example, Ambu bags) between patients.</textblock>
    <textblock>239,283-285</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IA</textblock>
    <textblock>c. Remove faucet aerators.640</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY II</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Interruption of Person-to-Person Transmission of Bacteria</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Handwashing</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
