<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00038</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Summary of Factors Affecting the Species</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 4 of the Endangered Species Act (16 U.S.C. 1531</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>)</textblock>
    <textblock>and regulations (50 CFR part 424) promulgated to implement the listing</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions of the Act set forth the procedures for adding species to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Lists. A species may be determined to be an endangered or</textblock>
    <textblock>threatened species due to one or more of the five factors described in</textblock>
    <textblock>section 4(a)(1). These factors and their application to the California</textblock>
    <textblock>red-legged frog (</textblock>
    <textblock>Rana aurora draytonii</textblock>
    <textblock>) are as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>A.</textblock>
    <textblock>The present or threatened destruction, modification, or</textblock>
    <textblock>curtailment of its habitat or range.</textblock>
    <textblock>Herpetologists have noted the</textblock>
    <textblock>decline or extirpation of California red-legged frogs from the San</textblock>
    <textblock>Francisco Bay area (Sean J. Barry, University of California, Davis,</textblock>
    <textblock>in</textblock>
    <textblock>litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1992; Robert C. Stebbins, University of California, Berkeley,</textblock>
    <textblock>in</textblock>
    <textblock>litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993; John S. Applegarth, herpetologist,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993; Ed Ely,</textblock>
    <textblock>herpetologist,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993), the Salinas River drainage (Lawrence E.</textblock>
    <textblock>Hunt, University of California, Santa Barbara,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993), the San</textblock>
    <textblock>Luis Obispo, Santa Barbara, and Ventura County area (Aryan I. Roest,</textblock>
    <textblock>California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993; Samuel S. Sweet, University of California, Santa Barbara,</textblock>
    <textblock>in</textblock>
    <textblock>litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993), southern California (Patrick McMonagle, herpetologist,</textblock>
    <textblock>in</textblock>
    <textblock>litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993; John D. Goodman, zoologist,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1992; Robert B.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sanders, San Bernardino County Museum,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1992; John Stephenson,</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Forest Service,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993; Michael C. Long, Eaton Canyon Park</textblock>
    <textblock>Nature Center,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1992; Joseph F. Copp, herpetologist,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993; Glenn R. Stewart, California Polytechnic University, Pomona,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993; Walter B. Allen, herpetologist,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993; Robert</textblock>
    <textblock>Fisher, University of California, Davis,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993), central</textblock>
    <textblock>California (Martin R. Brittan, California State University, Sacramento,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993), and the northern and southern Sierra Nevada foothills</textblock>
    <textblock>(Jay Wright, Feather River College, Quincy,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993; Alan M.</textblock>
    <textblock>McCready, California State University, Sacramento,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1992).</textblock>
    <textblock>These observations and data provided by the petitioners indicate</textblock>
    <textblock>that the California red-legged frog has sustained a 75 percent reduction</textblock>
    <textblock>in its geographic range in California. Large aggregations of greater</textblock>
    <textblock>than 350 adults currently are known from only three areas: Pescadero</textblock>
    <textblock>Marsh Natural Preserve in coastal San Mateo County, Point Reyes National</textblock>
    <textblock>Seashore in Marin County, and canals west of San Francisco International</textblock>
    <textblock>Airport in the San Francisco Bay area (Jennings et al. 1992).</textblock>
    <textblock>Habitat loss and alteration are primary factors that have</textblock>
    <textblock>negatively affected the California red-legged frog throughout its range.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the Central Valley of California, over 90 percent of historic</textblock>
    <textblock>wetlands have been diked, drained, or filled primarily for agricultural</textblock>
    <textblock>development and secondarily for urban development (U.S. Fish and</textblock>
    <textblock>Wildlife Service 1978). Much of the wetland habitat lost, such as in</textblock>
    <textblock>the San Joaquin Valley, was prime habitat for the California red-legged</textblock>
    <textblock>frog (Jennings and Hayes 1984). Wetland alterations, including stream</textblock>
    <textblock>channelization, clearing of vegetation, and water diversions that often</textblock>
    <textblock>accompanied agricultural development, rendered remaining aquatic sites</textblock>
    <textblock>unsuitable for California red-legged frogs. As a result, California</textblock>
    <textblock>red-legged frogs on the floor of the Central Valley were eliminated</textblock>
    <textblock>probably sometime before 1960 (Jennings et al. 1992). Remaining</textblock>
    <textblock>aggregations in drainages around the Central Valley became isolated and</textblock>
    <textblock>fragmented.</textblock>
    <textblock>Historically, urbanization with its associated roadway, stream</textblock>
    <textblock>channelization, and large reservoir construction projects also has</textblock>
    <textblock>significantly altered or eliminated California red-legged frog habitat,</textblock>
    <textblock>with the greatest impact occurring in southern California. South of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Tehachapi Mountains in southern California, the California red-legged</textblock>
    <textblock>frog remains at only 4 of over 80 sites where it was found historically</textblock>
    <textblock>(Jennings et al. 1992). No California red-legged frogs were found</textblock>
    <textblock>during amphibian surveys in 1993 in Cleveland National Forest in</textblock>
    <textblock>southern California (J. Stephenson, pers. comm., 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>Urbanization poses a significant threat to the California red-</textblock>
    <textblock>legged frog. On the central California coast and south San Francisco</textblock>
    <textblock>Bay area, the Service is aware of numerous proposed residential</textblock>
    <textblock>developments that would degrade known California red-legged frog habitat</textblock>
    <textblock>either directly through on-site degradation of the stream environment or</textblock>
    <textblock>indirectly through instream flow reductions to accommodate new urban</textblock>
    <textblock>growth (U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service unpubl. data). These projects</textblock>
    <textblock>include the East County Area Plan in Alameda County, which involves</textblock>
    <textblock>development of up to 52,000 acres, and projects currently proposed in</textblock>
    <textblock>the Ruby Hills/Arroyo Del Valle watershed and south Livermore Valley;</textblock>
    <textblock>Reservoir Canyon ponds in Santa Clara County; Alamo, Shadow, and</textblock>
    <textblock>Brookside Creeks in Contra Costa County; Potrero, San Clemente, and San</textblock>
    <textblock>Jose Creeks and the Carmel River in Monterey County; and the Santa Ynez</textblock>
    <textblock>River in Santa Barbara County. In San Luis Obispo County, one of three</textblock>
    <textblock>counties with numerous drainages supporting California red-legged frogs,</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed residential and/or recreational development adjacent to San</textblock>
    <textblock>Simeon, Santa Rosa, San Juan, Chorro, and Cambria Meadows Creeks and</textblock>
    <textblock>Estrella and Salinas Rivers would degrade or eliminate California red-</textblock>
    <textblock>legged frog habitat. Updates to area plans for the North Coast, San</textblock>
    <textblock>Luis Obispo, and Paso Robles/Atascadero areas in San Luis Obispo County</textblock>
    <textblock>propose rezoning of over 240,000 acres primarily for urban development.</textblock>
    <textblock>Between the cities of Ventura and San Luis Obispo, development already</textblock>
    <textblock>has eliminated California red-legged frogs from at least eight drainages</textblock>
    <textblock>along the coast (Galen B. Rathbun and Mark R. Jennings, U.S. Fish and</textblock>
    <textblock>Wildlife Service,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
