<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00002</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Financial Security of National Forest System Timber Sale Contracts</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Forest Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 0596-AA33</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Forest Service, USDA.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice; adoption of final policy.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Forest Service is adopting final policy and procedure related to timber sale contract financial security. The final policy will increase the amount of the bid guarantee, revise the method for determining damages for failure to consummate a contract, eliminate the performance bond ceiling, and limit the applicability of the sale discounting procedures. The intent of the final policy is to better protect the public's interest in the sale of National Forest System timber by reducing the opportunity for speculative bidding and defaulting contract obligations. This policy is being issued to guide Forest Service personnel as Amendment No. 2400-93-</textblock>
    <textblock>XX</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Forest Service Manual (FSM) chapter 2430, Amendment No. 2400-93-</textblock>
    <textblock>XX</textblock>
    <textblock>to FSM chapter 2450 and Amendment No. 2409.18-93-</textblock>
    <textblock>XX</textblock>
    <textblock>to chapter 50 of FSH 2409.18, the Timber Sale Preparation Handbook.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>These amendments are effective February 2, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Questions about this policy should be addressed to Fred Walk, Timber Management Staff, Forest Service, USDA, P.O. 96090, Washington, DC 20090-6090, (202) 205-0858.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>After the timber market collapse of 1981, an unprecedent number of National Forest System timber sale contracts became unprofitable. Some contracts were defaulted and others were ``bought out'' by the Government under the Federal Timber Contract Payment Modification Act. The market decline during the 1980 period exposed a number of potential long-term difficulties with National Forest System timber sale procedures which, if not remedied, could result in speculative bidding and increase the potential for contract defaults in the future.</textblock>
    <textblock>In 1982, the Forest Service began implementing a number of contract reforms to reduce speculative and unsound bidding, to provide for an even flow of timber receipts into the Treasury, and to prevent sale defaults. The following changes or additions to financial requirements on National Forest System sales were made:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The timber sale bid guarantee was raised to 5 percent of the advertised value of contract;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A cash deposit was required. The initial deposit requirement was for 5 percent of the bid value of a sale; this was later increased to 10 percent;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The maximum amount of the performance bond was changed from $200,000 to $500,000; and</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
