<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00034</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(ii) The taxpayer has gross receipts of 75 million dollars after all section 482 adjustments. None of the adjustments is excluded under paragraph (d) (Amounts excluded from net section 482 adjustments) of this section, in determining the five million dollar or 10% of gross receipts test under section 6662(e)(1)(B)(ii). The net section 482 adjustment (4.5 million dollars) is less than the lesser of five million dollars or ten percent of gross receipts ($75 million × 10% = $7.5 million). Thus, there is no substantial valuation misstatement. However, the two million dollar adjustment is attributable to a gross valuation misstatement. Accordingly, the taxpayer may be subject to a penalty, under section 6662(h), equal to 40 percent of the underpayment of tax attributable to the gross valuation misstatement of two million dollars. The 2.5 million dollar adjustment is not subject to a penalty under section 6662(b)(3).</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 2.</textblock>
    <textblock>The facts are the same as in</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 1,</textblock>
    <textblock>except</textblock>
    <textblock>the taxpayer has gross receipts of 40 million dollars. The net</textblock>
    <textblock>section 482 adjustment ($4.5 million) is greater than the lesser</textblock>
    <textblock>of five million dollars or ten percent of gross receipts ($40</textblock>
    <textblock>million × 10% = $4 million). Thus, the five million dollar or</textblock>
    <textblock>10% of gross receipts test has been met. The two million dollar</textblock>
    <textblock>adjustment is attributable to a gross valuation misstatement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, the taxpayer is subject to a penalty, under section</textblock>
    <textblock>6662(h), equal to 40 percent of the underpayment of tax</textblock>
    <textblock>attributable to the gross valuation misstatement of two million</textblock>
    <textblock>dollars. The 2.5 million dollar adjustment is subject to a</textblock>
    <textblock>penalty under sections 6662(a) and 6662(b)(3), equal to 20</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of the underpayment of tax attributable to the</textblock>
    <textblock>substantial valuation misstatement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example</textblock>
    <textblock>3. (i) Applying section 482, the Internal Revenue</textblock>
    <textblock>Service makes the following transfer pricing adjustments for the</textblock>
    <textblock>taxable year:</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) None of the adjustments are excluded under paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) (Amounts excluded from net section 482 adjustments) in</textblock>
    <textblock>determining the twenty million dollar or 20% of gross receipts</textblock>
    <textblock>test under section 6662(h). The net section 482 adjustment (21</textblock>
    <textblock>million dollars) is greater than twenty million dollars and thus</textblock>
    <textblock>constitutes a gross valuation misstatement. Accordingly, the</textblock>
    <textblock>total adjustment is subject to the net adjustment penalty equal</textblock>
    <textblock>to 40 percent of the underpayment of tax attributable to the 21</textblock>
    <textblock>million dollar gross valuation misstatement. The six million</textblock>
    <textblock>dollar adjustment will not be separately included for purposes of</textblock>
    <textblock>any additional penalty under section 6662.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective date.</textblock>
    <textblock>This section applies to taxable years</textblock>
    <textblock>beginning after December 31, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Par. 5.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1.6664-O is amended by adding an entry for §1.6664-4T to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§1.6664-O</textblock>
    <textblock>Table of contents.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>§1.6664-4T Reasonable cause and good faith exception to section</textblock>
    <textblock>6662 penalties</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) through (c)␣[Reserved]</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Transactions between persons described in section 482 and net</textblock>
    <textblock>section 482 transfer price adjustments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Par. 6.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1.6664-4T is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§1.6664-4T</textblock>
    <textblock>Reasonable cause and good faith exception to section</textblock>
    <textblock>6662 penalties.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) through (c)␣[Reserved]</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Transactions between persons described in section 482</textblock>
    <textblock>and net section 482 transfer price adjustments.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of</textblock>
    <textblock>applying the reasonable cause and good faith exception of section</textblock>
    <textblock>6664(c) to net section 482 adjustments, the rules of §1.6662-6T(d) of the regulations apply. A taxpayer that does not satisfy</textblock>
    <textblock>the rules of §1.6662-T(d) for a net section 482 adjustment</textblock>
    <textblock>cannot satisfy the reasonable cause and good faith exception</textblock>
    <textblock>under section 6664(c). The rules of this section apply to</textblock>
    <textblock>underpayments subject to the transactional penalty in §1.6662-6T(b). If the standards of the net section 482 penalty exclusion</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions under §1.6662-6T(d) are met with respect to such</textblock>
    <textblock>underpayments, then the taxpayer will be considered to have acted</textblock>
    <textblock>with reasonable cause and good faith for purposes of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Par. 7.</textblock>
    <textblock>The authority citation for part 602 continues to</textblock>
    <textblock>read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>26 U.S.C. 7805.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Attributable to an adjustment that is 400 percent or more of the correct section 482 arm's length result</textblock>
    <textblock>$2,000,000</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Not a 200 or 400 percent adjustment</textblock>
    <textblock>2,500,000</textblock>
    <textblock>n,s</textblock>
    <textblock>Total</textblock>
    <textblock>4,500,000</textblock>
  </table>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Attributable to an adjustment that is</textblock>
    <textblock>400 percent or more of the correct section 482 arm's length result</textblock>
    <textblock>$6,000,000</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Not a 200 or 400 percent adjustment</textblock>
    <textblock>15,000,000</textblock>
    <textblock>n,s</textblock>
    <textblock>Total</textblock>
    <textblock>21,000,000</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
