<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00049</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Determinations</textblock>
    <textblock>On the basis of the record§</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>developed in the subject investigations, the Commission determines,</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to section 735(b) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (19 U.S.C. 1673d(b)) (the Act), that an industry in the United States is materially injured by reason of imports from Brazil and France of stainless steel wire rod, provided for in subheading 7221.00.00 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, that have been found by the Department of Commerce to be sold in the United States at less than fair value (LTFV).</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission instituted these investigations effective August 2, 1993, following preliminary determinations by the Department of Commerce that imports of stainless steel wire rod from Brazil and France were being sold at LTFV within the meaning of section 733(b) of the Act (19 U.S.C. 1673b(b)). Notice of the institution of the Commission's investigations and of a public hearing to be held in connection therewith was given by posting copies of the notice in the Office of the Secretary, U.S. International Trade Commission, Washington, DC, and by publishing the notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of August 18, 1993 (58 FR 43908). The hearing was held in Washington, DC, on October 14, 1993, and all persons who requested the opportunity were permitted to appear in person or by counsel.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission transmitted its determinations in these investigations to the Secretary of Commerce on January 21, 1994. The views of the Commission are contained in USITC Publication 2721 (January 1994), entitled ``Stainless Steel Wire Rod from Brazil and France: Investigations Nos. 636 and 637 (Final).''</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued: January 24, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By order of the Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Investigations Nos. 731-TA-636 and 637 (Final)]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Stainless Steel Wire Rod From Brazil and France</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The record is defined in §207.2(f) of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (19 CFR 207.2(f)).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Commissioner Brunsdale dissenting.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna R. Koehnke,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2338 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7020-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
