<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00074</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Modified debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>. In the case of a debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument issued in a debt-for-debt exchange that qualifies as</textblock>
    <textblock>an exchange under section 1001, the debt instrument is eligible</textblock>
    <textblock>for the election to be a cash method debt instrument if the other</textblock>
    <textblock>prerequisites to making the election in section 1274A(c) are met.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, if a principal purpose of the modification is to defer</textblock>
    <textblock>interest income or deductions through the use of the election,</textblock>
    <textblock>then the debt instrument is not eligible for the election.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>Debt incurred or continued to purchase or carry a cash</textblock>
    <textblock>method debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>. If a debt instrument is incurred or</textblock>
    <textblock>continued to purchase or carry a cash method debt instrument,</textblock>
    <textblock>rules similar to those under section 1277 apply to determine the</textblock>
    <textblock>timing of the interest deductions for the debt instrument. For</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of the preceding sentence, rules similar to those under</textblock>
    <textblock>section 265(a)(2) apply to determine whether a debt instrument is</textblock>
    <textblock>incurred or continued to purchase or carry a cash method debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument.</textblock>
    <textblock>§1.1275-1</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicability</textblock>
    <textblock>. The definitions contained in this</textblock>
    <textblock>section apply for purposes of sections 163(e) and 1271 through</textblock>
    <textblock>1275 and the regulations thereunder.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Adjusted issue price</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>In general</textblock>
    <textblock>. The adjusted</textblock>
    <textblock>issue price of a debt instrument at the beginning of the first</textblock>
    <textblock>accrual period is the issue price. Thereafter, the adjusted</textblock>
    <textblock>issue price of the debt instrument is the issue price of the debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Increased by the amount of OID previously includible in</textblock>
    <textblock>the gross income of any holder (determined without regard to</textblock>
    <textblock>section 1272(a)(7) and section 1272(c)(1)); and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Decreased by the amount of any payment previously made</textblock>
    <textblock>on the debt instrument other than a payment of qualified stated</textblock>
    <textblock>interest. See §1.1275-2(f) for rules regarding adjustments to</textblock>
    <textblock>adjusted issue price on a pro rata prepayment.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Adjusted issue price for subsequent holders</textblock>
    <textblock>. For</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of calculating OID accruals, acquisition premium, or</textblock>
    <textblock>market discount, a holder (other than a purchaser at original</textblock>
    <textblock>issuance) determines adjusted issue price in any manner</textblock>
    <textblock>consistent with the regulations under sections 1271 through 1275.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>OID</textblock>
    <textblock>. OID means original issue discount (as defined in</textblock>
    <textblock>section 1273(a) and §1.1273-1).</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>. Except as provided in section</textblock>
    <textblock>1275(a)(1)(B) (relating to certain annuity contracts), debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument means any instrument or contractual arrangement that</textblock>
    <textblock>constitutes indebtedness under general principles of Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>income tax law (including, for example, a certificate of deposit</textblock>
    <textblock>or a loan). Nothing in the regulations under sections 163(e),</textblock>
    <textblock>483, and 1271 through 1275, however, shall influence whether an</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument constitutes indebtedness for Federal income tax</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Tax-exempt obligations</textblock>
    <textblock>. For purposes of section</textblock>
    <textblock>1275(a)(3)(B), exempt from tax means exempt from Federal income</textblock>
    <textblock>tax.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue</textblock>
    <textblock>. Two or more debt instruments are part of the</textblock>
    <textblock>same issue if they have the same credit and payment terms and are</textblock>
    <textblock>sold reasonably close in time either pursuant to a common plan or</textblock>
    <textblock>as part of a single transaction or a series of related</textblock>
    <textblock>transactions. See §1.1275-2(d)(2) for special rules relating to</textblock>
    <textblock>reopenings of Treasury securities.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Debt instruments issued by a natural person</textblock>
    <textblock>. If an</textblock>
    <textblock>entity is a primary obligor under a debt instrument, the debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument is considered to be issued by the entity and not by a</textblock>
    <textblock>natural person even if a natural person is a co-maker and is</textblock>
    <textblock>jointly liable for the debt instrument's repayment. A debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument issued by a partnership is considered to be issued by</textblock>
    <textblock>the partnership as an entity even if the partnership is composed</textblock>
    <textblock>entirely of natural persons.</textblock>
    <textblock>(h)</textblock>
    <textblock>Publicly offered debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>. A debt instrument is</textblock>
    <textblock>publicly offered if it is part of an issue of debt instruments</textblock>
    <textblock>the initial offering of which_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Is registered with the Securities and Exchange</textblock>
    <textblock>Commission; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Would be required to be registered under the Securities</textblock>
    <textblock>Act of 1933 (15 U.S.C. 77a et seq.) but for an exemption from</textblock>
    <textblock>registration_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Under section 3 of the Securities Act of 1933 (relating</textblock>
    <textblock>to exempted securities);</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Under any law (other than the Securities Act of 1933)</textblock>
    <textblock>because of the identity of the issuer or the nature of the</textblock>
    <textblock>security; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Because the issue is intended for distribution to</textblock>
    <textblock>persons who are not United States persons.</textblock>
    <textblock>§1.1275-2</textblock>
    <textblock>Special rules relating to debt instruments.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Payment ordering rule_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>In general</textblock>
    <textblock>. Except as</textblock>
    <textblock>provided in paragraph (a)(2) of this section, each payment under</textblock>
    <textblock>a debt instrument is treated first as a payment of OID to the</textblock>
    <textblock>extent of the OID that has accrued as of the date the payment is</textblock>
    <textblock>due and has not been allocated to prior payments, and second as a</textblock>
    <textblock>payment of principal. Thus, no portion of any payment is treated</textblock>
    <textblock>as prepaid interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Exceptions</textblock>
    <textblock>. The rule in paragraph (a)(1) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section does not apply to_</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
