<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00044</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Service carefully has assessed the best scientific and</textblock>
    <textblock>commercial information available regarding the past, present, and future</textblock>
    <textblock>threats faced by the California red-legged frog in determining to</textblock>
    <textblock>propose this rule. Based on this evaluation, the preferred action is to</textblock>
    <textblock>list the California red-legged frog (</textblock>
    <textblock>Rana aurora draytonii</textblock>
    <textblock>) as</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered. This subspecies has been extirpated from 75 percent of its</textblock>
    <textblock>former range. Seventy-seven percent of remaining aggregations currently</textblock>
    <textblock>are threatened by one or more factors, including (1) introduction of</textblock>
    <textblock>exotic predators and competitors, (2) urban encroachment, (3) construction</textblock>
    <textblock>of large and small reservoirs, water diversions and well development, (4)</textblock>
    <textblock>flood control maintenance, (5) grazing, and (6) timber harvest. Only 44</textblock>
    <textblock>drainages, with the majority being in Monterey, Santa Barbara, and San</textblock>
    <textblock>Luis Obispo Counties, currently provide habitat free from the above</textblock>
    <textblock>threats. Fragmentation of habitat, however, renders these populations</textblock>
    <textblock>vulnerable to random extinction (stochastic) events. For the reasons</textblock>
    <textblock>discussed below, critical habitat is not being proposed at this time.</textblock>
    <textblock>Critical Habitat</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 4(a)(3) of the Act, as amended, and implementing</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations (50 CFR 424.12) require that, to the maximum extent prudent</textblock>
    <textblock>and determinable, the Secretary propose critical habitat at the time a</textblock>
    <textblock>species is proposed to be endangered or threatened. The Service finds</textblock>
    <textblock>that designation of critical habitat is not presently prudent for the</textblock>
    <textblock>California red-legged frog.</textblock>
    <textblock>As discussed under Factor B in the ``Summary of Factors Affecting</textblock>
    <textblock>the Species'' section, the California red-legged frog has been and</textblock>
    <textblock>continues to be threatened by taking, an activity difficult to control.</textblock>
    <textblock>Listing of the frog may result in an increase in the threat of</textblock>
    <textblock>vandalism, a concern expressed by the petitioners and other experts (M.</textblock>
    <textblock>Jennings, S, Sweet, pers. comms., 1993). California red-legged frogs</textblock>
    <textblock>occur in isolated and fragmented wetland habitat on private property and</textblock>
    <textblock>are at risk from vandalism. Publication of specific localities, which</textblock>
    <textblock>would be required in proposing critical habitat, would reveal precise</textblock>
    <textblock>locality data and thereby make the species more vulnerable to collection</textblock>
    <textblock>and acts of vandalism, and increase the difficulties of enforcement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Protection of this species' habitat will be addressed in the recovery</textblock>
    <textblock>process and through the section 7 consultation process. Therefore, it</textblock>
    <textblock>would not now be prudent to determine critical habitat of the California</textblock>
    <textblock>red-legged frog.</textblock>
    <textblock>Available Conservation Measures</textblock>
    <textblock>Conservation measures provided to species listed as endangered or</textblock>
    <textblock>threatened under the Endangered Species Act include recognition,</textblock>
    <textblock>recovery actions, requirements for Federal protection, and prohibitions</textblock>
    <textblock>against certain activities. Recognition through listing encourages and</textblock>
    <textblock>results in conservation actions by Federal, State, and private agencies,</textblock>
    <textblock>groups, and individuals. The Act provides for possible land acquisition and cooperation with the States and requires that recovery actions be</textblock>
    <textblock>carried out for all listed species. The protection required of Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies and the prohibitions against taking and harm are discussed, in</textblock>
    <textblock>part, below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 7(a) of the Act, as amended, requires Federal agencies to</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluate their actions with respect to any species that is proposed or</textblock>
    <textblock>listed as endangered or threatened and with respect to its critical</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat, if any is being designated. Regulations implementing this</textblock>
    <textblock>interagency cooperation provision of the Act are codified at 50 CFR part</textblock>
    <textblock>402. Section 7(a)(4) of the Act requires Federal agencies to confer</textblock>
    <textblock>informally with the Service on any action that is likely to jeopardize</textblock>
    <textblock>the continued existence of a proposed species or result in destruction</textblock>
    <textblock>or adverse modification of proposed critical habitat. If a species is</textblock>
    <textblock>listed subsequently, section 7(a)(2) requires Federal agencies to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>that activities they authorize, fund, or carry out are not likely to</textblock>
    <textblock>jeopardize the continued existence of such a species or to destroy or</textblock>
    <textblock>adversely modify its critical habitat. If a Federal action may affect a</textblock>
    <textblock>listed species or its critical habitat, the responsible Federal agency</textblock>
    <textblock>must enter into formal consultation with the Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal agencies that may be involved as a result of this proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule are the Bureau of Reclamation, Bureau of Land Management, National</textblock>
    <textblock>Park Service, Forest Service, and the Departments of the Army, Navy and</textblock>
    <textblock>Air Force. At several parks, the National Park Service has conducted or</textblock>
    <textblock>is planning to conduct surveys of California red-legged frogs on park</textblock>
    <textblock>property (Daphne A. Hatch, National Park Service,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1993; James</textblock>
    <textblock>Sleznick, National Park Service,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1992; Gary Fellers, National</textblock>
    <textblock>Park Service, pers. comm., 1993). The Forest Service has conducted and</textblock>
    <textblock>has ongoing amphibian surveys in many National Forests within the</textblock>
    <textblock>historic range of the California red-legged frog (J. Stephenson, pers.</textblock>
    <textblock>comm., 1993; D. Martin, pers. comm., 1993). The Bureau of Reclamation</textblock>
    <textblock>is cosponsoring a proposed reservoir construction project (Los Vaqueros</textblock>
    <textblock>Reservoir) on Kellogg Creek, Contra Costa County (Contra Costa Water</textblock>
    <textblock>District 1993). A mitigation and monitoring program is proposed to</textblock>
    <textblock>compensate for California red-legged frog habitat losses. The</textblock>
    <textblock>mitigation plan includes a bullfrog and exotic fish control program to</textblock>
    <textblock>be carried out for the life of the reservoir project (Contra Costa Water</textblock>
    <textblock>District 1993). The potential for success of the mitigation plan is</textblock>
    <textblock>unknown. The proposed Los Banos Grande reservoir project on Los Banos</textblock>
    <textblock>Creek in Merced County, also cosponsored by the Bureau of Reclamation,</textblock>
    <textblock>does not provide mitigation specifically for the California red-legged</textblock>
    <textblock>frog (Cay Goude, Fish and Wildlife Service, pers. comm., 1993). The</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Army Corps of Engineers would be involved through their permitting</textblock>
    <textblock>authority under section 404 of the Clean Water Act. Any of the above</textblock>
    <textblock>mentioned Federal agencies would be required to consult with the Service</textblock>
    <textblock>if any action they fund, authorize, or carry out is likely to jeopardize</textblock>
    <textblock>the continued existence of the California red-legged frog.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
