<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00174</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00074</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>C. Eligibility</textblock>
    <textblock>The only eligible applicants under this program are nonprofit organizations with section 501(c)(3) tax exemptions from the Internal Revenue Service. A single Sponsor shall not request more units in a given Region than permitted for that Region in the Invitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Initial Screening, Technical Processing and Selection Criteria</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Initial Screening</textblock>
    <textblock>Applications for section 811 capital advances that are received by HUD at the appropriate address by 4 p.m. local time on May 3, 1994, will be reviewed to determine if all parts of the application are included. HUD will not review the content of the application as part of initial screening. Deficiency letters will be sent informing Sponsors of any missing parts of the application. Sponsors must correct such deficiencies within 14 calendar days from the date of the deficiency letter. The deficiency letter is to be sent by certified mail. Any document requested as a result of the initial screening may be executed or prepared within the deficiency period, except for Forms HUD-92016-CAs, Articles of Incorporation, IRS exemption rulings, Forms SF-424, Board Resolution committing the minimum capital investment, and site control documents (all of these excepted items must be dated no later than the application deadline date).</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>Fiscal Year 1993 Allocation for Supportive Housing for Persons With Disabilities</textblock>
    <textblock>1Region</textblock>
    <textblock>1Capital advance</textblock>
    <textblock>1Units</textblock>
    <textblock>I</textblock>
    <textblock>$8,714,817</textblock>
    <textblock>121</textblock>
    <textblock>II</textblock>
    <textblock>22,768,105</textblock>
    <textblock>305</textblock>
    <textblock>III</textblock>
    <textblock>16,738,362</textblock>
    <textblock>280</textblock>
    <textblock>IV</textblock>
    <textblock>31,171,649</textblock>
    <textblock>615</textblock>
    <textblock>V</textblock>
    <textblock>26,794,525</textblock>
    <textblock>449</textblock>
    <textblock>VI</textblock>
    <textblock>14,990,460</textblock>
    <textblock>314</textblock>
    <textblock>VII</textblock>
    <textblock>5,869,593</textblock>
    <textblock>113</textblock>
    <textblock>VIII</textblock>
    <textblock>2,583,448</textblock>
    <textblock>52</textblock>
    <textblock>IX</textblock>
    <textblock>24,127,484</textblock>
    <textblock>345</textblock>
    <textblock>X</textblock>
    <textblock>4,110,557</textblock>
    <textblock>69</textblock>
    <textblock>n,s</textblock>
    <textblock>National total</textblock>
    <textblock>$157,869,000</textblock>
    <textblock>2663</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
