<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00122</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>B. In Existing Facilities With No Cases of Nosocomial Aspergillosis</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Place high-risk patients in protected environment that meets the conditions outlined in Section II-A-1-a through II-A-1-e above.</textblock>
    <textblock>424,437,479,488,660,661,665</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Routinely inspect air-handling systems in high-risk patient-care areas, maintain adequate air exchanges and pressure differentials, and eliminate air leakages. Coordinate repairs of the system with relocation of high-risk patients to other areas with optimal air-handling capabilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>418,428,437</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Minimize the time high-risk patients spend outside their rooms for diagnostic procedures and other activities; and when high-risk patients leave their rooms, require them to wear well-fitting masks capable of filtering</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus</textblock>
    <textblock>spp. spores.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Regularly clean ceiling tiles, air-duct grates, and other surfaces in patient rooms to prevent dust accumulation, and maintain adequate seals on windows to prevent room infiltration by outside air, especially in areas occupied by patients at high-risk for developing aspergillosis. Conduct such cleaning when the rooms are not occupied by patients.437</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Systematically review and coordinate infection-control strategies with personnel in charge of hospital engineering, maintenance, central supply and distribution, and catering.</textblock>
    <textblock>418,473</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>6. When planning hospital construction and renovation activities, assess whether patients at high-risk for aspergillosis are likely to be exposed to high ambient-air spore counts of</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus</textblock>
    <textblock>spp. from construction and renovation sites, and develop a plan to prevent such exposures.418,473</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>7. During construction or renovation activities:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Construct barriers between patient-care and construction areas to prevent dust from entering patient-care areas; these barriers (e.g., plastic or drywall) should be impermeable to</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus</textblock>
    <textblock>spp.418,428,472,473</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) In construction/renovation areas inside the hospital, create and maintain negative pressure relative to that in adjacent patient-care areas if there are no contraindications for such pressure differential, e.g., there are patients with infectious tuberculosis in the adjacent patient-care areas.418,428,472,473,488</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY II</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Direct pedestrian traffic from construction areas away from patient-care areas to limit opening and closing of doors (or other barriers) that may cause dust dispersion, entry of contaminated air, or tracking of dust into patient areas.418,428,472,473</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) Clean newly constructed areas before allowing patients to enter the areas.418,473</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Eliminate exposures of patients at high-risk for</textblock>
    <textblock>aspergillosis</textblock>
    <textblock>to activities, such as floor or carpet vacuuming, that may cause spores of Aspergillus spp. and other fungi to be aerosolized.418,437,473</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Eliminate exposures of patients at high-risk for aspergillosis to potential environmental sources of Aspergillus spp., such as</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus</textblock>
    <textblock>-contaminated food, potted plants, or flower arrangements.418,437,473,662-664</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY II</textblock>
    <textblock>10. Prevent birds from gaining access to hospital air-intake ducts.474</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>C. When a Case of Nosocomial Aspergillosis Occurs</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Begin a prospective search for additional cases in hospitalized patients and an intensified retrospective review of the hospital's microbiologic, histopathologic, and postmortem records.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>2. If there is no evidence of continuing transmission, continue routine maintenance procedures to prevent nosocomial aspergillosis, as in Section II-B-1 through II-B-10 above.</textblock>
    <textblock>CATEGORY IB</textblock>
    <textblock>3. If evidence of continuing</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus</textblock>
    <textblock>spp. infection exists, conduct an environmental investigation to determine and eliminate the source.</textblock>
    <textblock>424,427,428,472,484,488</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
