<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00059</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00043</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given to the NIH Consensus Development Conference on ``Helicobacter Pylori and Peptic Ulcer Disease,'' which will be held February 7-9, 1994, in the Masur Auditorium of the National Institutes of Health, 9000 Rockville Pike, Bethesda, Maryland 20892. This conference is sponsored by the National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases and the NIH Office of Medical Applications of Research. The conference is cosponsored by the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases. The conference begins at 8:30 a.m. on February 7 and 8 and at 9 a.m. on February 9.</textblock>
    <textblock>One in a series of NIH Consensus Development Conferences, this conference will evaluate all the data that are available on H. pylori and its role in causing peptic ulcer disease and gastric malignancy and on the best and most appropriate means of diagnosing and treating H. pylori infection. The conference will bring together specialists in gastroenterology, infectious disease, epidemiology, and pathology, as well as representatives from the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>Following 11/2 days of presentations and discussion by the audience, an independent non-Federal consensus panel will weigh the scientific evidence and write a draft statement in response to the following key questions:</textblock>
    <textblock>•What is the role of H. pylori infection in causing peptic ulcer disease and gastric malignancy?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Does eradication of H. pylori infection alter the natural history of peptic ulcer disease?</textblock>
    <textblock>•Which patients with H. pylori infection should be treated?</textblock>
    <textblock>•What are the best and most appropriate means of diagnosis and monitoring of H. pylori infection?</textblock>
    <textblock>•What are the best means of eradication of H. pylori infection?</textblock>
    <textblock>•What are the most important issues to be addressed by future research in H. pylori infection?</textblock>
    <textblock>On the final day of the meeting, the consensus panel chairman will read the draft statement to the conference audience and invite comments and questions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Advance information on the conference program and conference registration materials may be obtained from: Laura Hazan, Technical Resources, Inc., 3202 Tower Oaks Blvd., suite 200, Rockville, Maryland 20852, (301) 770-3153.</textblock>
    <textblock>The final consensus statement will be submitted for publication in professional journals and other publications. The final consensus statement will be available approximately April 1, 1994. Requests for the final consensus statement should be addressed to the NIH Consensus Program Information Service, P.O. Box 2577, Kensington, Maryland 20891, phone 1-800-NIH-OMAR (1-800-644-6627).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Institutes of Health</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Consensus Development Conference on Helicobacter Pylori and Peptic Ulcer Disease</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Harold Varmus,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, NIH.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2448 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4140-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
