<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00066</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(ii) The instrument provides for a payment of stated</textblock>
    <textblock>interest on the first payment date within 1 year of the issue</textblock>
    <textblock>date that equals or exceeds the amount of the pre-issuance</textblock>
    <textblock>accrued interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Exclusion of pre-issuance accrued interest from issue</textblock>
    <textblock>price.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a debt instrument meets the requirements of paragraph</textblock>
    <textblock>(m)(1) of this section, the instrument's issue price may be</textblock>
    <textblock>computed by subtracting from the issue price (as otherwise</textblock>
    <textblock>computed under this section) the amount of pre-issuance accrued</textblock>
    <textblock>interest. If the issue price of the debt instrument is computed</textblock>
    <textblock>in this manner, a portion of the stated interest payable on the</textblock>
    <textblock>first payment date must be treated as a return of the excluded</textblock>
    <textblock>pre-issuance accrued interest, rather than as an amount payable</textblock>
    <textblock>on the instrument.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Example.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following example illustrates the rule of</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (m) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Facts.</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 15, 1995, A purchases at</textblock>
    <textblock>original issue, for $1,005, B corporation's debt instrument. The</textblock>
    <textblock>debt instrument provides for a payment of principal of $1,000 on</textblock>
    <textblock>January 1, 2005, and provides for semiannual interest payments of</textblock>
    <textblock>$60 on January 1 and July 1 of each year, beginning on July 1,</textblock>
    <textblock>1995.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Determination of pre-issuance accrued interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraphs (m)(1) and (m)(2) of this section, $5 of the $1,005</textblock>
    <textblock>initial purchase price of the debt instrument is allocable to</textblock>
    <textblock>pre-issuance accrued interest. Accordingly, the debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument's issue price may be computed by subtracting the</textblock>
    <textblock>amount of pre-issuance accrued interest ($5) from the issue price</textblock>
    <textblock>otherwise computed under this section ($1,005), resulting in an</textblock>
    <textblock>issue price of $1,000. If the issue price is computed in this</textblock>
    <textblock>manner, $5 of the $60 payment made on July 1, 1995, must be</textblock>
    <textblock>treated as a repayment by B of the pre-issuance accrued interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>§1.1274-1</textblock>
    <textblock>Debt instruments to which section 1274 applies.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>In general.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subject to the exceptions and limitations</textblock>
    <textblock>in paragraph (b) of this section, section 1274 and this section</textblock>
    <textblock>apply to any debt instrument issued in consideration for the sale</textblock>
    <textblock>or exchange of property. For purposes of section 1274, property</textblock>
    <textblock>includes debt instruments and investment units, but does not</textblock>
    <textblock>include money, services, or the right to use property. For the</textblock>
    <textblock>treatment of certain obligations given in exchange for services</textblock>
    <textblock>or the use of property, see sections 404 and 467. For purposes</textblock>
    <textblock>of this paragraph (a), money includes functional currency and, in</textblock>
    <textblock>certain circumstances, nonfunctional currency. See §1.988-2(b)(2) for circumstances when nonfunctional currency is treated</textblock>
    <textblock>as money rather than as property.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Exceptions_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Debt instrument with adequate stated</textblock>
    <textblock>interest and no OID.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1274 does not apply to a debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) All interest payable on the instrument is qualified</textblock>
    <textblock>stated interest;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The stated rate of interest is at least equal to the</textblock>
    <textblock>test rate of interest (as defined in §1.1274-4);</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) The debt instrument is not issued in a potentially</textblock>
    <textblock>abusive situation (as defined in §1.1274-3); and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) No payment from the buyer-borrower to the seller-lender</textblock>
    <textblock>designated as points or interest is made at the time of issuance</textblock>
    <textblock>of the debt instrument.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Exceptions under sections 1274(c)(1)(B), 1274(c)(3),</textblock>
    <textblock>1274A(c), and 1275(b)(1)_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>In general.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections</textblock>
    <textblock>1274(c)(1)(B), 1274(c)(3), 1274A(c), and 1275(b)(1) describe</textblock>
    <textblock>certain transactions to which section 1274 does not apply. This</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (b)(2) provides certain rules to be used in applying</textblock>
    <textblock>those exceptions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Special rules for certain exceptions under section</textblock>
    <textblock>1274(c)(3)_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A)</textblock>
    <textblock>Determination of sales price for certain sales of</textblock>
    <textblock>farms.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of section 1274(c)(3)(A), the determination</textblock>
    <textblock>as to whether the sales price cannot exceed $1,000,000 is made</textblock>
    <textblock>without regard to any other exception to, or limitation on, the</textblock>
    <textblock>applicability of section 1274 (e.g., without regard to the</textblock>
    <textblock>special rules regarding sales of principal residences and land</textblock>
    <textblock>transfers between related persons). In addition, the sales price</textblock>
    <textblock>is determined without regard to section 1274 and without regard</textblock>
    <textblock>to any stated interest. The sales price includes the amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>any liability included in the amount realized from the sale or</textblock>
    <textblock>exchange. See §1.1001-2.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B)</textblock>
    <textblock>Sales involving total payments of $250,000 or less.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under section 1274(c)(3)(C), the determination of the amount of</textblock>
    <textblock>payments due under all debt instruments and the amount of other</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration to be received is made as of the date of the sale</textblock>
    <textblock>or exchange or, if earlier, the contract date. If the precise</textblock>
    <textblock>amount due under any debt instrument or the precise amount of any</textblock>
    <textblock>other consideration to be received cannot be determined as of</textblock>
    <textblock>that date, section 1274(c)(3)(C) applies only if it can be</textblock>
    <textblock>determined that the maximum of the aggregate amount of payments</textblock>
    <textblock>due under the debt instruments and other consideration to be</textblock>
    <textblock>received cannot exceed $250,000. For purposes of section</textblock>
    <textblock>1274(c)(3)(C), if a liability is assumed or property is taken</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to a liability, the aggregate amount of payments due</textblock>
    <textblock>includes the outstanding principal balance or adjusted issue</textblock>
    <textblock>price (in the case of an obligation originally issued at a</textblock>
    <textblock>discount) of the obligation.</textblock>
    <textblock>(C)</textblock>
    <textblock>Coordination with section 1273 and §1.1273-2.</textblock>
    <textblock>In</textblock>
    <textblock>accordance with section 1274(c)(3)(D), section 1274 and this</textblock>
    <textblock>section do not apply if the issue price of a debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>issued in consideration for the sale or exchange of property is</textblock>
    <textblock>determined under paragraph (a)(1), (b)(1), or (c)(1) of §1.1273-2.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Other exceptions to section 1274_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Holders of certain</textblock>
    <textblock>below-market instruments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1274 does not apply to any</textblock>
    <textblock>holder of a debt instrument that is issued in consideration for</textblock>
    <textblock>the sale or exchange of personal use property (within the meaning</textblock>
    <textblock>of section 1275(b)(3)) in the hands of the issuer and that</textblock>
    <textblock>evidences a below-market loan described in section 7872(c)(1).</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Transactions involving certain demand loans.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section</textblock>
    <textblock>1274 does not apply to any debt instrument that evidences a</textblock>
    <textblock>demand loan that is a below-market loan described in section</textblock>
    <textblock>7872(c)(1).</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Certain transfers subject to section 1041.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section</textblock>
    <textblock>1274 does not apply to any debt instrument issued in</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration for a transfer of property subject to section 1041</textblock>
    <textblock>(relating to transfers of property between spouses or incident to</textblock>
    <textblock>divorce).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
