<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00085</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00062</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Modification of a Railroad Signal System or Relief From the</textblock>
    <textblock>Requirements of 49 CFR Part 236</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to 49 CFR part 235 and 49 U.S.C. App. 26, the following railroads have petitioned the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) seeking approval for the discontinuance or modification of the signal system or relief from the requirements of 49 CFR part 236 as detailed below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Block Signal Application (BS-AP)-No. 3274</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant: Kansas City Southern Railway Company,</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. M. W. Hahn,</textblock>
    <textblock>Vice President_Transportation,</textblock>
    <textblock>4601 Blanchard Road,</textblock>
    <textblock>Shreveport, Louisiana 71107.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Kansas City Southern Railway Company seeks approval of the proposed modification of the traffic control system, on the single main track, near Gentry, Arkansas, milepost 225.19, on the Second Subdivision; consisting of the discontinuance and removal of automatic block signal No. 2252.</textblock>
    <textblock>The reason given for the proposed changes is to improve train operation and avoid unnecessary blocking of highway traffic at Flint Creek Road.</textblock>
    <textblock>BS-AP-No. 3275</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant: CSX Transportation,</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. W. J. Scheerer,</textblock>
    <textblock>Chief Engineer_Train Control,</textblock>
    <textblock>500 Water Street,</textblock>
    <textblock>Jacksonville, Florida 32202.</textblock>
    <textblock>CSX Transportation seeks approval of the proposed modification of the signal system, on all main tracks and No. 1 and No. 2 tracks, between CP 43, milepost PLE43.4, near</textblock>
    <textblock>New Castle, Pennsylvania, and CP 17Y, milepost PLY16.8, near Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, on the Cumberland Division, Pittsburgh Subdivision, consisting of the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The discontinuance and removal of 52 controlled signals, 20 automatic signals, and 2 power-operated derails;</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The relocation of 45 controlled signals and 12 automatic signals; and</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The conversion of 10 power-operated switches to hand operation.</textblock>
    <textblock>The reason given for the proposed changes is the installation of new signal equipment to replace inadequate and deteriorated signal facilities.</textblock>
    <textblock>BS-AP-No. 3276</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicant: Union Pacific Railroad Company,</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. P. M. Abaray,</textblock>
    <textblock>Chief Engineer_Signals &amp; Construction,</textblock>
    <textblock>1416 Dodge Street, room 1000,</textblock>
    <textblock>Omaha, Nebraska 68179.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Union Pacific Railroad Company seeks approval of the proposed modification of the traffic control system, on the two main tracks and siding, near Browder, Texas, milepost 216.6,</textblock>
    <textblock>Ft. Worth Division, Dallas Subdivision, consisting of the following:</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Railroad Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Application for Approval of Discontinuance or</textblock>
  </doctitle>
</doc>
