<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00112</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>VIRAL PNEUMONIAS</textblock>
    <textblock>Viruses can be an important and often unappreciated cause of nosocomial pneumonia.</textblock>
    <textblock>489,490</textblock>
    <textblock>In one prospective study of endemic nosocomial infections, approximately 20% of patients with pneumonia had viral infections.</textblock>
    <textblock>490</textblock>
    <textblock>}</textblock>
    <textblock>Although early diagnosis and treatment of viral infections have become possible in recent years,</textblock>
    <textblock>491-494</textblock>
    <textblock>many hospitalized patients remain at high risk for developing severe and sometimes fatal viral infections.</textblock>
    <textblock>489,495-502</textblock>
    <textblock>Based on these data and on well-documented outbreaks with nosocomial viral transmission,</textblock>
    <textblock>503-506</textblock>
    <textblock>measures to prevent viral transmission should be instituted.</textblock>
    <textblock>Nosocomial respiratory viral infections (1) usually follow community outbreaks that occur during a particular period every year,</textblock>
    <textblock>505,507-510</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) confer only short-term immunity,</textblock>
    <textblock>511</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) affect healthy and ill persons,</textblock>
    <textblock>497,498,504,512-514</textblock>
    <textblock>and (4) have exogenous sources. A number of viruses, including adenoviruses, influenza virus, measles virus, parainfluenza viruses, respiratory syncytial virus (RSV), rhinoviruses, and varicella-zoster virus can cause nosocomial pneumonia;</textblock>
    <textblock>498,505,506,515-521</textblock>
    <textblock>however, adenoviruses, influenza or parainfluenza viruses, and RSV have been reported to account for most (70%) of nosocomial pneumonias due to viruses.</textblock>
    <textblock>522,523</textblock>
    <textblock>Because influenza and RSV infections account for a substantial portion of morbidity and mortality due to viral pneumonia and have been well studied epidemiologically, this section focuses on the principles and approaches to control these infections. However, because the modes of transmission of RSV (i.e., by large droplets or by contact with contaminated hands or other fomites) are the same as those of parainfluenza viruses and similar to those of adenoviruses and rhinoviruses (i.e., mainly by large droplets or contact with contaminated hands or other fomites, but also possibly by aerosol inhalation), infection-control measures recommended for RSV infection are applicable to infections caused by the other three viruses.</textblock>
    <textblock>524-529</textblock>
    <textblock>Prevention of nosocomial infections due to measles and varicella-zoster is addressed in another document.</textblock>
    <textblock>213</textblock>
    <textblock>RSV INFECTION</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Epidemiology</textblock>
    <textblock>RSV infection is most common during infancy and early childhood, but may also occur in adults.</textblock>
    <textblock>134,512,515,530,531</textblock>
    <textblock>Infection usually causes mild or moderately severe upper respiratory illness. However, life-threatening pneumonia or bronchiolitis has been reported in children with chronic cardiac and pulmonary disease, immunocompromised patients, and the elderly.</textblock>
    <textblock>497,499,514,515,532,533</textblock>
    <textblock>Recent surveillance of 10 U.S. hospital laboratories performing cultures for RSV suggests that community outbreaks occur yearly between December and March, last from 3-5 months, and are associated with increased hospitalization and deaths among infants and young children.</textblock>
    <textblock>534</textblock>
    <textblock>During community outbreaks of RSV, children admitted to the hospital with respiratory symptoms often serve as reservoirs for RSV.</textblock>
    <textblock>503,505</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Diagnosis</textblock>
    <textblock>The clinical characteristics of RSV infection, especially in neonates, are often indistinguishable from those of other viral respiratory tract infections.</textblock>
    <textblock>515,516</textblock>
    <textblock>Culture of RSV from respiratory secretions remains the ``gold standard'' for diagnosis. Although rapid antigen-detection kits utilizing direct immunofluorescence or enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay are available and can provide results within hours, the benefit of using these tests to identify infected and susceptible patients depends on the sensitivity and specificity of the test. The reported sensitivity and specificity of RSV enzyme immunoassays vary between 80% and 95%, and may even be lower in actual practice.</textblock>
    <textblock>535-538</textblock>
    <textblock>In general, once laboratory-confirmed cases of RSV infection are identified in a hospital, a presumptive diagnosis of RSV infection in subsequent cases with manifestations suggestive of RSV infection may be acceptable for infection control purposes.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
