<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00038</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00025</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>[Docket No. TM94-8-29-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Transcontinental Gas Pipe Line Corp.; Proposed Changes in FERC Gas Tariff</textblock>
    <textblock>January 27, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 24, 1994 Transcontinental Gas Pipe Line Corporation (TGPL) tendered for filing as part of its FERC Gas Tariff, Third Revised Volume No. 1, certain revised tariff sheets included in Appendix A attached to the filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>TGPL states that the purpose of the instant filing is to track rate changes attributable to (1) transportation service purchased from Texas Gas Transmission Corporation (Texas Gas) under its Rate Schedule FT the costs of which are included in the rates and charges payable under TGPL's Rate Schedule FT-NT, (2) transportation service purchased from National Fuel Gas Supply Corporation (National Fuel) under its Rate Schedule X-42 the costs of which are included in the rates and charges payable under TGPL's Rate Schedule LSS, (3) transportation service purchased from National Fuel under its Rate Schedule X-54 the costs of which are included in the rates and charges payable under TGPL's Rate Schedule SS-2 and (4) transportation service purchased from National Fuel under its Rate Schedule X-58 the costs of which are included in the rates and charges payable under TGPL's Niagara Import Point Project_System Expansion (NIPPs-SE) firm transportation service. The tracking filing is being made pursuant to Section 4 of TGPL's Rate Schedule FT-NT, Section 4 of TGPL's Rate Schedule LSS, Section 4 of TGPL's Rate Schedule SS-2 and Section 8.01(i) of TGPL's NIPPs-SE Rate Schedules X-315, X-316, X-318 and X-324.</textblock>
    <textblock>TGPL states that included in Appendices B through E attached to the filing are the explanations of the rate changes and details regarding the computation of the revised FT-NT, LSS, SS-2 and NIPPs-SE rates, respectively.</textblock>
    <textblock>TGPL states that copies of the filing are being mailed to each of its FT-NT, LSS, SS-2 and NIPPs-SE customers and interested State Commissions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE. Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Sections 385.214 and 385.211 of the Commission's Rules and Regulations. All such motions or protests should be filed on or before February 3, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection in the public reference room.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock/>
  <doctitle/>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2317 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
