<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00041</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Prior to 1950, California red-legged frogs were used sporadically</textblock>
    <textblock>for research in high schools and universities. At present, the</textblock>
    <textblock>California red-legged frog is sold commercially from suppliers located</textblock>
    <textblock>outside California in the pet trade. Because the State of California</textblock>
    <textblock>prohibits possession of wild California red-legged frogs, frogs sold in</textblock>
    <textblock>the pet trade presumably are reared in captivity (M. Jennings, pers.</textblock>
    <textblock>comm., 1993). However, California red-legged frogs occur in isolated</textblock>
    <textblock>and fragmented wetland habitat on private property and are at risk from</textblock>
    <textblock>vandalism.</textblock>
    <textblock>C.</textblock>
    <textblock>Disease or predation</textblock>
    <textblock>. There have been no documented instances</textblock>
    <textblock>of disease adversely affecting the California red-legged frog.</textblock>
    <textblock>Few data are available on the effect of native predators on the</textblock>
    <textblock>California red-legged frog. Bitterns (</textblock>
    <textblock>Botaurus lentiginosus</textblock>
    <textblock>) and black-</textblock>
    <textblock>crowned night herons (</textblock>
    <textblock>Nycticorax nycticorax</textblock>
    <textblock>) are likely predators of</textblock>
    <textblock>adult frogs (Jennings and Hayes 1990). Juvenile California red-legged</textblock>
    <textblock>frogs, which are more active diurnally and less wary than adults, may be</textblock>
    <textblock>more susceptible to predation by diurnal predators, such as the great</textblock>
    <textblock>blue heron (</textblock>
    <textblock>Ardea herodias</textblock>
    <textblock>) and several species of garter snakes</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>Thamnophis</textblock>
    <textblock>sp.) (Fitch 1940, Fox 1952), including the endangered San</textblock>
    <textblock>Francisco garter snake (</textblock>
    <textblock>Thamnophis sirtalis tetrataenia</textblock>
    <textblock>) (Barry 1978,</textblock>
    <textblock>Wharton et al. 1986). Recent post-metamorphs also may be particularly vulnerable to predation by garter snakes, as was found in other species</textblock>
    <textblock>of ranid frogs by Arnold and Wassersug (1978).</textblock>
    <textblock>Introduced predators of particular concern are the bullfrog, red</textblock>
    <textblock>swamp crayfish (</textblock>
    <textblock>Procambarus clarkii</textblock>
    <textblock>), signal crayfish (</textblock>
    <textblock>Pacifastacus</textblock>
    <textblock>leniusculus</textblock>
    <textblock>), and several species of fish, including bass (</textblock>
    <textblock>Micropterus</textblock>
    <textblock>spp.), catfish (</textblock>
    <textblock>Ictalurus</textblock>
    <textblock>spp.), sunfish (</textblock>
    <textblock>Lepomis</textblock>
    <textblock>spp.), and mosquitofish (</textblock>
    <textblock>Gambusia affinis</textblock>
    <textblock>) (Moyle 1973; Hayes and Jennings 1986,</textblock>
    <textblock>1988). All species were introduced into California in the late 1800s</textblock>
    <textblock>and early 1900s, and through range expansions, reintroductions, and</textblock>
    <textblock>transplants have become established throughout most of the state (Riegel</textblock>
    <textblock>1959, Bury and Luckenbach 1976, Moyle 1976).</textblock>
    <textblock>Several researchers in central California have noted the decline</textblock>
    <textblock>and eventual disappearance of California red-legged frogs once bullfrogs</textblock>
    <textblock>become established at the same site (L. Hunt,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>, 1993; S. Barry,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1992; S. Sweet,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993). Moyle (1973) attributed the disappearance of California red-legged frogs from the San Joaquin Valley</textblock>
    <textblock>and Sierran foothill region primarily to a combination of bullfrog</textblock>
    <textblock>predation and competition. All sites in the Sierra Nevada mountains</textblock>
    <textblock>that supported California red-legged frogs in the 1970s now are</textblock>
    <textblock>inhabited by bullfrogs (M. Jennings,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993). Over 65 percent</textblock>
    <textblock>of the streams or drainages currently known to support California red-</textblock>
    <textblock>legged frogs also are inhabited by bullfrogs, either in association with</textblock>
    <textblock>California red-legged frogs or in other portions of the drainage. Over</textblock>
    <textblock>the last decade, Jennings (</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993) has observed bullfrogs moving</textblock>
    <textblock>upstream and/or downstream into formerly isolated California red-legged</textblock>
    <textblock>frog habitat in a number of drainages, including streams in Ventura,</textblock>
    <textblock>Santa Barbara, San Luis Obispo, Merced, Stanislaus, and San Mateo</textblock>
    <textblock>Counties. Game fish are introduced into drainages by stocking of</textblock>
    <textblock>reservoirs and ponds, dispersal and colonization, conveyance of project</textblock>
    <textblock>water from other streams inhabited by these exotics, and releases by</textblock>
    <textblock>individuals. At The Nature Conservancy Santa Rosa Plateau Reserve in</textblock>
    <textblock>Riverside County (the only site south of the Santa Clara River</textblock>
    <textblock>supporting California red-legged frogs), a docent found a school teacher</textblock>
    <textblock>attempting to introduce bullfrog tadpoles into the preserve in the 1980s</textblock>
    <textblock>(M. Jennings,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993). Once established, it is virtually</textblock>
    <textblock>impossible to eliminate bullfrogs (M. Jennings,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993; Cecil</textblock>
    <textblock>Schwalbe, National Park Service, Tuscon, Arizona, pers. comm., 1993;</textblock>
    <textblock>Frank Slavens, Woodland Park Zoological Gardens, Seattle, Washington,</textblock>
    <textblock>pers. comm., 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>Bullfrogs prey on California red-legged frogs (Twedt 1993; S.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sweet,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993) and other amphibians and aquatic reptiles</textblock>
    <textblock>(Schwalbe and Rosen 1988). Twedt (1993) documented 4 juvenile red-</textblock>
    <textblock>legged frogs in the contents of a total of 22 adult bullfrog stomachs.</textblock>
    <textblock>He also found a subadult bullfrog in one of the adult bullfrog stomachs;</textblock>
    <textblock>this prey item was between the size of an adult male (approximately 55</textblock>
    <textblock>millimeters (2 inches)) and adult female (approximately 70 millimeters</textblock>
    <textblock>(3 inches)) red-legged frog, indicating that bullfrogs also undoubtedly</textblock>
    <textblock>prey on adult red-legged frogs. Bullfrogs may have a competitive</textblock>
    <textblock>advantage over red-legged frogs because of their (1) larger size, (2)</textblock>
    <textblock>generalized food habits (Bury and Whelan 1984), (3) extended breeding</textblock>
    <textblock>season (Storer 1933), which allows for production of two clutches of</textblock>
    <textblock>eggs during a breeding season (Emlen 1977), (4) apparent olfactory</textblock>
    <textblock>rejection of larvae by predatory fish (Kruse and Francis 1977), and (5)</textblock>
    <textblock>diminished activity periods (Woodward 1983), which also reduces their</textblock>
    <textblock>exposure to predators. Bullfrogs also interfere with red-legged frog</textblock>
    <textblock>reproduction. Several researchers have noted red-legged frogs in</textblock>
    <textblock>amplexus (mounted on) with bullfrogs (Jennings and Hayes 1990; Twedt</textblock>
    <textblock>1993; M. Jennings,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993; Stebbins</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1993). However, the extent to which bullfrog predation, competition, and reproductive</textblock>
    <textblock>interference adversely affects red-legged frogs has not been studied in</textblock>
    <textblock>the field (Hayes and Jennings 1986). Habitat alterations, including</textblock>
    <textblock>removal of riparian or aquatic vegetation, reduced stream flows, and</textblock>
    <textblock>sedimentation of pools, often provide conditions detrimental to red-</textblock>
    <textblock>legged frogs but favorable to bullfrogs (Hayes and Jennings 1986;</textblock>
    <textblock>Jennings, pers. comm., 1993).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
