<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00031</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(C) The extent to which the taxpayer followed the relevant requirements set forth in regulations under section 482 with respect to the application of the method.</textblock>
    <textblock>(D) The extent to which the taxpayer reasonably relied on the analysis of, or a study done by, a professional qualified to conduct such an analysis or study, including an attorney, accountant, or economist. Whether the professional is an employee of, or related to, the taxpayer is not determinative in evaluating the reliability of that analysis or study, as long as the analysis or study is objective, thorough, and well reasoned. Such reliance is reasonable only if the taxpayer disclosed to the professional all relevant information regarding the controlled transactions at issue. A transfer pricing study or analysis that was reasonably relied upon in a prior year may reasonably be relied upon in the current year if the relevant facts and circumstances have not changed or if the study or analysis has been appropriately modified to reflect any change in facts and circumstances.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Documentation requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>_(A)</textblock>
    <textblock>In general.</textblock>
    <textblock>The documentation requirement of this paragraph (d)(2)(iii) is met if the taxpayer maintains sufficient documentation to establish that the taxpayer reasonably concluded that, given the available data and the applicable pricing methods, the method (and its application of that method) provided the most accurate measure of an arm's-length result under the principles of the best method rule in ยง1.482-1T(b)(2)(iii), and provides that documentation to the Internal Revenue Service within 30 days of a request for it. That documentation must be in existence when the return is filed. The district director may, in his discretion, excuse a minor or inadvertent failure to provide required documents, but only if the taxpayer has made a good faith effort to comply, and the taxpayer promptly remedies the failure when it becomes known. The required documentation is divided into two categories, principal and background documents, as described in paragraphs (d)(2)(iii) (B) and (C) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B)</textblock>
    <textblock>Principal documents.</textblock>
    <textblock>The principal documents should accurately and completely describe the basic transfer pricing analysis conducted by the taxpayer. The documentation must include the following_</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) An overview of the taxpayer's business, including an analysis of the economic and legal factors that affect the pricing of its property or services;</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) A description of the taxpayer's organizational structure (including an organization chart) covering all related parties engaged in transactions potentially relevant under section 482, including foreign affiliates whose transactions directly or indirectly affect the pricing of property or services in the United States;</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>) Any documentation explicitly required by the regulations under section 482;</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
    <textblock>) A description of the specified method selected and an explanation of why that method was selected;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
