<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00042</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00029</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4831-4]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Radiation Cleanup Regulation Subcommittee of the National Advisory Council for Environmental Policy and Technology; Public Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of public meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the Federal Advisory Committee Act, PL92563, EPA gives notice that the Radiation Cleanup Regulation Subcommittee of the National Advisory Council for Environmental Policy and Technology's (NACEPT) Environmental Information and Assessments (EIA) Committee will meet by conference call on Thursday, February 24, 1994, from 1 p.m. to 4 p.m., EST. The Subcommittee provides advice to EPA regarding the development of regulations to be applied to sites contaminated with radioactive material.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Agency received the benefit of Subcommittee members' views on appropriate risk/cleanup levels, future land use, and site specific public involvement at the open subcommittee meeting of October 18-19, 1993. This conference call will provide an update on how those views have helped inform the Agency's decision-making process to date as regulatory development progresses. There will also be a limited discussion of regulations governing the disposal of wastes generated during cleanup operations, which are in the preliminary stages of development. This conference call is primarily intended to provide an intermediate update for subcommittee members. It is anticipated that a full-scale subcommittee meeting will be held in the Spring for in-depth discussion of all pertinent issues.</textblock>
    <textblock>For additional information, contact Miles Kahn, Designated Federal Official, Office of Radiation and Indoor Air, Radiation Studies Division, Mailcode 6603J, 401 M Street, SW., Washington, DC 20460. Phone: 202-233-9384 or FAX: 202-233-9650. Individuals wishing to participate in the conference call as audience or commenters should call the Designated Federal Official as soon as possible, since there is a limited number of conference lines available.</textblock>
    <textblock>Members of the public wishing to submit comments on the issues discussed by the subcommittee should submit them in writing to: USEPA_Mail Stop 6102; Air Docket No. A-93-27; Room M-1500; First Floor, Waterside Mall; 401 M St., SW., Washington, DC 20460.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 24, 1994.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Morris Altschuler,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Office of Cooperative Environmental Management.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2276 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
