<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00073</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Wraparound indebtedness</textblock>
    <textblock>. For purposes of paragraph (a)</textblock>
    <textblock>of this section, the issuance of wraparound indebtedness is not</textblock>
    <textblock>considered an assumption.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Consideration attributable to assumed debt</textblock>
    <textblock>. If, as part</textblock>
    <textblock>of the consideration for the sale or exchange of property, the</textblock>
    <textblock>buyer assumes, or takes the property subject to, an indebtedness</textblock>
    <textblock>that was issued with OID (including a debt instrument issued in a</textblock>
    <textblock>prior sale or exchange to which section 1274 applied), the</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of the buyer's basis in the property and the seller's</textblock>
    <textblock>amount realized attributable to the debt instrument equals the</textblock>
    <textblock>adjusted issue price of the debt instrument as of the date of the</textblock>
    <textblock>sale or exchange.</textblock>
    <textblock>Par. 12.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 1.1274A-1, 1.1275-1 and 1.1275-2 are added to</textblock>
    <textblock>read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง1.1274A-1</textblock>
    <textblock>Special rules for certain transactions where stated</textblock>
    <textblock>principal amount does not exceed $2,800,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>In general</textblock>
    <textblock>. Section 1274A allows the use of a lower</textblock>
    <textblock>test rate for purposes of sections 483 and 1274 in the case of a</textblock>
    <textblock>qualified debt instrument (as defined in section 1274A(b)) and,</textblock>
    <textblock>if elected by the borrower and the lender, the use of the cash</textblock>
    <textblock>receipts and disbursements method of accounting for interest on a</textblock>
    <textblock>cash method debt instrument (as defined in section 1274A(c)(2)).</textblock>
    <textblock>This section provides special rules for qualified debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instruments and cash method debt instruments.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rules for both qualified and cash method debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instruments</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Sale-leaseback transactions</textblock>
    <textblock>. A debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>issued in a sale-leaseback transaction (within the meaning of</textblock>
    <textblock>section 1274(e)) cannot be either a qualified debt instrument or</textblock>
    <textblock>a cash method debt instrument.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Debt instruments calling for contingent payments</textblock>
    <textblock>. A</textblock>
    <textblock>debt instrument that provides for contingent payments cannot be a</textblock>
    <textblock>qualified debt instrument unless it can be determined at the time</textblock>
    <textblock>of the sale or exchange that the maximum stated principal amount</textblock>
    <textblock>due under the debt instrument cannot exceed the amount specified</textblock>
    <textblock>in section 1274A(b). Similarly, a debt instrument that provides</textblock>
    <textblock>for contingent payments cannot be a cash method debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>unless it can be determined at the time of the sale or exchange</textblock>
    <textblock>that the maximum stated principal amount due under the debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument cannot exceed the amount specified in section</textblock>
    <textblock>1274A(c)(2)(A).</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Aggregation of transactions</textblock>
    <textblock>_(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>General rule</textblock>
    <textblock>. The</textblock>
    <textblock>aggregation rules of section 1274A(d)(1) are applied using a</textblock>
    <textblock>facts and circumstances test.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Examples</textblock>
    <textblock>. The following examples illustrate the</textblock>
    <textblock>application of section 1274A(d)(1) and paragraph (b)(3)(i) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 1</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Aggregation of two sales to a single person</textblock>
    <textblock>. In</textblock>
    <textblock>two transactions evidenced by separate sales agreements, A sells</textblock>
    <textblock>undivided half interests in Blackacre to B. The sales are</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant to a plan for the sale of a 100 percent interest in</textblock>
    <textblock>Blackacre to B. These sales or exchanges are part of a series of</textblock>
    <textblock>related transactions and, thus, are treated as a single sale for</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of section 1274A.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 2</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Aggregation of two purchases by unrelated</textblock>
    <textblock>individuals</textblock>
    <textblock>. Pursuant to a plan, unrelated individuals X and Y</textblock>
    <textblock>purchase undivided half interests in Blackacre from A and</textblock>
    <textblock>subsequently contribute these interests to a partnership in</textblock>
    <textblock>exchange for equal interests in the partnership. These purchases</textblock>
    <textblock>are treated as part of the same transaction and, thus, are</textblock>
    <textblock>treated as a single sale for purposes of section 1274A.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 3</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Aggregation of sales made pursuant to a tender</textblock>
    <textblock>offer</textblock>
    <textblock>. Fifteen unrelated individuals own all of the stock of X</textblock>
    <textblock>Corporation. Y Corporation makes a tender offer to these 15</textblock>
    <textblock>shareholders. The terms offered to each shareholder are</textblock>
    <textblock>identical. Shareholders holding a majority of the shares of X</textblock>
    <textblock>Corporation elect to tender their shares pursuant to Y</textblock>
    <textblock>Corporation's offer. These sales are part of the same</textblock>
    <textblock>transaction and, thus, are treated as a single sale for purposes</textblock>
    <textblock>of section 1274A.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 4</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>No aggregation for separate sales of similar</textblock>
    <textblock>property to unrelated persons</textblock>
    <textblock>. Pursuant to a newspaper</textblock>
    <textblock>advertisement, X Corporation offers for sale similar condominiums</textblock>
    <textblock>in a single building. The prices of the units vary due to a</textblock>
    <textblock>variety of factors, but the financing terms offered by X</textblock>
    <textblock>Corporation to all buyers are identical. The units are purchased</textblock>
    <textblock>by unrelated buyers who decided whether to purchase units in the</textblock>
    <textblock>building at the price and on the terms offered by X Corporation,</textblock>
    <textblock>without regard to the actions of other buyers. Because each</textblock>
    <textblock>buyer acts individually, the sales are not part of the same</textblock>
    <textblock>transaction or a series of related transactions and, thus, are</textblock>
    <textblock>treated as separate sales.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>Inflation adjustment of dollar amounts</textblock>
    <textblock>. Under section</textblock>
    <textblock>1274A(d)(2), the dollar amounts specified in sections 1274A(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>and 1274A(c)(2)(A) are adjusted for inflation. The dollar</textblock>
    <textblock>amounts, adjusted for inflation, are published in the Internal</textblock>
    <textblock>Revenue Bulletin (see ยง601.601(d)(2)(ii) of this chapter).</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rules for cash method debt instruments</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Time and</textblock>
    <textblock>manner of making cash method election</textblock>
    <textblock>. The borrower and lender</textblock>
    <textblock>make the election described in section 1274A(c)(2)(D) by jointly</textblock>
    <textblock>signing a statement that includes the names, addresses, and</textblock>
    <textblock>taxpayer identification numbers of the borrower and lender, a</textblock>
    <textblock>clear indication that an election is being made under section</textblock>
    <textblock>1274A(c)(2), and a declaration that the debt instrument with</textblock>
    <textblock>respect to which the election is being made fulfills the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of a cash method debt instrument. Both the borrower</textblock>
    <textblock>and the lender must sign this statement not later than the</textblock>
    <textblock>earlier of the last day (including extensions) for filing the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal income tax return of the borrower or lender for the</textblock>
    <textblock>taxable year in which the debt instrument is issued. The</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower and lender should attach this signed statement (or a</textblock>
    <textblock>copy thereof) to their timely filed Federal income tax returns.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Successors of electing parties</textblock>
    <textblock>. Except as otherwise</textblock>
    <textblock>provided in this paragraph (c)(2), the cash method election under</textblock>
    <textblock>section 1274A(c) applies to any successor of the electing lender</textblock>
    <textblock>or borrower. Thus, for any period after the transfer of a cash</textblock>
    <textblock>method debt instrument, the successor takes into account the</textblock>
    <textblock>interest (including unstated interest) on the instrument under</textblock>
    <textblock>the cash receipts and disbursements method of accounting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Nevertheless, if the lender (or any successor thereof) transfers</textblock>
    <textblock>the cash method debt instrument to a taxpayer who uses an accrual</textblock>
    <textblock>method of accounting, section 1272 rather than section 1274A(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>applies to the successor of the lender with respect to the debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument for any period after the date of the transfer. The</textblock>
    <textblock>borrower (or any successor thereof), however, remains on the cash</textblock>
    <textblock>receipts and disbursements method of accounting with respect to</textblock>
    <textblock>the cash method debt instrument.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
