<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00058</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00042</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) announced in the Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on January 6, 1994 (59 FR 771) that applications are being accepted for fiscal year (FY) 1994, Grants for Interdisciplinary Training for Health Care for Rural Areas under the authority of section 778, title VII of the Public Health Service (PHS) Act, as amended by the Health Professions Education Extension Amendments of 1992, Public Law 102-408, dated October 13, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 778 of the Public Health Service Act, as amended, authorizes the Secretary to award grants for interdisciplinary training projects designed to provide or improve access to health care in rural areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>To provide additional time for applicants to complete applications, the deadline date for this program is extended to February 15, 1994. Applications will be considered to be ``on time'' if they are either:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Received on or before</textblock>
    <textblock>the established deadline date, or</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Sent on or before</textblock>
    <textblock>the established deadline date and received in time for orderly processing. (Applicants should request a legibly dated U.S. Postal Service postmark or obtain a legibly dated receipt from a commercial carrier or U.S. Postal Service. Private metered postmarks shall not be acceptable as proof of timely mailing.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Late applications not accepted for processing will be returned to the applicant.</textblock>
    <textblock>If additional programmatic information is needed, please contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Marcia Brand, Program Officer,</textblock>
    <textblock>Division of Associated, Dental and Public</textblock>
    <textblock>Health Professions,</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Health Professions, HRSA,</textblock>
    <textblock>Parklawn Building, room 8C-02,</textblock>
    <textblock>5600 Fishers Lane,</textblock>
    <textblock>Rockville, MD 20857,</textblock>
    <textblock>Telephone: 301-443-6763,</textblock>
    <textblock>FAX: 301-443-1164.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 26, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Extension of Deadline Date for Grants for Interdisciplinary Training for Health Care for Rural Areas for FY 1994</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William A. Robinson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2270 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-15-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
