<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00036</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00023</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 27, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 24, 1994, Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation (Texas Eastern) submitted for filing as part of its FERC Gas Tariff, Sixth Revised Volume No. 1, the following tariff sheets:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed to be Effective October 1, 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>Revised 2nd Sub Original Sheet No. 628</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed to be Effective October 3, 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>2nd Revised 2nd Sub Original Sheet No. 628</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed to be Effective November 1, 1993</textblock>
    <textblock>2nd Sub First Revised Sheet No. 628</textblock>
    <textblock>Texas Eastern states that the proposed tariff sheets reflect the inclusion of references to Rate Schedule LLFT, effective October 1, 1993, and Rate Schedule VKFT, effective October 3, 1993, in the definition of GSR Demand Account and in Section 15.2(D) of the General Terms and Conditions. In addition, Texas eastern states that the tariff sheets reflect the inclusion of the mitigation measure for Rate Schedule SCT Customers filed on November 15, 1993 in Docket No. RS92-11-020 and approved by the Commission's ``Fourth Order on Compliance Filing and Third Order on Rehearing'' issued December 17, 1993 in Docket No. RS92-11, et al</textblock>
    <textblock>., to be effective June 1, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed effective date of the tariff sheets are October 1, 1993, October 3, 1993 and November 1, 1993, as shown above.</textblock>
    <textblock>Texas Eastern states that copies of the filing were served on firm customers of Texas Eastern and interested state commissions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rules 211 and 214 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure. All such motions or protests should be filed on or before February 3, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. RP94-116-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Texas Eastern Transmission Corp.; Proposed Changes in FERC Gas Tariff</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2307 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
