<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00141</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>426. Rotstein C, Cummings KM, Tiddings J, et al. An outbreak of invasive aspergillosis among bone marrow transplants: a case-control study. Infect Control 1985; 6:347-355.</textblock>
    <textblock>427. Aisner J, Schimpff SC, Bennett JE, et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus</textblock>
    <textblock>infections in cancer patients. Association with fireproofing materials in a new hospital. JAMA 1976; 235:411-412.</textblock>
    <textblock>428. Arnow PM, Anderson RI, Mainous PD, Smith EJ. Pulmonary aspergillosis during hospital renovation. Am Rev Respir Dis 1978; 118:49-53.</textblock>
    <textblock>429. Streifel AJ, Laner JL, Vesley D, et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus fumigatus</textblock>
    <textblock>and other thermotolerant fungi generated by hospital building demolition. Appl Environ Microbiol 1983; 46:375-378.</textblock>
    <textblock>430. Hopkins CC, Weber DJ, Rubin RH. Invasive aspergillosis infection: possible non-ward common source within the hospital environment. J Hosp Infect 1989; 13:19-25.</textblock>
    <textblock>431. Gurwith MJ, Stinson EB, Remington JS.</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus</textblock>
    <textblock>infection complicating cardiac transplantation: report of five cases. Arch Intern Med 1971; 128:541-545.</textblock>
    <textblock>432. Weiland D, Ferguson RM, Peterson PK, Snover DC, Simmons RL, Najarian JS. Aspergillosis in 25 renal transplant patients. Ann Surg 1983; 198:622-629.</textblock>
    <textblock>433. Hofflin JM, Potasman I, Baldwin JC, Oyster PE, Stinson EB, Remington JS. Infectious complications in heart transplant recipients receiving cyclosporine and corticosteroids. Ann Intern Med 1987; 106:209-216.</textblock>
    <textblock>434. Schulman LL, Smith CR, Drusin R, Rose EA, Enson Y, Reemtsma K. Respiratory complications of cardiac transplantation. Am J Med Sci 1988; 296:1-10.</textblock>
    <textblock>435. Gustafson TL, Schaffner W, Lavely GB, Stratton CW, Johnson HK, Hutcheson RH. Invasive aspergillosis in renal transplant recipients: correlation with corticosteroid therapy. J Infect Dis 1983; 148:230-238.</textblock>
    <textblock>436. Ho M, Dummer JS. Risk factors and approaches to infections in transplant recipients. In: Mandell GL, Douglas RG,Jr., Bennett JE, eds. Principles and Practice of Infectious Diseases. 3rd ed. New York: Churchill Livingstone, Inc., 1990:2284-2291.</textblock>
    <textblock>437. Rhame FS, Streifel AJ, Kersey JHJ. Extrinsic risk factors for pneumonia in the patient at high risk for infection. Am J Med 1984; 76:42-52.</textblock>
    <textblock>438. Aisner J, Murillo J, Schimpff SC, Steere AC. Invasive aspergillosis in acute leukemia: correlation with nose cultures and antibiotic use. Ann Intern Med 1979; 90:4-9.</textblock>
    <textblock>439. Ho M, Dummer JS, Peterson PK, Simmons RL. Infections in solid organ transplant recipients. In: Mandell GL, Douglas RG,Jr., Bennett JE, eds. Principles and Practice of Infectious Diseases. 3rd ed. New York: Churchill Livingstone, 1990:2294-2303.</textblock>
    <textblock>440. Walsh TR, Guttendorf J, Dummer S, et al. The value of protective isolation procedures in cardiac transplant recipients. Ann Thorac Surg 1989; 47:539-545.</textblock>
    <textblock>441. Denning DW, Stevens DA. Antifungal and surgical treatment of invasive aspergillosis: review of 2121 published cases. Rev Infect Dis 1990; 12:1147-1201.</textblock>
    <textblock>442. Pannuti CS, Pfaller MA, Wenzel RP. Nosocomial pneumonia in adult patients undergoing bone marrow transplantation: a 9-year study. J Clin Oncol 1991; 9:77-84.</textblock>
    <textblock>443. Weinberger M, Elattaar I, Marshall D, et al. Patterns of infection in patients with aplastic anaemia and the emergence of aspergillus as a major cause of death. Medicine 1992; 71:24-43.</textblock>
    <textblock>444. Orr DP, Myerowitz RL, Jemkins R, et al. Patho-radiologic correlation of invasive pulmonary aspergillosis in the compromised host. Case report and review of literature. Cancer 1978; 41:2028-2039.</textblock>
    <textblock>445. Young RC, Bennett JE, Vogel CL, Carbone PP, DeVita VT. Aspergillosis: the spectrum of the disease in 98 patients. Medicine 1970; 49:147-173.</textblock>
    <textblock>446. Meyer RD, Young LS, Armstrong D, et al. Aspergillosis complicating neoplastic disease. Am J Med 1973; 54:6-15.</textblock>
    <textblock>447. Yu VL, Muder RR, Poorsattar A. Significance of isolation of</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus</textblock>
    <textblock>from the respiratory tract in diagnosis of invasive pulmonary aspergillosis. Results of a three-year prospective study. Am J Med 1986; 81:249-254.</textblock>
    <textblock>448. Martino P, Raccah R, Gentile G, Venditti M, Girmenea C, Mandelli F.</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus</textblock>
    <textblock>colonization of the nose and pulmonary aspergillosis in neutropenic patients: a retrospective study. Hematologica 1989; 74:263-265.</textblock>
    <textblock>449. Richet HM, McNeil MM, Davis BJ, et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus fumigatus</textblock>
    <textblock>sternal wound infections in patients undergoing open heart surgery. Am J Epidemiol 1992; 135:48-58.</textblock>
    <textblock>450. Albelda SM, Talbot GH, Gerson SL, Miller WT, Cassileth PA. Role of fiberoptic bronchoscopy in the diagnosis of invasive pulmonary aspergillosis in patients with acute leukemia. Am J Med 1984; 76:1027-1034.</textblock>
    <textblock>451. Kahn FW, Jones JM, England DM. The role of bronchoalveolar lavage in the diagnosis of invasive pulmonary aspergillosis. Am J Clin Pathol 1986; 86:518-523.</textblock>
    <textblock>452. Saito H, Anaissie EJ, Morice RC, Dekmezian R, Bodey GP. Bronchoalveolar lavage in the diagnosis of pulmonary infiltrates in patients with acute leukemia. Am J Med 1984; 76:1027-1034.</textblock>
    <textblock>453. Cohen J. Clinical manifestations and management of aspergillosis in the compromised patient. In: Warnock DW, Richardson MD, eds. Fungal Infections in the Compromised Patient. London: John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd., 1991:117-152.</textblock>
    <textblock>454. Pepys J, Riddell RW, Citron KM, Clayton YM, Short EI. Clinical and immunologic significance of</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus fumigatus</textblock>
    <textblock>in the sputum. Am Rev Respir Dis 1959; 80:167-180.</textblock>
    <textblock>455. Karam GH, Griffin JR. Invasive pulmonary aspergillosis in nonimmunocompromised, non-neutropenic hosts. Rev Infect Dis 1986; 8:357-363.</textblock>
    <textblock>456. Kammer RB, Utz JP.</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus</textblock>
    <textblock>species endocarditis: the new face of a not so rare disease. Am J Med 1974; 56:506-521.</textblock>
    <textblock>457. Holmberg K, Berdischewsky M, Young LS. Serologic immunodiagnosis of invasive aspergillosis. J Infect Dis 1980; 141:656-664.</textblock>
    <textblock>458. Matthews R, Burnie JP, Fox A, Tabaqchali S. Immunoblot analysis of serological responses in invasive aspergillosis. J Clin Path 1985; 38:1300-1303.</textblock>
    <textblock>459. Burnie JP, Matthews RC, Clark I, Milne LJ. Immunoblot fingerprinting of</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus fumigatus.</textblock>
    <textblock>J Immunol Methods 1989; 118:179-186.</textblock>
    <textblock>460. Talbot GH, Weiner MH, Person SL, Provencher M, Hurwitz S. Serodiagnosis of invasive aspergillosis in patients with hematologic malignancy: validation of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus fumigatus</textblock>
    <textblock>antigen radioimmunoassay. J Infect Dis 1987; 155:12-27.</textblock>
    <textblock>461. Dupont B, Huber M, Kim SJ, Bennett JE. Galactomannan antigenemia and antigenuria in aspergillosis: studies in patients and experimentally infected rabbits. J Infect Dis 1987; 155:1-11.</textblock>
    <textblock>462. Gerson SL, Talbot GH, Hurwitz S, Strom B, Lusk EJ. Prolonged granulocytopenia: the major risk factor for invasive pulmonary aspergillosis in patients with leukemia. Ann Intern Med 1984; 100:345-351.</textblock>
    <textblock>463. Wingard JR, Beals SU, Santos GW, Mertz WG, Saral R. Aspergillus infections in bone marrow transplant recipients. Bone Marrow Transplant 1987; 2:175-181.</textblock>
    <textblock>464. Peters WP. Use of cytokines during prolonged neutropenia associated with autologous bone marrow transplantation. Rev Infect Dis 1991; 13:993-996.</textblock>
    <textblock>465. Lieschke GJ, Burgess AW. Granulocyte colony-stimulating factor and granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor. N Engl J Med 1992; 327:28-35.</textblock>
    <textblock>466. Karp JE, Burch PA, Merz WG, et al. An approach to intensive antileukemia therapy in patients with previous invasive aspergillosis. Am J Med 1988; 85:203-206.</textblock>
    <textblock>467. Meunier-Carpentier F, Snoeck R, Gerain J, et al. Chemoprophylaxis of fungal infections. Am J Med 1984; 76:652-656.</textblock>
    <textblock>468. Wajszczuk CP, Dummer JS, Ho M, et al. Fungal infections in liver transplant recipients. Transplantation 1985; 40:347-353.</textblock>
    <textblock>469. Rhame FS, Streifel A, Stevens P, et al. Endemic</textblock>
    <textblock>Aspergillus</textblock>
    <textblock>airborne spore levels are a major risk factor for aspergillosis in bone marrow transplant patients. Abstracts of the 25th Interscience Conference on Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy 1985; (abstract)</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
