<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00102</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <table>
    <textblock>Table</textblock>
    <textblock>15.812(e)(1)._</textblock>
    <textblock>Quick Reference Table for Federal Pilotage Requirements for Inspected, Self-Propelled Vessels</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1␣</textblock>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>Navigable waters of the U.S. designated as first class pilotage waters (routes for which First Class Pilot's licenses are issued)1</textblock>
    <textblock>Navigable waters of the U.S. not designated as first class pilotage waters (between the three mile line and the start of traditional pilotage routes).</textblock>
    <textblock>Inspected self-propelled vessels greater than 1,600 GT, authorized by their Certificate of Inspection (COI) to proceed beyond the Boundary Line, or operating on the Great Lakes</textblock>
    <textblock>First Class Pilot</textblock>
    <textblock>Master or Mate may serve as pilot if the individual:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Is at least 21 years old.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Has an annual physical exam.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Maintains current knowledge of the waters to be navigated.</textblock>
    <textblock>Inspected self-propelled vessels not more than 1,600 GT, authorized by their Certificate of Inspection to proceed beyond the Boundary Line, or operating on the Great Lakes</textblock>
    <textblock>First Class Pilot,</textblock>
    <textblock>or</textblock>
    <textblock>Master or Mate may serve as pilot if the individual:</textblock>
    <textblock>1.Is a least 21 years old.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Maintains current knowledge of the waters to be navigated.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Has 4 round trips over the route</textblock>
    <textblock>Master or Mate may serve as pilot if the individual:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Is at least 21 years old.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Maintains current knowledge of the waters to be navigated.</textblock>
    <textblock>Inspected self-propelled vessels greater than 1,600 GT, not authorized by their COI to proceed beyond the Boundary Line (Inland route vessels); other than vessels operating on the Great Lakes</textblock>
    <textblock>First Class Pilot</textblock>
    <textblock>Master or Mate may serve as pilot if the individual:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Is at least 21 years old.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Has an annual physical exam.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Maintains current knowledge of the waters to be navigated.</textblock>
    <textblock>Inspected self-propelled vessels not more than 1,600 GT, not authorized by their COI to proceed beyond the Boundary Line (Inland route vessels); other than vessels operating on the Great Lakes</textblock>
    <textblock>No pilotage requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>No pilotage requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>1Navigable waters of the U.S. for pilotage purposes include all inland waters and offshore waters to a distance of 3 nautical miles from the baseline from which the Territorial Sea is measured.</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
