<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00059</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>ยง1.1272-3</textblock>
    <textblock>Election by a holder to treat all interest on a debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument as OID.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Election</textblock>
    <textblock>. A holder of a debt instrument may elect to</textblock>
    <textblock>include in gross income all interest that accrues on the</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument by using the constant yield method described in</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (c) of this section. For purposes of this election,</textblock>
    <textblock>interest includes stated interest, acquisition discount, OID, de</textblock>
    <textblock>minimis OID, market discount, de minimis market discount, and</textblock>
    <textblock>unstated interest, as adjusted by any amortizable bond premium or</textblock>
    <textblock>acquisition premium.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Scope of election</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>In general</textblock>
    <textblock>. Except as provided</textblock>
    <textblock>in paragraph (b)(2) of this section, a holder may make the</textblock>
    <textblock>election for any debt instrument.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Exceptions, limitations, and special rules</textblock>
    <textblock>_(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument with amortizable bond premium (as determined under</textblock>
    <textblock>section 171)</textblock>
    <textblock>. (A) A holder may make the election for a debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument with amortizable bond premium only if the instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>qualifies as a bond under section 171(d).</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) If a holder makes the election under this section for a</textblock>
    <textblock>debt instrument with amortizable bond premium, the holder is</textblock>
    <textblock>deemed to have made the election under section 171(c)(2) for the</textblock>
    <textblock>taxable year in which the instrument was acquired. If the holder</textblock>
    <textblock>has previously made the election under section 171(c)(2), the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of that election with respect to any debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>are satisfied by electing to amortize the bond premium under the</textblock>
    <textblock>rules provided by this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Debt instrument with market discount</textblock>
    <textblock>. (A) A holder may</textblock>
    <textblock>make the election under this section for a debt instrument with</textblock>
    <textblock>market discount only if the holder is eligible to make an</textblock>
    <textblock>election under section 1278(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) If a holder makes the election under this section for a</textblock>
    <textblock>debt instrument with market discount, the holder is deemed to</textblock>
    <textblock>have made both the election under section 1276(b)(2) for that</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument and the election under section 1278(b) for the taxable</textblock>
    <textblock>year in which the instrument was acquired. If the holder has</textblock>
    <textblock>previously made the election under section 1278(b), the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of that election with respect to any debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>are satisfied by electing to include the market discount in</textblock>
    <textblock>income in accordance with the rules provided by this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Tax-exempt debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>. A holder may not make the</textblock>
    <textblock>election for a tax-exempt obligation as defined in section</textblock>
    <textblock>1275(a)(3).</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Mechanics of the constant yield method</textblock>
    <textblock>_(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>In general</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of this section, the amount of interest that accrues</textblock>
    <textblock>during an accrual period is determined under rules similar to</textblock>
    <textblock>those under section 1272 (the constant yield method). In</textblock>
    <textblock>applying the constant yield method, however, a debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to the election is treated as if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The instrument is issued for the holder's adjusted basis immediately after its acquisition by the holder;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The instrument is issued on the holder's acquisition</textblock>
    <textblock>date; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) None of the interest payments provided for in the</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument are qualified stated interest payments.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Special rules to determine adjusted basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes</textblock>
    <textblock>of paragraph (c)(1)(i) of this section_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) If the debt instrument is acquired in an exchange for</textblock>
    <textblock>other property (other than in a reorganization defined in section</textblock>
    <textblock>368) and the basis of the debt instrument is determined, in whole</textblock>
    <textblock>or in part, by reference to the basis of the other property, the</textblock>
    <textblock>adjusted basis of the debt instrument may not exceed its fair</textblock>
    <textblock>market value immediately after the exchange; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) If the debt instrument was acquired with amortizable</textblock>
    <textblock>bond premium (as determined under section 171), the adjusted</textblock>
    <textblock>basis of the debt instrument is reduced by an amount equal to the</textblock>
    <textblock>value attributable to any conversion feature.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Time and manner of making the election.</textblock>
    <textblock>The election</textblock>
    <textblock>must be made for the taxable year in which the holder acquires</textblock>
    <textblock>the debt instrument. A holder makes the election by attaching to</textblock>
    <textblock>the holder's timely filed Federal income tax return a statement</textblock>
    <textblock>that the holder is making an election under this section and that</textblock>
    <textblock>identifies the debt instruments subject to the election. A</textblock>
    <textblock>holder may make the election for a class or group of debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instruments by attaching a statement describing the type or types</textblock>
    <textblock>of debt instruments being designated for the election.</textblock>
    <textblock>(e)</textblock>
    <textblock>Revocation of election.</textblock>
    <textblock>The election may not be revoked</textblock>
    <textblock>unless approved by the Commissioner.</textblock>
    <textblock>(f)</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective date.</textblock>
    <textblock>This section applies to debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instruments acquired on or after April 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
