<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00040</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Livestock grazing is another form of habitat alteration that is</textblock>
    <textblock>contributing to declines in the California red-legged frog. Jennings et</textblock>
    <textblock>al. (1992) found livestock grazing to occur at all known historic</textblock>
    <textblock>locations of the California red-legged frog in the Central Valley</textblock>
    <textblock>hydrographic basin. Livestock grazing also has been implicated as a</textblock>
    <textblock>contributing factor in the decline and disappearance of California red-</textblock>
    <textblock>legged frogs from the lower Salinas River (L. Hunt,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.</textblock>
    <textblock>, 1993) and</textblock>
    <textblock>the San Francisco peninsula (S. Barry,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.</textblock>
    <textblock>, 1992). Two remaining</textblock>
    <textblock>aggregations of California red-legged frogs in the Central Valley</textblock>
    <textblock>hydrographic basin (Corral Hollow Ecological Reserve and Frank Raines</textblock>
    <textblock>Regional Park) are threatened by sedimentation of aquatic habitats</textblock>
    <textblock>either directly or indirectly caused by livestock grazing and off-road</textblock>
    <textblock>vehicle use (Jennings et al. 1992). Rathbun (pers. comm., 1993) reports</textblock>
    <textblock>that grazing is adversely altering California red-legged frog habitat on</textblock>
    <textblock>Pico, Van Gordon, San Simeon, Santa Rosa, Cambria Meadows, and Cayucos</textblock>
    <textblock>Creeks in San Luis Obispo County.</textblock>
    <textblock>Numerous studies, summarized in Behnke and Raleigh (1978) and</textblock>
    <textblock>Kauffman and Krueger (1984), have shown that livestock grazing</textblock>
    <textblock>negatively affects riparian habitat. Cattle have a disproportionately</textblock>
    <textblock>greater adverse affect on riparian and other wetland habitats because</textblock>
    <textblock>they tend to concentrate in these areas, particularly during the dry</textblock>
    <textblock>season (Marlow and Pogacnik 1985). Cattle trample and eat emergent and</textblock>
    <textblock>riparian vegetation, often eliminating or severely reducing plant cover</textblock>
    <textblock>(Gunderson 1968, Duff 1979). Loss of riparian vegetation results in</textblock>
    <textblock>increased water temperatures (Van Velson 1979), which encourage bullfrog</textblock>
    <textblock>reproduction (bullfrogs are a predator and competitor of California</textblock>
    <textblock>red-legged frogs). Riparian vegetation loss due to cattle grazing</textblock>
    <textblock>includes the loss of willows (Duff 1979), which are associated with the</textblock>
    <textblock>highest densities of California red-legged frogs (Jennings 1988b).</textblock>
    <textblock>Cattle grazing also results in increased erosion in the watershed (Lusby</textblock>
    <textblock>1970, Winegar 1977), which results in the sedimentation of deep pools</textblock>
    <textblock>(Gunderson 1968) used by California red-legged frogs and adversely</textblock>
    <textblock>affects aquatic invertebrates (Cordone and Kelley 1961), which are</textblock>
    <textblock>common prey items of California red-legged frogs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Off-road vehicle use adversely affects California red-legged frogs</textblock>
    <textblock>in ways similar to livestock grazing. Off-road vehicles damage riparian</textblock>
    <textblock>vegetation and increase siltation in pools. Off-road vehicles also</textblock>
    <textblock>disturb the water in stream channels and may crush eggs, larvae,</textblock>
    <textblock>juveniles or adults. California red-legged frogs were eliminated either</textblock>
    <textblock>all or in part by off-road vehicle activities at the Mojave River above</textblock>
    <textblock>Hesperia, at Rincon Station on the San Gabriel River, and at Piru Creek</textblock>
    <textblock>above Pyramid Lake (M. Jennings, pers. comm., 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>Timber harvest threatens California red-legged frogs through loss</textblock>
    <textblock>of riparian vegetation, which is needed for cover and water temperature</textblock>
    <textblock>regulation, and increased erosion in the watershed, which fills pools</textblock>
    <textblock>with sediment and smothers egg masses. In Santa Cruz County, timber</textblock>
    <textblock>harvest is proposed adjacent to Adams Creek (Celia Scott, private</textblock>
    <textblock>citizen, pers. comm., 1993), 1 of 12 remaining streams in the county</textblock>
    <textblock>that support California red-legged frogs.</textblock>
    <textblock>B.</textblock>
    <textblock>Overutilization for commercial, recreational, scientific, or</textblock>
    <textblock>educational purposes</textblock>
    <textblock>. Records of harvesting California red-legged frogs</textblock>
    <textblock>for food date back to an account by Lockington (1879) of the commercial</textblock>
    <textblock>harvest of this species for the San Francisco market. From 1890 to</textblock>
    <textblock>1900, the California red-legged frog supported a significant commercial</textblock>
    <textblock>fishery (Smith 1895) with about 80,000 frogs harvested annually</textblock>
    <textblock>(Jennings and Hayes 1984). Counties surrounding San Francisco Bay</textblock>
    <textblock>provided the bulk of the frog harvest in the early to mid 1890s, with</textblock>
    <textblock>the Sacramento and San Joaquin Valleys increasing in importance by the</textblock>
    <textblock>end of the decade (Chamberlain 1898, Jennings and Hayes 1985). By 1900,</textblock>
    <textblock>harvest figures for California red-legged frogs fell dramatically,</textblock>
    <textblock>indicating that overharvesting may have occurred. Jennings and Hayes</textblock>
    <textblock>(1985) hypothesized that this rapid decline in the California red-legged</textblock>
    <textblock>frog population was the result of selective harvesting of the larger</textblock>
    <textblock>females. Introduction of the bullfrog in California in 1896 was</textblock>
    <textblock>probably in response to the dwindling California red-legged frog</textblock>
    <textblock>population (Jennings and Hayes 1985).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
