<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00080</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00059</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 26, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>On August 20, 1993, the National Securities Clearing Corporation (``NSCC'') filed a proposed rule change (File No. SR-NSCC-93-11) with the Securities and Exchange Commission (``Commission'') pursuant to Section 19(b) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (``Act'').</textblock>
    <textblock>On August 23, 1993, NSCC filed an amendment to the proposed rule change. Notice of the proposal was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on November 12, 1993, to solicit comments from interested persons.</textblock>
    <textblock>Two comment letters were received; both of which were in support of the proposed rule change.</textblock>
    <textblock>As discussed below, this order approves the proposal.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Description</textblock>
    <textblock>NSCC has revised its capital standards for broker-dealers and banks that desire to join NSCC to use only NSCC'S mutual fund services</textblock>
    <textblock>and for entities that desire to join NSCC to become Funds Members.</textblock>
    <textblock>NSCC also has revised its clearing fund requirements for members that limit their use of NSCC services to only NSCC's mutual fund services. The revisions are to better reflect the risks and nature of NSCC's mutual fund services, which are not guaranteed by NSCC.</textblock>
    <textblock>Broker-dealer applicants for NSCC membership that wish to restrict their NSCC activities to the mutual fund services will be required to have $25,000 in excess net capital over the minimum net capital requirement imposed by the Commission or their designated examining authority, whichever is greater. Bank or trust company applicants will be required to have $100,000 in excess capital over the capital requirement imposed by their state or federal regulatory authority.</textblock>
    <textblock>Members who are accepted under these proposed alternative standards will be required, depending on their level of settlement debits with NSCC, to make deposits to the clearing funds for their mutual fund services activities of $10,000, $20,000, or $40,000 instead of the current $5,000, $10,000, or $20,000, respectively.</textblock>
    <textblock>Broker-dealer applicants for Fund Member status that distribute shares for investment companies with aggregate assets under management of $500,000 or more will be required to have $25,000 in excess net capital over the minimum net capital requirement imposed by the Commission or their designated examining authority, whichever is greater. Applicants that distribute shares for investment companies with aggregate assets under management of less than $500,000 will be required to have excess net capital of $50,000 over the minimum net capital requirements imposed by the Commission or their designated examining authority, whichever is greater. Investment company applicants will be permitted to become Fund Members provided that they have a minimum of $100,000 in assets under management.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Discussion</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission believes the proposal is consistent with Section 17A of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Specifically, Section 17A(b)(3)(B) requires a clearing agency's rules to provide for the participation of registered broker-dealers, registered clearing agencies, registered investment companies, and banks deemed appropriate to the development of a national system for the clearance and settlement of securities transactions.</textblock>
    <textblock>NSCC's rule change expands the number of members eligible to clear and settle their mutual fund transactions through NSCC's facilities. Access to NSCC's mutual fund services is increasingly important to all entities in the mutual fund industry. Lower net capital requirements will enable smaller mutual funds, broker-dealers, banks, and trust companies to participate in NSCC's mutual fund services. Smaller entities thus achieve a parity with their larger competitors in terms of access to orderly, automated transaction processing systems, which are now the industry standard. A common automated means of communication among those entities involved in mutual fund transactions serves the public interest by eliminating the existence of inefficient, error-prone manual data interchanges.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission also believes that NSCC's rule change satisfies the requirements of Sections 17A(b)(3)(A) and (F) that a clearing agency be organized and that its rules be designed to safeguard securities and funds in its custody or control or for which it is responsible.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because NSCC does not guarantee the completion of mutual fund transactions under its mutual fund services program, the Commission does not believe that any additional risk to NSCC will result from the lower net capital requirements for those members that use only the mutual fund services of NSCC and does not believe that NSCC's ability to safeguard securities or funds will be impaired. Along with lower net capital requirements, NSCC is imposing increased clearing fund requirements for members who participate in NSCC's mutual fund services program under the alternative net capital requirements approved in this order. The Commission believes that the increased clearing funds requirements will help protect NSCC and its participants from the risk of default by members using NSCC's mutual fund services.</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Conclusion</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons stated above, the Commission finds that NSCC's proposal is consistent with section 17A of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>It is therefore ordered,</textblock>
    <textblock>pursuant section 19(b)(2) of the Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>that the proposed rule change (File No. SR-NSCC-93-11) be, and hereby is, approved.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Commission by the Division of Market Regulation, pursuant to delegated authority.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Release No. 34-33525; File No. SR-NSCC-93-11]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Self-Regulatory Organizations; National Securities Clearing Corporation; Order Approving a Proposed Rule Change Relating to Capital and Clearing Fund Requirements for Users of Mutual Fund Services</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Securities Exchange Act Release No. 33157 (November 4, 1993), 58 FR 60077.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Letters from Donald J. Boteler, Vice President_Operations, Investment Company Institute, to Jonathan G. Katz, Secretary, Commission (November 16, 1993) and Steven J. Paggioli, Robert H. Wadsworth &amp; Associates, Inc., to Jonathan G. Katz, Secretary, Commission (December 1, 1993).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>NSCC's mutual fund services are described in detail in NSCC Rule 52, ``Mutual Fund Services.''</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Entities qualifying as Fund Members are governed primarily by NSCC Rule 51, ``Fund Member,'' and Addendum I, ``Standards of Financial Responsibility and Operational Capacity for Fund Members'' of NSCC Rules and Procedures. Fund Members are broker-dealer distributors of mutual fund shares that are not full clearing members of NSCC but utilize NSCC's mutual fund services.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The proposed rule change also will change the definition of the term ``Mutual Fund Services Broker-Dealer'' to ``Mutual Fund Services Member'' in order to include broker-dealers, banks, trust companies, and other entities as members whose activities are limited to the mutual fund services at NSCC.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>NSCC's clearing fund formula is set forth in Part XV of NSCC's Procedures. Pursuant to proposed Section A.I.(b)(ii) of Part (XV, a member accepted for membership under the proposed mutual fund services only standards will have a clearing fund requirement of $10,000 if its daily settlement debits are no more than $100,000, $20,000 if its daily settlement debits are no more than $500,000, and $40,000 if its daily settlement debits are more than $500,000.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78q-1 (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78q-1(b)(3)(B) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78q-1(b)(3)(A) and (F) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>11</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C 78q-1 (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>11</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>12</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(2) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>12</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>13</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 200.30-3(a)(12) (1992).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>13</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2321 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
