<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00035</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Endangered and Threatened Wildlife and Plants; Proposed Endangered Status for the California Red-legged Frog</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>50 CFR Part 17</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1018-AC34</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (Service) proposes to determine the California red-legged frog (</textblock>
    <textblock>Rana aurora draytonii</textblock>
    <textblock>) as endangered pursuant to the Endangered Species Act of 1973, as amended (Act). The California red-legged frog is found primarily in wetlands and streams in coastal drainages of central California. It has been extirpated from 75 percent of its former range. This subspecies is threatened throughout its remaining range by a wide variety of human impacts, including urban encroachment, construction of reservoirs and water diversions, introduction of exotic predators and competitors, and stochastic events. This proposed rule, if made final, would extend the Act's protection to the California red-legged frog. The Service seeks data and comments from the public on this proposed rule.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments from all interested parties must be received by April 4, 1994. Public hearing requests must be received by March 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments and materials concerning this proposed rule should be submitted to the Field Supervisor, Sacramento Field Office, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, 2800 Cottage Way, room E-1803, Sacramento, California 95825-1846. Comments and materials received will be available for public inspection, by appointment, during normal business hours at the above address.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Wayne S. White, State Supervisor, at the above address or telephone 916/978-4613.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>The California red-legged frog (</textblock>
    <textblock>Rana aurora draytonii</textblock>
    <textblock>) is one of two subspecies of the red-legged frog (</textblock>
    <textblock>Rana aurora</textblock>
    <textblock>) found on the Pacific coast.</textblock>
    <textblock>R. a. draytonii</textblock>
    <textblock>was first described by Baird and Girard in 1852 from specimens collected at or near the city of San Francisco (Storer 1925). The historical range of the California red-legged frog extended from the vicinity of Point Reyes National Seashore, Marin County, California, coastally and from the vicinity of Redding, Shasta County, California, inland southward to northwestern Baja California, Mexico (Jennings and Hayes 1985, Hayes and Krempels 1986). The northern red- legged frog (</textblock>
    <textblock>Rana aurora aurora</textblock>
    <textblock>) ranges from Vancouver Island, British Columbia, Canada, south along the Pacific coast west of the Cascade ranges to northern California (Del Norte County). Red-legged frogs found in the intervening area (Humboldt to northern Marin County) between the two subspecies exhibit intergrade characteristics of both</textblock>
    <textblock>R. a. aurora</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>R. a. draytonii</textblock>
    <textblock>(Hayes and Krempels 1986). Systematic relationships between the two subspecies are not completely understood (Hayes and Miyamoto 1984, Green 1985a, Green 1986, Hayes and Krempels 1986). However, significant morphological and behavioral differences between the two subspecies suggest that they may actually be two species in secondary contact (Hayes and Krempels 1986).</textblock>
    <textblock>Northern Marin County represents the approximate dividing line between</textblock>
    <textblock>Rana aurora draytonii</textblock>
    <textblock>and intergrade populations along the coastal range (M. Jennings, pers. comm., 1993). California red-legged frogs found in Nevada (Linsdale 1938, Green 1985b) were introduced. This rule would not extend the Act's protection to any</textblock>
    <textblock>Rana aurora</textblock>
    <textblock>in Humboldt, Trinity, and Mendocino Counties, California, and Sonoma County, California, north and west of 38</textblock>
    <textblock>○30</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N and 123</textblock>
    <textblock>○ W, as well as the introduced population in Nevada.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
