<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00075</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(i) A payment of qualified stated interest;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) A payment of points deductible under section 461(g)(2),</textblock>
    <textblock>in the case of the issuer;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) A pro rata prepayment described in paragraph (f)(2) of</textblock>
    <textblock>this section; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) A payment of additional interest or a similar charge</textblock>
    <textblock>provided with respect to amounts that are not paid when due.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Debt instruments distributed by corporations with</textblock>
    <textblock>respect to stock_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Treatment of distribution.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purposes of</textblock>
    <textblock>determining the issue price of a debt instrument distributed by a</textblock>
    <textblock>corporation with respect to its stock, the instrument is treated</textblock>
    <textblock>as issued by the corporation for property. See section</textblock>
    <textblock>1275(a)(4). Thus, under section 1273(b)(3), the issue price of a</textblock>
    <textblock>distributed debt instrument that is traded on an established</textblock>
    <textblock>market is its fair market value. The issue price of a</textblock>
    <textblock>distributed debt instrument that is not traded on an established</textblock>
    <textblock>market is determined under section 1274 or section 1273(b)(4).</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue date.</textblock>
    <textblock>The issue date of a debt instrument</textblock>
    <textblock>distributed by a corporation with respect to its stock is the</textblock>
    <textblock>date of the distribution.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Aggregation of debt instruments_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>General rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Except as provided in paragraph (c)(2) of this section, debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instruments issued in connection with the same transaction or</textblock>
    <textblock>related transactions (determined based on all the facts and</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances) are treated as a single debt instrument for</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of sections 1271 through 1275 and the regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>thereunder. This rule ordinarily applies only to debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instruments of a single issuer that are issued to a single</textblock>
    <textblock>holder. The Commissioner may, however, aggregate debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instruments that are issued by more than one issuer or that are</textblock>
    <textblock>issued to more than one holder if the debt instruments are issued</textblock>
    <textblock>in an arrangement that is designed to avoid the aggregation rule</textblock>
    <textblock>(e.g., debt instruments issued by or to related parties or debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instruments originally issued to different holders with the</textblock>
    <textblock>understanding that the debt instruments will be transferred to a</textblock>
    <textblock>single holder).</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Exception if separate issue price established.</textblock>
    <textblock>Paragraph (c)(1) of this section does not apply to a debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument if_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) The debt instrument is part of an issue a substantial</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of which is traded on an established market within the</textblock>
    <textblock>meaning of ยง1.1273-2(f); or</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) The debt instrument is part of an issue a substantial</textblock>
    <textblock>portion of which is issued for money (or for property traded on</textblock>
    <textblock>an established market within the meaning of ยง1.1273-2(f)) to</textblock>
    <textblock>parties who are not related to the issuer or holder and who do</textblock>
    <textblock>not purchase other debt instruments of the same issuer in</textblock>
    <textblock>connection with the same transaction or related transactions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Special rule for debt instruments that provide for the</textblock>
    <textblock>issuance of additional debt instruments.</textblock>
    <textblock>If, under the terms of</textblock>
    <textblock>a debt instrument (the original debt instrument), the holder may</textblock>
    <textblock>receive one or more additional debt instruments of the issuer,</textblock>
    <textblock>the additional debt instrument or instruments are aggregated with</textblock>
    <textblock>the original debt instrument. Thus, the payments made pursuant</textblock>
    <textblock>to an additional debt instrument are treated as made on the</textblock>
    <textblock>original debt instrument, and the distribution by the issuer of</textblock>
    <textblock>the additional debt instrument is not considered to be a payment</textblock>
    <textblock>made on the original debt instrument. This paragraph (c)(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>applies regardless of whether the right to receive an additional</textblock>
    <textblock>debt instrument is fixed as of the issue date or is contingent</textblock>
    <textblock>upon subsequent events. See ยง1.1272-1(c) for the treatment of</textblock>
    <textblock>certain rights to issue additional debt instruments in lieu of</textblock>
    <textblock>cash payments.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4)</textblock>
    <textblock>Examples.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following examples illustrate the rules</textblock>
    <textblock>set forth in paragraphs (c)(1) and (c)(2) of this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 1. Exception for debt instruments issued separately</textblock>
    <textblock>to other purchasers.</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 1, 1995, Corporation M issues</textblock>
    <textblock>two series of bonds, Series A and Series B. The two series are</textblock>
    <textblock>sold for cash and have different terms. Although some holders</textblock>
    <textblock>purchase bonds from both series, a substantial portion of the</textblock>
    <textblock>bonds is issued to different holders. H purchases bonds from</textblock>
    <textblock>both series. Under the exception in paragraph (c)(2)(ii) of this</textblock>
    <textblock>section, the Series A and Series B bonds purchased by H are not</textblock>
    <textblock>aggregated.</textblock>
    <textblock>Example 2. Tiered REMICs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Z forms a dual tier real estate</textblock>
    <textblock>mortgage investment conduit (REMIC). In the dual tier structure,</textblock>
    <textblock>Z forms REMIC A to acquire a pool of real estate mortgages and to</textblock>
    <textblock>issue a residual interest and several classes of regular</textblock>
    <textblock>interests. Contemporaneously, Z forms REMIC B to acquire as</textblock>
    <textblock>qualified mortgages all of the regular interests in REMIC A.</textblock>
    <textblock>REMIC B issues several classes of regular interests and a</textblock>
    <textblock>residual interest, and Z sells all of those interests to</textblock>
    <textblock>unrelated parties in a public offering. Under the general rule</textblock>
    <textblock>set out in paragraph (c)(1) of this section, all of the regular</textblock>
    <textblock>interests issued by REMIC A and held by REMIC B are treated as a</textblock>
    <textblock>single debt instrument for purposes of sections 1271 through</textblock>
    <textblock>1275.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d)</textblock>
    <textblock>Special rules for Treasury securities_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue price</textblock>
    <textblock>and issue date.</textblock>
    <textblock>The issue price of an issue of Treasury</textblock>
    <textblock>securities is the average price of the debt instruments sold.</textblock>
    <textblock>The issue date of an issue of Treasury securities is the first</textblock>
    <textblock>settlement date on which a substantial amount of the securities</textblock>
    <textblock>in the issue is sold.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Reopenings of Treasury securities_</textblock>
    <textblock>(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Treatment of</textblock>
    <textblock>additional Treasury securities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional Treasury securities</textblock>
    <textblock>issued in a qualified reopening are part of the same issue as the</textblock>
    <textblock>original Treasury securities and have the same issue date as the</textblock>
    <textblock>original Treasury securities. The issue price of both the</textblock>
    <textblock>original Treasury securities and the additional Treasury</textblock>
    <textblock>securities is the average price at which the original Treasury</textblock>
    <textblock>securities were sold. This paragraph (d)(2) applies to qualified</textblock>
    <textblock>reopenings that occur on or after March 25, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions_</textblock>
    <textblock>(A)</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional Treasury securities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional Treasury securities are Treasury securities with terms</textblock>
    <textblock>that are in all respects identical to the terms of the original</textblock>
    <textblock>Treasury securities and that are issued (without regard to</textblock>
    <textblock>paragraph (d)(2)(i) of this section) not more than 12 months</textblock>
    <textblock>after the original Treasury securities were first issued to the</textblock>
    <textblock>public.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
