<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00041</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-2-00028</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4832-5]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Public Water System Supervision Program Revision for Puerto Rico</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>United States Environmental Protection Agency (USEPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that Puerto Rico is revising its approved Public Water System Supervision Primacy Program. Puerto Rico has adopted drinking water regulations that satisfy the national Primary Drinking Water Regulations (NPDWR) for the Surface Water Treatment Rule (SWTR) and the Total Coliforms Rule (TCR) promulgated by USEPA on June 29, 1989 (54 FR 27486 and 54 FR 27544) respectively.</textblock>
    <textblock>The USEPA has determined that Puerto Rico's SWTR and TCR regulations are no less stringent than the corresponding Federal regulations and that Puerto Rico continues to meet all requirements for primary enforcement responsibility as specified in 40 CFR 142.10.</textblock>
    <textblock>All interested parties, other than Federal Agencies, may request a public hearing. A request for a public hearing must be submitted to the USEPA Regional Administrator at the address shown below within thirty (30) days after the date of this</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice. If a substantial request for a public hearing is made within the required thirty-day period, a public hearing will be held and a notice will be given in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>and a newspaper of general circulation. Frivolous or insubstantial requests for a hearing may be denied by the Regional Administrator. If no timely and appropriate request for a hearing is received and the Regional Administrator does not choose to hold a hearing on his or her own motion, this determination shall become final and effective thirty (30) days after publication of this</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any request for a public hearing shall include the following information:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The name, address and telephone number of the individual organization or other entity requesting a hearing;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A brief statement of the requesting person's interest in the Regional Administrator's determination and a brief statement on information that the requesting person intends to submit at such hearing; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The signature of the individual making the requests or, if the request is made on behalf of an organization or other entity, the signature of a responsible official of the organization or other entity.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Requests for Public Hearing shall be addressed to: Regional Administrator, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency_Region II, Jacob K. Javits Federal Building, 26 Federal Plaza, New York, New York 10278.</textblock>
    <textblock>All documents relating to this determination are available for inspection between the hours of 9 a.m. and 4:30 p.m., Monday through Friday, at the following offices:</textblock>
    <textblock>Puerto Rico Department of Health, Public Water System Supervision Program, Edificio A. Centro Medico, Call Box 70184, San Juan, Puerto Rico 00909.</textblock>
    <textblock>USEPA-Caribbean Field Office, Office 2A, Podiatry Center Building, 1413 Fernandez Juncos Avenue, Santurce, Puerto Rico 00909.</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency_Region II, Public Water System Supervision Section Room 853, Jacob K. Javits Federal Building, 26 Federal Plaza, New York, New York 10278.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Walter E. Andrews, Chief, Drinking and Groundwater Protection Branch, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency_Region II, (212) 264-1800.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1413 of the Safe Drinking Water Act, as amended, and 40 CFR 142.10 of the NPDWR.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 11, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William J. Muszynski,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Adminstrator, EPA, Region 2</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2283 Filed 2-1-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
