<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00040</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Section 1.1274A-1␣Special Rules for Certain Transactions Where</textblock>
    <textblock>Stated Principal Amount Does Not Exceed $2,800,000</textblock>
    <textblock>No comments were received on these regulations and no</textblock>
    <textblock>material changes were made to this section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1.1275-1␣Definitions</textblock>
    <textblock>In response to a comment, the definition of issue has been</textblock>
    <textblock>expanded. As a result, debt instruments issued in different</textblock>
    <textblock>markets or for different consideration can be part of the same</textblock>
    <textblock>issue.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1.1275-2␣Special Rules Relating to Debt Instruments</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations provide that all payments (other</textblock>
    <textblock>than qualified stated interest payments) consist first of accrued</textblock>
    <textblock>but unpaid OID, then of principal. Several commentators</textblock>
    <textblock>suggested that unscheduled prepayments should be treated as</textblock>
    <textblock>partial retirements of the debt instrument. In response to these</textblock>
    <textblock>comments, the final regulations add new rules for the treatment</textblock>
    <textblock>of pro rata prepayments. In general, a pro rata prepayment is an</textblock>
    <textblock>unscheduled payment made on a debt instrument prior to maturity</textblock>
    <textblock>that results in a substantially pro rata reduction of each</textblock>
    <textblock>payment of principal and interest remaining on the instrument.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a prepayment on a debt instrument is a pro rata prepayment,</textblock>
    <textblock>the prepayment is treated as a payment in retirement of a portion</textblock>
    <textblock>of the instrument, which may result in gain or loss to the</textblock>
    <textblock>holder. The gain or loss is calculated by assuming that the debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument consists of two instruments, one that is retired and</textblock>
    <textblock>one that remains outstanding, and by allocating the adjusted</textblock>
    <textblock>issue price, the holder's adjusted basis, and the accrued but</textblock>
    <textblock>unpaid qualified stated interest between the two instruments</textblock>
    <textblock>based on the portion of the instrument that is treated as retired</textblock>
    <textblock>by the pro rata prepayment. In the case of a pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>prepayment, the issuer may realize discharge of indebtedness</textblock>
    <textblock>income (as determined under §1.61-12) or repurchase premium (as</textblock>
    <textblock>determined under §1.163-7).</textblock>
    <textblock>Partial retirement treatment is restricted to pro rata</textblock>
    <textblock>prepayments because the IRS and Treasury believe that this type</textblock>
    <textblock>of prepayment is common. The extension of the rule to non-pro</textblock>
    <textblock>rata prepayments would add undue complexity to the regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, extension of the rule to non-pro rata prepayments</textblock>
    <textblock>may cause inappropriate recognition of gain or loss if, in</textblock>
    <textblock>addition to a prepayment, the interest rate or the payment</textblock>
    <textblock>schedule is altered. Furthermore, as noted by one commentator, a</textblock>
    <textblock>rule for non-pro rata prepayments may not be necessary because an</textblock>
    <textblock>unscheduled prepayment may, depending on the circumstances,</textblock>
    <textblock>result in a deemed exchange under section 1001.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations contain a number of rules that</textblock>
    <textblock>generally require a holder to follow the issuer's treatment of an</textblock>
    <textblock>item, such as whether a debt instrument is issued in a</textblock>
    <textblock>potentially abusive situation. In response to comments, the</textblock>
    <textblock>final regulations provide that the issuer must make information</textblock>
    <textblock>relating to its treatment of the item available to the holder in</textblock>
    <textblock>a reasonable manner.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1.1275-2T, which is published elsewhere in this</textblock>
    <textblock>issue of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, provides for an anti-abuse rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the rule, the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, in certain</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances, can apply or depart from the final regulations in</textblock>
    <textblock>a manner that ensures a reasonable result in light of the</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of the statutes governing OID.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
