<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00037</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940202-0-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>A commentator requested that an immediate deduction be</textblock>
    <textblock>allowed for a repurchase premium in a debt-for-debt exchange even</textblock>
    <textblock>if the issue price of the debt instrument received in the</textblock>
    <textblock>exchange is determined under section 1274. The IRS and Treasury,</textblock>
    <textblock>however, believe that taxpayers could inappropriately accelerate</textblock>
    <textblock>deductions in these situations because of the flexibility</textblock>
    <textblock>inherent in section 1274 for determining the issue price of a</textblock>
    <textblock>debt instrument. Thus, the final regulations retain the rule in</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1.446-2␣Method of Accounting for Interest</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations provide a special payment</textblock>
    <textblock>allocation rule for certain small transactions. Because of the</textblock>
    <textblock>rule's limited scope and uncertainty regarding its application,</textblock>
    <textblock>the IRS and Treasury believe that the rule should not be</textblock>
    <textblock>finalized. However, to allow further comment on the need for</textblock>
    <textblock>this rule, §1.446-2(e)(3) is reserved in the final regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>and remains in proposed form.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1.483-1 Through 1.483-3␣Unstated Interest</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations provide that stated or unstated</textblock>
    <textblock>interest under a contract subject to section 483 is taken into</textblock>
    <textblock>account under a taxpayer's regular method of accounting. One</textblock>
    <textblock>commentator suggested that an accrual method taxpayer should</textblock>
    <textblock>account for unstated interest in the year a payment is due, which</textblock>
    <textblock>was the rule in previous final regulations under section 483.</textblock>
    <textblock>The IRS and Treasury, however, believe that it is appropriate to</textblock>
    <textblock>treat stated and unstated interest consistently. Thus, the final</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations retain the rule in the proposed regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sections 1.1001-1(g) and 1.1012-1(g)␣Amount Realized and Basis</textblock>
    <textblock>If a debt instrument is issued in exchange for property, the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations provide that the issue price of the debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument is used to determine the seller's amount realized and</textblock>
    <textblock>the buyer's basis. The final regulations adopt the rules of the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations, but clarify the treatment of a debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument with an issue price determined under section</textblock>
    <textblock>1273(b)(4).</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1.1271-1␣Special Rules Applicable to Amounts Received on</textblock>
    <textblock>Retirement, Sale, or Exchange of Debt Instruments</textblock>
    <textblock>As requested by a commentator, the final regulations provide</textblock>
    <textblock>that the intention to call rules do not apply to debt instruments</textblock>
    <textblock>sold pursuant to a private placement memorandum that is</textblock>
    <textblock>distributed to more than ten offerees and that is subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>certain sanctions of the Securities Act of 1933 or the Securities</textblock>
    <textblock>Exchange Act of 1934.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 1.1272-1␣Current Inclusion of OID in Income</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations provide that accrual periods may be</textblock>
    <textblock>of any length and may vary in length over the term of the debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument, provided that each accrual period is not longer than</textblock>
    <textblock>one year and that all payments are made at the end of an accrual</textblock>
    <textblock>period. In response to one comment, the final regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>provide that payments also may be made on the first day of an</textblock>
    <textblock>accrual period.</textblock>
    <textblock>The rule permitting accrual periods to vary in length was</textblock>
    <textblock>provided in response to commentators who criticized the prior</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed regulations as too mechanical and inflexible. While</textblock>
    <textblock>commentators commended the flexibility of the rule, they noted</textblock>
    <textblock>that the rule raised several technical issues: (1) the accrual</textblock>
    <textblock>periods used to determine whether an instrument is an applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>high yield debt obligation under section 163(i); (2) the accrual</textblock>
    <textblock>periods used by a subsequent holder to determine adjusted issue</textblock>
    <textblock>price for purposes of OID accruals, market discount, and</textblock>
    <textblock>acquisition premium; and (3) the accrual periods used for Form</textblock>
    <textblock>1099 reporting. As noted above, §1.163-7 of the final</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations provides that the issuer's determination of accrual</textblock>
    <textblock>periods controls for purposes of determining whether a debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument is an applicable high yield debt obligation. In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition, §1.1275-1(b)(2) of the final regulations provides that</textblock>
    <textblock>a subsequent holder determines adjusted issue price for purposes</textblock>
    <textblock>of OID accruals, market discount, and acquisition premium in any</textblock>
    <textblock>manner consistent with these final regulations. Rules on Form</textblock>
    <textblock>1099 reporting will be addressed in a separate project. Until</textblock>
    <textblock>guidance regarding Form 1099 reporting is issued, however, an</textblock>
    <textblock>issuer should use the same accrual periods for Form 1099 purposes</textblock>
    <textblock>as it uses for computing OID deductions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed regulations provide rules to determine the</textblock>
    <textblock>yield and maturity of a debt instrument with a stated contingency</textblock>
    <textblock>that could result in the acceleration or deferral of payments if</textblock>
    <textblock>the timing and amounts payable upon occurrence of the contingency</textblock>
    <textblock>are fixed. The contingency is ignored unless, based on all the</textblock>
    <textblock>facts and circumstances, the contingency is more likely than not</textblock>
    <textblock>to occur. The final regulations clarify that this rule applies</textblock>
    <textblock>when the contingency, if triggered, would result in an</textblock>
    <textblock>alternative payment schedule as long as the timing and amounts of</textblock>
    <textblock>the payments comprising the alternative payment schedule are</textblock>
    <textblock>known as of the issue date. The final regulations also clarify</textblock>
    <textblock>that these rules apply if the debt instrument is subject to</textblock>
    <textblock>multiple contingencies that result in alternative payment</textblock>
    <textblock>schedules. The final regulations retain the rule in the proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>regulations for determining the yield and the maturity of a debt</textblock>
    <textblock>instrument in the case of a put or call option.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
