<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00019</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>COMMITTEE FOR THE IMPLEMENTATION OF TEXTILE AGREEMENTS</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Soliciting Public Comment on Bilateral Negotiations During 1994</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements (CITA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Announcement.</textblock>
  </action>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The U.S. Government anticipates holding negotiations during 1994 concerning expiring bilateral agreements covering certain cotton, wool, man-made fiber, silk blend and other vegetable fiber textiles and apparel from Bangladesh (January 31, 1995), Brazil (March 31, 1994), Dominican Republic (December 31, 1994), Guatemala (December 31, 1994), Haiti (December 31, 1994), Indonesia (June 30, 1994), Lesotho (November 30, 1994), Malaysia (December 31, 1994), Panama (March 31, 1994), Romania (December 31, 1994), Sri Lanka (June 30, 1994) and Uruguay (June 30, 1994). (The dates noted in parenthesis are the expiration dates of the agreements.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Anyone who wishes to comment or provide data or information regarding these agreements, or to comment on domestic production or availability of textiles and apparel affected by these agreements, is invited to submit such comments or information in 10 copies to Rita D. Hayes, Chairman, Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements, U.S. Department of Commerce, Washington, DC, 20230; ATTN: Helen L. LeGrande. The comments received will be considered in the context of the consultations held with respect to these agreements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because the exact timing of the consultations is not yet certain, comments should be submitted promptly. Comments or information submitted in response to this notice will be available for public inspection in the Office of Textiles and Apparel, room H3100, U.S. Department of Commerce, 14th and Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC. Further comment may be invited regarding particular comments or information received from the public which the Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements considers appropriate for further consideration.</textblock>
    <textblock>The solicitation of comments regarding any aspect of the agreements or the implementation thereof is not a waiver in any respect of the exemption contained in 5 U.S.C. 553(a)(1) relating to matters which constitute ``a foreign affairs function of the United States.''</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rita D. Hayes,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc.94-2614 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DR-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
