<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00006</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Regulations and Procedures Technical Advisory Committee; Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>A meeting of the Regulations and Procedures Technical Advisory Committee will be held February 24, 1994, at 9 a.m., in the Herbert C. Hoover Building, room 1617M(2), 14th Street and Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., Washington, DC. The Committee advises the Office of Technology and Policy Analysis on implementation of the Export Administration Regulations (EARS), and provides for continuing review to update the EARS as needed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agenda</textblock>
    <textblock>General Session</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Opening remarks by the Chairman</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Presentation of papers or comments by the public</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Discussion of Foreign Policy Report</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Regulatory Update</textblock>
    <textblock>5. RPTAC Working Group and Project Reports</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Session</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Discussion of matters properly classified under Executive Order 12356, dealing with the U.S. and COCOM control program and strategic criteria related thereto</textblock>
    <textblock>The General Session of the meeting will be open to the public and a limited number of seats will be available. To the extent that time permits, members of the public may present oral statements to the Committee. Written statements may be submitted at any time before or after the meeting. However, to facilitate the distribution of public presentation materials to the Committee members, the Committee suggests that presenters forward the public presentation materials two weeks prior to the meetings date to the following address: Ms. Lee Ann Carpenter, TAC Unit/OAS/EA, room 3886C, Bureau of Export Administration, U.S. Department of Commerce, Washington, DC 20230</textblock>
    <textblock>The Assistant Secretary for Administration, with the concurrence of the delegate of the General Counsel, formally determined on January 18, 1993, pursuant to section 10(d) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act, as amended, that the series of meetings or portions of meeting of the Committee and of any Subcommittees thereof, dealing with the classified materials listed in 5 U.S.C. 552b(c)(1) shall be exempt from the provisions relating to public meetings found in section 10 (a)(1) and (a)(3), of the Federal Advisory Committee Act. The remaining series of meetings or portions thereof will be open to the public.</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the Notice of Determination to close meetings or portions of meetings of the Committee is available for public inspection and copying in the Central Reference and Records Inspection Facility, room 6020, U.S. Department of Commerce, Washington, DC. For further information, call Lee Ann Carpenter at (202) 482-2583.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Export Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Betty Ferrell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Technical Advisory Committee Unit.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2612 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DT-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
