<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00064</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00039</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 31, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on December 3, 1993, Hill Transportation Company, Inc., (Hill) filed a motion for limited modification of the May 11, 1991, Stipulation and Agreement in Docket No. PR91-4-000. The purpose of the requested modification is to permit Hill to terminate transportation service under section 3111 of the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978 (NGPA), rather than filing to rejustify its section 311 rate under section 284.123(b)(2) of the Commission's regulations, as required by the settlement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Hill notes that the only section 311 service it provided, transportation for DeNovo Oil and Gas, Inc., (DeNovo) terminated on March 1, 1993. Hill provides no other Section 311 services. Hill states that in the event it reinstates service under Section 311, it will at that time make the appropriate filings under Part 284, Subpart C of the Commission's regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to participate in this proceeding must file a motion to intervene in accordance with Sections 385.211 and 385.214 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedures. All motions must be filed with the Secretary of the Commission on or before February 22, 1994. The motion is on file with the Commission and is available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. PR94-5-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Hill Transportation Company, Inc.; Motion to Modify Settlement</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2495 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
