<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00042</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00026</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>12. Wisconsin Public Service Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-904-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 13, 1994, Wisconsin Public Service Corporation (WPSC) tendered for filing a modification to its service agreement with the City of Wisconsin Rapids Water Works and Lighting Commission, pursuant to which Wisconsin Rapids takes service under WPSC's W-1 Tariff. The modification provides for Wisconsin Rapids to take a service on a month-to-month basis pending the effective date of a power supply agreement between WPSC and Wisconsin Rapids.</textblock>
    <textblock>WPSC states that copies of this filing have been served on Wisconsin Rapids and on the Public Service Commission of Wisconsin and that a copy has been posted in accord with Commission regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 10, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>13. WestPlains Energy, a Division of UtiliCorp United, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-907-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 14, 1994, WestPlains Energy, a division of UtiliCorp United, Inc. (WestPlains) tendered for filing revised full requirements contracts between WestPlains and the cities of Isabel and Luray Kansas. Both of these cities currently take full requirements service pursuant to Service Schedule 88-MWH-5. Under the new agreements, the cities will take service pursuant to existing Service Schedule 89-MWH-5. WestPlains requests that the agreements be made effective as soon as practicable, but in no event later than 60 days from the date of this filing</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the filing was served on each of the cities and the Kansas Corporation Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 10, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>14. Panda-Brandywine, L.P.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. QF94-31-001]</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 28, 1993, Panda-Brandywine, L.P. of 4100 Spring Valley Road, Suite 1001, Dallas, Texas 75244, submitted for filing an application for certification of a facility as a qualifying cogeneration facility pursuant to section 292.207(b) of the Commission's Regulations. No determination has been made that the submittal constitutes a complete filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>According to the applicant, the topping-cycle cogeneration facility, which will be located in Brandywine, Maryland, will consist of two combustion turbines, and two heat recovery steam generators with a maximum net electric power production capacity of 283 MW. Installation of the facility is expected to commence in October, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>Thirty days from publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Standard Paragraphs</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with Rules 211 and 214 of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (18 CFR 385.211 and 18 CFR 385.214). All such motions or protests should be filed on or before the comment date. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2566 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
