<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00070</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The California Environmental Quality Act and California Endangered</textblock>
    <textblock>Species Act are the primary environmental legislation passed at the</textblock>
    <textblock>State level that potentially benefits the conservation of the Alameda</textblock>
    <textblock>whipsnake. The animal was listed as a threatened species by the State</textblock>
    <textblock>of California in 1971 (California Department of Fish and Game 1987).</textblock>
    <textblock>Although these State laws provide a measure of protection to the species</textblock>
    <textblock>and have resulted in the formulation of mitigation measures to reduce or</textblock>
    <textblock>offset impacts for projects proposed in certain Alameda whipsnake</textblock>
    <textblock>habitats, these laws are not adequate to protect the species in all</textblock>
    <textblock>cases. Numerous activities do not fall under the purview of this</textblock>
    <textblock>legislation, such as certain projects proposed by the Federal government</textblock>
    <textblock>and projects falling under State statutory exemptions. Where overriding</textblock>
    <textblock>social and economic considerations can be demonstrated, these laws allow</textblock>
    <textblock>project proposals to go forward, even in cases where the continued</textblock>
    <textblock>existence of the species may be jeopardized or where adverse impacts are</textblock>
    <textblock>not mitigated to the point of insignificance.</textblock>
    <textblock>E.</textblock>
    <textblock>Other natural or man-made factors affecting their continued</textblock>
    <textblock>existence</textblock>
    <textblock>. Use of insecticides could be a threat to the two butterfly</textblock>
    <textblock>species. Silverspot butterfly larvae are extremely sensitive to</textblock>
    <textblock>pesticides and even the accumulation of runoff in the soil after</textblock>
    <textblock>spraying has proven lethal to the larvae of members of the genus</textblock>
    <textblock>Speyeria</textblock>
    <textblock>(Mattoon</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1971). There is the potential that species in</textblock>
    <textblock>the food chain of the snake would be impacted as well.</textblock>
    <textblock>High levels of grazing by livestock may pose a threat to the extant</textblock>
    <textblock>populations of the two butterfly species. Overgrazing could cause</textblock>
    <textblock>trampling and the ingestion of the larval foodplants and the adult</textblock>
    <textblock>nectar sources. Low levels of grazing could allow other plants to</textblock>
    <textblock>outcompete the species required by the callippe and Behren's silverspot</textblock>
    <textblock>butterflies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Grazing has adversely affected the habitat of the Alameda whipsnake</textblock>
    <textblock>in many areas east of the coast range (McGinnis 1992). Livestock</textblock>
    <textblock>grazing that significantly reduces or eliminates shrub and grass cover</textblock>
    <textblock>is detrimental to this animal. Most snake species, including the</textblock>
    <textblock>Alameda whipsnake, avoid open barren areas because of the increased</textblock>
    <textblock>danger from predators and the lack of prey (McGinnis 1992). Overgrazing</textblock>
    <textblock>has eliminated otherwise suitable Alameda whipsnake habitat in the area</textblock>
    <textblock>between Black Diamond Mines Regional Park and Marsh Creek Road in Contra</textblock>
    <textblock>Costa County and along the west facing slopes of the Altamont Pass</textblock>
    <textblock>region between Vasco Road and Altamont Pass Road in Alameda County.</textblock>
    <textblock>Off-road vehicles and human or horse foot traffic may pose a threat</textblock>
    <textblock>to the colonies of the two butterfly species. These activities could</textblock>
    <textblock>result in harassment, injury, or death of individuals of these two</textblock>
    <textblock>species by trampling or crushing the eggs, larvae, or pupae.</textblock>
    <textblock>Adequate levels of</textblock>
    <textblock>Viola</textblock>
    <textblock>are critical for the long-term survival of</textblock>
    <textblock>populations of the two butterfly species (Mattoon,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1989,</textblock>
    <textblock>1991). However, California's native grassland and coastal prairie have</textblock>
    <textblock>been adversely affected by the introduction and invasion of numerous</textblock>
    <textblock>non-native plants (Heady 1988, Heady et al. 1988). Often these</textblock>
    <textblock>introduced and alien plants, such as iceplant (</textblock>
    <textblock>Carprobrotus</textblock>
    <textblock>sp.), gum</textblock>
    <textblock>trees (</textblock>
    <textblock>Eucalyptus</textblock>
    <textblock>spp.), and French broom (</textblock>
    <textblock>Ulex europaeus</textblock>
    <textblock>), outcompete</textblock>
    <textblock>and largely supplant the native vegetation. Without control and</textblock>
    <textblock>eradication programs, the introduced and alien taxa will continue to</textblock>
    <textblock>invade and eliminate the remaining native plant communities, including</textblock>
    <textblock>the host plants of the callippe and Behren's silverspot butterflies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Non-native vegetative communities also may eliminate habitat for the</textblock>
    <textblock>Alameda whipsnake.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
