<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00017</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Small Entities</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. 601</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>), the Coast Guard must consider whether this regulation will have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities. ``Small Entities'' include independently owned and operated small businesses that are not dominant in their field and that otherwise qualify as ``small business concerns'' under section 3 of the Small Business Act (15 U.S.C. 632). It is anticipated that the impact of this regulation on non-participating small entities will actually benefit their business due to the increase in local tourism. The Coast Guard will certify under 5 U.S.C. 605(b), that this regulation will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federalism Assessment</textblock>
    <textblock>This action has been analyzed in accordance with the principles and criteria contained in Executive Order 12612, and it is anticipated that this regulation will not raise sufficient federalism implications to warrant the preparation of a Federalism Assessment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Assessment</textblock>
    <textblock>This regulation has been thoroughly reviewed by the Coast Guard and determined to be categorically excluded from further environmental documentation in accordance with section 2.B.2.c of Commandant Instruction M16475.1B. A Categorical Exclusion Determination statement has been prepared and placed in the rulemaking docket, and is available for inspection or copying where indicated under</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 33 CFR Part 100</textblock>
    <textblock>Marine safety, Navigation (water), Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Waterways.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>In consideration of the foregoing, part 100 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 100_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 100 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>33 U.S.C. 1233; 49 CFR 1.46 and 33 CFR 100.35.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. A new §100.520 is added to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§100.520</textblock>
    <textblock>Rudee Inlet, Lake Rudee, Atlantic Ocean, Virginia Beach, Virginia.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Regulated area. The waters of Rudee Inlet and Lake Rudee including the Owl Creek Boat Ramp. The waters of the Atlantic Ocean enclosed by:</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Coast Guard Patrol Commander.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Coast Guard Patrol Commander will be a commissioned, warrant, or petty officer who will be designated by the Commander, Group Hampton Roads.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Special local regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Except for persons or vessels authorized by the Coast Guard Patrol Commander, no person or vessel may enter or remain in the regulated area.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The operator of any vessel in the immediate vicinity of this area shall:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Stop the vessel immediately upon being directed to do so by any commissioned, warrant, or petty officer on board a vessel displaying a Coast Guard ensign.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Proceed as directed by any commissioned, warrant, or petty officer on board a vessel displaying a Coast Guard ensign.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Any spectator vessel may anchor outside of the regulated area specified in paragraph (a)(1) of these regulations but may not block a navigable channel.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c)</textblock>
    <textblock>Effective period.</textblock>
    <textblock>This section is effective during, and one hour before any scheduled event starts. The Commander, Fifth Coast Guard District will publish a notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>and the Fifth Coast Guard District Local Notice to Mariners that announces the times and dates that this section is in effect.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 13, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>Latitude</textblock>
    <textblock>1Longitude</textblock>
    <textblock>36</textblock>
    <textblock>○54</textblock>
    <textblock>’23.0</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N</textblock>
    <textblock>75</textblock>
    <textblock>○59</textblock>
    <textblock>’26.0</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W</textblock>
    <textblock>36</textblock>
    <textblock>○54</textblock>
    <textblock>’38.0</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N</textblock>
    <textblock>75</textblock>
    <textblock>○56</textblock>
    <textblock>’55.0</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W</textblock>
    <textblock>36</textblock>
    <textblock>○49</textblock>
    <textblock>’06.0</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N</textblock>
    <textblock>75</textblock>
    <textblock>○55</textblock>
    <textblock>’58.0</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W</textblock>
    <textblock>36</textblock>
    <textblock>○48</textblock>
    <textblock>’53.0</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ N</textblock>
    <textblock>75</textblock>
    <textblock>○57</textblock>
    <textblock>’58.0</textblock>
    <textblock>’</textblock>
    <textblock>’ W</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>W.T. Leland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Rear Admiral, U.S. Coast Guard, Commander, Fifth Coast Guard District.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2604 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-14-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
