<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00068</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Ms. Dee Warenycia petitioned the Service to list the callippe</textblock>
    <textblock>silverspot butterfly as an endangered species in a letter dated January</textblock>
    <textblock>14, 1991, which was received on January 22, 1991. The Service completed</textblock>
    <textblock>a status review and determined that enough information exists to propose</textblock>
    <textblock>the species for listing. This proposal constitutes the final finding</textblock>
    <textblock>for the petitioned action.</textblock>
    <textblock>On March 20, 1975, Behren's silverspot butterfly was listed as 1 of</textblock>
    <textblock>42 insects whose status was being reviewed for listing as either</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered or threatened by the Service (40 FR 12691). This insect was</textblock>
    <textblock>listed as a category 2 species in the May 22, 1984 (49 FR 21664), and</textblock>
    <textblock>January 6, 1989 (54 FR 554), Animal Notices of Review. Dr. Dennis</textblock>
    <textblock>Murphy of Stanford University petitioned the Service to list Behren's</textblock>
    <textblock>silverspot butterfly as an endangered species in a letter dated June 28,</textblock>
    <textblock>1989, which was received on June 29, 1989. The Service determined that</textblock>
    <textblock>the petition contained substantial information indicating that the</textblock>
    <textblock>requested action may be warranted and published notice of the 90-day</textblock>
    <textblock>finding on November 1, 1990 (55 FR 46080). The Service did not receive</textblock>
    <textblock>any new information in response to the November 1, 1990, notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>However, the species was listed as a category 1 species in the November</textblock>
    <textblock>21, 1991 (56 FR 58804), Animal Notice of Review on the basis of</textblock>
    <textblock>significant increases in habitat loss and threats occurring throughout</textblock>
    <textblock>its range. This proposal constitutes the final finding for the</textblock>
    <textblock>petitioned action.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Alameda whipsnake (as the Alameda striped racer) was listed as</textblock>
    <textblock>a category 2 candidate species in the September 18, 1985 (50 FR 37958),</textblock>
    <textblock>Vertebrate Wildlife Notice of Review. In the January 6, 1989 (54 FR</textblock>
    <textblock>554), Animal Notice of Review, the Service again included the Alameda</textblock>
    <textblock>whipsnake as a category 2 candidate species and solicited additional</textblock>
    <textblock>information on its status. The November 21, 1991 (56 FR 58804), Animal</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Review included the Alameda whipsnake as a category 1</textblock>
    <textblock>candidate species on the basis of significant increases in habitat loss</textblock>
    <textblock>and threats occurring throughout its range.</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposal to list the callippe silverspot butterfly, Behren's</textblock>
    <textblock>silverspot butterfly, and Alameda whipsnake is based on the best</textblock>
    <textblock>available scientific and commercial information, various scientific</textblock>
    <textblock>papers and unpublished reports available to the Service, and information</textblock>
    <textblock>gathered from various scientists specializing in these taxa, especially</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Sterling Mattoon and Mr. John Steiner.</textblock>
    <textblock>Summary of Factors Affecting the Species</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 4 of the Endangered Species Act (16 U.S.C. 1531</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>)</textblock>
    <textblock>and regulations (50 CFR part 424) promulgated to implement the listing</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions of the Act set forth the procedures for adding species to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Lists. Species may be determined to be endangered or threatened due to one or more of the five factors described in section 4(a)(1).</textblock>
    <textblock>These factors and their application to the callippe silverspot butterfly</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>Speyeria callippe callippe</textblock>
    <textblock>), Behren's silverspot butterfly (</textblock>
    <textblock>Speyeria</textblock>
    <textblock>zerene behrensii</textblock>
    <textblock>), and Alameda whipsnake (</textblock>
    <textblock>Masticophis lateralis</textblock>
    <textblock>euryxanthus</textblock>
    <textblock>) are as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>A.</textblock>
    <textblock>The present or threatened destruction, modification, or</textblock>
    <textblock>curtailment of their habitat or range</textblock>
    <textblock>. The primary cause of the</textblock>
    <textblock>declines of the callippe silverspot butterfly, Behren's silverspot</textblock>
    <textblock>butterfly, and Alameda whipsnake is the loss of habitat from human</textblock>
    <textblock>activities. These species are imperiled by the current and potential</textblock>
    <textblock>future destruction and alteration of their habitats due to off-road</textblock>
    <textblock>vehicle use, trampling by hikers and equestrians, unsuitable levels of</textblock>
    <textblock>livestock grazing, and invasive exotic vegetation. The Alameda</textblock>
    <textblock>whipsnake and Behren's silverspot butterfly also are imperiled by</textblock>
    <textblock>residential and commercial development. Off-road vehicles and human or</textblock>
    <textblock>horse trampling pose threats to the colonies of the two butterfly</textblock>
    <textblock>species as these activities could crush the foodplants of the larvae or</textblock>
    <textblock>the adult nectar sources.</textblock>
    <textblock>The callippe silverspot butterfly was once more widespread in the</textblock>
    <textblock>San Francisco Bay Area. At least five populations of this species have</textblock>
    <textblock>been eliminated by urban development and other causes. The species</textblock>
    <textblock>currently is known only from two sites in San Mateo and Alameda</textblock>
    <textblock>Counties. One of the known extant populations of the callippe</textblock>
    <textblock>silverspot butterfly is located in a city park. This colony is small</textblock>
    <textblock>and may be imperiled by human-induced and natural causes (Mattoon,</textblock>
    <textblock>in</textblock>
    <textblock>litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1991). The other known extant population of the callippe</textblock>
    <textblock>silverspot butterfly is found on San Bruno Mountain in San Mateo County</textblock>
    <textblock>(Mattoon,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1991; Thomas Reid Associates 1982). Although the</textblock>
    <textblock>majority of the natural areas on San Bruno Mountain have been preserved</textblock>
    <textblock>and will remain undeveloped in perpetuity, collection of specimens by</textblock>
    <textblock>amateur lepidopterists poses a threat, as discussed under Factor B.</textblock>
    <textblock>Behren's silverspot butterfly has been extirpated from a</textblock>
    <textblock>significant portion of its former range, which extended from the mouth</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Russian River in Sonoma County north to southern Mendocino</textblock>
    <textblock>County. One of the six known historic colonies was eliminated by a</textblock>
    <textblock>housing development (Mattoon,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt</textblock>
    <textblock>., 1989). No specimens have been</textblock>
    <textblock>observed at the other historic colonies since 1987. Currently, this</textblock>
    <textblock>animal is known only from a recently discovered locality northwest of</textblock>
    <textblock>the town of Point Arena in Mendocino County (Sally DeBecker, Pacific Gas</textblock>
    <textblock>and Electric, pers. comm., 1990). The site is subject to grazing by</textblock>
    <textblock>livestock. Although no plans have been proposed for the site, urban</textblock>
    <textblock>development is occurring in the area.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
