<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00044</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Summary of Comments and Recommendations</textblock>
    <textblock>In the December 11, 1992 proposed rule, all interested parties were</textblock>
    <textblock>requested to submit factual reports or information that might contribute</textblock>
    <textblock>to the development of a final determination. Appropriate Federal and</textblock>
    <textblock>State agencies, county governments, scientific organizations, and other</textblock>
    <textblock>interested parties were contacted and requested to comment. Newspaper</textblock>
    <textblock>notices were published in The Los Angeles Times on January 1, 1993, The</textblock>
    <textblock>San Francisco Sunday Examiner and Chronicle on January 3, 1993, and The</textblock>
    <textblock>San Diego Union-Tribune on February 4, 1993. The public comment period</textblock>
    <textblock>ended on February 9, 1993. A total of 548 comments were received. The</textblock>
    <textblock>Service received one letter from a Federal agency, three letters from</textblock>
    <textblock>State offices, and five from city or county agencies. Five hundred and</textblock>
    <textblock>ten of the comments were post cards from individuals urging support for</textblock>
    <textblock>the listing of the species. The Service received 29 letters from</textblock>
    <textblock>individuals and private organizations. Of those, only one expressed an</textblock>
    <textblock>opinion in opposition to listing the tidewater goby as endangered.</textblock>
    <textblock>The National Park Service (Santa Monica Mountains National</textblock>
    <textblock>Recreation Area) stated support for the listing of the tidewater goby as</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered and suggested locations within the recreation area boundaries</textblock>
    <textblock>that may be candidates for reintroduction of the species. The National</textblock>
    <textblock>Park Service also sought assistance from the Service in determining</textblock>
    <textblock>potential habitat locations on lands not under public ownership that may</textblock>
    <textblock>be acquired under its land acquisition program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Three California State agencies offered comments. The Topanga-Las</textblock>
    <textblock>Virgenes Resource Conservation District, a subdivision of State</textblock>
    <textblock>government, expressed full support for the listing of the goby. The</textblock>
    <textblock>California Coastal Commission stated, ``The acute vulnerability of the</textblock>
    <textblock>tidewater goby to man-induced changes of estuarine habitat makes the</textblock>
    <textblock>development of comprehensive management strategies and plans, including</textblock>
    <textblock>development of recovery plans, for this species imperative.'' The</textblock>
    <textblock>California Department of Fish and Game submitted information pertaining</textblock>
    <textblock>to a project to reestablish a population of tidewater gobies on Waddell</textblock>
    <textblock>Creek Lagoon. The population was reintroduced in the fall of 1991 and</textblock>
    <textblock>subsequently sampled in November 1992. Gobies were reported from three</textblock>
    <textblock>sites in the lagoon. The Department will continue to obtain information</textblock>
    <textblock>on that population as it is surveyed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Five letters of information were received from city or county</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies. Two of these, one from the County of Santa Barbara Resource</textblock>
    <textblock>Management Department and one from the City of Santa Cruz, detailed</textblock>
    <textblock>population occurrences that were already known to the Service. Two</textblock>
    <textblock>letters from the cities of San Buenaventura and Santa Barbara cited</textblock>
    <textblock>possible impacts to goby habitat due to proposed or ongoing projects.</textblock>
    <textblock>These letters listed threats that are discussed under Factor A in the</textblock>
    <textblock>``Summary of Factors Affecting the Species'' section. The Santa Barbara</textblock>
    <textblock>County Flood Control and Water Conservation District stated support for</textblock>
    <textblock>listing, but expressed concerns regarding the designation of critical</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Environmental Defense Center identified three issues concerning</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 1:</textblock>
    <textblock>The critical habitat finding failed to meet the standards</textblock>
    <textblock>of section 4 of the Endangered Species Act and under</textblock>
    <textblock>Northern Spotted</textblock>
    <textblock>Owl</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Lujan,</textblock>
    <textblock>758 F. Supp. 621 (W.D. Wash. 1991).</textblock>
    <textblock>Service Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service concurs that critical habitat should</textblock>
    <textblock>be designated for the tidewater goby. Information needed to complete</textblock>
    <textblock>required economic impact analyses consists of identifying Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>actions that might be precluded or modified by the destruction/adverse</textblock>
    <textblock>modification standard but not by the jeopardy standard. Moreover, it</textblock>
    <textblock>will be necessary to describe how these actions may be modified by</textblock>
    <textblock>application of the destruction/adverse modification standard. This</textblock>
    <textblock>information will provide a basis for analyses on the economic effects of</textblock>
    <textblock>designating critical habitat.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
