<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00112</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00081</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act and Section 908 of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Emergency Unemployment Compensation Act of 1991 and the Unemployment Compensation Amendments of 1993, the Secretary of Labor has renewed the charter of the Advisory Council on Unemployment Compensation (hereinafter called the Council).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Council will advise the President and Congress on the effectiveness of the unemployment compensation program and shall conduct a study to evaluate the unemployment compensation program, including the purpose, goals, countercyclical effectiveness, coverage, benefit adequacy, trust fund solvency, funding of State administrative costs, administrative efficiency and any other aspects of the program and make recommendations for improvement.</textblock>
    <textblock>No later than February 1, 1995, the Council shall prepare and submit a written report to the President and to the appropriate committees of Congress. This report will contain_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) The findings and recommendations of the Council as a result of its evaluation of the unemployment compensation program under Section 908 of the Social Security Act; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) The findings and recommendations with respect to determining eligibility for extended unemployment benefits on the basis of unemployment statistics for regions, States, or subdivisions of States.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Council's renewed charter is for two years.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Unemployment Insurance Service of the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor will provide the Council with appropriate administrative assistance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons are invited to submit comments regarding the charter renewal of the Advisory Council on Unemployment Compensation. Such comments should be addressed to: Esther R. Johnson, Department of Labor, Employment and Training Administration, Unemployment Insurance Service, 200 Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20210; Telephone (202) 219-7831.</textblock>
    <textblock>Signed at Washington, D.C. this 31st day of January 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Advisory Council on Unemployment Compensation; Notice of Renewal</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Doug Ross,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary of Labor.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2544 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 a.m.]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4510-30-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
