<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00063</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Service has carefully assessed the best scientific and</textblock>
    <textblock>commercial information available regarding the past, present, and future</textblock>
    <textblock>threats faced by these taxa in determining to make this rule final.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because three of the four plants are threatened by one or more of the</textblock>
    <textblock>following factors_urban and agricultural development, recreational</textblock>
    <textblock>use, sand mining, dune stabilization projects, or extinction from</textblock>
    <textblock>stochastic events_the preferred action is to list</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegiana, Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>(inclusive of vars.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegii</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>), and</textblock>
    <textblock>Erysimum teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>as endangered. Other alternatives</textblock>
    <textblock>to this action were considered but not preferred because not listing</textblock>
    <textblock>these species at all or listing these species as threatened would not</textblock>
    <textblock>provide adequate protection and would not be in keeping with the</textblock>
    <textblock>purposes of the Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>is also threatened by the same</textblock>
    <textblock>factors listed above, as well as by ongoing military activities on the</textblock>
    <textblock>Fort Ord Army Base and its pending disposal. However, the wider range</textblock>
    <textblock>and greater number of populations and individuals of this species</textblock>
    <textblock>indicate that it is not now in danger of extinction throughout a</textblock>
    <textblock>significant portion of its range, as are the other three species, but is</textblock>
    <textblock>likely to become endangered within the foreseeable future. Therefore,</textblock>
    <textblock>the preferred action is to list</textblock>
    <textblock>C. pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>as threatened.</textblock>
    <textblock>Not listing this species would not provide adequate protection and would</textblock>
    <textblock>not be in keeping with the purposes of the Act. For reasons discussed</textblock>
    <textblock>below, the Service is not designating critical habitat for these species</textblock>
    <textblock>at this time.</textblock>
    <textblock>Critical Habitat</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 4(a)(3) of the Act, as amended, requires that, to the</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum extent prudent and determinable, the Secretary designate</textblock>
    <textblock>critical habitat at the time a species is determined to be endangered or</textblock>
    <textblock>threatened. Section 4(b)(6)(C) further indicates that a concurrent</textblock>
    <textblock>critical habitat designation is not required if the Service finds that a</textblock>
    <textblock>prompt determination of endangered or threatened status is essential to</textblock>
    <textblock>the conservation of the involved species or that critical habitat is not</textblock>
    <textblock>then determinable. The Service finds that designation of critical</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat for</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>is</textblock>
    <textblock>prudent but presently not determinable and that designation of critical</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat for</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegiana</textblock>
    <textblock>and for</textblock>
    <textblock>Erysimum</textblock>
    <textblock>teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>is not prudent.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service will propose designation of critical habitat for</textblock>
    <textblock>certain populations of</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>that would likely not be imperiled by the threat of vandalism,</textblock>
    <textblock>collecting, or other human activities. Section 7(a)(2) requires Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies to insure that their activities are not likely to destroy or</textblock>
    <textblock>adversely modify critical habitat of a listed species. This stipulation</textblock>
    <textblock>for Federal agencies is in addition to the requirement to insure that</textblock>
    <textblock>their actions do not jeopardize the continued existence of federally</textblock>
    <textblock>listed species. Therefore on lands where Federal actions, funding,</textblock>
    <textblock>authorizations, or licensing occurs, critical habitat would provide an</textblock>
    <textblock>added benefit to the conservation of these species. On non-Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>land, the designation of critical habitat may result in increased</textblock>
    <textblock>awareness of the need for protection. The designation of critical</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat could be useful for State landowners because they could use the</textblock>
    <textblock>designation to identify areas of special concern and to help establish</textblock>
    <textblock>priorities for their own land management.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 4(b)(2) of the Act requires the Service to consider</textblock>
    <textblock>economic and other impacts of designating a particular area as critical</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat. The Service must evaluate the effects of activities that occur</textblock>
    <textblock>within the ranges of these plants. The Service must gather data on</textblock>
    <textblock>precise habitat needs and ownership boundaries to be able to precisely</textblock>
    <textblock>define the critical habitat of these two plant taxa. In addition, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Service must analyze the economic impacts that could result from the</textblock>
    <textblock>designation of particular areas as critical habitat. Designation of</textblock>
    <textblock>critical habitat for</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>is currently not determinable due to the need for this type of</textblock>
    <textblock>information. A proposal to designate critical habitat at this time</textblock>
    <textblock>would delay this final rule to list the species as threatened or</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered. The Service believes that a prompt determination of</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered or threatened status for these species is essential to ensure</textblock>
    <textblock>the benefits of conservation measures provided to species upon listing under the Act. Once the Service has gathered the necessary data, it</textblock>
    <textblock>will publish a proposal to designate critical habitat for</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe</textblock>
    <textblock>robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
