<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00105</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00076</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Burlington Northern Railroad Company; Abandonment Exemption in King County, WA</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>INTERSTATE COMMERCE COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. AB-6 (Sub-No. 357X)]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interstate Commerce Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of exemption.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission exempts from the prior approval requirements of 49 U.S.C. 10903-10904 the abandonment by Burlington Northern Railroad Company (BN) of a 3.57-mile rail line between Interbay and Terry Avenue in Seattle, WA [BN Engineering Station (ES) 267+00 to ES 143+48 and ES 118+28.7-6+60.3 to ES 34+55.2]. The Commission issues a notice of interim trail use for the line and also makes the exemption subject to standard employee protective conditions and a condition that BN consult with the State of Washington Department of Ecology and the Seattle District of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers prior to initiating any salvage activities.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Provided no formal expression of intent to file an offer of financial assistance has been received, this exemption will be effective on March 6, 1994. Formal expressions of intent to file an offer</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>of financial assistance under 49 CFR 1152.27(c)(2) must be filed by February 14, 1994 and requests for a public use condition must be filed by February 24, 1994. Petitions to stay must be filed by February 22, 1994, and petitions to reopen must be filed by March 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See Exempt. of Rail Abandonment_Offers of Finan. Assist., 4 I.C.C.2d 164 (1987).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send pleadings referring to Docket No. AB-6 (Sub-No. 357X) to: (1) Office of the Secretary, Case Control Branch, Interstate Commerce Commission, Washington, DC 20423; (2) Petitioner's representative: Sarah J. Whitley, 3800 Continental Plaza, 777 Main Street, Fort Worth, Texas 76012-5384.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Richard B. Felder (202) 927-5610 [TDD for hearing impaired: (202) 927-5721].</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Additional information is contained in the Commission's decision. To purchase a copy of the full decision, write to, call, or pick up in person from: Dynamic Concepts, Inc., room 2229, Interstate Commerce Commission Building, Washington, DC 20423. Telephone: (202) 289-4357/4359. [Assistance for the hearing impaired is available through TDD service (202) 927-5721.]</textblock>
    <textblock>Decided: January 27, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Commission, Chairman McDonald, Vice Chairman Phillips, Commissioners Simmons, and Philbin.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Sidney L. Strickland, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2581 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7035-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
