<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00047</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The California Coastal Act regulates the approval of developments</textblock>
    <textblock>within the coastal zone. Although a significant slowing in wetland</textblock>
    <textblock>losses has occurred, the continued loss and degradation of coastal</textblock>
    <textblock>wetlands since the California Coastal Act was enacted in 1974 attests</textblock>
    <textblock>to the limitations of this legislation.</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Other natural or manmade factors affecting its continued</textblock>
    <textblock>existence.</textblock>
    <textblock>By far, the most significant natural factor adversely</textblock>
    <textblock>affecting the tidewater goby is drought and resultant deterioration of</textblock>
    <textblock>coastal and riparian habitats. California has recently experienced 5</textblock>
    <textblock>consecutive years of lower than average rainfall. These drought</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions, when combined with human induced water reductions (i.e.,</textblock>
    <textblock>diversions of water from streams, excessive groundwater withdrawals),</textblock>
    <textblock>have degraded coastal and riparian ecosystems and have created extremely</textblock>
    <textblock>stressful conditions for most aquatic species. Formerly large</textblock>
    <textblock>populations of tidewater gobies have declined in numbers because of the</textblock>
    <textblock>reduced availability of suitable lagoon habitats (i.e., San Simeon</textblock>
    <textblock>Creek, Pico Creek), others disappeared when the lagoons dried (i.e.,</textblock>
    <textblock>Santa Rosa Creek). In San Luis Obispo County alone, 6 of 20 populations</textblock>
    <textblock>of tidewater gobies were extirpated between 1984 and 1989 because of</textblock>
    <textblock>drought, water diversions, and pollution (K. Worcester, pers. comm.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1991).</textblock>
    <textblock>Habitat degradation and losses of the tidewater goby from weather</textblock>
    <textblock>related phenomena commonly occur due to the restriction of the species</textblock>
    <textblock>to coastal lagoon systems and its dependence on freshwater inflows.</textblock>
    <textblock>Events such as river flooding and heavy rainfall have been reported to</textblock>
    <textblock>destroy goby burrows and wash gobies out to sea. Storm surges that</textblock>
    <textblock>enter a lagoon may also adversely affect entire goby populations by</textblock>
    <textblock>rapidly changing its salinity.</textblock>
    <textblock>The tidewater goby was undoubtedly subjected to such natural flood</textblock>
    <textblock>events even before major human alteration of drainage basins. As</textblock>
    <textblock>mentioned under Factor A, channelization and urbanization have increased</textblock>
    <textblock>the frequency and perhaps the intensity of such flood events. In</textblock>
    <textblock>addition, populations of gobies are becoming more isolated from one</textblock>
    <textblock>another as intervening populations are extirpated, thus further</textblock>
    <textblock>decreasing the likelihood of successfully colonizing and reestablishing</textblock>
    <textblock>a population lost to a ``natural'' flood.</textblock>
    <textblock>Competition with introduced species is a potential threat to the</textblock>
    <textblock>tidewater goby. Although problems have not been documented so far, the</textblock>
    <textblock>spread of two introduced oriental gobies (yellowfin goby (</textblock>
    <textblock>Acanthogobius</textblock>
    <textblock>flavimanus</textblock>
    <textblock>) and chameleon goby (</textblock>
    <textblock>Tridentiger trigonocephalus</textblock>
    <textblock>)) may have a detrimental effect on the tidewater goby. According to Swift</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1990), the chameleon goby was recently found in Pyramid Lake, probably</textblock>
    <textblock>imported with central California water. If this goby becomes</textblock>
    <textblock>established in the Santa Clara River as other imported species have</textblock>
    <textblock>(e.g., prickly sculpin (</textblock>
    <textblock>Cottus asper</textblock>
    <textblock>)), the tidewater goby population at</textblock>
    <textblock>the mouth of the Santa Clara River may be at risk.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service has carefully assessed the best scientific and</textblock>
    <textblock>commercial information available regarding the past, present, and future</textblock>
    <textblock>threats faced by this species in determining to make this rule final.</textblock>
    <textblock>The tidewater goby has been extirpated from nearly 50 percent of the</textblock>
    <textblock>lagoons within its historic range, including 74 percent of the lagoons</textblock>
    <textblock>south of Morro Bay. Forty-three populations remain; however, only six</textblock>
    <textblock>are large in number and reasonably free from immediate threats. Based</textblock>
    <textblock>on this evaluation, the preferred action is to list the tidewater goby</textblock>
    <textblock>as endangered. The tidewater goby has experienced a substantial decline</textblock>
    <textblock>throughout its historic range and faces threats indicating that this</textblock>
    <textblock>downward trend is likely to continue. This species lives within</textblock>
    <textblock>specific habitat zones that have been, and will continue to be, targeted</textblock>
    <textblock>for development and degradation by human activities. The goby is</textblock>
    <textblock>extremely vulnerable to adverse habitat modification and water quality</textblock>
    <textblock>changes. The tidewater goby is in imminent danger of extinction</textblock>
    <textblock>throughout its range and requires the full protection of listing as</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered under the Act to survive. For reasons discussed below, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Service is not proposing to designate critical habitat for this fish</textblock>
    <textblock>species at this time.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
