<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00048</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 14 CFR Part 39</textblock>
    <textblock>Air transportation, Aircraft, Aviation safety, Safety.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Proposed Amendment</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, pursuant to the authority delegated to me by the Administrator, the Federal Aviation Administration proposes to amend 14 CFR part 39 of the Federal Aviation Regulations as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 39_AIRWORTHINESS DIRECTIVES</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 39 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>49 U.S.C. App. 1354(a), 1421 and 1423; 49 U.S.C. 106(g); and 14 CFR 11.89.</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง39.13</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 39.13 is amended by adding the following new airworthiness directive:</textblock>
    <textblock>Jetstream Aircraft Limited:</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket 93-NM-199-AD.</textblock>
    <textblock>Applicability:</textblock>
    <textblock>Model 4101 airplanes; constructors numbers 41004 through 41018 inclusive; certificated in any category.</textblock>
    <textblock>Compliance:</textblock>
    <textblock>Required as indicated, unless accomplished previously.</textblock>
    <textblock>To prevent reduced controllability of the airplane, accomplish the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Within 3 months after the effective date of this AD, modify the aileron drive quadrant support structure below the flight compartment floor in accordance with Jetstream Series 4100 Service Bulletin J41-53-011, dated October 15, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) An alternative method of compliance or adjustment of the compliance time that provides an acceptable level of safety may be used if approved by the Manager, Standardization Branch, ANM-113, FAA, Transport Airplane Directorate. Operators shall submit their requests through an appropriate FAA Principal Maintenance Inspector, who may add comments and then send it to the Manager, Standardization Branch, ANM-113.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information concerning the existence of approved alternative methods of compliance with this AD, if any, may be obtained from the Standardization Branch, ANM-113.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Special flight permits may be issued in accordance with FAR 21.197 and 21.199 to operate the airplane to a location where the requirements of this AD can be accomplished.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Renton, Washington, on January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>James V. Devany,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Manager, Transport Airplane Directorate, Aircraft Certification Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2525 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-U</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
