<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00147</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00102</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Organizations, Functions, and Authority Delegations: Special Counsel and Director of Civil Penalty Adjudications</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of delegation of authority.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA is giving notice of a new delegation of authority from the Administrator to the Special Counsel and Director for Civil Penalty Adjudications regarding civil penalty actions under 14 CFR part 13, subpart G. The delegation was set forth in a memorandum signed by the Administrator on October 22, 1993. The FAA is publishing the text of the delegation so that it is available to interested parties. This delegation of authority does not affect the delegation of authority by the Administrator to the Chief Counsel and the Assistant Chief Counsel for Litigation signed by the Administrator on October 27, 1992, and published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 9, 1992. 57 FR 58280; December 9, 1992.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Vicki S. Leemon, Manager, Adjudications Branch (AGC-710), Federal Aviation Administration, 701 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW., suite 925, Washington, DC 20004; telephone (202) 376-6470.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>In August, 1993, the position of Special Counsel and Director of Civil Penalty Adjudications was created. The duties of the incumbent of that position include serving as an advisor to the FAA decisionmaker in appeals of initial decisions and orders by administrative law judges in civil penalty actions under 14 CFR part 13, subpart G. In these proceedings, the Administrator serves as the FAA decisionmaker.</textblock>
    <textblock>By memorandum dated October 22, 1993, the Administrator delegated limited authority as FAA decisionmaker to the Special Counsel and Director of Civil Penalty Adjudications. The delegation of authority was designed to eliminate the need for the Administrator, acting in the capacity as FAA decisionmaker, to review and consider minor, procedural or unopposed matters.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Administrator delegated similar authority as FAA decisionmaker to the Chief Counsel and the Assistant Chief Counsel for Litigation by memorandum dated October 27, 1992, and published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on December 9, 1992. 57 FR 58280; December 9, 1992. The delegation of authority to the Special Counsel and Director of Civil Penalty Adjudications does not supercede or otherwise affect that delegation to the Chief Counsel and the Assistant Chief Counsel for Litigation.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the October 27, 1992, memorandum, the Administrator delegated the authority to issue orders staying, pending judicial review, orders of the FAA decisionmaker, and to consent to the entry of judicial stays regarding such orders. That delegation was unnecessary because a final order of the FAA decisionmaker shall not be considered an order assessing civil penalty if a petition for review is filed in an appropriate U.S. Court of Appeals in a timely manner. See 14 CFR 13.16(b)(4) and 13.233(j)(2). Consequently, since there is no need for that particular delegation, the Administrator did not include that delegation in the memorandum dated October 22, 1993. Otherwise, the authority delegated to the Chief Counsel and the Assistant Chief Counsel for Litigation is identical to the authority delegated to the new Special Counsel and Director of Civil Penalty Adjudications.</textblock>
    <textblock>The text of the delegation of authority to the Special Counsel and Director of Civil Penalty Adjudications signed by the Administrator on October 22, 1993, in pertinent part, is as follows: Under 49 U.S.C. 322(b) and 14 CFR 13.202, I [David R. Hinson, Administrator] delegate to the Special Counsel and Director of Civil Penalty Adjudications the authority of the FAA decisionmaker in all civil penalty actions under 14 CFR part 13, subpart G, as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>a. To grant or deny extensions of time to file briefs, petitions for reconsideration, motions, and replies to petitions for reconsideration and motions; to grant or deny requests to file additional briefs; and to approve or disapprove other deviations from, or requests for changes in, procedural requirements;</textblock>
    <textblock>b. To correct typographical, grammatical and similar errors in the FAA decisionmaker's orders, and to make editorial changes in those orders that do not involve substantive matters;</textblock>
    <textblock>c. To issue orders dismissing appeals from initial decisions upon request of the appellant, or due to the withdrawal of the complaint; to grant or deny motions to dismiss appeals from initial decisions, or to issue orders</textblock>
    <textblock>sua sponte</textblock>
    <textblock>, for failure to file a timely appeal or failure to perfect an appeal;</textblock>
    <textblock>d. To stay the effectiveness of decisions and orders pending reconsideration by the FAA decisionmaker;</textblock>
    <textblock>e. To dismiss summarily petitions to reconsider or modify that are repetitious or frivolous;</textblock>
    <textblock>f. To issue orders construing notices of appeal or other documents that meet the requirements for appeal briefs as appeal briefs, and to set a date for the filing of a reply brief.</textblock>
    <textblock>This delegation of authority does not affect the delegation of authority to the Chief Counsel and the Assistant Chief Counsel for Litigation by memorandum dated October 27, 1992, signed by Thomas C. Richards, Administrator.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC on January 26, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Daniel J. Peterson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Special Counsel and Director of Civil Penalty Adjudications.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2554 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
