<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00146</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00101</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Intent to Rule on Application to Impose and Use the Revenue From a Passenger Facility Charge (PFC) at the Muscle Shoals Regional Airport, Muscle Shoals, AL</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of intent to rule on application.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA proposes to rule and invites public comment on the application to impose and use the revenue from a PFC at the Muscle Shoals Regional Airport under the provisions of the Aviation Safety and Capacity Expansion Act of 1990 (title IX of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990) (Public Law 101-508) and part 158 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (14 CFR part 158).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before March 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this application may be mailed or delivered in triplicate to the FAA at the following address: FAA/Airports District Office, 120 North Hangar Drive, suite B, Jackson, Mississippi 39208-2306.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, one copy of any comments submitted to the FAA must be mailed or delivered to Mr. John B. Lehrter, Airport Director, Muscle Shoals Regional Airport Authority at the following address: Muscle Shoals Regional Airport, T. Ed Campbell Drive, Muscle Shoals, Alabama 35661-2016.</textblock>
    <textblock>Air carriers and foreign air carriers may submit copies of written comments previously provided to the Muscle Shoals Regional Airport Authority under ยง158.23 of part 158.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Elton E. Jay, Principal Engineer, FAA Airports District Office, 120 North Hangar Drive, suite B, Jackson, Mississippi 39208-2306, telephone number 601-965-4628. The application may be reviewed in person at this same location.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA proposes to rule and invites public comment on the application to impose and use the revenue from a PFC at the Muscle Shoals Regional Airport under the provisions of the Aviation Safety and Capacity Expansion Act of 1990 (Title IX of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990) (Public Law 101-508) and part 158 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (14 CFR part 158).</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 20, 1994, the FAA determined that the application to impose and use the revenue from a PFC submitted by the Muscle Shoals Airport Authority was substantially complete within the requirements of ยง158.25 of part 158. The FAA will approve or disapprove application, in whole or in part, no later than May 18, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following is a brief overview of the application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Level of the proposed PFC:</textblock>
    <textblock>$3.00.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed charge effective date:</textblock>
    <textblock>October 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed charge expiration date:</textblock>
    <textblock>September 30, 1996.</textblock>
    <textblock>Total estimated PFC revenue:</textblock>
    <textblock>$60,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>Brief description of proposed project(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>1_Purchase ARFF vehicle.</textblock>
    <textblock>2_Complete construction of Taxiway B.</textblock>
    <textblock>3_Install security fence.</textblock>
    <textblock>4_Seal air carrier ramp.</textblock>
    <textblock>Class or classes of air carriers which the public agency has requested not be required to collect PFCs:</textblock>
    <textblock>None.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person may inspect the application in person at the FAA office listed above under</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, any person may, upon request, inspect the application, notice and other documents germane to the application in person at the office of the Muscle Shoals Regional Airport Authority, located in the terminal building at the Muscle Shoals Regional Airport.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Atlanta, Georgia, on January 21, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Troy R. Butler,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>PFC Program Manager, Airports Division, Southern Region.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2557 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
