<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00040</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00026</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Multitrade of Pittsylvania County, L.P. et al.; Electric Rate and Corporate Regulation Filings</textblock>
    <textblock>January 26, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that the following filings have been made with the Commission:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Multitrade of Pittsylvania County, L.P.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. EC94-9-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 25, 1994, Multitrade of Pittsylvania County, L.P. (``MPC'') (c/o James B. Vasile, Newman &amp; Holtzinger, P.C., 1615 L Street, NW, suite 1000, Washington, DC 20036) tendered for filing an Application for Approval of Sale of Partnership Interest Pursuant to Section 203 of the Federal Power Act. MPC proposes to transfer a limited partnership interest to Energy Investors Fund II, L.P. MPC is engaged in the construction of a qualifying small power production facility which is subject to the Federal Power Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 10, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. 2322133 Nova Scotia Limited</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. EG94-17-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 18, 1994, 2322133 Nova Scotia Limited (Holding Sub) c/o Kelly A. Tomblin, Energy Initiatives, Inc., One Upper Pond Road, Parsippany, New Jersey 07054 filed an application for determination of exempt wholesale generator status pursuant to Part 365 of the Commission's regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>Holding Sub is a Nova Scotia corporation formed to acquire all of the capital stock of two subsidiaries. One such subsidiary will acquire a limited partnership interest in Brooklyn Energy Limited Partnership, a Nova Scotia limited partnership formed to own an electric and steam generating facility to be located in Brooklyn, the Province of Nova Scotia, Canada. The other subsidiary will perform certain operation and maintenance services for the facility.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 14, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Citizens Utilities Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER93-889-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that Citizens Utilities Company (Citizens) on January 14, 1994, tendered for filing a second amendment to its filing in the above-captioned docket. The amendment serves to address certain questions raised in a December 15, 1993, deficiency letter.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 9, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Citizens Utilities Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER93-890-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that Citizens Utilities Company (Citizens) on January 14, 1994, tendered for filing a second amendment to its filing in the above-captioned docket. The amendment serves to address certain questions raised in a December 15, 1993, deficiency letter.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 9, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. New England Power Company</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER93-920-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that New England Power Company (NEP), on January 13, 1994, tendered an amendment to its compliance filing in this proceeding. The amended compliance filing includes Second Revised Page 5 and First Revised Pages 6 through 9, Schedule II of NEP's Tariff No. 8.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 10, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Enron Power Marketing, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. ER94-24-002]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 3, 1994, Enron Power Marketing, Inc. tendered for filing its compliance filing in the above-referenced docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 9, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph E at the end of this notice.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. EC94-9-000, et al.]</textblock>
  </rindock>
</doc>
