<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00031</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00023</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Availability of Draft Federal Report on Energy Facility Siting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Policy, Planning and Program Evaluation, U.S. Department of Energy.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of extension of public comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 16, 1993, U.S. Department of Energy (DOE) announced the availability of a draft report on energy facility siting, Energy Infrastructure of the United States and Projected Siting Needs: Scoping Ideas, Identifying Issues and Options; Draft Report of the Department of Energy Working Group on Energy Facility Siting to the Secretary (58 FR 65703). The purpose of the draft report is to address key issues impeding the siting of energy facilities. The report presents data and analysis regarding energy service needs, infrastructure requirements, and constraints to siting of energy facilities. The report also presents a series of potential initiatives to help improve the overall siting process for energy facilities. The draft report is accompanied by a second volume that provides documentation on the methodology used to conduct the analysis. This notice announces the extension of the comment period due to requests from interested parties.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals wishing to present their views on the draft report should do so in writing by April 30, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the draft report and the documentation summary is available for inspection and reproduction at the public reading room of the U.S. Department of Energy, Forrestal Building, 1000 Independence Ave., SW., Washington, DC. The public reading room is open from 9 a.m. to 4 p.m.; you may contact reading room staff at (202) 586-6020. If you wish to have a copy of the draft report mailed to you directly, please contact Dr. Barry Gale at the address below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Four copies of the written comments should be addressed to Dr. Barry G. Gale, Office of Policy, Planning and Program Evaluation, U.S. Department of Energy, 1000 Independence Ave., SW., PO-63, Washington, DC 20585.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Dr. Barry G. Gale, Office of Policy, Planning and Program Evaluation, U.S. Department of Energy, 1000 Independence Ave., SW., PO-63, Washington, DC 20585, (202) 586-6708.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC on January 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Abraham E. Haspel,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Assistant Secretary for Economic and Environmental Policy.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2599 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6450-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
