<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00152</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00103</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In the Matter of HPH Aviation</textblock>
    <textblock>Order No. 93-33 (11/18/93)</textblock>
    <textblock>Withdrawal of Appeal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondent withdrew its notice of appeal. Respondent's appeal is dismissed.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the Matter of Castle Aviation</textblock>
    <textblock>Order No. 93-34 (11/23/93)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dismissal of Appeal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondent failed to perfect its appeal by filing an appeal brief as required by 14 CFR 13.233(c). Respondent's appeal is dismissed.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the Matter of Steel City Aviation</textblock>
    <textblock>Order No. 93-35 (11/23/93)</textblock>
    <textblock>Dismissal of Appeal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondent failed to perfect its appeal by filing an appeal brief as required by 14 CFR 13.233(c). Respondent's appeal is dismissed.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the Matter of Valley Air Services, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>Order No. 93-36 (12/21/93)</textblock>
    <textblock>Allegation of Operating Without Timely Overhaul of Governors.</textblock>
    <textblock>The complaint alleged that Valley Air operated its aircraft when the propeller governors had not been overhauled as required. Respondent's defense was that it had obtained a letter from the manufacturer extending the time between overhaul, and that this letter was a valid ``maintenance instruction'' within the meaning of 14 CFR 135.421(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>``Maintenance Instruction'' Defined.</textblock>
    <textblock>Maintenance instructions are general instructions that manufacturers are required to furnish to all operators, and that operators in turn are required to obey. Maintenance instructions do not include either ``instructions'' issued to particular operators, or optional ``instructions.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Manfuacturer's Letter of Extension Was Not A Maintenance Instruction.</textblock>
    <textblock>Contrary to the law judge's holding, the manufacturer's extension of time for overhaul of the propeller governors was not a ``maintenance instruction'' within the meaning of Section 135.421. Woodward's extension of the time between overhaul was issued to Respondent alone_not to all operators. Also, the effect of the letter was to</textblock>
    <textblock>relieve</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondent of the requirement to overhaul the governors at 1,800 hours.</textblock>
    <textblock>Extension Was Not Retroactive.</textblock>
    <textblock>Even if the extension letter were found to be a maintenance instruction, Respondent had already flown the aircraft 103.5 hours past the 1,800-hour limit when the inspector discovered the problem. Thus, the rules had already been violated when Respondent sought and obtained the extension letter from Woodward. Although Woodward may have intended its purported extension to be retroactive, it simply did not have the power to exonerate Respondent from a pre-existing violation of the rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>Sanction.</textblock>
    <textblock>In light of all the circumstances of this case, including the uncontroverted evidence in the record that Respondent had already flown its aircraft 103.5 hours past the 1,800-hour limit before the manufacturer was even contacted, a sanction of $4,000 is appropriate.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
