<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00049</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Act and implementing regulations found at 50 CFR 17.21 set</textblock>
    <textblock>forth a series of general prohibitions and exceptions that apply to all</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered wildlife. These prohibitions, in part, would make it illegal</textblock>
    <textblock>for any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to take</textblock>
    <textblock>(includes harass, harm, pursue, hunt, shoot, wound, kill, trap, capture,</textblock>
    <textblock>or collect; or attempt any of these), import or export, transport in</textblock>
    <textblock>interstate or foreign commerce in the course of commercial activity, or</textblock>
    <textblock>sell or offer for sale in interstate or foreign commerce any listed</textblock>
    <textblock>species. It also is illegal to possess, sell, deliver, carry,</textblock>
    <textblock>transport, or ship any such wildlife that has been taken illegally.</textblock>
    <textblock>Certain exceptions apply to agents of the Service and State conservation</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Act and 50 CFR 17.22 and 17.23 also provide for the issuance of</textblock>
    <textblock>permits to carry out otherwise prohibited activities involving</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered wildlife species under certain circumstances. Such permits</textblock>
    <textblock>are available for scientific purposes, to enhance the propagation or</textblock>
    <textblock>survival of the species, for incidental take in connection with</textblock>
    <textblock>otherwise lawful activities, and for economic hardship under certain</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances. Requests for copies of the regulations on listed plants</textblock>
    <textblock>and wildlife and inquiries regarding them may be addressed to the U.S.</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service, Ecological Services, Permit Branch, 911 N.E. 11th Avenue, Portland, Oregon 97232-4181, telephone 503/231-6241,</textblock>
    <textblock>FAX 503/231-6243.</textblock>
    <textblock>National Environmental Policy Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The Fish and Wildlife Service has determined that an Environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>Assessment or Environmental Impact Statement, as defined under the</textblock>
    <textblock>authority of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, need not be</textblock>
    <textblock>prepared in connection with regulations adopted pursuant to section 4(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Endangered Species Act of 1973, as amended. A notice outlining</textblock>
    <textblock>the Service's reasons for this determination was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on October 25, 1983 (48 FR 49244).</textblock>
    <textblock>References Cited</textblock>
    <textblock>A complete list of all references cited herein, as well as others,</textblock>
    <textblock>is available upon request from the Ventura Field Office (see</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>section).</textblock>
    <textblock>Authors</textblock>
    <textblock>The primary authors of this final rule are Donna C. Brewer, Cathy</textblock>
    <textblock>Brown, and Thomas Davidson of the Ventura Field Office (see</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>section).</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 50 CFR Part 17</textblock>
    <textblock>Endangered and threatened species, Exports, Imports, Reporting and</textblock>
    <textblock>recordkeeping requirements, Transportation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulation Promulgation</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, part 17, subchapter B of chapter I, title 50 of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Code of Federal Regulations, is amended as set forth below:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 17_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 17 continues to read as</textblock>
    <textblock>follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 1361-1407; 16 U.S.C. 1531-1544; 16 U.S.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>4201-4245; Pub. L. 99-625, 100 Stat. 3500; unless otherwise noted.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Amend §17.11(h) by adding the following species, in</textblock>
    <textblock>alphabetical order under the group FISHES, to the List of Endangered and</textblock>
    <textblock>Threatened Wildlife to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§17.12</textblock>
    <textblock>Endangered and threatened wildlife.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(h) *␣*␣*</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
