<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00101</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00072</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Park Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Park Service; Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor Commission, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice sets forth the date of the forthcoming meeting of the Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor Commission.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 16, 1994 at 1:30 p.m.</textblock>
    <textblock>INCLEMENT WEATHER RESCHEDULE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>None.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Allentown City Hall, 435 Hamilton Street, 5th Floor Conference Room, Allentown, PA 18101.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>Millie Alvarez, Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor Commission, 10 East Church Street, Room P-208, Bethlehem, PA 18018, (215) 861-8345.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission was established by Public Law 100-692 to assist the Commonwealth and its political subdivisions in planning and implementing an integrated strategy for protecting and promoting cultural, historical and natural resources. The Commission will report to the Secretary of the Interior and to Congress. The agenda for the meeting will focus on the planning process.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be open to the public. Any member of the public may file a written statement concerning agenda items. The statement should be addressed to Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor Commission, 10 E. Church Street, Room P-208, Bethlehem, PA 18018, Attention: Millie Alvarez. Minutes of the meeting will be available for inspection four weeks after the meeting, at the above-named address.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>B.J. Griffin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Regional Director, Mid-Atlantic Region.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2551 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-70-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
