<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00079</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Summer Flounder Fishery</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>50 CFR Part 625</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[I.D. 013194A]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of availability of a fishery management plan amendment and request for comments.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>NMFS issues this notice that the Mid-Atlantic Fishery Management Council (Council) has submitted Amendment 6 to the Fishery Management Plan for the Summer Flounder Fishery (FMP) for review by the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) and is requesting comments from the public.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments on Amendment 6 must be received on or before March 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments should be mailed to Richard B. Roe, Regional Director, National Marine Fisheries Service, Northeast Regional Office, One Blackburn Drive, Gloucester, MA 01930-3799. Mark the outside of the envelope ``Comments on Summer Flounder Plan''.</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the amendment are available from David R. Keifer, Executive Director, Mid-Atlantic Fishery Management Council, room 2115, Federal Building, 300 S. New Street, Dover, DE 19901-6790.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Myles Raizin, Resource Policy Analyst, 508-281-9104.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act (16 U.S.C. 1801</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>) (Magnuson Act) requires that each regional fishery management council submit any fishery management plan or plan amendment it prepares to the Secretary for review and approval, disapproval, or partial disapproval. The Magnuson Act also requires that the Secretary, upon receiving the plan or amendment, must immediately publish a notice that it is available for public review and comment. The Secretary will consider the public comments in determining whether to approve, disapprove, or partially disapprove the FMP amendment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Current regulations prohibit otter trawl vessels retaining 100 pounds or more of summer flounder between May 1 and October 31, or 200 pounds or more of summer flounder between November 1 and April 30, and having any net, or any piece of net not meeting the minimum mesh size requirements on board. Amendment 6 would allow nets not meeting the minimum mesh size to be on board a vessel even if the above thresholds are exceeded, provided the nets are appropriately stowed. Once the threshold amounts of summer flounder are retained, nets that do not meet the minimum mesh size requirements could not be used for the remainder of the fishing trip.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed amendment would also modify the schedule for establishing the annual management measures for the recreational fishery for summer flounder. The regulations setting the recreational possession limit would be revised to allow the measure to be set later in the year to provide an opportunity to review data from the previous year. The timing provisions would be revised to require the Regional Director to publish the proposed commercial quota and other measures by October 15 and the proposed recreational measures by February 15 of the year for which the specifications are being proposed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Amendment 6 would also clarify the language prohibiting twisted mesh, authorize an experimental fishery under certain conditions, and make the definition of a fish box consistent with that in the Fishery Management Plan for the Northeast Multispecies Fishery.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations proposed by the Council and based on this amendment are scheduled to be published within 15 days.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 1801</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Davis S. Crestin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Office of Fisheries Conservation and Management, National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2502 Filed 1-31-94; 4:31 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
