<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00048</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Critical Habitat</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 4(a)(3) of the Act, as amended, requires that, to the</textblock>
    <textblock>maximum extent prudent and determinable, the Secretary designate</textblock>
    <textblock>critical habitat concurrently with determining a species to be</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered or threatened. Furthermore, the Service is to designate</textblock>
    <textblock>critical habitat on the basis of the best scientific and commercial data</textblock>
    <textblock>available after taking into consideration the economic and other</textblock>
    <textblock>relevant impacts of specifying an area as critical habitat (16 U.S.C.</textblock>
    <textblock>1533(b)(2)). In the case of the tidewater goby, critical habitat is not</textblock>
    <textblock>presently determinable. A final designation of critical habitat</textblock>
    <textblock>requires detailed information on the possible economic effects of such a</textblock>
    <textblock>designation. The Service does not currently have sufficient information</textblock>
    <textblock>needed to perform the economic analysis. A delay in the determination</textblock>
    <textblock>to list the species to gather additional information and perform</textblock>
    <textblock>analyses would not serve the needs of the species. Information is</textblock>
    <textblock>needed on actions that may be proposed within tidewater goby habitat and</textblock>
    <textblock>the degree to which a designation of critical habitat may affect these</textblock>
    <textblock>actions over and above effects associated with listing the goby as</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered (i.e., the jeopardy standard alone). It will also be</textblock>
    <textblock>necessary to determine how and to what extent application of the</textblock>
    <textblock>destruction/adverse modification standard will change various Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>actions. These data will be used in the economic analyses to determine</textblock>
    <textblock>the economic effects of critical habitat designation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Available Conservation Measures</textblock>
    <textblock>Conservation measures provided to species listed as endangered or</textblock>
    <textblock>threatened under the Endangered Species Act include recognition,</textblock>
    <textblock>recovery actions, requirements for Federal protection, and prohibitions</textblock>
    <textblock>against certain activities. Recognition through listing encourages and</textblock>
    <textblock>results in conservation actions by Federal, State, and private agencies,</textblock>
    <textblock>groups, and individuals. The Endangered Species Act provides for</textblock>
    <textblock>possible land acquisition and cooperation with the States and requires</textblock>
    <textblock>that recovery actions be carried out for all listed species. The</textblock>
    <textblock>protection required of Federal agencies and the prohibitions against</textblock>
    <textblock>taking and harm are discussed, in part, below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 7(a) of the Act, as amended, requires Federal agencies to</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluate their actions with respect to any species that is proposed or</textblock>
    <textblock>listed as endangered or threatened and with respect to its critical</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat, if any is being designated. Regulations implementing this</textblock>
    <textblock>interagency cooperation provision of the Act are codified at 50 CFR part</textblock>
    <textblock>402. Section 7(a)(2) requires Federal agencies to ensure that</textblock>
    <textblock>activities they authorize, fund, or carry out are not likely to</textblock>
    <textblock>jeopardize the continued existence of such a species or to destroy or</textblock>
    <textblock>adversely modify its critical habitat. If a Federal action may affect a</textblock>
    <textblock>listed species or its critical habitat, the responsible Federal agency</textblock>
    <textblock>must enter into formal consultation with the Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>A number of Federal agencies or departments control lands that</textblock>
    <textblock>support the tidewater goby. These include the Department of Defense</textblock>
    <textblock>(U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, U.S. Navy, U.S. Air Force, and U.S.</textblock>
    <textblock>Marine Corps), Department of Agriculture (U.S. Forest Service), and</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Interior (National Park Service and U.S. Fish and</textblock>
    <textblock>Wildlife Service). Federal actions that may be affected by this</textblock>
    <textblock>determination would be the funding or authorization of projects within</textblock>
    <textblock>the species' habitat, including the construction of roads, bridges, and</textblock>
    <textblock>dredging projects subject to section 404 of the Clean Water Act (33</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S.C. 1344</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>) and section 10 of the Rivers and Harbors Act of</textblock>
    <textblock>1899 (33 U.S.C. 401</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>), and special use permits. Other Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>actions that are subject to environmental review under the National</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Policy Act would also require consultation with the</textblock>
    <textblock>Service. Projects on federally owned land would also be subject to the</textblock>
    <textblock>provisions of section 7 of the Endangered Species Act.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
