<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00043</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The tidewater goby occurs in loose aggregations of a few to several</textblock>
    <textblock>hundred individuals on the substrate in shallow water less than 1 meter</textblock>
    <textblock>(3 feet) deep (Swift</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1989), although gobies have been observed at</textblock>
    <textblock>depths of 1.5 to 2.3 meters (4.9 to 7.6 feet) (Dan Holland, University</textblock>
    <textblock>of Southwestern Louisiana,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993). Peak nesting activities</textblock>
    <textblock>commence in late April through early May, when male gobies dig a</textblock>
    <textblock>vertical nesting burrow 10 to 20 centimeters (4 to 8 inches) deep in</textblock>
    <textblock>clean, coarse sand. Suitable water temperatures for nesting are 18 to</textblock>
    <textblock>22</textblock>
    <textblock>○C (75.6 to 79.6</textblock>
    <textblock>○F) with salinities of 5 to 10 ppt. Male gobies</textblock>
    <textblock>remain in the burrows to guard eggs, which are hung from the ceiling and</textblock>
    <textblock>walls of the burrow until hatching. Larval gobies are found midwater</textblock>
    <textblock>around vegetation until they become benthic (Swift</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1989).</textblock>
    <textblock>Although the potential for year round spawning exists, it is probably</textblock>
    <textblock>unlikely because of seasonal low temperatures and disruptions of lagoons</textblock>
    <textblock>during winter storms. Ecological studies performed at two sites</textblock>
    <textblock>documented spawning occurring as early as the first week in January</textblock>
    <textblock>(Swenson</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993). Although usually associated with lagoons, the</textblock>
    <textblock>tidewater goby has been documented in ponded freshwater habitats as far</textblock>
    <textblock>as 8 kilometers (5 miles) upstream from San Antonio lagoon in Santa</textblock>
    <textblock>Barbara County (Irwin and Stoltz 1984).</textblock>
    <textblock>The tidewater goby is discontinuously distributed throughout</textblock>
    <textblock>California, ranging from Tillas Slough (mouth of the Smith River) in Del</textblock>
    <textblock>Norte County south to Agua Hedionda Lagoon in San Diego County. Areas</textblock>
    <textblock>of precipitous coastlines that preclude the formation of lagoons at</textblock>
    <textblock>stream mouths have created three natural gaps in the distribution of the</textblock>
    <textblock>goby. Gobies are apparently absent from three sections of the coast</textblock>
    <textblock>between: (1) Humboldt Bay and Ten Mile River, (2) Point Arena and Salmon</textblock>
    <textblock>Creek, and (3) Monterey Bay and Arroyo del Oso.</textblock>
    <textblock>Roughly 10 percent of the coastal lagoons presently containing</textblock>
    <textblock>populations of tidewater goby are under Federal ownership. Over 40</textblock>
    <textblock>percent of the remaining populations are either entirely or partly owned</textblock>
    <textblock>and managed by the State of California. The remainder are privately</textblock>
    <textblock>owned.</textblock>
    <textblock>Previous Federal Action</textblock>
    <textblock>The tidewater goby was first classified by the Service as a</textblock>
    <textblock>category 2 species in 1982 (47 FR 58454). It was reclassified as a</textblock>
    <textblock>category 1 candidate in 1991 (56 FR 58804) based on status and threat</textblock>
    <textblock>information in Swift</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1989). Category 2 applies to taxa for</textblock>
    <textblock>which information now in the possession of the Service indicates that</textblock>
    <textblock>proposing to list as endangered or threatened is possibly appropriate,</textblock>
    <textblock>but for which conclusive data on biological vulnerability and threats</textblock>
    <textblock>are not currently available to support a listing proposal. Category 1</textblock>
    <textblock>applies to taxa for which the Service has on file substantial</textblock>
    <textblock>information on biological vulnerability and threats to support proposals</textblock>
    <textblock>to list them as endangered or threatened species.</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 24, 1990, the Service received a petition from Dr. Camm</textblock>
    <textblock>Swift, Associate Curator of Fishes at the Los Angeles Museum of Natural</textblock>
    <textblock>History, to list the tidewater goby as endangered (Swift 1990). The</textblock>
    <textblock>petition, status surveys, and accompanying data describe the goby as</textblock>
    <textblock>threatened because of past and continuing losses of coastal and riparian</textblock>
    <textblock>habitats within its historic range. The Service's finding that this</textblock>
    <textblock>petition presented substantial information that the requested action may</textblock>
    <textblock>be warranted was published on March 22, 1991 (56 FR 12146). Following</textblock>
    <textblock>this finding, the Service initiated a status review on the tidewater</textblock>
    <textblock>goby.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 4(b)(3)(B) of the Endangered Species Act (Act), as amended</textblock>
    <textblock>in 1982, requires the Secretary to make a finding within 12 months of</textblock>
    <textblock>the date a petition is received as to whether or not the requested</textblock>
    <textblock>action is warranted. On December 11, 1992, the Service published a</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal to list the tidewater goby as an endangered species (57 FR</textblock>
    <textblock>58770). The proposed rule constituted the 12-month finding that the</textblock>
    <textblock>petitioned action was warranted.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
