<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00073</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In 1982, a habitat conservation plan (HCP) was completed and a</textblock>
    <textblock>section 10(a) incidental take permit was issued to the cities of</textblock>
    <textblock>Brisbane, Daly City, and South San Francisco and the county of San Mateo</textblock>
    <textblock>for the endangered mission blue butterfly (</textblock>
    <textblock>Icaricia icarioides</textblock>
    <textblock>missionensis</textblock>
    <textblock>), San Bruno elfin butterfly (</textblock>
    <textblock>Incisalia mossii bayensis</textblock>
    <textblock>),</textblock>
    <textblock>and San Francisco garter snake (</textblock>
    <textblock>Thamnophis sirtiralis tetrataenia</textblock>
    <textblock>). The</textblock>
    <textblock>HCP, entitled ``San Bruno Mountain Habitat Conservation Plan'' (U.S. Fish</textblock>
    <textblock>and Wildlife Service permit number PRT 2-9818), permanently protects</textblock>
    <textblock>about 1,115 hectares (2,752 acres) of natural habitat at this site. The</textblock>
    <textblock>conference report on the 1982 amendments to the Endangered Species Act</textblock>
    <textblock>of 1973 indicates that Congress intended HCPs to encompass both listed</textblock>
    <textblock>and unlisted species, especially unlisted species that might later be</textblock>
    <textblock>protected. Although the callippe silverspot butterfly was not included</textblock>
    <textblock>in the section 10(a) permit, the San Bruno Mountain HCP included</textblock>
    <textblock>specific considerations and provisions in the event it did become listed</textblock>
    <textblock>by the Service. Habitat of one of the two known extant populations of</textblock>
    <textblock>the callippe silverspot butterfly is protected under this HCP. The</textblock>
    <textblock>permit allows for the loss of animals and habitat through urban</textblock>
    <textblock>development containing approximately 8 percent of the San Bruno Mountain</textblock>
    <textblock>population of the callippe silverspot butterfly. Although habitat is</textblock>
    <textblock>protected, the Service is aware of numerous preserved specimens of the</textblock>
    <textblock>callippe silverspot butterfly that have been collected recently on San</textblock>
    <textblock>Bruno Mountain on lands where the animal is not protected.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Act and implementing regulations found at 50 CFR 17.21 for</textblock>
    <textblock>endangered species set forth a series of prohibitions and exceptions</textblock>
    <textblock>that apply to all endangered wildlife. These prohibitions, in part,</textblock>
    <textblock>make it illegal for any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United</textblock>
    <textblock>States to take (including harass, harm, pursue, hunt, shoot, wound,</textblock>
    <textblock>kill, trap, capture, collect, or attempt any such activity), import or</textblock>
    <textblock>export, transport in interstate or foreign commerce in the course of</textblock>
    <textblock>commercial activity, or sell or offer for sale in interstate or foreign</textblock>
    <textblock>commerce any such species. It also is illegal to possess, sell,</textblock>
    <textblock>deliver, carry, transport, or ship any such wildlife that was taken</textblock>
    <textblock>illegally. Certain exceptions can apply to agents of the Service and</textblock>
    <textblock>State conservation agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Permits may be issued to carry out otherwise prohibited activities</textblock>
    <textblock>involving endangered animal species under certain circumstances.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulations governing permits are at 50 CFR 17.22 and 17.23. Such</textblock>
    <textblock>permits are available for scientific purposes, to enhance the</textblock>
    <textblock>propagation or survival of the species, and/or for incidental take in</textblock>
    <textblock>connection with otherwise lawful activities. Further information</textblock>
    <textblock>regarding regulations and requirements for permits may be obtained from</textblock>
    <textblock>the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Office of Management Authority,</textblock>
    <textblock>Permits Branch, 4401 North Fairfax Drive, room 420C, Arlington, Virginia</textblock>
    <textblock>22203-3507 (telephone 703/358-2104).</textblock>
    <textblock>Public Comments Solicited</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service intends that any final action resulting from this</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal will be as accurate and effective as possible. Therefore any</textblock>
    <textblock>comments or suggestions from the public, other concerned government</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies, the scientific community, industry, or any other interested</textblock>
    <textblock>party concerning any aspect of this proposal are hereby solicited.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments particularly are sought concerning:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Biological, commercial, trade, or other relevant data</textblock>
    <textblock>concerning any threat (or the lack thereof) to the callippe silverspot</textblock>
    <textblock>butterfly, Behren's silverspot butterfly, and Alameda whipsnake;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
