<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00056</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>During the comment periods, the Service received written and oral</textblock>
    <textblock>comments from 48 parties. CDFG, California Department of Parks and</textblock>
    <textblock>Recreation, The Nature Conservancy, California Native Plant Society,</textblock>
    <textblock>National Audubon Society, Sierra Club, Environmental Council of Santa</textblock>
    <textblock>Cruz County, Southridge Watershed Association, and the Resource Defense</textblock>
    <textblock>Fund were some of the 38 commenters expressing support for the listing</textblock>
    <textblock>proposal. Eight commenters opposed the listing of</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegii.</textblock>
    <textblock>The city of Marina opposed the listing of</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens.</textblock>
    <textblock>Two commenters, one of whom offered technical comments on the proposal, were neutral. In addition, results of additional surveys for the plants (Army Corps of Engineers 1992, Habitat</textblock>
    <textblock>Restoration Group 1992) were incorporated into this final rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written comments and oral statements obtained during the public hearing</textblock>
    <textblock>and comment periods are combined in the following discussion. Opposing</textblock>
    <textblock>comments and other comments questioning the rule were organized into</textblock>
    <textblock>specific issues. These issues and the Service's response to each are</textblock>
    <textblock>summarized as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 1:</textblock>
    <textblock>Several commenters felt that there was insufficient</textblock>
    <textblock>scientific evidence to list</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegii.</textblock>
    <textblock>Others stated that the Service used data that were skewed or selectively chosen to support the listing of this plant; ``relied on the expertise of an</textblock>
    <textblock>amateur botanist whose opinion [is cited] without investigation of</textblock>
    <textblock>contrary opinions by, arguably, more qualified professionals;'' and did</textblock>
    <textblock>not utilize information supplied by Dr. Thomas that challenged the</textblock>
    <textblock>appropriateness of listing</textblock>
    <textblock>C. robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegii.</textblock>
    <textblock>Service Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>In preparing the proposed rule, the Service</textblock>
    <textblock>utilized information from botanical collections and observations that</textblock>
    <textblock>date from the mid-1800s, as well as data that were submitted to the</textblock>
    <textblock>Service in response to a request for information made to local and State</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies and other interested parties. The Service therefore maintains</textblock>
    <textblock>that the best available commercial and scientific information was</textblock>
    <textblock>utilized in preparation of the proposed rule. No data were submitted to</textblock>
    <textblock>support the contention that the Service skewed or selectively chose data</textblock>
    <textblock>to support the proposal. During preparation of the proposal, the</textblock>
    <textblock>Service consulted with a number of professional botanists, and other</textblock>
    <textblock>professional biologists commented during the comment period. These</textblock>
    <textblock>botanists and biologists gave biological bases that supported the</textblock>
    <textblock>listing of</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegii.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service, therefore, believes that this determination to list the plant as endangered under</textblock>
    <textblock>C. robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>is appropriate and is supported by the botanical community.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 2:</textblock>
    <textblock>Several commenters pointed out that the California Fish</textblock>
    <textblock>and Game Commission rejected a proposal to State list</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe</textblock>
    <textblock>robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegii,</textblock>
    <textblock>and it was, therefore, inappropriate for the</textblock>
    <textblock>Service to pursue Federal listing due to the ``doctrine of comity'' (the</textblock>
    <textblock>informal and voluntary recognition by courts of one jurisdiction of the</textblock>
    <textblock>laws and judicial decision of another).</textblock>
    <textblock>Service Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The California Fish and Game Commission did not</textblock>
    <textblock>reject a proposal to State list</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegii,</textblock>
    <textblock>rather it determined that not enough information was available to</textblock>
    <textblock>petition the plant for State listing. The opinions of the California</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and Game Commission were not shared by CDFG, which supported the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal listing at the public hearing and in writing (Ken Berg, CDFG,</textblock>
    <textblock>pers. comm., 1992). The Act does not require agreement among State</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies. Moreover, CDFG, in collaboration with The Nature Conservancy</textblock>
    <textblock>and the California Native Plant Society, supplied the Service with data,</textblock>
    <textblock>through the CNDDB (1990), that supports Federal listing of the four</textblock>
    <textblock>plants.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
