<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00175</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00122</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>FEDERAL DEPOSIT INSURANCE CORPORATION</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Agency Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the provisions of the ``Government in the Sunshine Act'' (5 U.S.C. 552b), notice is hereby given that the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation's Board of Directors will meet in open session at 2 p.m. on Tuesday, February 8, 1994, to consider the following matters:</textblock>
    <textblock>Summary Agenda:</textblock>
    <textblock>No matters scheduled.</textblock>
    <textblock>Discussion Agenda:</textblock>
    <textblock>Memorandum and resolution re: Interim rule with respect to notice of mutual-to-stock conversions which would (1) require FDIC-insured State-chartered savings banks that are not members of the Federal Reserve System (State savings banks) that have applied to their applicable State banking regulator to convert from the mutual to stock form of ownership to provide the Corporation with a notice of the proposed conversion and a copy of the application materials, and (2) require that State savings banks not finalize a mutual-to-stock conversion until they receive a notice of the Corporation's intention not to object to the proposed conversion.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held in the Board Room on the sixth floor of the FDIC Building located at 550_17th Street NW., Washington, DC.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FDIC will provide attendees with auxiliary aids (e.g., sign language interpretation) required for this meeting. Those attendees needing such assistance should call (202) 942-3132 (Voice); (202) 942-3111 (TTY), to make necessary arrangements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Requests for further information concerning the meeting may be directed to Mr. Robert E. Feldman, Acting Executive Secretary of the Corporation, at (202) 898-6757.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Patti C. Fox,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Deputy Executive Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2649 Filed 2-1-94; 4:35 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6714-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
