<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00036</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00017</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>List of Subjects</textblock>
    <textblock>40 CFR Part 52</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental protection, Air pollution control, Carbon monoxide, Incorporation by reference, Intergovernmental relations.</textblock>
    <textblock>40 CFR Part 81</textblock>
    <textblock>Air pollution control.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note_</textblock>
    <textblock>Incorporation by reference of the State Implementation Plan for the State of Ohio was approved by the Director of the Federal Register on July 1, 1982.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 2, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Valdas V. Adamkus,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Regional Administrator.</textblock>
    <textblock>Chapter I, title 40 of the Code of Federal Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 52_APPROVAL AND PROMULGATION OF IMPLEMENTATION PLANS</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 52 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 7401-7671q.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart KK_Ohio</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 52.1870 is amended by adding a new paragraph (c) (93) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§52.1870</textblock>
    <textblock>Identification of plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(93) In a letter dated October 16, 1992, the OEPA submitted a revision to the Carbon Monoxide State Implementation Plan for Cuyahoga County. This revision contains a maintenance plan that the area will use to maintain the CO NAAQS. The maintenance plan contains an oxygenated fuels program as a contingency measure to be implemented if the area violates the CO NAAQS.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Incorporation by reference. (A) Letter dated October 16, 1992, from Donald R. Schregardus, Director, Ohio Environmental Protection Agency to Valdas Adamkus, Regional Administrator, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region 5 and its enclosures entitled ``Table 1 Cuyahoga County Carbon Monoxide Emission Inventory'', Enclosure B ``Cuyahoga County carbon monoxide SIP submittal'', and section 6.0 of Enclosure C ``Cuyahoga County Carbon Monoxide Modeling Study Final Report.''</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Additional information.</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Letter dated January 14, 1993, from Donald R. Schregardus, Director, Ohio Environmental Protection Agency to Valdas Adamkus, Regional Administrator, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region 5.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Letter dated February 10, 1993, from Robert F. Hodanbosi, Chief, Division of Air Pollution Control, Ohio Environmental Protection Agency to David Kee, Director, Air and Radiation Division, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region 5.</textblock>
    <textblock>(C) Letter dated July 29, 1993, from Robert F. Hodanbosi, Chief, Division of Air Pollution Control, Ohio Environmental Protection Agency to David Kee, Director, Air and Radiation Division, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region 5.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
