<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00054</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The only known extant populations of</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegii</textblock>
    <textblock>occur in Scotts Valley in the Santa Cruz Mountains north of</textblock>
    <textblock>the city of Santa Cruz. The plant occurs primarily on pockets of Santa</textblock>
    <textblock>Cruz mudstones and Purisima sandstones and is associated with annual</textblock>
    <textblock>grasslands and wildflower fields (Reveal and Morgan 1989). These</textblock>
    <textblock>islands of unique substrates are host to a number of rare plants. Three</textblock>
    <textblock>populations of the plant, each consisting of numerous small colonies,</textblock>
    <textblock>are scattered over an area 1 mile in diameter on three parcels in</textblock>
    <textblock>private ownership. In 1989, shortly after the taxon was rediscovered,</textblock>
    <textblock>the total number of individuals was estimated to be approximately 6,000</textblock>
    <textblock>(California Natural Diversity Data Base (CNDDB) 1990). As a result of</textblock>
    <textblock>two proposals for development that were pending at the time, additional</textblock>
    <textblock>surveys were conducted during the next few years. Results of 1992</textblock>
    <textblock>surveys were that the two populations on land proposed for a development</textblock>
    <textblock>named Glenwood Estates totalled between 30,000 and 100,000 individuals</textblock>
    <textblock>(Habitat Restoration Group 1992). The numbers of this annual plant are</textblock>
    <textblock>expected to fluctuate from year to year, depending on climatic</textblock>
    <textblock>conditions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegiana</textblock>
    <textblock>(Ben Lomond spineflower) has</textblock>
    <textblock>dark pinkish to purple scarious margins on the involucral lobes and a</textblock>
    <textblock>slightly ascending to erect habit. The heads are medium in size (1 to</textblock>
    <textblock>1.5 cm (0.4 to 0.6 in) in diameter) and distinctly aggregate. The plant</textblock>
    <textblock>is found on sandy soils that are the basis for the Ben Lomond sandhills</textblock>
    <textblock>communities in the Santa Cruz Mountains, mostly on privately owned land.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegiana</textblock>
    <textblock>is confined to outcrops of sandstone soils</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Santa Cruz Mountains from Big Basin State Park to the Felton area</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Santa Cruz Mountains. These sandstone soils support several</textblock>
    <textblock>unique plant communities, including the ponderosa pine-dominated Ben</textblock>
    <textblock>Lomond sandhills. The majority of occurrences of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegiana</textblock>
    <textblock>are found on privately owned lands within the area generally</textblock>
    <textblock>bounded by the communities of Ben Lomond, Glenwood, Scotts Valley, and</textblock>
    <textblock>Felton.</textblock>
    <textblock>Erysimum teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>(Ben Lomond wallflower) was first collected</textblock>
    <textblock>at Glenwood, Santa Cruz County, by Horace Davis in 1914. This plant was</textblock>
    <textblock>described by Alice Eastwood in 1938 as</textblock>
    <textblock>E. filifolium,</textblock>
    <textblock>not realizing that</textblock>
    <textblock>this combination was already applied to another plant (Eastwood 1938).</textblock>
    <textblock>It was therefore renamed</textblock>
    <textblock>E. teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>in the following year (Eastwood</textblock>
    <textblock>1939).</textblock>
    <textblock>E. teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>is a biennial, or occasionally an annual, plant</textblock>
    <textblock>of the mustard family (Brassicaceae). Seedlings form a basal rosette of</textblock>
    <textblock>leaves, which then wither as the main stem develops flowers clustered in</textblock>
    <textblock>a terminal raceme. The flowers are a deep yellow with petals 1.3 to 2.5</textblock>
    <textblock>cm (0.5 to 1.0 in) long; the slender capsule reaches 10 cm (4.0 in) in</textblock>
    <textblock>length and is covered with three-parted hairs. The leaves are simple</textblock>
    <textblock>and narrowly linear, a characteristic that separates this plant from</textblock>
    <textblock>other wallflowers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Erysimum teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>is endemic to pockets of sandstone deposits</textblock>
    <textblock>in the Santa Cruz Mountains and is presently known from only a dozen</textblock>
    <textblock>scattered occurrences. These sandstone deposits support the unique</textblock>
    <textblock>ponderosa pine sandhill community, and</textblock>
    <textblock>E. teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>seems to prefer</textblock>
    <textblock>sites with loose, uncompacted sand in openings between scattered</textblock>
    <textblock>chaparral shrubs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>is found in close</textblock>
    <textblock>proximity with</textblock>
    <textblock>E. teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>at some locations. A dozen populations</textblock>
    <textblock>of</textblock>
    <textblock>E. teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>occur within the area generally bounded by the</textblock>
    <textblock>communities of Ben Lomond, Glenwood, Scotts Valley, and Felton, with one</textblock>
    <textblock>outlying population occurring in the Bonny Doon area, 5 miles west of</textblock>
    <textblock>Felton. One population occurs at Quail Hollow Ranch, which is jointly</textblock>
    <textblock>owned by Santa Cruz County, The Nature Conservancy, and the California</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Fish and Game (CDFG). All other populations are on</textblock>
    <textblock>privately owned lands.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
