<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00058</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00034</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>6. Columbia Gas Transmission</textblock>
    <textblock>Corporation )</textblock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. CP94-192-000]</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 21, 1994, Columbia Gas Transmission Corporation (Columbia), 1700 MacCorkle Avenue, SE., Charleston, West Virginia 25314, filed in Docket No. CP94-192-000 a request pursuant to Sections 157.205 and 157.211 of the Commission's Regulations under the Natural Gas Act (18 CFR 157.205, 157.211) for authorization to construct and operate facilities necessary to establish six new points of delivery to existing customers for firm transportation service under Columbia's blanket certificate issued in Docket No. CP83-76-000 pursuant to Section 7 of the Natural Gas Act, all as more fully set forth in the request that is on file with the Commission and open to public inspection.</textblock>
    <textblock>Specifically, Columbia proposes to establish the delivery points for the for the following customers:</textblock>
    <textblock>Columbia expects the quantities to be provided through the new delivery points to be within its authorized level of services. Also, Columbia estimates that the cost of installing the new taps to be approximately $150 per tap and that project No. 1 to cost approximately $14,100, which would be reimbursed by Columbia Gas of Ohio.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment date:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 14, 1994, in accordance with Standard Paragraph G at the end of this notice.</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Customer</textblock>
    <textblock>1Residential</textblock>
    <textblock>1Est. d/qty</textblock>
    <textblock>1Est. annl. qty</textblock>
    <textblock>Columbia Gas of Ohio</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>23.5 dth</textblock>
    <textblock>8,180 dth</textblock>
    <textblock>Mountaineer Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
    <textblock>4.5 dth</textblock>
    <textblock>450 dth</textblock>
    <textblock>Waterville Gas &amp; Oil Company</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>1.5</textblock>
    <textblock>140 dth</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
