<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00013</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>F. Review Under Section 32 of the Federal Energy</textblock>
    <textblock>Administration Authorization Act</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 32 of the Federal Energy Administration Act of 1974</textblock>
    <textblock>(15 U.S.C. 788) imposes certain requirements when a proposed</textblock>
    <textblock>rule contains commercial standards or authorizes or requires</textblock>
    <textblock>the use of such standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>The commercial standards proposed today incorporate</textblock>
    <textblock>commercial standards to measure the energy consumption and</textblock>
    <textblock>range of electric vehicles. The commercial standards are</textblock>
    <textblock>the Society of Automotive Engineers Electric Vehicle Energy</textblock>
    <textblock>Consumption and Range Test Procedure J1634.</textblock>
    <textblock>DOE has evaluated the promulgation of these standards in</textblock>
    <textblock>light of the public participation criteria of section 32(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department is unable to conclude whether development of</textblock>
    <textblock>these standards fully complied with section 32(b) regarding</textblock>
    <textblock>the manner of public participation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Finally, as required by section 32(c), DOE will consult with</textblock>
    <textblock>the Attorney General and the Chairman of the Federal Trade</textblock>
    <textblock>Commission concerning the impact of these standards on</textblock>
    <textblock>competition, prior to prescribing final test procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>G. Review Under Executive Order 12778</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 2 of Executive Order 12778 instructs each agency</textblock>
    <textblock>subject to Executive Order 12291 to adhere to certain</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements in promulgating new regulations and reviewing</textblock>
    <textblock>existing regulations. These requirements, set forth in</textblock>
    <textblock>sections 2(a) and (b)(2), include eliminating drafting</textblock>
    <textblock>errors and needless ambiguity, drafting the regulations to</textblock>
    <textblock>minimize litigation, providing clear and certain legal</textblock>
    <textblock>standards for affected conduct, and promoting simplification</textblock>
    <textblock>and burden reduction. Agencies are also instructed to make</textblock>
    <textblock>every reasonable effort to ensure that the regulation</textblock>
    <textblock>specifies clearly any preemptive effect, effect on existing</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal law or regulation, and retroactive effect; describes</textblock>
    <textblock>any administrative proceedings to be available prior to</textblock>
    <textblock>judicial review and any provisions for the exhaustion of</textblock>
    <textblock>such administrative proceedings; and defines key terms. The</textblock>
    <textblock>DOE certifies that today's proposed rule meets the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of sections 2(a) and (b)(2) of Executive Order</textblock>
    <textblock>12778.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 10 CFR Part 474:</textblock>
    <textblock>Electric power, Energy</textblock>
    <textblock>conservation, Incorporation by reference, Motor vehicles,</textblock>
    <textblock>Research.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the reasons set forth in the preamble, DOE proposes to</textblock>
    <textblock>amend part 474 of chapter II of title 10 of the Code of</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Regulations as set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on January 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Christine A. Ervin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Secretary,</textblock>
    <textblock>Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
