<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00046</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00028</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 27, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) has received</textblock>
    <textblock>an application for a new license for the Leaburg-Walterville</textblock>
    <textblock>Hydroelectric Project, FERC No. 2496. The hydropower project is</textblock>
    <textblock>located on the McKenzie River in Oregon.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FERC staff has determined that licensing this project</textblock>
    <textblock>would constitute a major federal action significantly affecting the</textblock>
    <textblock>quality of the human environment. Therefore, the staff intends to</textblock>
    <textblock>prepare an environmental impact statement (EIS) on the</textblock>
    <textblock>hydroelectric project in accordance with the National Environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>Policy Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>The staff's EIS will objectively consider both site specific</textblock>
    <textblock>and cumulative environmental impacts of the project and reasonable</textblock>
    <textblock>alternatives, and will include an economic, financial and</textblock>
    <textblock>engineering analysis.</textblock>
    <textblock>The draft EIS will be issued and circulated for review by all</textblock>
    <textblock>the interested parties. All comments filed on the draft will be</textblock>
    <textblock>analyzed by the staff and considered in a final EIS. The staff's</textblock>
    <textblock>conclusions and recommendations will then be presented for</textblock>
    <textblock>consideration by the Commission in reaching a licensing decision.</textblock>
    <textblock>Scoping Meeting</textblock>
    <textblock>A project site visit for FERC staff, agencies and all other</textblock>
    <textblock>interested parties is scheduled for Tuesday, February 15, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The site visit will commence at 9 a.m. at Water Board Park</textblock>
    <textblock>located adjacent to the Leaburg Dam, just off of Highway 126. The</textblock>
    <textblock>site visit will likely extend into the afternoon. The site visit</textblock>
    <textblock>will provide an opportunity for interested parties to observe</textblock>
    <textblock>environmental conditions in the project area. All those interested</textblock>
    <textblock>are encouraged to attend.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FERC staff will conduct two scoping meetings. The evening</textblock>
    <textblock>scoping meeting is primarily for public input while the morning</textblock>
    <textblock>meeting will focus on resource agency concerns. All interested</textblock>
    <textblock>individuals, organizations, and agencies are invited to attend</textblock>
    <textblock>either or both sessions to assist the staff in identifying the</textblock>
    <textblock>scope of environmental issues that should be analyzed in the EIS.</textblock>
    <textblock>On the evening of Wednesday, February 16, 1994, we will hold</textblock>
    <textblock>the first scoping meeting, primarily for the public, from 7-10 p.m. at the Thurston High School Auditorium in Springfield,</textblock>
    <textblock>Oregon. The high school is located just off Highway 126, at 333</textblock>
    <textblock>North 58th Street.</textblock>
    <textblock>The second scoping meeting, primarily for resource agencies,</textblock>
    <textblock>will be from 9:30 a.m.-12 p.m. the following morning, Thursday,</textblock>
    <textblock>February 17, 1994, at the Springfield Chamber of Commerce, Freight</textblock>
    <textblock>Room. The Springfield Chamber of Commerce is located on South A</textblock>
    <textblock>Street, between Mill Street and Pioneer Parkway West.</textblock>
    <textblock>To help focus discussions, a preliminary EIS scoping document</textblock>
    <textblock>(Scoping Document 1) outlining subject areas to be addressed at the</textblock>
    <textblock>meetings will be distributed by mail to parties on the FERC service</textblock>
    <textblock>list. Copies of Scoping Document 1 will also be available at the</textblock>
    <textblock>scoping meetings.</textblock>
    <textblock>Objectives</textblock>
    <textblock>At the scoping meetings the staff will:</textblock>
    <textblock>•Identify reasonable alternative measures that should be</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluated in the EIS;</textblock>
    <textblock>•Identify significant environmental issues related to the</textblock>
    <textblock>proposed project;</textblock>
    <textblock>•Determine the depth of analysis for issues addressed in</textblock>
    <textblock>the EIS; and</textblock>
    <textblock>•Identify resource issues that are not important and that</textblock>
    <textblock>do not require detailed analysis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Procedures</textblock>
    <textblock>The meetings will be recorded by a stenographer and all</textblock>
    <textblock>statements (oral and written) thereby become a part of the formal</textblock>
    <textblock>record of the Commission proceedings on the Leaburg-Walterville</textblock>
    <textblock>Project. Individuals presenting statements at the meeting will be</textblock>
    <textblock>asked to clearly identify themselves for the record.</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals, organizations, and agencies with environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>expertise and concerns are encouraged to attend either or both of</textblock>
    <textblock>the meetings and to assist the staff in defining and clarifying the</textblock>
    <textblock>issues to be addressed in the EIS.</textblock>
    <textblock>Concerned parties are encouraged to offer us verbal guidance</textblock>
    <textblock>during public meetings. Speaking time allowed for individuals will</textblock>
    <textblock>be determined before each meeting, based on the number of persons</textblock>
    <textblock>wishing to speak and the approximate amount of time available for</textblock>
    <textblock>the session, but all speakers will be provided at least five</textblock>
    <textblock>minutes to present their views.</textblock>
    <textblock>People choosing not to speak, but wishing to express an</textblock>
    <textblock>opinion, as well as speakers unable to summarize their positions</textblock>
    <textblock>within their allotted time, may submit written statements at the</textblock>
    <textblock>meeting for inclusion in the public record.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written scoping comments may also be filed with the Secretary,</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street</textblock>
    <textblock>NE., Washington, DC 20426, until March 18, 1994. Filings by</textblock>
    <textblock>the applicant and intervenors should contain an original and eight</textblock>
    <textblock>copies. Other interested parties may file original comments</textblock>
    <textblock>without copies, but failure to file an original and eight copies</textblock>
    <textblock>may result in appropriate staff not receiving the benefit of your</textblock>
    <textblock>comments in a timely manner. See 18 CFR 4.34(h).</textblock>
    <textblock>All correspondence should clearly show the following caption</textblock>
    <textblock>on the first page:</textblock>
    <textblock>Leaburg-Walterville Hydroelectric Project, FERC No. 2496, Oregon</textblock>
    <textblock>All those attending the meeting are urged to refrain from</textblock>
    <textblock>making any communication concerning the merits of the</textblock>
    <textblock>application(s) to any member of the Commission staff or the</textblock>
    <textblock>Commission's contractor outside of the established process for</textblock>
    <textblock>developing the record as stated above. Any such communications</textblock>
    <textblock>will be entered by staff into the record of the proceeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further, interested persons are reminded of the Commission's</textblock>
    <textblock>Rules of Practice and Procedure, requiring participants (as defined</textblock>
    <textblock>in 18 CFR 385.2010) filing documents with the Commission, to serve</textblock>
    <textblock>a copy of the document on each person whose name is on the official</textblock>
    <textblock>service list for this proceeding. See 18 CFR 4.34(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>For further information please contact Edward R. Meyer at</textblock>
    <textblock>(202) 208-7998.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Project No. 2496]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Eugene Water &amp; Electric Board; Notice of Intent to Prepare an Environmental Impact Statement and Conduct Public Scoping Meetings</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2504 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
