<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00042</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Friday</textblock>
    <textblock>February 4, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part III</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of the Interior</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service</textblock>
    <textblock>50 CFR Part 17</textblock>
    <textblock>Endangered and Threatened Wildlife and Plants; Determinations of Endangered Status; Final Rules</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 24␣/␣Friday, February 4, 1994␣/␣Rules and Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>50 CFR Part 17</textblock>
    <textblock>Endangered and Threatened Wildlife and Plants; Determination of Endangered Status for the Tidewater Goby</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1018-AB88</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Fish and Wildlife Service, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Fish and Wildlife Service (Service) determines endangered status pursuant to the provisions of the Endangered Species Act of 1973, as amended (Act), for the tidewater goby (</textblock>
    <textblock>Eucyclogobius newberryi</textblock>
    <textblock>). The tidewater goby is a fish that occurs in tidal streams associated with coastal wetlands in California. Since 1900, the tidewater goby has disappeared from nearly 50 percent of the coastal lagoons within its historic range, including 74 percent of the lagoons south of Morro Bay in central California. Only three populations currently exist south of Ventura County. This rule implements the protection and recovery provisions provided by the Act for the tidewater goby.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The complete file for this rule is available for inspection, by appointment, during normal business hours at the Ventura Field Office, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, 2140 Eastman Avenue, suite 100, Ventura, California 93003.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Carl Benz at the above address</textblock>
    <textblock>(805/644-1766).</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>The tidewater goby (</textblock>
    <textblock>Eucyclogobius newberryi</textblock>
    <textblock>) is a small fish,</textblock>
    <textblock>rarely exceeding 50 millimeters (2 inches) standard length, and is</textblock>
    <textblock>characterized by large pectoral fins and a ventral sucker-like disk</textblock>
    <textblock>formed by the complete fusion of the pelvic fins. The tidewater goby</textblock>
    <textblock>was first described as a new species (</textblock>
    <textblock>Gobius newberryi</textblock>
    <textblock>) by Girard</textblock>
    <textblock>(1856), from specimens collected in the San Francisco Bay area. Based</textblock>
    <textblock>on Girard's specimens, Gill (1862) reassigned</textblock>
    <textblock>Gobius newberryi</textblock>
    <textblock>to the</textblock>
    <textblock>newly described genus</textblock>
    <textblock>Eucyclogobius</textblock>
    <textblock>(Eschmeyer 1990).</textblock>
    <textblock>A member of the family Gobiidae, the tidewater goby is the only</textblock>
    <textblock>species in the genus</textblock>
    <textblock>Eucyclogobius</textblock>
    <textblock>and is almost unique among fishes</textblock>
    <textblock>along the Pacific coast of the United States in its restriction to</textblock>
    <textblock>waters with low salinities in California's coastal wetlands. All life</textblock>
    <textblock>stages of tidewater gobies are found at the upper end of lagoons in</textblock>
    <textblock>salinities less than 10 parts per thousand (ppt); however, gobies from</textblock>
    <textblock>two populations have been collected and reared in slightly higher</textblock>
    <textblock>salinities (Ramona Swenson, University of California, Berkeley,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.</textblock>
    <textblock>1993). Although its closest relatives are marine species, the tidewater</textblock>
    <textblock>goby does not have a marine life history phase. This lack of a marine</textblock>
    <textblock>phase severely restricts the frequency of genetic exchange between</textblock>
    <textblock>coastal lagoon populations and significantly lowers the potential for</textblock>
    <textblock>natural recolonization of a locality once extirpated. Studies by</textblock>
    <textblock>Crabtree (1985) noted that some populations of gobies have</textblock>
    <textblock>differentiated genetically, indicating a long period of isolation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Tidewater gobies have a short lifespan and seem to be an annual species</textblock>
    <textblock>(Irwin and Stoltz 1984, Swift 1990), further restricting their potential</textblock>
    <textblock>to recolonize habitats from which they have been extirpated.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
