<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00106</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00077</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>NEBKOTA Railway, Inc. (NEBKOTA), a noncarrier, has filed a notice of exemption under 49 CFR 1150.31 to acquire and operate a 73.5-mile line of the Chicago and North Western Transportation Company (CNW) between Merriman, NE, at or near milepost 331.0, and Chadron, NE., at or near milepost 404.5.</textblock>
    <textblock>The transaction includes incidental trackage rights for NEBKOTA over a 27.8-mile CNW rail line between Chadron, NE, at or near milepost 404.5, and Crawford, NE, at or near milepost 432.3, to allow NEBKOTA to interchange with Burlington Northern Railroad Company. The transaction was to become effective on or after January 10, 1994. The parties certify that NEBKOTA's projected revenues do not exceed those that would qualify it as a class III carrier.</textblock>
    <textblock>If the notice of exemption contains false or misleading information, the exemption is void</textblock>
    <textblock>ab initio</textblock>
    <textblock>. Petitions to revoke the exemption under 49 U.S.C. 10505(d) may be filed at any time. The filing of a petition to revoke will not automatically stay the transaction. Pleadings must be filed with the Commission and served on Thomas F. McFarland, Jr., Belnap, Spencer, McFarland &amp; Herman, 20 North Wacker Drive, suite 3118, Chicago, IL 60606-3103.</textblock>
    <textblock>Decided: January 14, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Commission, David M. Konschnik, Director, Office of Proceedings.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Corrected Notice of Exemption</textblock>
    <textblock>Nebkota Railway, Inc._Acquisition and Operation Exemption; Line of Chicago and North Western Transportation Company</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footcite/>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>A notice served and published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on January 24, 1994, incorrectly conditioned the exemption to protect employees affected by the acquisition and operation under</textblock>
    <textblock>New York Dock Ry._Control_Brooklyn Eastern Dist.</textblock>
    <textblock>, 360 I.C.C. 60 (1979), and employees affected by the trackage rights under</textblock>
    <textblock>Norfolk and Western R. Co._Trackage Rights_BN</textblock>
    <textblock>, 354 I.C.C. 605 (1978), as modified in</textblock>
    <textblock>Mendocino Coast Ry., Inc._Lease and Operate</textblock>
    <textblock>, 360 I.C.C. 653 (1980). Those conditions should not have been included; they are not routinely imposed in an exemption from the requirements of 49 U.S.C. 10901.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Finance Docket No. 32442]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Sidney L. Strickland, Jr.,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2585 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7035-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
