<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00031</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00016</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>This action has been classified as a table 3 action by the Regional Administrator under the procedures published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on January 19, 1989 (54 FR 2214-2225). On January 6, 1989, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) waived tables 2 and 3 SIP revisions (54 FR 2222) from the requirements of section 3 of Executive Order 12291 for two years. EPA has submitted a request for a permanent waiver for table 2 and table 3 SIP revisions. OMB has agreed to continue the waiver until such time as it rules on EPA's request. This request continues in effect under Executive Order 12866 which superseded Executive Order 12291 on September 30, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Nothing in this action shall be construed as permitting or allowing or establishing a precedent for any future request for a revision to any SIP. Each request for revision to the SIP shall be considered separately in light of specific technical, economic, and environmental factors and in relation to relevant statutory and regulatory requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under the Regulatory Flexibility Act, 5 U.S.C. 600</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.,</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA must prepare a regulatory flexibility analysis assessing the impact of any proposed or final rule on small entities. (5 U.S.C. 603 and 604) Alternatively, EPA may certify that the rule will not have a significant impact on a substantial number of small entities. Small entities include small businesses, small not-for-profit enterprises, and government entities with jurisdiction over populations of less than 50,000.</textblock>
    <textblock>SIP approvals under section 110 and subchapter I, part D of the CAA do not create any new requirements, but simply approve requirements that the State is already imposing. Therefore, because the federal SIP-approval does not impose any new requirements, I certify that it does not have a significant impact on any small entities affected. Moreover, due to the nature of the federal-state relationship under the CAA, preparation of a regulatory flexibility analysis would constitute federal inquiry into the economic reasonableness of state action. The CAA forbids EPA to base its actions concerning SIPs on such grounds.</textblock>
    <textblock>Union Electric Co.</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. E.P.A.,</textblock>
    <textblock>427 U.S. 246, 256-66 (S.Ct. 1976); 42 U.S.C. 7410(a)(2).</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 40 CFR Part 52</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental protection, Air pollution control, Incorporation by reference, Intergovernmental relations, Particulate matter, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 17, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Patrick M. Tobin,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Administrator.</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 52 of chapter I, title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 52_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 52 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 7401-7671q.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart B_Alabama</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 52.50 is amended by adding paragraph (c)(63) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§52.50</textblock>
    <textblock>Identification of plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(63) Provisions for coke ovens were submitted by the Alabama Department of Environmental Management on September 25, 1985.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Incorporation by reference</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Alabama Department of Environmental Management Administrative Code, Chapter 335-3-4-.17, Steel Mills Located in Etowah County, adopted September 18, 1985.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Other material.</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) None.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2520 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
