<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00066</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00013</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>The callippe silverspot butterfly (</textblock>
    <textblock>Speyeria callippe callippe</textblock>
    <textblock>) is a</textblock>
    <textblock>member of the Nymphalidae family. The animal was described by J.A.</textblock>
    <textblock>Boisduval (1852) from specimens collected during the month of June by</textblock>
    <textblock>Pierre Lorquin in San Francisco, California (dos Passos and Grey 1947).</textblock>
    <textblock>Arnold (1983, 1985) conducted taxonomic studies on the subspecies of</textblock>
    <textblock>Speyeria callippe</textblock>
    <textblock>using wing characters. His investigation concluded</textblock>
    <textblock>that the species consisted of 3 subspecies rather than the widely</textblock>
    <textblock>recognized and accepted 16 subspecies. Based on his study, the range of</textblock>
    <textblock>Speyeria callippe callippe</textblock>
    <textblock>would extend from Oregon to southern</textblock>
    <textblock>California and east into the Great Basin (Arnold 1985). A comprehensive</textblock>
    <textblock>analysis of this species found that the original classification remains</textblock>
    <textblock>more appropriate and that subspecies</textblock>
    <textblock>callippe</textblock>
    <textblock>is restricted to the</textblock>
    <textblock>northern San Francisco Bay region (Hammond 1986, Murphy undated).</textblock>
    <textblock>Hammond determined that the analysis by Arnold used invalid</textblock>
    <textblock>morphological characteristics. The Service recognizes the conclusions</textblock>
    <textblock>of Hammond (1986) and the distribution of the callippe silverspot</textblock>
    <textblock>butterfly as described by Sterling Mattoon (Sterling Mattoon, amateur</textblock>
    <textblock>lepidopterist,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1991).</textblock>
    <textblock>The callippe silverspot butterfly is a medium-sized butterfly with</textblock>
    <textblock>a wingspan of approximately 55 millimeters (2.17 inches). The upper</textblock>
    <textblock>wings are brown with extensive black spots and lines, and the basal</textblock>
    <textblock>areas are extremely melanic (dark-colored). The undersides are brown,</textblock>
    <textblock>orange-brown, and tan with black lines and distinctive black and bright</textblock>
    <textblock>silver spots. The basal areas of the wings and body are densely</textblock>
    <textblock>pubescent (hairy). The discal area on the upper wings of the callippe</textblock>
    <textblock>silverspot butterfly is darker and more extensively yellow on the</textblock>
    <textblock>hindwings than the related Lilian's silverspot butterfly (</textblock>
    <textblock>Speyeria</textblock>
    <textblock>callippe liliana</textblock>
    <textblock>). The callippe silverspot butterfly is larger and has</textblock>
    <textblock>a darker ground color with more melanic areas on the basal areas of the</textblock>
    <textblock>wings than Comstock's silverspot butterfly (</textblock>
    <textblock>Speyeria callippe</textblock>
    <textblock>comstocki</textblock>
    <textblock>).</textblock>
    <textblock>The callippe silverspot butterfly is found in native grassland and</textblock>
    <textblock>adjacent habitats (Steiner 1990; Mattoon,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1991; Thomas Reid</textblock>
    <textblock>Associates 1982). The females lay their eggs on the dry remains of the</textblock>
    <textblock>larval foodplant, Johnny jump-up (</textblock>
    <textblock>Viola pedunculata</textblock>
    <textblock>), or on the</textblock>
    <textblock>surrounding debris (Arnold 1981, Thomas Reid Associates 1982). Upon</textblock>
    <textblock>hatching after about a week, the larvae eat their egg shells. The</textblock>
    <textblock>caterpillars wander a short distance and spin a silk pad upon which they</textblock>
    <textblock>spend the summer and winter. The larvae are dark-colored with many</textblock>
    <textblock>branching sharp spines on the back. Upon termination of diapause in the</textblock>
    <textblock>spring, the caterpillars immediately seek out the foodplant. In May,</textblock>
    <textblock>after having gone through five instars (i.e., skin sheddings), the</textblock>
    <textblock>larvae form pupa within a chamber of leaves that they have drawn</textblock>
    <textblock>together with silk. The adults emerge in about 2 weeks and live for</textblock>
    <textblock>approximately 3 weeks. Depending upon environmental conditions, the</textblock>
    <textblock>flight period of this single-brooded butterfly ranges from mid-May to</textblock>
    <textblock>late July. The adults exhibit hilltopping behavior, a phenomenon in</textblock>
    <textblock>which males and females seek a topographic summit to mate (Shields</textblock>
    <textblock>1967).</textblock>
    <textblock>The callippe silverspot butterfly was known historically to occur</textblock>
    <textblock>in seven populations in the San Francisco Bay region. This animal does</textblock>
    <textblock>not occur north of the Golden Gate or Carquinez Straits (Mattoon,</textblock>
    <textblock>in</textblock>
    <textblock>litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1991; Paul Opler, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, pers. comm.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1992). The historic range of the callippe silverspot butterfly includes</textblock>
    <textblock>the inner coast range on the eastern shore of San Francisco Bay from</textblock>
    <textblock>northwestern Contra Costa County south to the Castro Valley area in</textblock>
    <textblock>Alameda County. On the west side of the Bay, it ranged from San</textblock>
    <textblock>Francisco south to the vicinity of La Honda in San Mateo County. Five</textblock>
    <textblock>colonies, including the one located at Twin Peaks in San Francisco, were</textblock>
    <textblock>extirpated. The remaining colonies exist on mostly privately owned</textblock>
    <textblock>land, but also on city, county, and State owned land. Currently, extant</textblock>
    <textblock>colonies are known only from San Bruno Mountain in San Mateo County and</textblock>
    <textblock>a city park (Mattoon,</textblock>
    <textblock>in litt.,</textblock>
    <textblock>1991).</textblock>
    <textblock>Behren's silverspot butterfly (</textblock>
    <textblock>Speyeria zerene behrensii</textblock>
    <textblock>) is a</textblock>
    <textblock>member of the Nymphalidae family. William H. Edwards described this</textblock>
    <textblock>taxon in 1869 based on an adult male collected by an unknown</textblock>
    <textblock>lepidopterist in Mendocino, California (dos Passos and Grey 1947,</textblock>
    <textblock>Edwards 1869). It is a medium-sized butterfly with a wingspan of</textblock>
    <textblock>approximately 55 millimeters (2.17 inches). The upper surfaces are</textblock>
    <textblock>golden brown with numerous black spots and lines. The undersides are</textblock>
    <textblock>brown, orange-brown, and tan with black lines and distinctive silver and</textblock>
    <textblock>black spots. The basal areas of the wings and body are densely</textblock>
    <textblock>pubescent.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
