<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00143</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00098</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Intent To Rule on Application To Impose and Use the Revenue From a Passenger Facility Charge (PFC) at the Chattanooga Metropolitan Airport, Chattanooga, TN</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of intent to rule on application.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>To FAA proposes to rule and invites public comment on the application to impose and use the revenue from a PFC at the Chattanooga Metropolitan Airport under the provisions of the Aviation Safety and Capacity Expansion Act of 1990 (title IX of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990) (Public Law 101-508) and part 158 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (14 CFR part 158).</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be received on or before March 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this application may be mailed or delivered in triplicate to the FAA at the following address: Memphis Airports District Office, 2851 Directors Cove, suite</textblock>
    <textblock>#3</textblock>
    <textblock>, Memphis, TN 38131-0301.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, one copy of any comments submitted to the FAA must be mailed or delivered to Mr. Don L. Jones, Chairman of the Chattanooga Metropolitan Airport Authority at the following address: Chattanooga Metropolitan Airport, P.O. Box 224444, 1001 Airport Road, Chattanooga, TN 37422.</textblock>
    <textblock>Air carriers and foreign air carriers may submit copies of written comments previously provided to the Chattanooga Metropolitan Airport Authority under ยง158.2 of part 158.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Memphis Airports District Office; ATTN: Mr. Paul Fruzzetti, Airports Planner; 2851 Directors Cove, suite</textblock>
    <textblock>#3</textblock>
    <textblock>; Memphis, Tennessee 38131-0301; Telephone (901) 544-3495. The application may be reviewed in person at this location.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA proposes to rule and invites public comment on the application to impose and use the revenue from a PFC at the Chattanooga Metropolitan Airport under provisions of the Aviation Safety and Capacity Expansion Act of 1990 (title IX of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990) (Public law 101-508) and part 158 of the Federal Aviation Regulations (14 CFR part 158).</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 26, 1994 the FAA determined that the application to impose and use the revenue from a PFC submitted by the Chattanooga Metropolitan Airport Authority was substantially complete within the requirements of ยง158.25 of part 158. The FAA will approve or disapprove the application, in whole or in part, no later than April 26, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The following is a brief overview of the application.</textblock>
    <textblock>Level of the proposed PFC:</textblock>
    <textblock>$3.00.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed charge effective date:</textblock>
    <textblock>May 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed charge expiration date:</textblock>
    <textblock>December 25, 2001.</textblock>
    <textblock>Total estimated net PFC revenue:</textblock>
    <textblock>$7,822,048.</textblock>
    <textblock>Brief description of proposed project(s):</textblock>
    <textblock>Install Baggage Claim Devices</textblock>
    <textblock>Install Loading Bridges</textblock>
    <textblock>Install Security System</textblock>
    <textblock>Miscellaneous Terminal Improvements</textblock>
    <textblock>Reconstruct Passenger Terminal Complex</textblock>
    <textblock>Master Plan and part 150 Noise Study Update</textblock>
    <textblock>Modify/Replace Airfield Signage</textblock>
    <textblock>Install Ramp Security System</textblock>
    <textblock>PFC Administrative Costs</textblock>
    <textblock>Widen/Strengthen Taxiway A</textblock>
    <textblock>Class or classes of air carriers which the public agency has requested not be required to collect PFCs:</textblock>
    <textblock>Air Taxi Operators_that class of Air Carriers operating under part 135 or part 298 of the Federal Aviation Regulations on an on-demand, non-scheduled basis, and not selling tickets to individual passengers.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person may inspect the application in person at the FAA office listed above under</textblock>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, any person may, upon request, inspect the application, notice and other documents germane to the application in person at the Chattanooga Metropolitan Airport Authority.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Atlanta, Georgia on January 27, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Troy R. Butler,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>PFC Program Manager, Airports Division, Southern Region.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2560 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
