<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00008</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00005</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Delegations of Authority and Organization; Emergency Permit Matters</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>21 CFR Part 5</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration, HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is amending the regulations for delegations of authority relating to general redelegations of authority from the Commissioner of Food and Drugs by making revisions to the regulations on initial emergency permit orders and notices of confirmation of effective date of final regulations on food matters. This amendment to the regulations will include foods for animal as well as human consumption and will add the Director and Deputy Director, Center for Veterinary Medicine (CVM), to those already delegated authority.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ellen Rawlings, Division of Management Systems and Policy (HFA-340), Food and Drug Administration, 5600 Fishers Lane, Rockville, MD 20857, 301-443-4976.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>FDA is amending the regulations in §5.62</textblock>
    <textblock>Issuance of initial emergency permit orders and notices of confirmation of effective date of final regulations on food matters</textblock>
    <textblock>(21 CFR 5.62) to include foods for animal as well as human consumption, and to give the Director and Deputy Director, CVM authority to issue initial emergency permit orders under §508.5 (21 CFR 508.5) and to confirm the effective date of final regulations on animal food matters.</textblock>
    <textblock>This document is issued as a final rule because the rulemaking requirements in 5 U.S.C. 553 do not apply to rules of agency organization, procedure, or practice.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further redelegation of the authority delegated is not authorized. Authority delegated to a position by title may be exercised by a person officially designated to serve in such position in an acting capacity or on a temporary basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 21 CFR Part 5</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority delegations (Government agencies), Imports, Organization and functions (Government agencies).</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and under authority delegated to the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, 21 CFR part 5 is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 5_DELEGATIONS OF AUTHORITY AND ORGANIZATION</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for 21 CFR part 5 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>5 U.S.C. 504, 552, App. 2; 7 U.S.C. 138a, 2271; 15 U.S.C. 638, 1261-1282, 3701-3711a; secs. 2-12 of the Fair Packaging and Labeling Act (15 U.S.C. 1451-1461); 21 U.S.C. 41-50, 61-63, 141-149, 467f, 679(b), 801-886, 1031-1309; secs. 201-903 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. 321-394); 35 U.S.C. 156; secs. 301, 302, 303, 307, 310, 311, 351, 352, 361, 362, 1701-1706, 2101, 2125, 2127, 2128 of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 241, 242, 242a, 242l, 242n, 243, 262, 263, 264, 265, 300u-300u-5, 300aa-1, 300aa-25, 300aa-27, 300aa-28); 42 U.S.C. 1395y, 3246b, 4332, 4831(a), 10007-10008; E.O. 11490, 11921, and 12591; secs. 312, 313, 314 of the National Childhood Vaccine Injury Act of 1986, Pub. L. 99-660 (42 U.S.C. 300aa-1 note).</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 5.62 is amended by revising the section heading and the text, by redesignating the text as paragraph (a), and by adding new paragraph (b) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§5.62</textblock>
    <textblock>Issuance of initial emergency permit orders and notices of confirmation of effective date of final regulations on food for human and animal consumption.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The Director and Deputy Director, Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition, are authorized to issue initial emergency permit orders under §108.5 of this chapter and notices of confirmation of effective date of final regulations on human food matters promulgated under section 701(e) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (the act).</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) The Director and Deputy Director, Center for Veterinary Medicine, are authorized to issue initial emergency permit orders under §508.5 of this chapter for foods for animals and notices of confirmation of the effective date of final regulations on animal food matters promulgated under section 701(e) of the act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 27, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Michael R. Taylor,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Commissioner for Policy.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2473 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
