<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00003</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Political activities (Federal employees).</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Office of Personnel Management.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lorraine A. Green,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Director.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, the Office of Personnel Management is revising 5 CFR part 733 to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 733_POLITICAL ACTIVITY_FEDERAL EMPLOYEES RESIDING IN DESIGNATED LOCALITIES</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec.</textblock>
    <textblock>733.101␣Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>733.102␣Political activities permitted_employees residing in designated localities.</textblock>
    <textblock>733.103␣Exclusion of employees in certain agencies and offices.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>5 U.S.C. 7325.</textblock>
    <textblock>§733.101</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>In this part:</textblock>
    <textblock>Employee</textblock>
    <textblock>means:</textblock>
    <textblock>Any individual (other than the President, the Vice President, or a member of the uniformed services) employed or holding office in_</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) An Executive agency other than the General Accounting Office;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A position within the competitive service which is not in an Executive agency;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The government of the District of Columbia, other than the Mayor or a member of the City Council or the Recorder of Deeds; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The United States Postal Service or the Postal Rate Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>Partisan political office</textblock>
    <textblock>means any office for which any candidate is nominated or elected as representing a party any of whose candidates for Presidential elector received votes in the last preceding election at which Presidential electors were selected, but does not include any office or position within a political party or affiliated organization.</textblock>
    <textblock>Political contribution</textblock>
    <textblock>means any gift, subscription, loan, advance, or deposit of money or anything of value, made for any political purpose. A political contribution includes:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Any contract, promise, or agreement, express or implied, whether or not legally enforceable, to make a contribution for any political purpose;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Any payment by any person, other than a candidate or a political party or affiliated organization, of compensation for the personal services of another person which are rendered to any candidate or political party or affiliated organization without charge for any political purpose; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The provision of personal services for any political purpose.</textblock>
    <textblock>§733.102</textblock>
    <textblock>Political activities permitted_employees residing in designated localities.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Employees who reside in a municipality or political subdivision designated by OPM under paragraph (d) of this section may:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Run as independent candidates for election to partisan political office in elections for local offices of the municipality or political subdivision; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Accept or receive political contributions in connection with the local elections of the municipality or political subdivision.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Employees may not solicit political contributions from the general public.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Candidacy for, and service in, a partisan political office shall not result in neglect of, or interference with, the performance of the duties of the employee or create a conflict, or apparent confict, of interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) OPM may designate a municipality or political subdivision in Maryland or Virginia in the immediate vicinity of the District of Columbia, or a municipality in which the majority of voters are employed by the Government of the United States, when OPM determines that, because of special or unusual circumstances, it is in the domestic interest of employees to participate in local elections. Information as to the documentation required to support a request for designation is furnished by the General Counsel of OPM on request. The following municipalities and political subdivisions have been designated, effective on the day specified:</textblock>
    <textblock>In Maryland</textblock>
    <textblock>Annapolis (May 16, 1941).</textblock>
    <textblock>Anne Arundel County (March 14, 1973).</textblock>
    <textblock>Berwyn Heights (June 15, 1944).</textblock>
    <textblock>Bethesda (Feb. 17, 1943).</textblock>
    <textblock>Bladensburg (Apr. 20, 1942).</textblock>
    <textblock>Bowie (Apr. 11, 1952).</textblock>
    <textblock>Brentwood (Sept. 26, 1940).</textblock>
    <textblock>Calvert County (June 18, 1992).</textblock>
    <textblock>Capitol Heights (Nov. 12, 1940).</textblock>
    <textblock>Cheverly (Dec. 18, 1940).</textblock>
    <textblock>Chevy Chase, Martin's Additions 1, 2, 3, and 4 (Feb. 13, 1941).</textblock>
    <textblock>Chevy Chase, section 1 and 2 (Mar. 4, 1941).</textblock>
    <textblock>Chevy Chase, section 3 (Oct. 8, 1940).</textblock>
    <textblock>Chevy Chase, section 4 (Oct. 2, 1940).</textblock>
    <textblock>Chevy Chase View (Feb. 26, 1941).</textblock>
    <textblock>College Park (June 13, 1945).</textblock>
    <textblock>Cottage City (Jan. 15, 1941).</textblock>
    <textblock>District Heights (Nov. 2, 1940).</textblock>
    <textblock>Edmonston (Oct. 24, 1940).</textblock>
    <textblock>Fairmont Heights (Oct. 24, 1940).</textblock>
    <textblock>Forest Heights (Apr. 22, 1949).</textblock>
    <textblock>Frederick County (May 31, 1991).</textblock>
    <textblock>Garrett Park (Oct. 2, 1940).</textblock>
    <textblock>Glenarden (May 21, 1941).</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
