<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00022</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Increasing the Amounts of the Rewards and Adding Money Laundering to the List of Offenses for Which Rewards May Be Paid for Information</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>POSTAL SERVICE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>39 CFR Part 233</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Postal Service.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In 1993, the Postal Service revised its reward policy by increasing the reward amounts and by adding money laundering to the list of offenses for which rewards may be paid for information and services leading to the arrest and conviction of persons committing postal crimes. Consequently, this rule amends the regulations to reflect the revised reward policy.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>H.J. Bauman, (202) 268-4415.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Postal Service offers rewards for information and services leading to the arrest and conviction of perpetrators of the following crimes: (1) Murder or manslaughter of a postal employee; (2) assault on a postal employee; (3) robbery or attempted robbery of any custodian of postal money or property; (4) burglary of a post office; (5) theft, possession, destruction, or obstruction of mail; (6) postage or meter tampering; (7) offenses involving money orders; (8) mailing bombs or explosives; (9) mailing poisons, controlled substances, or hazardous materials; (10) using the mails for child pornography; and (11) using the mails for money laundering.</textblock>
    <textblock>Postal Service regulations concerning these rewards are published in title 39 of the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR) as a note following ยง233.2(b). Since the Postal Service has decided to increase the amounts of the rewards, it is necessary to amend the CFR to reflect the revised Postal Service policy. In addition, the offense of money laundering (i.e., mailing or causing to be mailed any money which has been obtained illegally), has been added to the reward list.</textblock>
    <textblock>In summary, ยง233.2 is amended by: (1) Revising paragraph (b) to substitute ``Poster 296'' for ``Notice 96''; (2) adding paragraph (b)(1)(x) to add money laundering to the list of offenses; and (3) revising the note following paragraph (b)(2) to increase the reward amounts.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 39 CFR Part 233</textblock>
    <textblock>Crime, Law enforcement, Postal Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, 39 CFR part 233 is amended as set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 233_INSPECTION SERVICE/INSPECTOR GENERAL AUTHORITY</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 233 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>39 U.S.C. 101, 401, 402, 403, 404, 406, 410, 411, 3005(e)(1); 12 U.S.C. 3401-3422; 18 U.S.C. 981, 1956, 1957, 2254, 3061; 21 U.S.C. 881; Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended (Pub. L. No. 95-452, as amended), 5 U.S.C. App. 3.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 233.2 is amended by revising the introductory text of paragraph (b)(1), adding paragraph (b)(1)(x) and revising the Note after paragraph (b)(2) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง233.2</textblock>
    <textblock>Circulars and rewards.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rewards</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Rewards will be paid in the amounts and under the conditions stated in Poster 296,</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Reward,</textblock>
    <textblock>for the arrest and conviction of persons for the following postal offenses:</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
