<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00033</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(i) Loans made to related parties;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Loans outstanding at yearend to related parties;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Loans outstanding at yearend to related parties that are made on more favorable terms than those prevailing at the time for comparable transactions with unrelated borrowers; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Loans outstanding at yearend to related parties that involve more than a normal risk of collectibility (as defined in ยง620.1(i) of this chapter).</textblock>
    <textblock>(k)</textblock>
    <textblock>Relationship with independent public accountant.</textblock>
    <textblock>If a change in the accountant who has previously examined and expressed an opinion on the Systemwide combined financial statements has taken place since the last annual report to investors or if a disagreement with an accountant has occurred that the Funding Corporation would be required to report to the FCA under part 621 of this chapter, disclose the information required by ยง621.4(c) and (d) of this chapter.</textblock>
    <textblock>(l)</textblock>
    <textblock>Financial statements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Furnish Systemwide combined financial statements and related footnotes that have been prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles (GAAP) and instructions and other requirements of the Farm Credit Administration and that have been audited in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards by a qualified public accountant (as defined in ยง621.2(i) of this chapter) and an opinion expressed thereon. The Systemwide combined financial statements shall include the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) A balance sheet as of the end of each of the 2 most recent fiscal years; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Statements of income, statements of changes in capital stock and surplus (or, if applicable, statements of changes in protected borrower capital and capital stock and surplus), and statements of cash flows for each of the 3 most recent fiscal years.</textblock>
    <textblock>(m)</textblock>
    <textblock>Supplemental information.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Furnish supplemental information regarding the components of the Systemwide combined financial statements that has been prepared in accordance with the requirements of this paragraph and instructions of the FCA and that has been examined by a qualified public accountant for compliance with FCA regulations and guidelines and an opinion expressed thereon.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) At a minimum, the supplemental information shall include the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Supplemental balance sheet information as of the end of the most recent fiscal year; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Supplemental income statement information for the most recently completed fiscal year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) At a minimum, the report shall present supplemental information showing combined financial data for the following components, on a stand-alone basis:</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Banks;</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Associations;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Financial Assistance Corporation;</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Combined financial data of the System without Insurance Fund;</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) The Insurance Fund and related combination entries; and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
