<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00031</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-1-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(vi) Capital stock and surplus as a percentage of total assets at yearend.</textblock>
    <textblock>(vii) Debt to capital stock and surplus at yearend.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g)</textblock>
    <textblock>Discussion and analysis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Fully discuss any material aspects of financial condition, changes in financial condition, and results of operations of System institutions, on a combined basis, during the last 3 fiscal years or such other time periods specified in the following paragraphs of this section. Identify favorable and unfavorable trends, and significant events or uncertainties necessary to understand the financial condition and results of operations of the System. At a minimum, the discussion shall include the following:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Loan portfolio.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Describe the loan portfolio of the System by major loan purpose category, indicating the amount and approximate percentage of the total dollar portfolio represented by each major category.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Disclose the amount of loans outstanding that were used to finance the purchases of stock or other equities of System institutions, if any.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Risk exposure.</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Describe and analyze all high risk assets and other property owned, including an analysis of the nature and extent of significant credit risks and potential credit risk within the loan portfolio and of other information that could adversely affect the loan portfolio and other property owned.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Provide an analysis of the allowance for loan losses that includes the ratios of the allowance to loans (outstanding at yearend) and net chargeoffs to average loans, and a discussion of the adequacy of the allowance for losses to absorb the risk inherent in the loan portfolio and the basis for such determination.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv)</textblock>
    <textblock>Secondary market activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Describe and quantify System institutions' secondary market activities and the risk involved in such activities.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Provide an analysis of historical loss experience and the amount provided for risk of loss associated with secondary market activities, if any.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Results of operations.</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) Describe, on a comparative basis, changes in the major components of net interest income. Include a discussion of significant factors that contributed to the changes and quantify the amount of change(s) due to an increase or decrease in volume and the amount due to changes in interest rates earned and paid, based on averages for each period.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Describe any unusual or infrequent events or transactions or any significant economic changes that materially affected reported income and, in each case, indicate the extent to which income was so affected.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii) Discuss the factors underlying any material changes in the return on average assets and return on average capital stock and surplus.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iv) Describe, on a comparative basis, the major components of operating expense and any other significant components of income or expense, indicating the reasons for significant increases or decreases, if any.</textblock>
    <textblock>(v) Describe any known trends or uncertainties that have had, or that are reasonably expected to have, a material impact on net interest income or net income. Disclose any known events that will cause a material change in the relationship between costs and revenues.</textblock>
    <textblock>(vi) Explain the changes that have taken place, by major components on a comparative basis, in the Insurance Fund assets and related restricted capital and how such changes affected reported income.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3)</textblock>
    <textblock>Funding sources and liquidity.</textblock>
    <textblock>_(i)</textblock>
    <textblock>Funding sources.</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Provide in tabular form the component amounts and the total amount of FCS debt obligations, debt obligations issued by banks individually, and Financial Assistance Corporation debt obligations outstanding at yearend for each of the past 2 fiscal years. List debt obligations issued by System institutions separately by type, also separating insured obligations from uninsured obligations. For each type of debt obligation listed provide the following, at a minimum, for each fiscal year listed:</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
    <textblock>) The beginning balance, the total amount of debt issued, the total amount of debt retired, and the yearend balance;</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) The average maturities and the average interest rates on debt outstanding at yearend, and the average maturities and the average interest rates of new debt issued during the year.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Summarize any other sources of funds, including lines of credit with commercial lenders, and their terms.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Liquidity.</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) Describe any FCA regulations or System policies with regard to liquidity and liquidity reserves.</textblock>
    <textblock>(B) Identify any known trends, demands, commitments, events, or uncertainties that will result in, or that are reasonably likely to result in, System liquidity increasing or decreasing in any material way. If a material liquidity deficiency is identified, indicate the course of action that has been taken or is proposed to be taken by management of affected System institutions to remedy the deficiency.</textblock>
    <textblock>(iii)</textblock>
    <textblock>Investment.</textblock>
    <textblock>Briefly describe the System's investment policies and objectives, any regulatory limitations thereon, and the contents of the System's existing investment portfolio.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
