<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00053</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>(Monterey spineflower) has white</textblock>
    <textblock>(rarely pinkish) scarious margins on the involucral lobes and a</textblock>
    <textblock>prostrate to slightly ascending habit that distinguish it from</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegiana.</textblock>
    <textblock>The aggregate of flowers (heads)</textblock>
    <textblock>tend to be small (less than 1 centimeter (cm) (0.4 inches (in)) in</textblock>
    <textblock>diameter) and either distinctly or indistinctly aggregate. The plant is</textblock>
    <textblock>found scattered on sandy soils within coastal dune, coastal scrub,</textblock>
    <textblock>grassland, maritime chaparral, and oak woodland communities along and</textblock>
    <textblock>adjacent to the coast of southern Santa Cruz and northern Monterey</textblock>
    <textblock>Counties and inland to the coastal plain of Salinas Valley.</textblock>
    <textblock>Historically, the plant ranged along the coast from southern Santa Cruz</textblock>
    <textblock>County south to northern San Luis Obispo County and from Monterey inland</textblock>
    <textblock>to the Salinas Valley. Only one collection dating from 1842 was made</textblock>
    <textblock>from northern San Luis Obispo County; however, in recent years it was</textblock>
    <textblock>not collected south of Monterey Peninsula (Reveal and Hardham 1989).</textblock>
    <textblock>Along the immediate coast,</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>was</textblock>
    <textblock>documented at Manresa State Beach and the dunes near Marina. The plant</textblock>
    <textblock>probably was extirpated from a number of historical locations in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Salinas Valley, primarily due to conversion of the original grasslands</textblock>
    <textblock>and valley oak woodlands to agricultural crops (Reveal and Hardham</textblock>
    <textblock>1989). Significant populations of</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens,</textblock>
    <textblock>representing upwards of 70 percent of the range of the plant, were</textblock>
    <textblock>recently documented from Fort Ord (Army Corps of Engineers 1992). These</textblock>
    <textblock>surveys indicated that within grassland communities the plant occurs</textblock>
    <textblock>along roadsides, in firebreaks, and in other disturbed sites. In oak</textblock>
    <textblock>woodland, chaparral, and scrub communities, the plants occur in sandy</textblock>
    <textblock>openings between shrubs. In older stands with a high cover of shrubs,</textblock>
    <textblock>the plant is restricted to roadsides and firebreaks that bisect these</textblock>
    <textblock>communities. The highest densities of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>are</textblock>
    <textblock>located in the central portion of the firing range, where disturbance is</textblock>
    <textblock>the most frequent. Although studies were not conducted on factors that</textblock>
    <textblock>determine the pattern of distribution and the densities of</textblock>
    <textblock>C. pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>on Fort Ord, a correlation exists between open conditions</textblock>
    <textblock>resulting from activities that disturb habitat and high densities of</textblock>
    <textblock>C.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens.</textblock>
    <textblock>Prior to onset of human use of this area, this</textblock>
    <textblock>species was possibly restricted to openings created by wildfires within</textblock>
    <textblock>these communities.</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>(robust spineflower) is comprised of two</textblock>
    <textblock>varieties:</textblock>
    <textblock>C. robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>C. robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegii.</textblock>
    <textblock>A</textblock>
    <textblock>description of the species is broken out below by variety.</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>has thin white to pinkish scarious</textblock>
    <textblock>margins along the basal portions of the teeth and an erect to spreading</textblock>
    <textblock>or prostrate habit. The heads are large (1.5 to 2 cm (0.6 to 0.8 in) in</textblock>
    <textblock>diameter) and distinctly aggregate. The plant once ranged from Alameda</textblock>
    <textblock>to Monterey Counties, but is currently known only from sandy and</textblock>
    <textblock>gravelly soils along and adjacent to the coast of southern Santa Cruz</textblock>
    <textblock>and northern Monterey Counties. Many of the areas from which</textblock>
    <textblock>collections were made in Alameda and San Mateo Counties were urbanized,</textblock>
    <textblock>and no new collections were made from there or from Monterey County for</textblock>
    <textblock>30 years (Ertter 1990). As with</textblock>
    <textblock>C. pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens,</textblock>
    <textblock>the coastal</textblock>
    <textblock>dune and scrub communities were affected by recreational use, urban</textblock>
    <textblock>development, and military activities, and the coastal plain vegetation</textblock>
    <textblock>of the Salinas Valley was converted to agricultural crops. The only</textblock>
    <textblock>known extant populations occur northeast of the city of Santa Cruz on</textblock>
    <textblock>property recently acquired by the city from the University of California</textblock>
    <textblock>and near Sunset and Manresa State Beaches, approximately 12 miles away.</textblock>
    <textblock>The total number of individuals of the plant was estimated to be less</textblock>
    <textblock>than 7,000 in 1990.</textblock>
    <textblock>Specimens collected from certain populations of</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe</textblock>
    <textblock>in the</textblock>
    <textblock>vicinity of Sunset State Beach are ``comparable to</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>''</textblock>
    <textblock>according to Ertter (1990). The Service believes that these populations</textblock>
    <textblock>are best assigned to</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens.</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegii</textblock>
    <textblock>has rose-pink involucral margins</textblock>
    <textblock>confined to the basal portion of the teeth and an erect habit. The</textblock>
    <textblock>heads are medium in size (1 to 1.5 cm (0.4 to 0.6 in) in diameter) and</textblock>
    <textblock>distinctly aggregate. The plant is endemic to Purisima sandstone and</textblock>
    <textblock>Santa Cruz mudstone in Scotts Valley in the Santa Cruz Mountains. Where</textblock>
    <textblock>C. robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegii</textblock>
    <textblock>occurs on Purisima sandstone, the bedrock is</textblock>
    <textblock>overlain with a thin soil layer that supports a meadow community</textblock>
    <textblock>comprised of herbs and low-growing grasses. The presence of certain</textblock>
    <textblock>associated species, such as toad rush (</textblock>
    <textblock>Juncus bufonis</textblock>
    <textblock>), sand pigmyweed</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>Crassula erecta</textblock>
    <textblock>), mosses, and lichens, suggest a high seasonal moisture</textblock>
    <textblock>content. Where the plant occurs on Santa Cruz mudstone, the bedrock is</textblock>
    <textblock>variously mixed with scree or a thin soil layer that also supports a</textblock>
    <textblock>meadow community of herbs and grasses, though of somewhat different</textblock>
    <textblock>composition than those on Purisima sandstone, and with a lower frequency</textblock>
    <textblock>of toadrush, pigmyweed, and lichens (Habitat Restoration Group 1992).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
