<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00025</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Per Diem, Travel and Transportation Allowance Committee</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Office of the Secretary</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Per Diem, Travel and Transportation Allowance Committee.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Publication of changes in per diem rates.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Per Diem, Travel and Transportation Allowance Committee is publishing Civilian Personnel Per Diem Bulletin Number 175. This bulletin lists changes in per diem rates prescribed for U.S. Government employees for official travel in Alaska, Hawaii, Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands and Possessions of the United States. Bulletin Number 175 is being published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>to assure that travelers are paid per diem at the most current rates.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>1 February 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document gives notice of changes in per diem rates prescribed by the Per Diem, Travel and Transportation Allowance Committee for non-foreign areas outside the continental United States. Distribution of Civilian Personnel Per Diem Bulletins by mail was discontinued effective 1 June 1979. Per Diem Bulletins published periodically in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>now constitute the only notification of change in per diem rates to agencies and establishments outside the Department of Defense.</textblock>
    <textblock>The text of the Bulletin follows:</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 5000-04-M</textblock>
  </billing>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEN04FE94.001</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEN04FE94.002</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEN04FE94.003</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEN04FE94.004</textblock>
  </import>
  <import>
    <textblock>E:GRAPHICSEN04FE94.005</textblock>
  </import>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 5000-04-C</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
