<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00081</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00056</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>January 26, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>On May 10, 1990, the Commission accepted the Public Safety Plan for Florida (Region 9). On October 25, 1993, Region 9 submitted a proposed amendment to its plan that would, in part, add an additional subregion, clarify timeframes for applications for pooled and dedicated channel allotments, add explicit channel loading requirements, and clarify and enlarge upon mutual aid requirements. Because the proposed amendment is a major change to the Region 9 plan, the Commission is soliciting comments from the public before taking action. (See Report and Order, General Docket No. 87-112, 3 FCC Rcd 905 (1987), at paragraph 57.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested parties may file comments to the proposed amendment on or before March 4, 1994 and reply comments on or before March 21, 1994. Commenters should send an original and five copies of comments to the Secretary, Federal Communications Commission, Washington, DC 20554 and should clearly identify them as submissions to Gen. Docket 90-119 Florida-Public Safety Region 9.</textblock>
    <textblock>Questions regarding this public notice may be directed to Betty Woolford, Private Radio Bureau, (202) 632-6497 or Ray LaForge, Office of Engineering and Technology, (202) 653-8112.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[DA 94-74]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Comments Invited on Florida Public Safety Plan Amendment</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William F. Caton,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2479 Filed 2-3-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
