<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00064</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Each of the four plants face anthropogenic threats (see Factor A</textblock>
    <textblock>and Factor B in ``Summary of Factors Affecting the Species''), and many of</textblock>
    <textblock>the remaining populations of these species occur on privately owned</textblock>
    <textblock>property for which development is proposed or on which vandalism has</textblock>
    <textblock>already been noted. Due to the small number of populations of</textblock>
    <textblock>C.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegiana</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>Erysimum teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>and the documented</textblock>
    <textblock>vandalism and proposed development of their habitats, the publication of</textblock>
    <textblock>precise maps and descriptions of critical habitat in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal</textblock>
    <textblock>Register</textblock>
    <textblock>would make them more vulnerable to such incidents and could</textblock>
    <textblock>contribute to their decline. In addition, no known Federal action,</textblock>
    <textblock>authorization, licensing, or funding on these lands exist, hence a</textblock>
    <textblock>designation of critical habitat would provide no additional protection</textblock>
    <textblock>under section 7 of the Act. Therefore, it would not be prudent to</textblock>
    <textblock>designate critical habitat for these two species. The appropriate</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies and landowners can be notified of the locations and management</textblock>
    <textblock>needs of these plants. Protection of these populations will be</textblock>
    <textblock>addressed through the recovery process.</textblock>
    <textblock>Available Conservation Measures</textblock>
    <textblock>Conservation measures provided to species listed as endangered or</textblock>
    <textblock>threatened under the Endangered Species Act include recognition, recovery actions, requirements for Federal protection, and prohibitions</textblock>
    <textblock>against certain activities. Recognition through listing encourages and</textblock>
    <textblock>results in conservation actions by Federal, State, and private agencies,</textblock>
    <textblock>groups, and individuals. The Endangered Species Act provides for</textblock>
    <textblock>possible land acquisition and cooperation with the States and requires</textblock>
    <textblock>that recovery actions be carried out for all listed species. The</textblock>
    <textblock>protection required of Federal agencies and the prohibitions against</textblock>
    <textblock>certain activities involving listed plants are discussed, in part,</textblock>
    <textblock>below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Section 7(a) of the Act, as amended, requires Federal agencies to</textblock>
    <textblock>evaluate their actions with respect to any species that is proposed or</textblock>
    <textblock>listed as endangered or threatened and with respect to its critical</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat, if any is being designated. Regulations implementing this</textblock>
    <textblock>interagency cooperation provision of the Act are codified at 50 CFR part</textblock>
    <textblock>402. Section 7(a)(2) requires Federal agencies to insure that</textblock>
    <textblock>activities they authorize, fund, or carry out are not likely to</textblock>
    <textblock>jeopardize the continued existence of such a species or to destroy or</textblock>
    <textblock>adversely modify its critical habitat. If a Federal action may affect a</textblock>
    <textblock>listed species or its critical habitat, the responsible Federal agency</textblock>
    <textblock>must enter into formal consultation with the Service.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal activities potentially impacting one or more of the four</textblock>
    <textblock>taxa include road and building construction projects and perhaps</textblock>
    <textblock>waterfowl management practices on Federal land. Populations of one of</textblock>
    <textblock>the four plants occur, at least in part, on Federal land. Fort Ord,</textblock>
    <textblock>which is managed by the Department of Defense, supports populations of</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>on the western and southern portion of</textblock>
    <textblock>the base. The Department of Defense indicated that closure and transfer</textblock>
    <textblock>of the base at Fort Ord will be phased over many years. Therefore,</textblock>
    <textblock>potential impacts to</textblock>
    <textblock>C. pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>as a result of the land</textblock>
    <textblock>transfer cannot be determined at this time.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>is</textblock>
    <textblock>also thought to occur on the Salinas River National Wildlife Refuge,</textblock>
    <textblock>which is managed by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service; currently no</textblock>
    <textblock>activities occur on the Refuge that are known to affect the</textblock>
    <textblock>C. pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens.</textblock>
    <textblock>Activities relating to the discharge of fill materials into waters</textblock>
    <textblock>of the United States and other special aquatic sites are regulated by</textblock>
    <textblock>section 404 of the Clean Water Act and may affect Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegiana</textblock>
    <textblock>and</textblock>
    <textblock>Erysimum teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>where they occur adjacent to</textblock>
    <textblock>sand quarry operations. The pending proposal to develop the two</textblock>
    <textblock>Glenwood Estates parcels in Scotts Valley may also involve the discharge</textblock>
    <textblock>of fill materials. The Army Corps of Engineers would be required to</textblock>
    <textblock>consult with the Service on any section 404 permitting actions that may</textblock>
    <textblock>affect these species.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Act and its implementing regulations found at 50 CFR 17.61,</textblock>
    <textblock>17.62, and 17.63 for endangered species and 17.71 and 17.71 for</textblock>
    <textblock>threatened species set forth a series of general prohibitions and</textblock>
    <textblock>exceptions that apply to all endangered or threatened plants. With</textblock>
    <textblock>respect to the four plant taxa that are the subject of this final rule,</textblock>
    <textblock>all trade prohibitions of section 9(a)(2) of the Act, implemented by 50</textblock>
    <textblock>CFR 17.61 and 17.71, apply. These prohibitions, in part, make it</textblock>
    <textblock>illegal for any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States</textblock>
    <textblock>to import or export, transport in interstate or foreign commerce in the</textblock>
    <textblock>course of a commercial activity, sell or offer for sale in interstate or</textblock>
    <textblock>foreign commerce, or to remove and reduce to possession any such species</textblock>
    <textblock>from areas under Federal jurisdiction. Seeds from cultivated specimens</textblock>
    <textblock>of threatened plant species, in this case</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens,</textblock>
    <textblock>are exempt from these prohibitions provided that a statement of</textblock>
    <textblock>``cultivated origin'' appears on their containers. In addition, for</textblock>
    <textblock>listed plants, the Act prohibits malicious damage or destruction of any</textblock>
    <textblock>such species on any area under Federal jurisdiction, and the removal,</textblock>
    <textblock>cutting, digging up, or damaging or destroying any such species on any</textblock>
    <textblock>other area in knowing violation of any State law or regulation, or in</textblock>
    <textblock>the course of any violation of a State criminal trespass law. Certain</textblock>
    <textblock>exceptions apply to agents of the Service and State conservation</textblock>
    <textblock>agencies. The Act and 50 CFR 17.62 and 17.63 also provide for the</textblock>
    <textblock>issuance of permits to carry out otherwise prohibited activities</textblock>
    <textblock>involving endangered or threatened plant species under certain</textblock>
    <textblock>circumstances. It is anticipated that few trade permits would ever be</textblock>
    <textblock>sought or issued because the four plant species are not common in</textblock>
    <textblock>cultivation or in the wild. Requests for copies of the regulations on</textblock>
    <textblock>plants and inquiries regarding them may be addressed to the Office of</textblock>
    <textblock>Management Authority, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, room 420C, 4401</textblock>
    <textblock>North Fairfax Drive, Arlington, Virginia 22203-3507 (703/358-2104).</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
