<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00058</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Issue 7:</textblock>
    <textblock>Several commenters charged that the proposed rule for</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegii</textblock>
    <textblock>was promulgated merely to fulfill requirements of a settlement resulting from the lawsuit filed against</textblock>
    <textblock>the Service by the California Native Plant Society. They further</textblock>
    <textblock>contended that this deprived Glenwood Development Company of its rights</textblock>
    <textblock>and is contrary to the intent and language of the Endangered Species</textblock>
    <textblock>Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Service Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The California Native Plant Society lawsuit</textblock>
    <textblock>settlement requires the Service to propose for listing those plant taxa</textblock>
    <textblock>that were identified as category 1 candidates for listing in the</textblock>
    <textblock>February 21, 1990, notice of review (56 FR 58804). Of the five taxa</textblock>
    <textblock>included in the proposed rule, only</textblock>
    <textblock>Erysimum teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>was a category</textblock>
    <textblock>1 candidate in the February 21, 1991, notice of review, and is the only</textblock>
    <textblock>one of the four taxa subject to the requirements of the lawsuit</textblock>
    <textblock>settlement. However, Federal action on all five taxa began prior to the</textblock>
    <textblock>settlement of the California Native Plant Society lawsuit (see section</textblock>
    <textblock>on ``Previous Federal Action''). As stated under the Service Response to</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 5 above, the Endangered Species Act directs the Service to list</textblock>
    <textblock>species on the basis of biological vulnerability.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 8:</textblock>
    <textblock>One commenter stated that the Service failed to publish</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed rule within 1 year of having received the petition, which</textblock>
    <textblock>therefore failed to meet statutory time requirements, and requested that</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed rule be withdrawn.</textblock>
    <textblock>Service Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service endeavors to meet statutory</textblock>
    <textblock>timeframes; however, nothing in the statute suggests that the Service is</textblock>
    <textblock>required to withdraw proposals because deadlines are missed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 9:</textblock>
    <textblock>One commenter stated that the Service failed to prepare</textblock>
    <textblock>environmental assessments as required by the National Environmental</textblock>
    <textblock>Policy Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Service Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service is exempt from preparing</textblock>
    <textblock>environmental assessments regarding the listing of species pursuant to</textblock>
    <textblock>the National Environmental Policy Act for reasons outlined in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on October 25, 1983 (48 FR 49244). This is stated in</textblock>
    <textblock>the proposed rule and this final rule under the section titled ``National</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Policy Act.''</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 10:</textblock>
    <textblock>One commenter stated that</textblock>
    <textblock>Erysimum teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>is a</textblock>
    <textblock>weed and that he had ``seen it in many places in the county'' and on ``all</textblock>
    <textblock>kinds of roadbanks,'' presumably meaning that the species is more</textblock>
    <textblock>widespread than is indicated in the proposed rule. He also felt that</textblock>
    <textblock>the public should be encouraged to grow it as a garden plant, presumably</textblock>
    <textblock>to assist in perpetuating the species.</textblock>
    <textblock>Service Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>No information was submitted to the Service to</textblock>
    <textblock>substantiate the locations of additional populations of</textblock>
    <textblock>Erysimum</textblock>
    <textblock>teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>. Since the time the proposal was published, no</textblock>
    <textblock>documentation has been made of additional populations of the plant found</textblock>
    <textblock>by any botanists that contribute to CNDDB (CNDDB 1993). The Service,</textblock>
    <textblock>therefore, maintains that this decision is based on the best and most</textblock>
    <textblock>current information available and that it is sufficient to warrant</textblock>
    <textblock>making a determination on its status. With regard to the suggestion to</textblock>
    <textblock>cultivate</textblock>
    <textblock>E. teretifolium</textblock>
    <textblock>as a garden plant, the Service recognizes the</textblock>
    <textblock>value of maintaining cultivated collections of rare species. Such</textblock>
    <textblock>collections, however, do not replace protection for native ecosystems,</textblock>
    <textblock>which is the intent of the Endangered Species Act.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 11:</textblock>
    <textblock>Two agencies (CDFG and California Department of Parks</textblock>
    <textblock>and Recreation) recommended that the Service list</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>as threatened rather than endangered.</textblock>
    <textblock>Service Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Since publication of the proposal, the Service</textblock>
    <textblock>has reviewed additional biological information, including surveys for</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>pungens</textblock>
    <textblock>recently conducted on Fort Ord by an environmental consulting firm, Jones and Stokes Associates (Army Corps</textblock>
    <textblock>of Engineers 1992). Substantial new populations were located on Fort</textblock>
    <textblock>Ord, but the pending disposal of Fort Ord still places these populations</textblock>
    <textblock>at risk. The Service therefore determined that threatened status for</textblock>
    <textblock>this plant is appropriate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 12:</textblock>
    <textblock>Several commenters requested that the Service designate</textblock>
    <textblock>critical habitat for</textblock>
    <textblock>Chorizanthe robusta</textblock>
    <textblock>var.</textblock>
    <textblock>hartwegii.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
