<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00149</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-2-00103</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Since that first index was issued on October 26, 1990 (55 FR 45984; October 31, 1990), the FAA has issued supplementary notices containing the quarterly indexes of the Administrator's civil penalty decisions as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>In the notice published on January 19, 1993, the Administrator announced that for the convenience of the users of these indexes, the order number index published at the end of the year would reflect all of the civil penalty decisions for that year. 58 FR 5044; 1/19/93. The order number indexes for the first, second, and third quarters would be non-cumulative.</textblock>
    <textblock>As noted at the beginning of the digests, the digests do not constitute legal authority, and should not be cited or relied upon as such. The digests are not intended to serve as a substitute for proper legal research. Parties, attorneys, and other interested persons should always consult the full text of the Administrator's decisions before citing them in any context.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Administrator's final decisions and orders, indexes, and digests are available for public inspection and copying at all FAA legal offices. (The addresses of the FAA legal offices are listed at the end of this notice.)</textblock>
    <textblock>In addition, the Administrator's decisions and orders have been published by commercial publishers and are available on computer databases. (Information about these commercial publications and computer databases is provided at the end of this notice.)</textblock>
  </text>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Dates of quarter</textblock>
    <textblock>1Federal Register publication</textblock>
    <textblock>10/1/90-12/31/90</textblock>
    <textblock>56 FR 44886; 2/6/91</textblock>
    <textblock>1/1/91-3/31/91</textblock>
    <textblock>56 FR 20250; 5/2/91</textblock>
    <textblock>4/1/91-6/30/91</textblock>
    <textblock>56 FR 31984; 7/12/91</textblock>
    <textblock>7/1/91-9/30/91</textblock>
    <textblock>56 FR 51735; 10/15/91</textblock>
    <textblock>10/1/91-12/31/91</textblock>
    <textblock>57 FR 2299; 1/21/92</textblock>
    <textblock>1/1/92-3/31/92</textblock>
    <textblock>57 FR 12359; 4/9/92</textblock>
    <textblock>4/1/92-6/30/92</textblock>
    <textblock>57 FR 32825; 7/23/92</textblock>
    <textblock>7/1/92-9/30/92</textblock>
    <textblock>57 FR 48255; 10/22/92</textblock>
    <textblock>10/1/92-12/31/92</textblock>
    <textblock>58 FR 5044; 1/19/93</textblock>
    <textblock>1/1/93-3/31/93</textblock>
    <textblock>58 FR 21199; 4/19/93</textblock>
    <textblock>4/1/93-6/30/93</textblock>
    <textblock>58 FR 42120; 8/6/93</textblock>
    <textblock>7/1/93-9/30/93</textblock>
    <textblock>58 FR 58218; 10/29/93</textblock>
  </table>
</doc>
