<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00045</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940204-0-00020</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Issue 2:</textblock>
    <textblock>Without critical habitat, the Service lacks jurisdiction</textblock>
    <textblock>to prevent or modify certain actions affecting the tidewater goby.</textblock>
    <textblock>Service Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Although in some cases critical habitat may</textblock>
    <textblock>provide protection otherwise unavailable through the jeopardy standard,</textblock>
    <textblock>jurisdiction is available through the jeopardy standard and section 9,</textblock>
    <textblock>both of which may be aggressively applied to protect listed species.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 3:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service should at minimum propose the Santa Ynez</textblock>
    <textblock>estuary as critical habitat now.</textblock>
    <textblock>Service Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service intends to propose as critical</textblock>
    <textblock>habitat all tidewater goby habitat that may be essential to the species'</textblock>
    <textblock>conservation, as opposed to the piecemeal approach advocated in the</textblock>
    <textblock>recommendation to propose one estuary. In the interim, the Santa Ynez</textblock>
    <textblock>estuary is owned by the U.S. Air Force, which is subject to the section</textblock>
    <textblock>7(a)(1) affirmative conservation mandate and the prohibitions against</textblock>
    <textblock>jeopardy contained in section 7(a)(2).</textblock>
    <textblock>Summary of Factors Affecting the Species</textblock>
    <textblock>After a thorough review and consideration of all information</textblock>
    <textblock>available, the Service has determined that the tidewater goby should be</textblock>
    <textblock>classified as an endangered species. Procedures found at section 4 of</textblock>
    <textblock>the Endangered Species Act (16 U.S.C. 1531</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>) and regulations (50</textblock>
    <textblock>CFR part 424) promulgated to implement the listing provisions of the Act</textblock>
    <textblock>were followed. A species may be determined to be an endangered or</textblock>
    <textblock>threatened species due to one or more of the five factors described in</textblock>
    <textblock>section 4(a)(1). These factors and their application to the tidewater</textblock>
    <textblock>goby (</textblock>
    <textblock>Eucyclogobius newberryi</textblock>
    <textblock>) are as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>A. The present or threatened destruction, modification, or</textblock>
    <textblock>curtailment of its habitat or range.</textblock>
    <textblock>Coastal development projects that</textblock>
    <textblock>result in the loss of coastal saltmarsh habitat are currently the major</textblock>
    <textblock>factor adversely affecting the tidewater goby. Coastal marsh habitats</textblock>
    <textblock>have been drained and reclaimed for residential and industrial</textblock>
    <textblock>developments. Waterways have been dredged for navigation and harbors</textblock>
    <textblock>resulting in permanent and direct losses of wetland habitats, as well as</textblock>
    <textblock>indirect losses due to associated changes in salinity. Coastal road</textblock>
    <textblock>construction projects have severed the connection between marshes and</textblock>
    <textblock>the ocean, resulting in unnatural temperature and salinity profiles that</textblock>
    <textblock>the tidewater goby cannot tolerate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Furthermore, upstream water diversions adversely affect the</textblock>
    <textblock>tidewater goby by altering downstream flows, thereby diminishing the</textblock>
    <textblock>extent of marsh habitats that occurred historically at the mouths of</textblock>
    <textblock>most rivers and creeks in California. Alterations of flows upstream of</textblock>
    <textblock>coastal lagoons have already changed the distribution of downstream</textblock>
    <textblock>salinity regimes. Since the tidewater goby has relatively narrow</textblock>
    <textblock>salinity tolerances, changes in salinity distributions due to upstream</textblock>
    <textblock>water diversions may adversely affect both the size and distribution of</textblock>
    <textblock>goby populations (D. Holland, Univ. of Southwestern Louisiana, pers.</textblock>
    <textblock>comm., 1991).</textblock>
    <textblock>Historically, the tidewater goby occurred in at least 87 of</textblock>
    <textblock>California's coastal lagoons (Swift</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1989). Since 1900, it has</textblock>
    <textblock>disappeared from approximately 50 percent of formerly occupied lagoons.</textblock>
    <textblock>A rangewide status survey conducted in 1984 found that 22 historic</textblock>
    <textblock>populations of tidewater goby had been extirpated (Swift</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1989).</textblock>
    <textblock>Only 5 years later, a status survey documented the disappearance of an</textblock>
    <textblock>additional 21 populations. In the San Francisco Bay area, 9 of 10</textblock>
    <textblock>previously identified populations have disappeared (Swift</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1989,</textblock>
    <textblock>1990). Losses in the southern part of the State have been the greatest,</textblock>
    <textblock>including 74 percent of the coastal lagoons south of Morro Bay. Three</textblock>
    <textblock>populations currently remain south of Ventura County. Since 1989, three</textblock>
    <textblock>additional tidewater goby populations have been lost in San Luis Obispo</textblock>
    <textblock>and Santa Cruz Counties (Swift</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1989, 1990). Five small</textblock>
    <textblock>populations have been rediscovered since 1984, but the overall losses</textblock>
    <textblock>indicate a decline of 35 percent rangewide in 6 years (Holland 1991a,</textblock>
    <textblock>1991b, 1991c; Swift</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1991).</textblock>
    <textblock>Of the 43 remaining populations of tidewater gobies identified by</textblock>
    <textblock>Swift</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1990), most are small and threatened by a variety of human</textblock>
    <textblock>and natural factors. According to Swift</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>(1990), only eight</textblock>
    <textblock>extant localities contain populations that are considered large enough</textblock>
    <textblock>and free enough from habitat degradation to be safe for the immediate</textblock>
    <textblock>future. These areas are all located north of San Francisco Bay. The</textblock>
    <textblock>remaining lagoons are so small or modified that tidewater goby</textblock>
    <textblock>populations are restricted in distribution and vulnerable to elimination</textblock>
    <textblock>(Swift</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>1989, 1990). The number of extirpated localities of</textblock>
    <textblock>gobies has left remaining populations so widely separated throughout</textblock>
    <textblock>most of the species' range that recolonization is unlikely.</textblock>
    <textblock>Several specific proposed and ongoing coastal development</textblock>
    <textblock>activities threaten habitats supporting tidewater gobies, including road</textblock>
    <textblock>widening and bridge replacement projects along Highway 101, water</textblock>
    <textblock>diversion projects in San Luis Obispo County, expansion of several State</textblock>
    <textblock>Park Recreation areas in Santa Barbara and San Luis Obispo Counties, and</textblock>
    <textblock>hotel and golf course developments in San Luis Obispo and Marin</textblock>
    <textblock>Counties.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
