<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00192</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00093</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(i) in the case of proprietary information, officials of, and counsel for, the investigating authority, the person who submitted the proprietary information to the investigating authority and counsel of record for that person, and any persons who have been granted access to the information under a Disclosure Order or Protective Order, and</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) in the case of privileged information relied upon in an extraordinary challenge of a decision of a panel with respect to a final determination made in the United States, committee members and their assistants and persons with respect to whom the panel ordered disclosure of the privileged information under rule 55 of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Article 1904 Panel Rules</textblock>
    <textblock>, if those persons have filed with the responsible Secretariat a Protective Order with respect to the document.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Where a document containing personal information is filed with the Secretariat, each Secretary shall ensure that</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) the document is stored, maintained, handled, and distributed in accordance with the terms of any applicable Disclosure Order or of Protective Order; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) access to the document is limited to persons granted access to the information pursuant to subrule 46(1)(b).</textblock>
    <textblock>57. No document filed in an extraordinary challenge proceeding shall be removed from the offices of the Secretariat except in the ordinary course of the business of the Secretariat or pursuant to the direction of a committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>58. (1) Each Secretary shall permit access by any person to information in the file of an extraordinary challenge proceeding that is not proprietary information, privileged information or personal information.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Each Secretary shall, in accordance with the terms of any applicable Disclosure Order, Protective Order or order of a panel or committee, permit access to proprietary information, privileged information or personal information in the file of an extraordinary challenge proceeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Each Secretary shall, on request and on payment of the prescribed fee, provide copies of information in the file of an extraordinary challenge proceeding to any person who has been given access to that information.</textblock>
    <textblock>59. (1) Where a Request for an Extraordinary Challenge Committee pursuant to Article 1904.13(a)(ii) or (iii) of the Agreement is filed with the responsible Secretariat, the responsible Secretary shall, upon receipt thereof,</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) forward a copy of the Request and Index to the other Secretary; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) serve a copy of the Request and Index on the other Party and on the participants in the panel review, together with a statement setting out the date on which the Request was filed and stating that all briefs shall be filed within 21 days of the date of filing of the Request.</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Where a Request for an Extraordinary Challenge Committee pursuant to Article 1904.13(a)(i) of the Agreement is filed, the responsible Secretary shall, upon receipt thereof,</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) forward a copy of the Request, Index and annex to the other Secretary; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) serve a copy of the Request, Index and annex on the other Party, on the panelist against whom the allegation contained in the Request is made and on the participants in the panel review.</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The responsible Secretary shall serve orders and decisions of a committee and Notices of Completion of Extraordinary Challenge on the participants.</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Where the decision of a committee referred to in subrule (3) relates to a panel review of a final determination made in Canada, the decision shall be served by registered mail.</textblock>
    <textblock>60. The responsible Secretary shall cause notice of a final decision of a committee issued pursuant to rule 64, and any order that the committee directs the Secretary to publish, to be published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Canada Gazette</textblock>
    <textblock>and the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>61. Where the time period fixed, pursuant to rule 42, for filing an</textblock>
    <textblock>ex parte</textblock>
    <textblock>motion referred to in subrule 42(1)(c) has expired, the responsible Secretary shall serve on all participants.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) where no motion is filed pursuant to that subrule, the documents referred to in rules 40 and 42;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
