<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00102</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00073</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 19(b)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (``Act''),</textblock>
    <textblock>and Rule 19b-4 thereunder,</textblock>
    <textblock>notice is hereby given that on January 22, 1994, the Chicago Stock Exchange, Inc. (``CHX'' or ``Exchange'') filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission (``Commission'' or ``SEC'') the proposed rule change as described in Items I and II below, which Items have been prepared by the self-regulatory organization. The CHX has requested accelerated approval of the proposal. The Commission is publishing this notice to solicit comments on the proposed rule change from interested persons.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Self-Regulatory Organization's Statement of the Terms of Substance of the Proposed Rule Change</textblock>
    <textblock>The Exchange proposes to amend Interpretation and Policy .01 to Rule 3 of Article XXXVI that describes the capital requirement for the Designated Primary Market Maker (``DPM'') of the Chicago Stock Basket (``CXM'').</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Release No. 34-33571; File No. SR-CHX-94-01]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Self-Regulatory Organizations; Notice of Filing and Order Granting Accelerated Approval to Proposed Rule Change by Chicago Stock Exchange, Inc. Relating to the Capital Requirement for the Designated Primary Market Maker in the Chicago Stock Basket</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(1) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 240.19b-4 (1991).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The Commission notes that the CXM is a standardized basket product consisting of twenty-five shares of each of the stocks included in the Chicago Mercantile Exchange's futures contract that is based on the American Stock Exchange's Major Market Index (``MMI''). The MMI is a broad-based price-weighted index of twenty stocks listed on the New York Stock Exchange. See Securities Exchange Act Release No. 33053 (October 15, 1993), 58 FR 54610 (October 22, 1993) (File No. SR-CHX-93-18) (``CXM Approval Order''). the DPM acts as the specialist in the basket and is required to quote continuously a two-sided market in four CXM contracts. The DPM must be an Exchange member registered as a specialist in securities underlying the basket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Id.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
