<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00057</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00021</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Approval and Promulgation of Implementation Plans California State Implementation Plan Revision San Joaquin Valley Unified Air Pollution Control District</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>40 CFR Part 52</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[CA 22-2-6004; FRL-4817-4]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA is finalizing the approval of a revision to the California State Implementation Plan (SIP) proposed in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on May 18, 1993. The revision concerns a rule from the following District: San Joaquin Valley Unified Air Pollution Control District (SJVUAPCD). This approval action will incorporate this rule into the federally approved SIP. The intended effect of approving this rule is to regulate the emission of volatile organic compounds (VOCs) in accordance with the requirements of the Clean Air Act, as amended in 1990 (CAA or the Act). The revised rule controls VOC emissions from non-assembly line motor vehicle and mobile equipment refinishing operations. Thus, EPA is finalizing the approval of this revision into the California SIP under provisions of the CAA regarding EPA action on SIP submittals, SIPs for national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards and plan requirements for nonattainment areas.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>This action is effective on March 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the rule revision and EPA's evaluation report for the rule are available for public inspection at EPA's Region IX office during normal business hours. Copies of the submitted rule revision are available for inspection at the following locations:</textblock>
    <textblock>Rulemaking Section I (A-5-4), Air and Toxics Division, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region IX, 75 Hawthorne Street, San Francisco, CA 94105.</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency, Jerry Kurtzweg ANR 443, 401 ``M'' Street, SW., Washington, DC 20460.</textblock>
    <textblock>California Air Resources Board, Stationary Source Division, Rule Evaluation Section, 2020 ``L'' Street, Sacramento, CA 95814.</textblock>
    <textblock>San Joaquin Valley Unified Air Pollution Control District, 1745 West Shaw, Suite 104, Fresno, CA 93711.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Christine Vineyard, Rulemaking Section II (A-5-3), Air and Toxics Division, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region IX, 75 Hawthorne Street, San Francisco, CA 94105, Telephone: (415) 744-1195.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On May 18, 1993 in 58 FR 28944, EPA proposed to approve the following rule into the California SIP: SJVUAPCD's Rule 460.2, Motor Vehicle and Mobile Equipment Refinishing Operations. Rule 460.2 was adopted by SJVUAPCD on September 19, 1991. The rule was submitted by the California Air Resources Board (CARB) to EPA on January 28, 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule was submitted in response to EPA's 1988 SIP-Call and the CAA section 182(a)(2)(A) requirement that nonattainment areas fix their deficient reasonably available control technology (RACT) rules for ozone in accordance with EPA guidance that interpreted the requirements of the pre-amendment Act. A detailed discussion of the background for the above rule and nonattainment area is provided in the notice of proposed rulemaking (NPR) cited above.</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA has evaluated the above rule for consistency with the requirements of the CAA and EPA regulations and EPA interpretation of these requirements as expressed in the various EPA policy guidance documents referenced in the NPR cited above. EPA has found that the rule meets the applicable EPA requirements. A detailed discussion of the rule provision and evaluation has been provided in 58 FR 28944 and in the technical support document (TSD) available at EPA's Region IX office</textblock>
    <textblock>(Rule 460.2-TSD dated December 23, 1992).</textblock>
    <textblock>Response to Public Comments</textblock>
    <textblock>On March 22, 1993, EPA published a direct-final rulemaking notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>approving SJVUAPCD Rule 460.2, and one comment was received from the Flexible Packaging Association (FPA). Because of that comment, EPA published a withdrawal of the direct-final notice on May 18, 1993 and on the same day proposed approval of Rule 460.2 providing a 30-day public comment period (58 FR 28944)</textblock>
    <textblock>The comment from the FPA has been evaluated by EPA and a summary of the comment and EPA's response is set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comment</textblock>
    <textblock>: The FPA commented that they believe capture efficiency (CE) test protocols which require the use of a temporary total enclosure (TTE) are excessively expensive and not technically justified, compared to ``nonenclosed mass balance tests''. FPA is currently running side by side comparison testing in cooperation with EPA. FPA believes that a requirement to use the TTE method prior to an evaluation of this testing is premature.</textblock>
    <textblock>Response</textblock>
    <textblock>: EPA's interim policy on the implementation of CE protocols is to refrain from listing the lack of a CE test protocol as a rule deficiency while EPA develops and reviews possible alternatives to CE test protocols which use a TTE. However, EPA has continued to encourage states and local agencies to reference CE test protocols in their regulations where appropriate and to use EPA's recommended method for measuring CE where noncompliance is suspected. State and local agencies are free to include CE test protocol requirements in their regulations.</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA Action</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA is finalizing action to approve the above rule for inclusion into the California SIP. EPA is approving the submittal under section 110(k)(3) as meeting the requirements of section 110(a) and part D of the CAA. This approval action will incorporate this rule into the federally approved SIP. The intended effect of approving this rule is to regulate emissions of VOCs in accordance with the requirements of the CAA.</textblock>
    <textblock>Nothing in this action should be construed as permitting or allowing or establishing a precedent for any future request for revision to any state implementation plan. Each request for revision to the state implementation plan shall be considered separately in light of specific technical, economic, and environmental factors and in relation to relevant statutory and regulatory requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulatory Process</textblock>
    <textblock>This action has been classified as a Table 2 action by the Regional Administrator under the procedures published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on January 19, 1989 (54 FR 2214-2225). EPA has submitted a request for a permanent waiver for Table 2 and Table 3 SIP revisions. OMB has agreed to continue the temporary waiver until such time as it rules on EPA's request.</textblock>
    <textblock>Under section 307(b)(1) of the Act, petitions for judicial review of this action must be filed in the United States Court of Appeals for the appropriate circuit by [Insert date 60 days from the date of publication]. Filing a petition for reconsideration by the Administrator of this final rule does not affect the finality of this rule for the purposes of judicial review nor does it extend the time within which a petition for judicial review may be filed and shall not postpone the effectiveness of such rule or action. This action may not be challenged later in proceedings to enforce its requirements. (See section 307(b)(2).)</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 40 CFR Part 52</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental protection, Air pollution control, Hydrocarbons, Incorporation by reference, Intergovernmental relations, Ozone, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Note</textblock>
    <textblock>: Incorporation by reference of the State Implementation Plan for the State of California was approved by the Director of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on July 1, 1982.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 9, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Felicia Marcus,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Regional Administrator.</textblock>
    <textblock>Part 52, chapter I, title 40 of the Code of Federal Regulations is amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 52_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 52 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 7401-7671q.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart F_California</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 52.220 is amended by adding paragraph (c) (187)(i)(A)(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§52.220</textblock>
    <textblock>Identification of plan.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(187) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(A) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(</textblock>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
    <textblock>) Rule 460.2 adopted on September 19, 1991.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2660 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
