<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00136</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00032</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Tuesday</textblock>
    <textblock>February 8, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part VI</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Justice</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Prisons</textblock>
    <textblock>28 CFR Parts 511 and 551</textblock>
    <textblock>Control, Custody, Care, Treatment and Instruction of Inmates; Final Rule and Proposed Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 26␣/␣Tuesday,</textblock>
    <textblock>February 8, 1994␣/␣Rules and Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>28 CFR Part 511</textblock>
    <textblock>Control, Custody, Care, Treatment and Instruction of Inmates;</textblock>
    <textblock>Searching/Detaining of Non-Inmates</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Prisons</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 1120-AA01</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Prisons, Justice.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In this document, the Bureau of Prisons is amending its rule on searching/detaining of non-inmates to incorporate statutory changes concerning arrest authority for employees of the Bureau of Prisons, to clarify terminology concerning contraband and prohibited objects, and to make minor editorial changes.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of General Counsel, Bureau of Prisons, HOLC Room 754, 320 First Street, NW., Washington, DC 20534.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Roy Nanovic, Office of General Counsel, Bureau of Prisons, phone (202) 514-6655.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Bureau of Prisons is amending its regulations on searching/detaining of non-inmates. A final rule on this subject was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>November 1, 1984 (49 FR 44057) and amended July 18, 1986 (51 FR 26126) and February 1, 1991 (56 FR 4159). A summary of the changes promulgated in this document follows.</textblock>
    <textblock>Arrest authority for employees of the Bureau of Prisons, which is contained in section 3050 of title 18 of the United States Code, was broadened by Public Law 99-646. This document revises paragraph (b) of 28 CFR 511.10 to reflect that broadened authority. Paragraph (a) of §511.10 is revised to clarify the equivalence of contraband and prohibited objects. Section 511.11 is amended by clarifying the provisions in paragraph (a) concerning reasonable suspicion which is based upon confidential information, by removing extraneous language from paragraph (b) and correcting punctuation in paragraph (b) for the sake of editorial consistency, and by adding a definition of prohibited objects in new paragraph (c). In §511.12, paragraph (d) is amended by adding a phrase inadvertently omitted in a previous amendment to the section.</textblock>
    <textblock>Because these changes either merely conform the regulations to current provisions of the United States Code, clarify existing provisions, or are editorial in nature, the Bureau finds good cause for exempting the provisions of the Administrative Procedure Act (5 U.S.C. 553) requiring notice of proposed rulemaking, the opportunity for public comment, and delay in effective date. Members of the public may submit comments concerning this rule by writing to the previously cited address. These comments will be considered but will receive no response in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
