<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00097</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00072</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In its filing with the Commission, the self-regulatory organization included statements concerning the purpose of and basis for the proposed rule change and discussed any comments it received on the proposed rule change. The text of these statements may be examined at the places specified in Item III below. The self-regulatory organization has prepared summaries, set forth in Sections A, B, and C below, of the most significant aspects of such statements.</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Self-Regulatory Organization's Statement of the Purpose of, and Statutory Basis for, the Proposed Rule Change</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Purpose</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)</textblock>
    <textblock>OHT facility.</textblock>
    <textblock>By order dated May 24, 1991,</textblock>
    <textblock>the Commission approved for a two-year temporary period the OHT facility by which the Exchange offers its two off-hours trading sessions. ``Crossing Session I'' permits the execution of single-stock, single-sided closing-price orders and crosses of single-stock, closing-price buy and sell orders. ``Crossing Session II'' allows the execution of crosses of multiple-stock (portfolios of 15 or more securities) aggregate price buy and sell orders.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Exchange began offering the two sessions on June 13, 1991. On May 25, 1993, the Commission approved an extension of the Pilot until January 31, 1994 (``Extension Order'').</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule change seeks to extend approval of the pilot until April 30, 1994. The Exchange has submitted to the Commission contemporaneously with this proposed rule change a second proposed rule pursuant to which the Exchange has requested permanent approval of both Crossing Session I and Crossing Session II (``Permanent Approval Filing'').</textblock>
    <textblock>The Exchange therefore requests this extension until April 30, 1994, to provide for the continuity of the crossing sessions, pending Commission action on the Permanent Approval Filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>Matched MOC Orders.</textblock>
    <textblock>In File No SR-NYSE-91-35, the Exchange requested that procedures for using matched MOC orders and the exemption from SEC Rule 10a-1 (relating to short sales of securities)</textblock>
    <textblock>for such orders (which had originally been filed as part of the pilot extending expiration Friday pricing procedures for MOC orders for every trading day) run concurrently with the temporary period for the Exchange's OHT facility. In its order approving this filling, the Commission stated that ``it is appropriate to allow the Exchange additional time to compare and contrast the matched MOC procedures with Crossing Session II.''</textblock>
    <textblock>On May 25, 1993, the Crossing Session II approved an Exchange request to extend the pilot program for matched MOC procedures until January 31, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Exchange has reviewed program trading activity by its member firms through December 17, 1993, but has not found any instances of firms entering matched MOC orders up to that point. As with Crossing Session I and II, the Exchange has included in the Permanent Approval Filing a request for permanent approval of the matched MOC order procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Exchange requests an extension until April 30, 1994, so as to provide for the continuity of those procedures, pending Commission action on the Permanent Approval Filing.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Statutory Basis</textblock>
    <textblock>The basis under the Act for the Exchange's OHT facility and the matched MOC order procedures, and for this extension of approval of the facility and those procedures, is the requirement under section 6(b)(5) that an exchange have rules that are designed to prevent fraudulent and manipulative acts and practices, to promote just and equitable principles of trade, to remove impediments to and perfect the mechanism of a free and open market and a national market system, and, in general, to protect investors and the public interest.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Self-Regulatory Organization's Statement on Burden on Competition</textblock>
  </text>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See OHT Approval Order,</textblock>
    <textblock>supra</textblock>
    <textblock>note 3.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>8</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See Securities Exchange Act Release No. 32362,</textblock>
    <textblock>supra</textblock>
    <textblock>note 4.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>8See File No. SR-NYSE-93-50, filed with the Commission on December 23, 1993.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>11</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Rule 10a-1 under the Act, 17 CFR 240.10a-1 (1991), and Exchange Rule 440B, a short sale on the Exchange may not be effected at a price either (1) below the last reported price or (2) at the last reported price unless that price is higher than the last reported price.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>9</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See Securities Exchange Act Release No. 30004,</textblock>
    <textblock>supra</textblock>
    <textblock>note 5.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See</textblock>
    <textblock>supra</textblock>
    <textblock>note 5.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>11</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>12</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See File No. SR-NYSE-93-50,</textblock>
    <textblock>supra</textblock>
    <textblock>note 8.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>12</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
