<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00055</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>[Notice (94-011)]</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Aerospace Safety Advisory Panel; Meeting.</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of meeting.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act, Public Law 92-463, as amended, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration announces a forthcoming meeting of the Aerospace Safety Advisory Panel.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>March 23, 1994, 1:30 p.m. to 3 p.m.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Aeronautics and Space Administration, 300 E Street, SW., room 9H40, Washington, DC 20546.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Frank L. Manning, Code Q-1, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Washington, DC 20546 (202/358-0914).</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Aerospace Safety Advisory Panel will present its annual report to the NASA Administrator. This is pursuant to carrying out its statutory duties for which the Panel reviews, identifies, evaluates, and advises on those program activities, systems, procedures, and management activities that can contribute to program risk. Priority is given to those programs that involve the safety of manned flight. The major subjects covered will be the Space Shuttle, Space Station, and Aeronautical Operations. The Aerospace Safety Advisory Panel is chaired by Norman R. Parmet and is composed of 8 members and 5 consultants. The meeting will be open to the public up to the capacity of the room (approximately 50 persons including members of the Panel).</textblock>
    <textblock>Type of Meeting:</textblock>
    <textblock>Open.</textblock>
    <textblock>Agenda:</textblock>
    <textblock>Wednesday, March 23</textblock>
    <textblock>1:30 p.m._Presentation of the findings and recommendations of the Aerospace Safety Advisory Panel</textblock>
    <textblock>3 p.m._Adjourn.</textblock>
    <textblock>All attendees will be requested to sign an attendance register.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Timothy M. Sullivan,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Advisory Committee Management Officer, National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2762 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7510-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
