<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00101</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00072</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The stock exchanges continually are developing new trading procedures and products in an attempt to facilitate the trading of portfolios of securities. The matched MOC order pilot procedures and the NYSE's OHT facility are but two examples of such developments. Thus, due to the NYSE's ongoing attempt to understand how trades of member firms and their customers could be most efficiently facilitated, the Commission believes that it is appropriate to allow the Exchange additional time to compare and contrast the matched MOC procedures with Crossing Session II.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission finds it reasonable to extend the pilot program for matched MOC orders and the exemption from SEC Rule 10a-1 in order to give the Commission and Exchange the necessary time to evaluate the matched MOC order procedures. In addition, the Commission continues to emphasize that, during the course of the pilot program, the Exchange is under a continued obligation to inform the Commission of its members' use, if any, of the matched MOC procedures and to assess the impact of matched MOC orders on overall market quality and on any possible displacement of orders on the specialist's book or in the trading crowd.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission finds good cause for approving the proposed rule change prior to the thirtieth day after the date of publication of notice of filing thereof in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission believes that accelerated approval of the proposal is appropriate in order to allow the OHT and MOC procedures to remain in place on an uninterrupted basis, which in turn should benefit investors and promote competition among markets.</textblock>
    <textblock>It Is Therefore Ordered, pursuant to Section 19(b)(2) of the Act</textblock>
    <textblock>that the proposed rule change (SR-NYSE-93-51) is hereby approved on a pilot basis through April 30, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Commission, by the Division of Market Regulation, pursuant to delegated authority.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>20</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>25 U.S.C. 78s(b)(2) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>20</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>21</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 200.30-3(a)(12) (1991).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>21</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2772 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
