<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00194</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00093</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Form (1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Article 1904_Extraordinary Challenge Proceeding</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the United States-Canada Free Trade Agreement</textblock>
    <textblock>In the matter of:</textblock>
    <textblock>(Title of Panel Review)</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretariat File No.</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>Request For An Extraordinary Challenge Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Article 1904 of the Canada-United States Free Trade Agreement, (</textblock>
    <textblock>the Party</textblock>
    <textblock>) hereby requests an Extraordinary Challenge Committee review of the panel decision referenced below. The following information is provided pursuant to rules 39 and 40 of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Extraordinary Challenge Committee Rules</textblock>
    <textblock>:</textblock>
    <textblock>1.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The name of the Party filing this Request)</textblock>
    <textblock>2.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The name of counsel for the Party)</textblock>
    <textblock>3.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The service address, as defined by Rule 4 of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Extraordinary Challenge Committee Rules,</textblock>
    <textblock>including facsimile number, if any)</textblock>
    <textblock>4.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The telephone number of counsel for the Party)</textblock>
    <textblock>5.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The title of the panel review for which an Extraordinary Challenge Committee is requested)</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Concise statement of the allegations relied on, together with a concise statement of how the actions alleged have materially affected the panel's decision and the way in which the integrity of the panel review process is threatened.</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Items of the record of the panel review relevant to the allegations contained in the Request, and an Index of the items are attached (see rule 40(1)).</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Where a Request contains an allegation referred to in Article 1904.13(a)(i) of the Agreement</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) confidential annex is attached containing the identity of the panelist against whom such an allegation is made (</textblock>
    <textblock>see</textblock>
    <textblock>subrule 39(2)),</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) items of the record of the panel review relevant to the allegations contained in the Request, and an Index of the items are attached (</textblock>
    <textblock>see</textblock>
    <textblock>subrule 40(1)),</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) any other material relevant to the allegations contained in the Request is attached (</textblock>
    <textblock>see</textblock>
    <textblock>subrule 40(2)(a)), and</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) if the Request is filed more than 30 days after the panel issued a Notice of Final Panel Action pursuant to rule 79A of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Article 1905 Panel Rules,</textblock>
    <textblock>an affidavit certifying that the Party gained knowledge of the action of the panelist giving rise to the allegation no more than 30 days preceding the filing of the Request (</textblock>
    <textblock>see</textblock>
    <textblock>subrule 40(2)(b)).</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Where the Panel Decision Was Made in Canada:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) I intend to use the specified language in pleadings and oral proceedings (Specify one)</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>English</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>French</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) I request simultaneous translation of oral proceedings (Specify one)</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>Yes</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>No</textblock>
    <textblock>Date</textblock>
    <textblock>Signature of Counsel</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
