<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00181</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00093</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Adopt the following amended Rules of Procedure, effective on the date of publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, which from that day shall govern all extraordinary challenge committee proceedings conducted pursuant to Article 1904 of the Agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Short Title</textblock>
    <textblock>1. These rules may be cited as the</textblock>
    <textblock>Extraordinary Challenge Committee Rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>Application</textblock>
    <textblock>2. These rules apply to any proceeding in which a Request for an Extraordinary Challenge Committee is filed in respect of a panel review made pursuant to Article 1904 of the Agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Statement of General Intent</textblock>
    <textblock>3. These rules are intended to give effect to the provisions of Chapter Nineteen of the Agreement with respect to extraordinary challenges conducted pursuant to Article 1904 of the Agreement and are designed to result in decisions typically within 30 days after the establishment of the committee. Where a procedural question arises that is not covered by these rules, a committee may adopt an appropriate procedure that is not inconsistent with the Agreement. In the event of any ambiguity or inconsistency between the provisions of these Rules and the Agreement, the Agreement shall prevail.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interpretation</textblock>
    <textblock>4. In these rules,</textblock>
    <textblock>``Agreement'' means the Free Trade Agreement between Canada and the United States of America, signed on January 2, 1988;</textblock>
    <textblock>``Code of Conduct'' means the code of conduct established by the Parties pursuant to Article 1910 of the Agreement;</textblock>
    <textblock>``committee'' means an extraordinary challenge committee established pursuant to Annex 1904.13 to Chapter Nineteen of the Agreement;</textblock>
    <textblock>``counsel'' means</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) with respect to an extraordinary challenge of a final determination made in the United States, a person entitled to appear as counsel before a federal court in the United States; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) with respect to an extraordinary challenge of a final determination made in Canada, a person entitled to appear as counsel before the Federal Court of Canada;</textblock>
    <textblock>``Counsel of record'' means a counsel referred to in subrule 13(1);</textblock>
    <textblock>``Deputy Minister'' means the Deputy Minister of National Revenue for Customs and Excise, or the successor thereto, and includes any person authorized to perform a power, duty or function of the Deputy Minister under the Special Import Measures Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>as amended;</textblock>
    <textblock>``Disclosure Undertaking'' means an undertaking, in the prescribed form, which form_</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) in respect of a review of a final determination by the Deputy Minister, is available from the Deputy Minister, and</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) in respect of a review of a final determination by the Tribunal, is available from the Tribunal;</textblock>
    <textblock>``final determination'' means, in the case of Canada, a definitive decision within the meaning of subsection 77.1(1) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Special Import Measures Act,</textblock>
    <textblock>as amended;</textblock>
    <textblock>``investigating authority'' means the competent investigating authority that issued the final determination that was the subject of the panel review to which an extraordinary challenge relates and includes, in respect of the issuance, amendment, modification or revocation of a Disclosure Order or Protective Order, any person authorized by the investigating authority;</textblock>
    <textblock>``legal holiday'' means_</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) with respect to the United States Section of the Secretariat, every Saturday and Sunday,</textblock>
    <textblock>New Year's Day (January 1),</textblock>
    <textblock>Martin Luther King's Birthday (third Monday in January),</textblock>
    <textblock>Presidents' Day (third Monday in February),</textblock>
    <textblock>Memorial Day (last Monday in May),</textblock>
    <textblock>Independence Day (July 4),</textblock>
    <textblock>Labor Day (first Monday in September),</textblock>
    <textblock>Columbus Day (second Monday in October),</textblock>
    <textblock>Veterans' Day (November 11),</textblock>
    <textblock>Thanksgiving Day (fourth Thursday in November),</textblock>
    <textblock>Christmas Day (December 25),</textblock>
    <textblock>any other day designated as a holiday by the President or the Congress of the United States and any day on which the offices of the Government of the United States located in the District of Columbia are officially closed in whole or in part, and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
