<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00166</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00092</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>80. If no Request for an Extraordinary Challenge Committee is filed, the responsible Secretary shall cause to be published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Canada Gazette</textblock>
    <textblock>and the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>a Notice of Completion of Panel Review, effective</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) on the day on which a panel is terminated pursuant to subrule 73(2); or</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) in any other case, on the 31st day following the date on which the responsible Secretary issues a Notice of Final Panel Action.</textblock>
    <textblock>81. Except as provided in rule 80, where a Request for an Extraordinary Challenge Committee has been filed, the responsible Secretary shall cause to be published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Canada Gazette</textblock>
    <textblock>and the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>a Notice of Completion of Panel Review, effective on the day after the day referred to in rule 65 or subrule 66(a) of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Extraordinary Challenge Committee Rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>82. Reserved</textblock>
    <textblock>83. Reserved</textblock>
    <textblock>84. Reserved</textblock>
    <textblock>85. Panelists are discharged from their duties on the day on which a Notice of Completion of Panel Review is effective, or on the day on which an Extraordinary Challenge Committee vacates a panel review pursuant to subrule 66(b) of the Extraordinary Challenge Committee Rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>Schedule</textblock>
    <textblock>Procedural Forms</textblock>
    <textblock>Forms (1) through (7) follow.</textblock>
    <textblock>Form (1)</textblock>
    <textblock>Article 1904 Binational Panel Review pursuant to the United States-Canada Free Trade Agreement</textblock>
    <textblock>In the matter of:</textblock>
    <textblock>(Title of Final Determination)</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Intent to Commence Judicial Review</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Article 1904 of the Canada-United States Free-Trade Agreement, notice is hereby served that</textblock>
    <textblock>(interested person filing notice)</textblock>
    <textblock>intends to commence judicial review in the</textblock>
    <textblock>(name of the court)</textblock>
    <textblock>of the final determination referenced below. The following information is provided pursuant to Rule 33 of the Article 1904 Panel Rules:</textblock>
    <textblock>1.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The name of the interested person filing this notice)</textblock>
    <textblock>2.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The name of counsel for the interested person, if any)</textblock>
    <textblock>3.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The service address, as defined by Rule 3 of the Article 1904 Panel Rules,</textblock>
    <textblock>including facsimile number, if any)</textblock>
    <textblock>4.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The telephone number of counsel for the interested person or the telephone number of the interested person, if not represented by counsel)</textblock>
    <textblock>5.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The title of the final determination for which notice of intent to commence judicial review is served)</textblock>
    <textblock>6.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The investigating authority that issued the final determination)</textblock>
    <textblock>7.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The file number of the investigating authority)</textblock>
    <textblock>8. (a)</textblock>
    <textblock>(The citation and date of publication of the final determination in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>or</textblock>
    <textblock>Canada Gazette</textblock>
    <textblock>); or</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>(If the final determination was not published, the date notice of the final determination was received by the other Party)</textblock>
    <textblock>Date</textblock>
    <textblock>Signature of Counsel (or interested person, if not</textblock>
    <textblock>represented by counsel)</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
