<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00041</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00036</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL ELECTION COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Notice 1994-1]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Filing Dates for the Oklahoma Special Election</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Election Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of filing dates for special elections.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Oklahoma has scheduled 1994 special elections on March 8, April 5 and May 10 to fill the vacant U.S. House seat in the Sixth Congressional District.</textblock>
    <textblock>Committees required to file reports in connection with the Special Primary Election should file a 12-day Pre-Primary Report on February 24. Committees required to file reports in connection with a Special Runoff Election on April 5 must file a 12-day Pre-Runoff Report on March 24. Committees required to file reports in connection with the Special General Election to be held on May 10 must file a 12-day Pre-General Report on April 28 and a Post-General Report on June 9.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Bobby Werfel, Information Division, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, telephone: (202) 219-3420; Toll Free (800) 424-9530.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION</textblock>
    <textblock>Principal Campaign Committees</textblock>
    <textblock>Special Primary Only</textblock>
    <textblock>All principal campaign committees of candidates</textblock>
    <textblock>only</textblock>
    <textblock>involved in the Special Primary Election shall file a 12-day Pre-Primary Report on February 24, and an April Quarterly Report on April 15. (See the chart below for the closing date for each report).</textblock>
    <textblock>Special Primary and General Without Runoff</textblock>
    <textblock>Each party will hold a Special Primary Election to nominate a candidate for the Special General Election. Principal campaign committees of candidates</textblock>
    <textblock>only</textblock>
    <textblock>participating in the Special Primary and Special General Elections shall file a 12-day Pre-Primary Report on February 24, an April Quarterly Report on April 15, a 12-day Pre-General Election Report on April 28, and a Post-General Election Report on June 9. (See the chart below for the closing date of each report).</textblock>
    <textblock>Special Primary and Runoff Elections</textblock>
    <textblock>In the event that one candidate does not achieve more than 50% of the vote in his/her party's Special Primary Election, the two top vote-getters in that party's primary will participate in a Special Runoff Election.</textblock>
    <textblock>Principal campaign committees</textblock>
    <textblock>only</textblock>
    <textblock>participating in the Special Primary and Runoff Elections shall file a 12-day Pre-Primary Election Report on February 24, a 12-day Pre-Runoff Election Report on March 24, and an April Quarterly Report on April 15. (See the chart below for the closing date of each report.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Special Primary, Runoff and General Elections</textblock>
    <textblock>Principal campaign committees participating in the Special Primary, Runoff and General Elections must file a 12-day Pre-Primary Election Report on February 24, a 12-day Pre-Runoff Election Report on March 24, an April Quarterly Report on April 15, a 12-day Pre-General Election Report on April 28, and a Post-General Election Report on June 9. (See the chart below for the closing date of each report.)</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
