<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-1-00032</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-1-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments.</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be submitted (in duplicate, if possible) to: Air Docket Section (6102), ATTN: Docket No. A-92-38, Room M1500, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, 401 M Street, SW., Washington, DC 20460.</textblock>
    <textblock>Background Information Document.</textblock>
    <textblock>The background information document (BID) may be obtained from the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency Library (MD-35), Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711, telephone number (919) 541-2777. Please refer to ``Gasoline Distribution (Stage I)_Background Information for Proposed Standards,''.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. A-92-38, containing supporting information used in developing the proposed standards, is available for public inspection and copying between</textblock>
    <textblock>8:30 a.m. and 3:30 p.m., Monday through Friday, at the Agency's Air Docket Section, Waterside Mall, Room 1500,</textblock>
    <textblock>1st Floor, 401 M Street, SW., Washington, DC 20460. A reasonable fee may be charged for copying.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>For general or technical information concerning the proposed standards, contact Mr. Stephen Shedd at (919) 541-5397, Chemicals and Petroleum Branch, Emission Standards Division (MD-13), U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina 27711. For general information or information regarding the economic effects of the proposed standards, contact Mr. Scott Mathias at (919) 541-5310, Standards Development Branch, Emission Standards Division (MD-13), also at the above address.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>The information presented in this preamble is organized as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Description of the Source Category and Subcategories</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Background</textblock>
    <textblock>III. Summary of the Proposed Standards</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Sources Covered</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Applicability Determination</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Emission Points Covered</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Standards for Sources</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Effective Date for Compliance</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Compliance Extensions</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Compliance Testing and Monitoring</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Recordkeeping and Reporting</textblock>
    <textblock>IV. Summary of Estimated Environmental, Energy, and Economic Impacts of the Proposed Standards</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Number and Type of Affected Sources or Facilities</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Air Emission Reductions</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Secondary Environmental Impacts</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Energy Impacts</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Cost Impacts</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Economic Impacts</textblock>
    <textblock>V. Decision Process for Setting the NESHAP</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Authority for the Development of the NESHAP</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Criteria for Development of the NESHAP</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Regulatory Development Process for the NESHAP</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Determining Maximum Achievable Control Technology (MACT) ``Floors''</textblock>
    <textblock>VI. Selection Rationale</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Selection of Source Category(s) Controlled</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Selection of Emission Points to be Covered</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Selection of the Basis for the Proposed Standards for New and Existing Sources</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Determination of Applicability</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Determination of Floor Control Levels</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Formulation of Regulatory Alternatives</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Consideration of Environmental Impacts</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Consideration of Cost</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Consideration of Economic Impacts</textblock>
    <textblock>7. Consideration of Secondary Impacts</textblock>
    <textblock>8. Consideration of Energy Impacts</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Selection of the Proposed Standards</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Selection of the Format of the Proposed Standards</textblock>
    <textblock>E. Equivalent Systems of Emission Reduction</textblock>
    <textblock>F. Selection of Monitoring Requirements and Emission Test Methods</textblock>
    <textblock>G. Selection of Recordkeeping and Reporting Requirements</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
