<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00038</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00033</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4835-7]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Proposed Settlement Under Section 122(g) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation and Liability Act; In E.H. Schilling</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice; request for public comment.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of</textblock>
    <textblock>De Minimis</textblock>
    <textblock>Settlement: In accordance with section 122(i)(1) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation and Liability Act of 1980, as amended (CERCLA), notice is hereby given of a proposed administrative settlement concerning the remedial action at the E.H. Schilling, site Ironton, Ohio. The Department of Justice issused its approval for the proposed agreement on December 30, 1993.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be provided on or before March 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments should be addressed to the Docket Clerk, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region V, 77 West Jackson Boulevard, Chicago, Illinois, 60604-3590, and should refer to: E.H. Schilling Superfund Site in Ironton, Ohio, USEPA Docket No. V-W 94-C-225.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Monica Smyth, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Office of Regional Counsel, 77 W. Jackson, Blvd., Chicago, Illinois 60604.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Below are listed the parties who have executed binding certifications of their consent to participate in the settlement:</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Settlors</textblock>
    <textblock>Associated Metals and Minerals Corporation; Matlack, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>Matack Inc. will pay $39,200 and Associated Metal and Minerals Corporation (``ASOMA'') will pay $197,463 to reimburse EPA for their fair share of EPA's response costs at the E.H. Schilling Site.</textblock>
    <textblock>EPA is entering into this agreement under the authority of sections 122(g) and 107 of CERCLA. Section 122(g) authorizes settlements with</textblock>
    <textblock>de minimis</textblock>
    <textblock>parties to allow them to resolve their liabilities at Superfund sites without incurring substantial transaction costs. Under this authority, the agreement proposes to settle with these parties for the reimbursement of USEPA's remaining response costs at the E.H. Schilling Site. These two parties are responsible for much less than one percent of the total volume of waste sent to the site between 1969 and 1980. The proposed settlement reflects, and was agreed to based on, conditions as known to the parties as of September 1, 1993. Settling Parties will receive a complete release from further civil or administrative liabilities at the Site.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Environmental Protection Agency will receive written comments relating to this agreement for thirty days from the date of publication of this notice.</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the proposed administrative settlement agreement or additional background information relating to the settlement is available for review and may be obtained in person or by mail from Monica Smyth, Office of Regional Counsel, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region V, 77 W. Jackson, Mail Code CS-3T, Chicago, Illinois 60604.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, as amended, 42 U.S.C. 9601-9675.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>David A. Ullrich,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2846 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
