<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00041</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00019</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Director finds Iowa's proposed revision at IAC 27-40.34(9) to be consistent with SMCRA and the Federal regulations and is approving it.</textblock>
    <textblock>16. IAC 27-40.35 (10) and (11), Climatological Information</textblock>
    <textblock>a.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rain gauge identification</textblock>
    <textblock>Iowa proposes to revise IAC 27-40.35(10) by adding a paragraph (c) to the incorporated Federal regulation at 30 CFR 779.18 that would provide as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Location of the rain gauges nearest to the permit area, preferably in the same watershed as the permit itself, shall be marked on a map, and these shall be described in the text as well, along with the period of available record at these gauges.</textblock>
    <textblock>While the corresponding Federal regulations at 30 CFR 779.18 do not require this information, in accordance with section 505(b) of SMCRA and 30 CFR 730.11(b), the State regulatory authority has the discretion to impose land use and environmental controls and regulations on surface coal mining and reclamation operations that are more stringent than those imposed under SMCRA and the Federal regulations. Moreover, the State regulatory authority has the discretion to impose land use and environmental controls and regulations on surface coal mining and reclamation operations for which no Federal counterpart provision exists. Section 505(b) of SMCRA and 30 CFR 730.11 dictate that such State provisions shall not be construed to be inconsistent with the Federal program. Therefore, the Director is approving Iowa's proposed revision at IAC</textblock>
    <textblock>27-40.35(10).</textblock>
    <textblock>b.</textblock>
    <textblock>Climatological impact description.</textblock>
    <textblock>Iowa proposes to revise IAC</textblock>
    <textblock>27-40.35(11) by adding a paragraph (d) to the incorporated Federal regulation at 30 CFR 779.18 that would provide as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>A brief descrition shall be provided about the impact of the climatological factors on operation and reclamation plans, specifically what part of the year would be more conducive than others to various mining and reclamation operations.</textblock>
    <textblock>While the corresponding Federal regulations at 30 CFR 779.18 do not require this information, in accordance with section 505(b) of SMCRA and 30 CFR 730.11(b), the State regulatory authority has the discretion to impose land use and environmental controls and regulations on surface coal mining and reclamation operations that are more stringent than those imposed under SMCRA and the Federal regulations. Moreover, the State regulatory authority has the discretion to impose land use and environmental controls and regulations on surface coal mining and reclamation operations for which no Federal counterpart provision exists. Section 505(b) of SMCRA and 30 CFR 730.11 dictate that such State provisions shall not be construed to be inconsistent with the Federal program. Therefore, the Director is approving Iowa's proposed revision at IAC</textblock>
    <textblock>27-40.35(11).</textblock>
    <textblock>17. IAC 27-40.35 (12), (13) and (14) Maps: General Information</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
