<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00023</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00018</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 2, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Take notice that on January 28, 1994, Natural Gas Pipeline Company of America (Natural) tendered for filing as part of its FERC Gas Tariff, Sixth Revised Volume No. 1, First Revised Sheet No. 25, to be effective March 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Natural states that the filing is submitted to commerce recovering effective March 1, 1994, approximately $28 million in known and measurable gas supply realignment (GSR) costs which have been incurred by Natural as a consequence of Order No. 363.</textblock>
    <textblock>Natural requested whatever waivers may be necessary to permit the tariff sheet as submitted herein to become effective March 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Natural states that copies of the filing are being mailed to Natural's jurisdictional customers and interested state regulatory agencies.</textblock>
    <textblock>Natural states that it has reached a tentative settlement with members of the Natural Customer Group (NCG) regarding recovery from them of GSR costs. Members of the NCG may preserve their rights by filing an abbreviated protest which may be supplemented if the settlement is not finalized and approved.</textblock>
    <textblock>Any person desiring to be heard or to protest said filing should file a motion to intervene or a protest with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 825 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426, in accordance with sections 385.214 and 385.211 of the Commission's Rules and Regulations. All such protests should be filed on or before February 9, 1994. Protests will be considered by the Commission in determining the appropriate action to be taken, but will not serve to make protestants parties to the proceeding. Any person wishing to become a party must file a motion to intervene. Copies of this filing are on file with the Commission and are available for public inspection in the public reference room.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. RP94-122-000]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Natural Gas Pipeline Company of America; Proposed Changes in FERC Gas Tariff</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2808 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6717-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
