<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00039</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00034</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Federal Communications Commission has submitted the following information collection requirement to OMB for review and clearance under the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. 3507).</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of this submission may be purchased from the Commission's copy contractor, International Transcription Service, Inc., 2100 M Street, NW., suite 140, Washington, DC 20037, (202) 857-3800. For further information on this submission contact July Boley, Federal Communications Commission, (202) 632-0276. Persons wishing to comment on this information collection should contact Timothy Fain, Office of Management and Budget, room 3235 NEOB, Washington, DC 20503, (202) 395-3561.</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>3060-0444.</textblock>
    <textblock>Title:</textblock>
    <textblock>220 and 800 MHz Construction Letter.</textblock>
    <textblock>Form Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>FCC Form 800A.</textblock>
    <textblock>Action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Revision of a currently approved collection.</textblock>
    <textblock>Respondents:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals or households and businesses or other for-profit (including small businesses).</textblock>
    <textblock>Frequency of Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>On occasion reporting requirement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Estimated Annual Burden:</textblock>
    <textblock>11,200 responses; 1 hour average burden per response; 11,200 hours total annual burden.</textblock>
    <textblock>Needs and Uses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Licenses are required to provide the information listed on FCC Form 800A to verify a station has been placed into operation. PR Docket No. 92-210, effective 8/24/93, extends the maximum terms for slow growth systems from three to five years. Additionally, PR Docket No. 93-35, effective 12/27/93, provides for extended implementation in the 900 MHz (929-930) paging band to three years. The form has been revised to include these changes. The data is used by Commission staff to determine whether the licensee is entitled to their authorization to operate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL COMMUNICATIONS COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Public Information Collection Requirement Submitted to Office of Management and Budget for Review</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William F. Caton,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2817 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
