<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-1-00063</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-1-00011</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>G. Regulatory Review</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with Clean Air Act sections 112(d)(6) and 112(f)(2), this regulation will be reviewed within 8 years from the date of promulgation. This review may include an assessment of such factors as evaluation of the residual health risk, any overlap with other programs, the existence of alternative methods, enforceability, improvements in emission control technology and health data, and the recordkeeping and reporting requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 40 CFR Part 63</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental protection, Air pollution control, Hazardous substances, Incorporation by reference, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Petroleum bulk stations and terminals.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Carol M. Browner,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Administrator.</textblock>
    <textblock>For reasons set out in the preamble, title 40, chapter I, part 63 of the Code of Federal Regulations is proposed to be amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 63_NATIONAL EMISSION STANDARDS FOR HAZARDOUS AIR POLLUTANTS FOR SOURCE CATEGORIES</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 63 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>42 U.S.C. 7401,</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. It is proposed that part 63 be amended by adding subpart R, consisting of §§63.420-63.429, to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart R_National Emission Standards for Gasoline Distribution Facilities (Bulk Gasoline Terminals and Pipeline Breakout Stations)</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec.</textblock>
    <textblock>63.420␣Applicability.</textblock>
    <textblock>63.421␣Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>63.422␣Standards: Loading racks.</textblock>
    <textblock>63.423␣Standards: Storage vessels.</textblock>
    <textblock>63.424␣Standards: Equipment leaks.</textblock>
    <textblock>63.425␣Test methods and procedures.</textblock>
    <textblock>63.426␣Alternative means of emission limitation.</textblock>
    <textblock>63.427␣Continuous monitoring.</textblock>
    <textblock>63.428␣Reporting and recordkeeping.</textblock>
    <textblock>63.429␣Delegation of authority.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart R_National Emission Standards for Gasoline Distribution Facilities (Bulk Gasoline Terminals and Pipeline Breakout Stations)</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
