<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00116</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00075</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>13. Applicants acknowledge that the grant of the exemptive order requested by the application will not imply SEC approval, authorization, or acquiescence in any particular level of payments that the Funds may make pursuant to their 12b-1 Plans or any Shareholder Services Plans in reliance on the exemptive order.</textblock>
    <textblock>14. Applicants will comply with the provisions of proposed rule 6c-10 under the Act (see Investment Company Act Release No. 16619 (Nov. 2, 1988)), as such rule is currently proposed and as it may be reproposed, adopted or amended.</textblock>
    <textblock>15. Applicants will comply with section 19(a) and rule 19a-1 under the Act, including the provisions requiring dividend payments that include a return of capital to be accompanied by a written statement clearly indicating that investors are receiving a return of capital and identifying what portion of the payment is a return of capital.</textblock>
    <textblock>16. If in the future any investment company adopts a shareholder services plan that is not a 12b-1 Plan, such shareholder services plan will be adopted and operated in accordance with the procedures set forth in rule 12b-1 (b) through (f) as if the expenditures made thereunder were subject to rule 12b-1, except that shareholders need not enjoy the voting rights specified in rule 12b-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the SEC, by the Division of Investment Management under delegated authority.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2829 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
