<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00074</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00061</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>NATIONAL SCIENCE FOUNDATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Privacy Act of 1974; Establishment of a System of Records</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Science Foundation (NSF).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of establishment of a Privacy Act system of records.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the Office of Polar Programs (OPP) of the NSF is establishing a system of records. This action covers records in the agency's Antarctic Conservation Act Files.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>This action will be effective without further notice on March 10, 1994, unless comments are received that would result in a contrary determination.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons may submit written comments to Herman Fleming, Division of Contracts, Policy and Oversight, National Science Foundation, 4201 Wilson Boulevard, Room 1265, Arlington, Virginia 22230.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Herman Fleming, Privacy Act Officer, at (703) 306-1243.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to the Privacy Act of 1974 (5 U.S.C. 552a), as amended, notice is given that the NSF proposes to establish a system of records identified as:</textblock>
    <textblock>NSF-56_Antarctic Conservation Act Files</textblock>
    <textblock>Title 5 U.S.C. 552a(e) (4) and (11) provide that the public be provided a 30-day comment period in which to comment on a new record system.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 26, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Herman G. Fleming,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Reports Clearance and Privacy Act Officer, National Science Foundation.</textblock>
    <textblock>NSF-56</textblock>
    <textblock>System name:</textblock>
    <textblock>Antarctic Conservation Act Files.</textblock>
    <textblock>System location:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Polar Programs, National Science Foundation, 4201 Wilson Boulevard, Arlington, VA 22230.</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of individuals covered by the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals who have applied for permits pursuant to the Antarctic Conservation Act, and/or individuals who have been contacted regarding Antarctic Conservation Act compliance. This includes but is not limited to individuals who have sought Antarctic Conservation Act permits.</textblock>
    <textblock>Categories of records in the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>All documents and correspondence related to the individual's contact with the Antarctic Conservation Act system, including the permitting process, and investigations pertaining to compliance.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority for maintenance of the system:</textblock>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 2401,</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>(Pub. L. 95-452, as amended, 5 U.S.C. app.)</textblock>
    <textblock>Routine uses of records maintained in the system, including categories of users and purposes of such uses:</textblock>
    <textblock>Information from this system may be disclosed to:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Federal agencies involved in enforcing or implementing the Antarctic Conservation Act;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) A court, administrative or other adjudicative body, involved in enforcement of the Antarctic Conservation Act;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Federal, state, or local agencies, or foreign governments, where disclosure is necessary in order to obtain records in connection with an investigation of the Office of Polar Programs;</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Other Federal agencies in response to the issuance of a security clearance, the award of a contract, or the issuance of a license, grant, or other benefit by the requesting agency to the extent that the record is relevant;</textblock>
    <textblock>(5) A Federal agency where the records are relevant to an agency decision with regard to disciplinary or other administrative action concerning their employee;</textblock>
    <textblock>(6) The Merit Systems Protection Board (including the Office of the Special Counsel), in order to carry out its agency's functions;</textblock>
    <textblock>(7) Persons, including witnesses, who may have information, documents or knowledge relevant to an Antarctic Conservation Act investigation or enforcement proceeding;</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
