<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00081</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00066</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to delegation by the Commission dated December 29, 1972, published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register,</textblock>
    <textblock>37 FR 28710 (1972), and §§2.105, 2.700, 2.702, 2.714, 2.714a, 2.717 and 2.721 of the Commission's Regulations, all as amended, a single member of the Atomic Safety and Licensing Board Panel is hereby designated to rule on petitions for leave to intervene and/or requests for hearing and, if necessary, to serve as the presiding officer to conduct the hearing in the event that an informal adjudicatory hearing is ordered in the following Materials Licensing proceeding.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the matter of, UMETO Minerals Corporation, P.O. Box 1029, Grand Junction, Colorado 81502. Source Materials License No. SUA-1358.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Presiding Officer is being designated pursuant to 10 CFR 2.1207 of the Commission's Regulations, ``Informal Hearing Procedures for Materials Licensing Adjudications,'' published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register,</textblock>
    <textblock>54 FR 8269 (1989). This action is in response to a request for a hearing submitted by Envirocare of Utah, Inc. (Envirocare). Envirocare desires a hearing concerning NRC staff approval on August 2, 1993 of an amendment to UMETO Minerals Corporation's Source Materials License covering its White Mesa Mill located near Blanding, Utah.</textblock>
    <textblock>The presiding officer in this proceeding is Administrative Judge James P. Gleason.</textblock>
    <textblock>Following consultation with the Panel Chairman, pursuant to the provisions of 10 CFR 2.722, the Presiding Officer has appointed Administrative Judge Thomas D. Murphy to assist the Presiding Officer in taking evidence and in preparing a suitable record for review.</textblock>
    <textblock>All correspondence, documents and other materials shall be filed with Judge Gleason and Judge Murphy in accordance with 10 CFR 2.701. Their addresses are:</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative Judge James P. Gleason, Presiding Officer, Atomic Safety and Licensing Board Panel, U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555.</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative Judge Thomas D. Murphy, Special Assistant, Atomic Safety and Licensing Board Panel, U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued at Bethesda, Maryland, this 2nd day of February 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 40-08681-MLA-2; ASLBP No. 94-688-01-MLA-2]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>UMETCO Minerals Corp.; Designation of Presiding Officer</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>B. Paul Cotter, Jr.</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief Administrative Judge, Atomic Safety and Licensing Board Panel.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2794 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7590-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
