<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00007</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Walgreen Co., a Corporation; Provisional Acceptance of a Settlement Agreement and Order</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>CONSUMER PRODUCT SAFETY COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[CPSC Docket No. 94-C0008]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Consumer Product Safety Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Provisional acceptance of a Settlement Agreement under the Federal Hazardous Substances Act and the Consumer Product Safety Act.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>It is the policy of the Commission to publish settlements which it provisionally accepts in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>in accordance with the terms of 16 CFR 1118.20(e)-(h). Published below is a provisionally-accepted Settlement Agreement with Walgreen Co., a corporation.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Any interested person may ask the Commission not to accept this agreement or otherwise comment on its contents by filing a written request with the Office of the Secretary by February 23, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Persons wishing to comment on this Settlement Agreement should send written comments to Comment 94-C0008, Office of the Secretary, Consumer Product Safety Commission, Washington, DC 20207.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>Melvin I. Kramer, Trial Attorney, Office of Compliance and Enforcement, Consumer Product Safety Commission, Washington, DC 20207; telephone (301) 504-0626.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>(Attached).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Sheldon D. Butts,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>Settlement Agreement and Order</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Walgreen Co. (hereinafter, ``Walgreen''), a corporation, enters into this Settlement Agreement (hereinafter, ``Agreement'') with the staff of the Consumer Product Safety Commission, and agrees to the entry of the Order described herein. The purpose of the Agreement and Order is to settle the staff's allegations that Walgreen knowingly caused the export of certain banned hazardous substances, namely toys, in violation of section 14(d) of the Federal Hazardous Substances Act (FHSA), 15 U.S.C. 1273(d), which is a prohibited act under section 4(i) of the FHSA, 15 U.S.C. 1263(i).</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Jurisdiction</textblock>
    <textblock>2. The Commission has jurisdiction over Walgreen and the subject matter of this Settlement Agreement pursuant to section 30(a) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (hereinafter, ``CPSA''), 15 U.S.C. 2079(a), and sections 2 (f)(1)(D) and (s), 4 (a) and (i) and 5(c) of the Federal Hazardous Substances Act (hereinafter, ``FHSA''), 15 U.S.C. 1261(f)(1)(D) and (s), 1263 (a) and (i) and 1264(c).</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
