<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00057</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00047</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given in accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463) that the Maine Acadian Culture Preservation Commission will meet on Friday, February 18, 1994. The meeting will convene at 7 p.m. in the gymnasium of the Eagle Lake Elementary School, Eagle Lake, Aroostook County, Maine.</textblock>
    <textblock>The eleven-member Maine Acadian Culture Preservation Commission was appointed by the Secretary of the Interior pursuant to the Maine Acadian Culture Preservation Act (Pub. L. 101-543). The purpose of the Commission is to advise the National Park Service with respect to the development and implementation of an interpretive program of Acadian culture in the state of Maine; and the selection of sites for interpretation and preservation by means of cooperative agreements.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Agenda for this meeting is as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Review and approval of the summary report of the meeting held November 17, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Approval of the Maine Acadian Culture Preservation Commission's annual report (FY 1993).</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Reports of the following Maine Acadian Culture Preservation Commission working groups: Cooperating Organizations and Public Involvement.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Report of the National Park Service planning team.</textblock>
    <textblock>5. Opportunity for public comment.</textblock>
    <textblock>6. Proposed agenda, place, and date of the next Commission meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting is open to the public. Further information concerning Commission meetings may be obtained from the Superintendent, Acadia National Park. Interested persons may make oral/written presentations to the Commission or file written statements. Such requests should be made to the Superintendent at least seven days prior to the meeting by writing to Superintendent, Acadia National Park, P.O. Box 177, Bar Harbor, Maine 04609, or call</textblock>
    <textblock>(207) 288-5472.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Park Service</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Maine Acadian Culture Preservation Commission; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John C. Reed,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2765 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-70-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
