<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-1-00017</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-1-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The following rules submitted as amendments to existing requirements are proposed for inclusion in part 55, except the sections of the rules relating to toxics, administrative requirements, and RECLAIM requirements:</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 109␣Recordkeeping for Volatile Organic Compound Emissions</textblock>
    <textblock>(Adopted 3/6/92)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 204␣Permit Conditions (Adopted 3/6/92)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 212␣Standards for Approving Permits (Adopted 9/6/91) except (c)(3) section on toxics and (e) administrative requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 219␣Equipment Not Requiring a Written Permit (Adopted 9/11/92)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 301␣Permit Fees (Adopted 6/11/93) except all references to RECLAIM</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 304␣Equipment, Materials, and Ambient Air Analyses (Adopted 6/11/93)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 304.1␣Analyses Fees (Adopted 6/6/92)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 305␣Fees for Acid Deposition (Adopted 10/4/91)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 403␣Fugitive Dust (Adopted 7/9/93)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 431.1␣Sulfur Content of Gaseous Fuels (Adopted 10/2/92)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 465␣Vacuum Producing Devices or Systems (Adopted 11/1/91)</textblock>
    <textblock>Reg IX␣New Source Performance Standards (Adopted 4/9/93)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 1106␣Marine Coatings Operations (Adopted 8/2/91)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 1107␣Coating of Material Parts and Products (Adopted 8/2/91)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 1113␣Architectural Coatings (Adopted 9/6/91)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 1122␣Solvent Cleaners (Adopted 4/5/91)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 1146.1␣Emission of Oxides of Nitrogen From Small Industrial, Institutional, and Commercial Boilers, Steam Generators, and Process Heaters (Adopted 7/10/92)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 1168␣Control of Volatile Organic Compound Emissions from Adhesive Application (Adopted 12/4/92)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 1302␣Definitions (Adopted 5/3/91)</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 1304␣Exemptions (Adopted 9/11/92)</textblock>
    <textblock>Administrative Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Executive Order 12291 (Regulatory Impact Analysis)</textblock>
    <textblock>The Office of Management and Budget has exempted this rule from the</textblock>
    <textblock>requirements of section 3 of Executive Order 12291. This exemption continues in effect under Executive Order 12866 which superseded Executive Order 12291 on September 30, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The Regulatory Flexibility Act of 1980 requires each federal agency to perform a Regulatory Flexibility Analysis for all rules that are likely to have a ``significant impact on a substantial number of small entities.'' Small entities include small businesses,</textblock>
    <textblock>organizations, and governmental jurisdictions.</textblock>
    <textblock>As was stated in the final regulation, the OCS rule does not apply to any small entities, and in the structure of the rule averts direct impacts and mitigates indirect impacts on small entities. This consistency update merely incorporates onshore requirements into the OCS rule to maintain consistency with onshore regulations as required by section 328 of the Act and does not alter the structure of the rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>The EPA certifies that this notice of proposed rulemaking will not have a significant impact on a substantial number of small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The Office of Management and Budget (OMB) has approved the information</textblock>
    <textblock>collection requirements contained in the final OCS rulemaking dated September 4, 1992 under the provisions of the Paperwork Reduction Act, 44 U.S.C. 3501 et seq. and has assigned OMB control number 2060-0249. This consistency update does not add any further requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 40 CFR Part 55</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental protection, Administrative practice and procedures, Air pollution control, Hydrocarbons, Incorporation by reference, Intergovernmental relations, Nitrogen dioxide, Nitrogen oxides, Outer Continental Shelf, Ozone, Particulate matter, Permits, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, Sulfur oxides.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 28, 1994.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>John Wise,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Administrator.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
