<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00012</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>17 CFR Part 19</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Reports By Persons Holding Bona Fide Hedge Positions Pursuant To ยง1.3(z) Of This Chapter And By Merchants And Dealers In Cotton</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Commodity Futures Trading Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Conforming amendment.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document contains a amendment to 17 CFR Part 19 to reflect changes required by enactment of the Futures Trading Practices Act of 1992.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 8, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Barbara Webster Black, Office of General Counsel, Commodity Futures Trading Commission, 2033 K Street, NW., Washington, DC 20581. Telephone: (202) 254-9880.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>In light of the recent passage of the Futures Trading Practices Act of 1992, 102 Cong., 2d Sess., Public Law 102-546 (Oct. 28, 1992), which amended the Commodity Exchange Act, the Commission has determined that 17 CFR Part 19, Reports By Persons Holding Bona Fide Hedge Positions Pursuant to ยง1.3(z) Of This Chapter And By Merchants And Dealers In Cotton, should be amended to reflect the changes in the Commodity Exchange Act resulting from the Futures Trading Practices Act of 1992.</textblock>
    <textblock>Need for Correction</textblock>
    <textblock>As published, the regulations contain a reference to a designation of a statutory provision which has been changed and which is in need of clarification.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 17 CFR Part 19</textblock>
    <textblock>Commodity futures, cotton, grains, reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, 17 CFR Part 19 is amended by making the following conforming amendment:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 19_REPORTS BY PERSONS HOLDING BONA FIDE HEDGE POSITIONS PURSAUNT TO ยง1.3 (Z) OF THIS CHAPTER AND BY MERCHANTS AND DEALERS IN COTTON</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for Part 19 is revised to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>7 U.S.C. 6g(a), 6i, and 12a(5), unless otherwise noted.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC on January 25, 1994, by the Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jean A. Webb,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary of the Commission.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2148 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6351-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
