<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00092</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00071</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Sections 19 (b)(1) and (d)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (``Act'')</textblock>
    <textblock>and Rules 19b-4 and 19d-1(c)(2) thereunder</textblock>
    <textblock>notice is hereby given that on May 27, 1993, the New York Stock Exchange, Inc. (``NYSE'' or ``Exchange'') filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission (``Commission'') the proposed rule change as described in Items I, II and III below, which Items have been prepared by the self-regulatory organization (``SRO''). On June 9, 1993, the NYSE submitted to the Commission Amendment No. 1 to the proposed rule change.</textblock>
    <textblock>On January 3, 1994, the Commission received from the NYSE Amendment No. 2 to the proposed rule change.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission is publishing this notice to solicit comments on the proposed rule change from interested persons.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Self-Regulatory Organization's Statement of the Terms of Substance of the Proposed Rule Change</textblock>
    <textblock>This proposal would revise the Rule 476A Violations List for imposition of fines for minor violations of rules and/or policies by adding to the list violations of Exchange Rule 410A and the provision in Rule 72(b) which prohibits proprietary participation in a cross transaction.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Exchange proposes to adopt the following amendment:</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Exchange Rule Violations and Fines Applicable Thereto Pursuant to Rule 476A</textblock>
    <textblock>•Rule 72(b) requirements for ``clean'' agency crosses which cannot be broken up at the cross price</textblock>
    <textblock>•Rule 410A requirements for automated submission of trading data</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Release No. 34-33564; File No. SR-NYSE-93-27]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Self-Regulatory Organizations; Filing of Proposed Rule Change by the New York Stock Exchange, Inc. Relating to the Addition of Rules 72(b) and 410A to the ``List of Exchange Rule Violations and Fines Applicable Thereto Pursuant to Rule 476A'' and Amending Minor Rule Violation Enforcement and Reporting Plan</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s (b)(1) and (d)(1) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 240.19b-4 and 19d-1(c)(2) (1991).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See letter from Donald Siemer, Director, Market Surveillance, NYSE, to Diana Luka-Hopson, Branch Chief, Commission, submitted on June 9, 1993 by which the NYSE made corrections to its current Rule 476A Violations List.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See letter from Robert J. McSweeney, Senior Vice President, Market Surveillance, to Sandra Sciole, Special Counsel, Commission, dated December 23, 1993. Amendment No. 2 withdrew Rule 401 from the list of proposed additions to the Rule 476A list of minor rule violations and limited the violations of Rule 72(b) that would be eligible to be fined under Rule 476A to instances of proprietary participation with the cross.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The NYSE also has requested approval, under Rule 19d-1(c)(2), 17 CFR 240.19d-1(c)(2), to amend its Rule 19d-1 Minor Rule Violation Enforcement and Reporting Plan (``Plan'') to include Rules 72(b), 401 and 410A. See letter from James E. Buck, Senior Vice President and Secretary, NYSE, to Sharon Lawson, Assistant Director, Exchange and Options Regulation, Division of Market Regulation, Commission, dated May 26, 1993. Subsequent to this request, the Exchange amended the proposal to withdraw Rule 401 from the list of minor rule violations and to add violations of Rule 72(b) involving instances of proprietary participation with the cross to the list of minor rules. See Amendment No. 2,</textblock>
    <textblock>supra</textblock>
    <textblock>note 4.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>With respect to the following amendment, italicizing indicates new material and brackets indicate material to be deleted.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>6</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>As noted above, the minor rule list would include only the section of Rule 72(b) which prohibits instances of proprietary participation with the cross transaction. See Amendment No. 2,</textblock>
    <textblock>supra,</textblock>
    <textblock>note 4.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>7</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
