<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00180</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00093</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Rule 62, formerly rule 55, provides that all committee orders and decisions require a majority vote.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 63, which amends former rule 57, provides for Notices of Motion requesting dismissal.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subrule 63(1) provides that a committee may terminate an extraordinary challenge proceeding where a motion requesting dismissal of the proceeding has been filed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subrule 63(2) has been amended to remove the requirement for an order of the committee where termination is by consent of all participants. The subrule now provides that an extraordinary challenge proceeding is terminated when all participants consent to dismissal and an affidavit to that effect is filed.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 64, formerly rule 58, sets out three alternative actions which a committee may take on a final decision. The rule has been amended to include the possibility of a remand in a proceeding based on a Request for Extraordinary Challenge Committee filed under Article 1904.13(a)(i) of the Agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rules 65 to 67</textblock>
    <textblock>Rules 65 to 67 provide for the completion of extraordinary challenge proceedings.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 65 amends former rule 59 to provide that publication of a Notice of Termination on termination of an extraordinary challenge proceeding by consent occurs on the day after the day on which all requirements under subrule 63(2) are met, given that termination on consent no longer requires issuance of an order by the committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 66, formerly rule 60, provides for publication of a Notice of Completion of Extraordinary Challenge on issuance of a final decision by a committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subrule 60(c) has been amended to provide that on remand to a panel, it is the Secretary, not the panel as in the former rule, who gives notice to the committee that the panel has taken action not inconsistent with the decision of the committee.</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule 67, formerly rule 61, provides for discharge of committee members.</textblock>
    <textblock>United States-Canada Free Trade Agreement Rules of Procedure for Article 1904 Extraordinary Challenge Committees</textblock>
    <textblock>Contents</textblock>
    <textblock>Preamble</textblock>
    <textblock>Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Short Title</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Application</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Statement of General Intent</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Interpretation</textblock>
    <textblock>Part I_General</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Internal Functioning of Committees</textblock>
    <textblock>11. Computation of Time</textblock>
    <textblock>13. Counsel of Record</textblock>
    <textblock>14. Costs</textblock>
    <textblock>15. Protection of Non-Public Information</textblock>
    <textblock>23. Violation of Code of Conduct</textblock>
    <textblock>24. Pleadings and Simultaneous Translation of Extraordinary Challenge Proceedings in Canada</textblock>
    <textblock>Part II_Written Proceedings</textblock>
    <textblock>29. Filing, Service and Communications</textblock>
    <textblock>37. Form and Content of Pleadings</textblock>
    <textblock>38. Request for an Extraordinary Challenge Committee</textblock>
    <textblock>41. Notice of Appearance</textblock>
    <textblock>43. Filing and Content of Briefs and Appendices</textblock>
    <textblock>45. Motions</textblock>
    <textblock>Part III_Conduct of Oral Proceedings</textblock>
    <textblock>49. Oral Proceedings in Camera</textblock>
    <textblock>Part IV_Responsibilities of the Secretary</textblock>
    <textblock>Part V_Orders and Decisions</textblock>
    <textblock>Part VI_Completion of Extraordinary Challenges</textblock>
    <textblock>Schedule_Procedural Forms</textblock>
    <textblock>Preamble</textblock>
    <textblock>The Parties,</textblock>
    <textblock>Having regard to Chapter Nineteen of the Free Trade Agreement between Canada and the United States of America;</textblock>
    <textblock>Acting pursuant to paragraph 2 of Annex 1904.13 to Chapter Nineteen of the Agreement;</textblock>
    <textblock>Adopted Rules of Procedure governing all extraordinary challenge committee proceedings conducted pursuant to Article 1904 of the Agreement;</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
