<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00043</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00037</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL TRADE COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Cable Television Survey; Information Collection Requirements</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Trade Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of application to OMB under the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. 3501 et seq.) for clearance of an information collection to gather information on cable television systems' advertising policies.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>OMB clearance is being sought for a survey to gather information on cable television systems' advertising policies.</textblock>
    <textblock>A mail questionnaire to approximately 300 cable television systems is proposed to determine whether advertising time is sold in competition with broadcast television stations. Commission staff will use this information to analyze several aspects of competition in the cable television industry.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments on this clearance application must be submitted on or before March 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send comments to FTC Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, Office of Management and Budget, New Executive Office Building, room 3228, Washington, DC 20503. Copies of the application may be obtained from the Public Reference Section, room 130, Federal Trade Commission, Washington, DC 20580.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Michael Vita, Deputy Assistant Director for Economic Policy Analysis, Federal Trade Commission, Washington, DC 20580, (202) 326-3493.</textblock>
    <textblock>By direction of the Commission.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donald S. Clark,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2822 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6750-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
