<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00122</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00031</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Service Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Service is aware that including the Ward Valley site in critical habitat may threaten a portion of the investment made in siting the LLRWR facility and may result in potentially significant costs for the State of California. However, after considering these potential economic impacts, the Service has determined that the area should not be excluded from critical habitat designation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 61:</textblock>
    <textblock>Several letters suggested that designation of critical habitat would result in taking of private property.</textblock>
    <textblock>Service Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>The courts have held that the mere enactment of laws that may result in restrictions on property does not necessarily equate to a taking of property for which compensation is required (</textblock>
    <textblock>Hodel</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Virginia Surface Mining and Reclamation Association,</textblock>
    <textblock>452 U.S. 264, 295 (1981),</textblock>
    <textblock>Agins</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Tiburon,</textblock>
    <textblock>447 U.S. 255, 260-263 (1980)). Therefore, the Service concludes that publication of a final rule designating critical habitat for the desert tortoise does not equate to a taking of property requiring just compensation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Recognizing that governmental regulation involves adjustment of rights for the public good, the U.S. Supreme Court has found that a regulation that curtails the most profitable use of one's property, resulting in a reduction in value or limitations on use likewise does not necessarily equate to a taking (</textblock>
    <textblock>Andrus</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Allard</textblock>
    <textblock>, 444 U.S. 51, 66 (1979),</textblock>
    <textblock>Agins,</textblock>
    <textblock>447 U.S. at 262,</textblock>
    <textblock>Hodel,</textblock>
    <textblock>452 U.S. at 296). Where a regulation denies a property owner the economically viable use of his or her property, then a taking will likely occur (</textblock>
    <textblock>Agins,</textblock>
    <textblock>447 U.S. at 260). However, where regulations do not categorically prohibit use but merely regulate the conditions under which such use may occur, and do not regulate alternative uses, then no taking occurs (</textblock>
    <textblock>Hodel,</textblock>
    <textblock>452 U.S. at 296). With the designation of critical habitat, a property owner is not denied the economical viable use of his or her land. Use of land is not categorically prohibited but rather certain restrictions may be imposed upon Federal agency actions that may result in the destruction or adverse modification of critical habitat. As such, the Service concludes that designation of critical habitat will not result in a taking of private property.</textblock>
    <textblock>Furthermore, a property owner must establish that a ``concrete controversy'' exists before the court may even reach the merits of a takings claim (</textblock>
    <textblock>Hodel,</textblock>
    <textblock>452 U.S. at 294,</textblock>
    <textblock>Agins,</textblock>
    <textblock>447 U.S. at 260). The property owner must show a specific and real impact to specific properties before judicial resolution of a takings claim is made (</textblock>
    <textblock>MacDonald, Sommer, and Frates</textblock>
    <textblock>v.</textblock>
    <textblock>Yolo County,</textblock>
    <textblock>477 U.S. 340, 348-349,</textblock>
    <textblock>Agins,</textblock>
    <textblock>447 U.S. at 260). As applied to critical habitat designation, a claim of takings of property would not be ripe for judicial resolution until the consultation process is completed and exemption from the Endangered Species Committee is denied. Even then, it is highly unlikely that a takings claim would be successful because designation of critical habitat does not categorically prohibit use of the property owner's land. Therefore, the Service has concluded that designation of critical habitat for the desert tortoise does not pose significant takings implications.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 62:</textblock>
    <textblock>One letter stated that designation of State lands as critical habitat violates the ``trust'' responsibility of the Federal government to the States. The main purpose of these State lands is to provide funding for the State's schools.</textblock>
    <textblock>Service Response:</textblock>
    <textblock>Critical habitat designation will not affect State lands unless proposed actions on these lands are authorized, funded, or carried out by Federal agencies. Such actions would then be subject to consultation if they may affect the desert tortoise or its habitat pursuant to section 7 of the Act. As with private lands, State lands are already subject to prohibitions of section 9 of the Act, which prohibit unauthorized take of listed species.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issue 63:</textblock>
    <textblock>Several groups stated that conferencing on projects in proposed critical habitat is illegal because the desert tortoise is already listed and because critical habitat has been proposed years beyond the statutory deadline for such designation.</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
