<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00037</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00032</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Black Forest Drums Site, Black Forest, El Paso County, CO; Proposed Administrative Settlement Pursuant to the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act, as Amended by the Superfund Amendments and Reauthorization Act</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4835-8]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>agency:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (USEPA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of Proposed Administrative Settlement; Request for Public Comment.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>summary:</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 122(i) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act, 42 U.S.C. 9622(i), as amended by the Superfund Amendments and Reauthorization Act (``CERCLA''), notice is hereby given of a proposed Administrative Settlement concerning the Black Forest Drums Site in Black Forest, El Paso County, Colorado. The proposed Administrative Settlement resolves an EPA claim under Section 107 of CERCLA, 42 U.S.C. 9607 against the Estate of Herman Walsky and Walsky Construction Company, the settling parties for this site. The settlement requires the settling parties to pay $22,000.00 to the Hazardous Substances Superfund.</textblock>
    <textblock>For thirty (30) days following the date of publication of this notice, the Agency will receive written comments relating to the settlement. The Agency's response to any comments received will be available for public inspection at EPA Region VIII's Superfund Records Center, which is located on the 8th floor of the North Tower, at 999 18th Street, in Denver, Colorado.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>dates:</textblock>
    <textblock>Comments must be submitted by March 10, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>addresses:</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed Administrative Settlement and additional background information relating to the settlement are available for public inspection at EPA Region VIII's Superfund Records Center, at the address listed above. A copy of the proposed settlement may be obtained from Carol Pokorny (8HWM-ER), Enforcement Specialist, USEPA, 999 18th Street, suite 500, Denver, CO 80202-2466. Comments should reference the Black Forest Drums Site, Black Forest, CO, EPA Docket No. CERCLA-VIII-89-03, and should be addressed to Ms. Pokorny at the address given above.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>for further information contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Jessie Goldfarb, Office of Regional Counsel, at (303) 294-7592.</textblock>
    <textblock>It Is So Agreed:</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Kerrigan G. Clough,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Regional Administrator, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region VIII.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2849 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6560-50-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
