<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-1-00026</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-1-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>GENERAL SERVICES ADMINISTRATION</textblock>
    <textblock>NATIONAL AERONAUTICS AND SPACE ADMINISTRATION</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Acquisition Regulation, Withdrawal of Proposals</textblock>
    <textblock>AGENCIES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Department of Defense (DOD), General Services Administration (GSA), and National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA).</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>48 CFR Parts 15, 31, 42, 46, and 52</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FAR Cases 89-14, 89-21, 89-31, 89-61, 91-17, and 91-67]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Proposed rules; withdrawal.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Department of Defense, General Services Administration, and National Aeronautics and Space Administration have decided to withdraw six proposed rules. These rules appeared between 1989 and 1992 and have subsequently been determined to be unnecessary, incorporated into other rules, or need further review.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>0</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Beverly Fayson, FAR Secretariat, room 4037, GS Building, Washington, DC 20405 (202) 501-4755.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>FAR Case 89-14, Indirect Cost Rate Agreements</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule, published March 7, 1989, in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(54 FR 10133), is hereby withdrawn. The rule proposed changes to Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) 15.804-4(i), 42.705-1, 42.705-2, and the clause 52.216-13 to clarify the requirement for certification under the Truth-in-Negotiations Act for final indirect cost rate agreements. The rule subsequently was determined to be unnecessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>FAR Case 89-21, Inspection for Commercial, Off-the-Shelf Supplies</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule revising FAR 46.202-1, 46.301, and 46.302 published April 20, 1989, in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(54 FR 16094), is hereby withdrawn.</textblock>
    <textblock>Withdrawal is considered necessary because the subject matter associated with this case has been incorporated with a case which proposes changes to part 46, including inspection of commercial supplies.</textblock>
    <textblock>FAR Case 89-11, Title to Property Under the Progress Payments Clause</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule, published May 1, 1989, in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(54 FR 18631), is hereby withdrawn, as agreed upon by the Civilian Agency Acquisition Council and the Defense Acquisition Regulations Council. The proposed FAR clarifications published for public comment have been determined to be unnecessary because the current FAR adequately covers the issues addressed by the proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>The rule proposed a change to the progress payments clause at FAR 52.232-16. The councils published the proposed rule to assist in assessing whether the FAR should be revised to emphasize that it is and always has been the intent of the FAR that the interest taken by the Government in property covered by the clause is title in the form of ownership, and not a mere lien. The Councils have determined that there is no need to clarify the intent of the FAR. Contracts containing the Progress Payments clause clearly reflect the intention of the parties to grant title to the property to the Government and not grant merely a lien.</textblock>
    <textblock>FAR Case 89-61, Noncommercial Cost Principles</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule, published July 28, 1989, in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(54 FR 31480), is hereby withdrawn. The rule proposed revising FAR subparts 31.3, 31.6, and 31.7 to set forth a new rule on the allowability of costs incurred under Federal contracts with educational institutions, state and local governments, federally recognized Indian tribal governments, and nonprofit organizations. The statutory prohibitions at 10 U.S.C. 2324(e) on allowable costs under defense contracts have been published in the Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation Supplement and FAR coverage is not necessary. Civilian agency contracts that are awarded to these noncommercial entities rely on the cost principles promulgated by the Office of Management and Budget.</textblock>
    <textblock>FAR Case 91-17, Contractor Acquisition of Automatic Data Processing Equipment</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule, published May 3, 1991, in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(56 FR 20507), is hereby withdrawn. This rule proposed raising two dollar thresholds in FAR 31.205-2 from $500,000 to $1,000,000. The first threshold (31.205-2(b)(2)(iii)(B)) pertains to the initial decision to lease automatic data processing equipment (ADPE), which requires contracting officer's approval. The second threshold (31.205-2(d)(3)) pertains to a contractor requirement to furnish data supporting the annual justification for retaining or changing existing ADPE capability and the need to continue leasing. Revising the thresholds in FAR 31.205-2 will be considered further as a part of a comprehensive review of the cost principle.</textblock>
    <textblock>FAR Case 91-67, Employee Stock Ownership Plans</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposals rule, published February 4, 1992, in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>(57 FR 4181), is hereby withdrawn. The Councils published the proposed rule to clarify that the cost principle at FAR 31.205-6(j)(8), Employee stock ownership plans, applies to all employee stock ownership plans (ESOPs) regardless of whether or not an ESOP meets the definition of ``pension plan'' in FAR 31.205-6(j)(1) (i.e., provides a benefit payable for life). After consideration of public comments and further examination of the issues involved, the Councils determined that the proposed rule fails to adequately address major issues associated with the allowability of costs for ESOPs. The Councils plan to address these issues in a future proposed rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 48 CFR Parts 15, 31, 42, 46, and 52</textblock>
    <textblock>Government procurement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: November 9, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Albert A. Vicchiolla,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2626 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6820-34-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
