<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00124</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00081</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The following Applications for Certificates of Public Convenience and Necessity and Foreign Air Carrier Permits were filed under Subpart Q of the Department of Transportation's Procedural Regulations (see 14 CFR 302.1701 et. seq.). The due date for Answers, Conforming Applications, or Motions to Modify Scope are set forth below for each application. Following the Answer period DOT may process the application by expedited procedures. Such procedures may consist of the adoption of a show-cause order, a tentative order, or in appropriate cases a final order without further proceedings.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>49383.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date filed:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 24, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Due Date for Answers, Conforming Applications, or Motion to Modify Scope:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 22, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description:</textblock>
    <textblock>Application of Air Pacific Limited, pursuant to Section 402 of the Act and Subpart Q of the Regulations requests amendment of its foreign air carrier permit authorizing it to engage in foreign air transportation with respect to persons, property and mail between points in the United States and Points in Fiji.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>43430.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date filed:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 24, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Due Date for Answers, Conforming Applications, or Motion to Modify Scope:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 22, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description:</textblock>
    <textblock>Application of Trans World Airlines, Inc., pursuant to Section 401 of the Act and Subpart Q of the Regulations applies for renewal of that authority listed in its certificate of public convenience and necessity Route 147 that is scheduled to expire on September 17, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Number:</textblock>
    <textblock>45810.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date filed:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 28, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Due Date for Answers, Conforming Applications, or Motion to Modify Scope:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 25, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Description: Amendment of Qantas Airways Limited to its Application for Amendment of its Foreign Air Carrier Permit to perform foreign transportation between the United States and Australia.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Applications for Certificates of Public Convenience and Necessity and Foreign Air Carrier Permits Filed Under Subpart Q During the Week Ended January 28, 1994</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Phyllis T. Kaylor,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chief, Documentary Services Division.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2781 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-62-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
