<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00146</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00092</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>17. Internal Functioning of Panels</textblock>
    <textblock>19. Computation of Time</textblock>
    <textblock>21. Counsel of Record</textblock>
    <textblock>22. Filing, Service and Communications</textblock>
    <textblock>28. Pleadings and Simultaneous Translation of Panel Reviews in Canada</textblock>
    <textblock>32. Costs</textblock>
    <textblock>Part II_Commencement of Panel Review</textblock>
    <textblock>33. Notice of Intent to Commence Judicial Review</textblock>
    <textblock>34. Request for Panel Review</textblock>
    <textblock>37. Joint Panel Reviews</textblock>
    <textblock>39. Complaint</textblock>
    <textblock>40. Notice of Appearance</textblock>
    <textblock>41. Record for Review</textblock>
    <textblock>Part III_Panels</textblock>
    <textblock>44. Announcement of Panel</textblock>
    <textblock>45. Violation of Code of Conduct</textblock>
    <textblock>Part IV_Proprietary Information and Privileged Information</textblock>
    <textblock>46. Filing or Service under Seal</textblock>
    <textblock>48. Disclosure Orders and Protective Orders</textblock>
    <textblock>55. Privileged Information</textblock>
    <textblock>57. Violations of Disclosure Undertakings and Protective Orders</textblock>
    <textblock>Part V_Written Proceedings</textblock>
    <textblock>58. Form and Content of Pleadings</textblock>
    <textblock>60. Filing of Briefs</textblock>
    <textblock>61. Failure to File Briefs</textblock>
    <textblock>62. Content of Briefs and Appendices</textblock>
    <textblock>62A. Appendix to the Briefs</textblock>
    <textblock>63. Motions</textblock>
    <textblock>Part VI_Oral Proceedings</textblock>
    <textblock>67. Location</textblock>
    <textblock>68. Pre-hearing Conference</textblock>
    <textblock>69. Oral Argument</textblock>
    <textblock>70. Subsequent Authorities</textblock>
    <textblock>71. Oral Proceedings in Camera</textblock>
    <textblock>Part VII_Decisions and Completion of Panel Reviews</textblock>
    <textblock>72. Orders, Decisions and Terminations</textblock>
    <textblock>75. Panel Review of Action on Remand</textblock>
    <textblock>76. Re-examination of Orders and Decisions</textblock>
    <textblock>78. Delay in Delivery of Decisions</textblock>
    <textblock>Part VIII_Completion of Panel Review</textblock>
    <textblock>Schedule_Procedural Forms</textblock>
    <textblock>Preamble</textblock>
    <textblock>The Parties,</textblock>
    <textblock>Having regard to Chapter Nineteen of the Free Trade Agreement between Canada and the United States of America;</textblock>
    <textblock>Acting pursuant to Article 1904.14 of the Agreement;</textblock>
    <textblock>Adopted Rules of Procedure governing all panel reviews conducted pursuant to Article 1904 of the Agreement;</textblock>
    <textblock>Adopt the following amended Rules of Procedure, effective on the date of publication in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, which from that day shall govern all panel reviews conducted pursuant to Article 1904 of the Agreement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Short Title</textblock>
    <textblock>1. These rules may be cited as the</textblock>
    <textblock>Article 1904 Panel Rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>Application</textblock>
    <textblock>1A. These rules apply to a panel review of a final determination, unless any rules of procedure made pursuant to Article 1904 of the North American Free Trade Agreement are in force and apply to a panel review of a final determination.</textblock>
    <textblock>Statement of General Intent</textblock>
    <textblock>2. These rules are intended to give effect to the provisions of Chapter Nineteen of the Agreement with respect to panel reviews conducted pursuant to Article 1904 of the Agreement and are designed to result in decisions of panels within 315 days after the commencement of the panel review. The purpose of these rules is to secure the just, speedy and inexpensive review of final determinations in accordance with the objectives and provisions of Article 1904. Where a procedural question arises that is not covered by these rules, a panel may adopt the procedure to be followed in the particular case before it by analogy to these rules or may refer for guidance to rules of procedure of a court that would otherwise have had jurisdiction in the importing country. In the event of any ambiguity or inconsistency between the provisions of these rules and the Agreement, the Agreement shall prevail.</textblock>
    <textblock>2A. Where, in respect of a panel proceeding for which a request for panel review was made before January 1, 1994, the application of these rules would, in the opinion of the panel, be impracticable or would be prejudicial to a participant, the panel may:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) Apply one or more of the rules of procedure for Article 1904 panel proceedings that were in effect at the time the request for panel review was made; or</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Make such order, not inconsistent with the Agreement, as in the panel's opinion is in the circumstances required.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interpretation</textblock>
    <textblock>3. In these rules,</textblock>
    <textblock>``Agreement'' means the Free Trade Agreement between Canada and the United States of America, signed on January 2, 1988;</textblock>
    <textblock>``Code of Conduct'' means the code of conduct established by the Parties pursuant to Article 1910 of the Agreement;</textblock>
    <textblock>``Complainant'' means a Party or interested person who files a Complaint pursuant to rule 39;</textblock>
    <textblock>``Counsel'' means:</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) With respect to a panel review of a final determination made in the United States, a person entitled to appear as counsel before a federal court in the United States, and</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
