<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00020</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Animal Drugs, Feeds, and Related Products; Promazine Hydrochloride Tablets; Nitrofurazone Solution</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>21 CFR Parts 520 and 524</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Food and Drug Administration, HHS.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Final rule.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is amending the animal drug regulations to remove those portions of the regulations that reflect approval of two new animal drug applications (NADA's). One NADA is held by Wyeth-Ayerst Laboratories and provides for use of promazine hydrochloride tablets. The other NADA is held by Squire Laboratories, Inc., and provides for use of nitrofurazone solution. In a notice published elsewhere in this issue of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, FDA is withdrawing approval of the NADA's.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 18, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mohammad I. Sharar, Center for Veterinary Medicine (HFV-216), Food and Drug Administration, 7500 Standish Pl., Rockville, MD 20855, 301-594-0749.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>In a notice published elsewhere in this issue of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>, FDA is withdrawing approval of NADA 10-783 for Sparine Tablets (promazine hydrochloride) held by Wyeth-Ayerst Laboratories, Division of American Home Products Corp., P.O. Box 8299, Philadelphia, PA 19101, and NADA 138-455 for Fura-Zone Solution (nitrofurazone) held by Squire Laboratories, Inc., 100 Mill St., Revere, MA 02151. The sponsors requested withdrawal of approval of the NADA's. This document removes 21 CFR 520.1962(b) and amends 21 CFR 524.1580d(b) to reflect the withdrawal of approval of these NADA's.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 21 CFR Parts 520 and 524</textblock>
    <textblock>Animal drugs.</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and under authority delegated to the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and redelegated to the Center for Veterinary Medicine, 21 CFR parts 520 and 524 are amended as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 520_ORAL DOSAGE FORM NEW ANIMAL DRUGS</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for 21 CFR part 520 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 512 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. 360b).</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง520.1962</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 520.1962</textblock>
    <textblock>Promazine hydrochloride</textblock>
    <textblock>is amended by removing paragraph (b) and reserving it.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 524_OPHTHALMIC AND TOPICAL DOSAGE FORM NEW ANIMAL DRUGS</textblock>
    <textblock>3. The authority citation for 21 CFR part 524 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec. 512 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. 360b).</textblock>
    <textblock>ยง524.1580d</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>4. Section 524.1580d</textblock>
    <textblock>Nitrofurazone solution</textblock>
    <textblock>is amended in paragraph (b) by removing the last sentence.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 31, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard H. Teske,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Center for Veterinary Medicine.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2754 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4160-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
