<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00091</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00070</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In the original approval and extension orders, the Commission requested reports on the pilot programs, as well as weekly data.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission expects the Regional Exchanges to submit to the Commission by March 15, 1994, updated reports concerning pilot activity through February 28, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission continues to expect the Regional Exchanges, through use of their surveillance procedures, to monitor for, and report to the Commission, any patterns of manipulation or trading abuses or unusual trading activity resulting from these pilot programs. In addition, the Commission continues to request that the Exchanges keep the Commission apprised of any technical problems which may arise regarding the operation of the pilot programs, such as difficulties in order execution or order cancellation.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission believes that it is reasonable to extend the pilot programs until April 30, 1994, in order to provide the Commission with an opportunity to continue to review the reports submitted by the Exchanges. The Commission also will be considering the various requests for permanent approval of these programs during the three-month extensions.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission finds good cause for approving the proposed rule change prior to the thirtieth day after the date of publication of notice of filing thereof in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>. The Commission believes that accelerated approval of the proposal is appropriate in order to allow the Exchanges' procedures to remain in place on an uninterrupted basis. This will permit the Exchanges to continue to compete with Crossing Session I of the NYSE's OHT facility, which in turn should benefit investors and promote competition among markets.</textblock>
    <textblock>It Is Therefore Ordered, pursuant to Section 19(b)(2) of the Act</textblock>
    <textblock>that the CHX, BSE, PSE, and Phlx proposed rule changes (CHX-93-23, BSE-93-18, PSE-94-1, and Phlx-94-7) are hereby approved on a pilot basis until April 30, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Commission, by the Division of Market Regulation, pursuant to delegated authority.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>11</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See original approval orders and extension orders,</textblock>
    <textblock>supra</textblock>
    <textblock>note 4.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>10</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See</textblock>
    <textblock>supra</textblock>
    <textblock>note 6 for the information required to be provided in the updated report.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>11</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>12</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(2) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>12</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>13</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 200.30-3(a)(12) (1993).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>13</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Margaret H. McFarland,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2769 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 8010-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
