<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00135</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00087</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 26␣/␣Tuesday, February 8, 1994␣/␣Sunshine Act Meetings</textblock>
    <textblock>Vol. 59, No. 26</textblock>
    <textblock>Tuesday, February 8, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>BLACKSTONE RIVER VALLEY NATIONAL HERITAGE CORRIDOR COMMISSION</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given in accordance with Section 552b of Title 5, United States Code, that a meeting of the Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Commission will be held on Thursday, February 17, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission was established pursuant to Public Law 99-647. The purpose of the Commission is to assist federal, state and local authorities in the development and implementation of an integrated resource management plan for those lands and waters within the Corridor.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will convene at 7 p.m. at East Providence Community Center_Pawtucket Ave., East Providence, RI, for the following reasons:</textblock>
    <textblock>Agenda:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Signage Status</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Acitiviting opportunities in East Providence</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Budget Review</textblock>
    <textblock>It is anticipated that about twenty people will be able to attend the session in addition to the Commission members.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested persons may make oral or written presentations to the Commission or file written statements. Such requests should be made prior to the meeting to: James R. Pepper, Executive Director, Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Commission, P.O. Box 730, Uxbridge, MA 01569, Tel.: (508) 278-9400.</textblock>
    <textblock>Further information concerning this meeting may be obtained from James R. Pepper, Executive Director of the Commission at the aforementioned address.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>James R. Pepper,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Executive Director.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-3013 Filed 2-7-94; 3:55 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-70-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
