<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-1-00011</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-1-00004</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Aging Airplane Safety</textblock>
  </text>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>14 CFR Parts 121, 129, and 135</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 26718; Notice No. 93-14A]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>RIN 2120-AE42</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Aviation Administration, DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of proposed rulemaking, extension of comment period.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This document announces an extension of the comment period on Notice No. 93-14 entitled, ``Aging Airplane Safety'' (58 FR 51944; October 5, 1993). This comment period is extended from February 2, 1994, until March 4, 1994. The extension responds to the request of the Regional Airline Association (RAA) and is needed to permit RAA, and other affected parties, additional time to develop comments responsive to Notice 93-14.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The comment period is being extended from February 2, 1994, to March 4, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>As stated in Notice No. 93-14, comments should be mailed, or delivered in triplicate to: Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), Office of the Chief Counsel, Attn: Rules Docket (AGC-10), Docket No. 26718, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591. Comments may be examined in the Rules Docket, room 915G, weekdays between 8:30 a.m. and 5 p.m., except Federal holidays.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Frederick Sobeck, Flight Standards Service, Aircraft Maintenance Division (AFS-300), Federal Aviation Administration, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591, telephone (202) 267-7355.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On October 5, 1993, the FAA issued Notice No. 93-14, entitled ``Aging Airplane Safety'' that proposed changes that would require persons operating older airplanes to certify that certain airplane maintenance actions had been performed; would allow the Administrator to establish an airplane operational limit beyond which additional maintenance actions must be accomplished, would implement part of the FAA's Aging Airplane Program Plan; and would respond to the Aging Aircraft Safety Act of 1991. The proposed rules are intended to assure that older airplanes are properly maintained for continued use in air transportation.</textblock>
    <textblock>By a request dated January 21, 1994, RAA asked that the comment period be extended 30 days. Because of heavy commitments to recent Aviation Rulemaking Advisory Committee (ARAC) activities, and many questions from its member airlines on the proposals, RAA had not completed analyzing the potential effects of the proposed rulemaking and could not provide substantive comments prior to the close of the comment period.</textblock>
    <textblock>The FAA has determined that an extension of the comment period will allow RAA and its members additional time for a more thorough review of applicable issues and questions raised by the NPRM, and the drafting of responsive comments. The FAA recognizes, in addition, that the intervening holiday period may have impeded the ability of interested persons to formulate comprehensive responses to the issues in the NPRM.</textblock>
    <textblock>In order, therefore, to give all interested persons additional time to complete their comments, the FAA finds that it is in the public interest to extend the comment period. Accordingly, the comments period will close on March 4, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on February 2, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William J. White,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Flight Standards Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2833 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
