<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00062</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00051</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Commission's Section of Environmental Analysis (SEA) hereby notifies all interested parties that SEA will prepare a Draft Environmental Impact Statement (DEIS) and conduct scoping meetings in this proceeding. The Canadian Pacific Limited (CP) filed an application for authority to abandon and discontinue all freight and passenger operations over 201.2 miles of rail line between Skinner and Vanceboro, in Franklin, Somerset, Piscataquis, Penobscot, Aroostook and Washington Counties, Maine. Because of the proposed abandonment's potential for significant environmental impacts, SEA has determined that preparation of a DEIS is necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>The DEIS will address the environmental impacts associated with this proposed abandonment and will be served on all the parties to the proceeding and made available to the public. There will be a 45 day comment period from the date the DEIS is served to allow the public opportunity to comment. After assessing all of the comments to the DEIS, SEA will then issue a Final Environmental Impact Statement that will include SEA's final recommendations to the Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>SEA will conduct scoping meetings prior to the preparation of the DEIS. The purpose of the scoping process is to identify significant environmental issues and determine the scope of issues to be addressed in the DEIS. Persons that cannot attend the scoping meetings, may submit questions and comments in writing up to 30 days after the scoping meetings. The public will be notified of the time and location of the scoping meetings at least 20 days prior to the scheduled date.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. AB-213 (Sub 4)]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Canadian Pacific Limited_Abandonment_Line Between Skinner and Vanceboro, ME</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Phillis Johnson-Ball (202) 927-6213 or Elaine K. Kaiser, Chief, Section of Environmental Analysis (202) 927-6248. TDD for hearing impaired: (202) 927-5721.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Commission, Elaine K. Kaiser, Chief, Section of Environmental Analysis, Office of Economic and Environmental Analysis.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Sidney L. Strickland, Jr.</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2843 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7035-01-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
