<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00096</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00072</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>February 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Section 19(b)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (``Act''),</textblock>
    <textblock>and Rule 19b-4 thereunder,</textblock>
    <textblock>notice is hereby given that on December 23, 1993, the New York Stock Exchange, Inc. (``NYSE'' or ``Exchange'') filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission (``Commission'' or ``SEC'') the proposed rule change as described in Items I and II below, which Items have been prepared by the self-regulatory organization. The Exchange has requested accelerated approval of the proposal. The Commission is publishing this notice to solicit comments on the proposed rule change from interested persons.</textblock>
    <textblock>I. Self-Regulatory Organization's Statement of the Terms of Substance of the Proposed Rule Change</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission's order approving the Exchange's Off-Hours Trading (``OHT'') facility contained a two-year ``sunset'' provision.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission later extended the ``sunset'' date until January 31, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed rule change seeks to extend (i) that ``sunset,'' and (ii) the concurrent end of the pilot program for procedures regulating matched market-on-close (``MOC'') orders, to April 30, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Exchange requests accelerated approval of the proposed rule change. Accelerated approval would enable the Exchange to continue Crossing Session I and Crossing Session II, and the matched MOC pilot program, as described below, on an uninterrupted basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>II. Self-Regulatory Organization's Statement of the Purpose of, and Statutory Basis for, the Proposed Rule Change</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Release No. 34-33563; File No. SR-NYSE-93-51]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Self-Regulatory Organizations; Filing and Order Granting Accelerated Approval of Proposed Rule Change by the New York Stock Exchange, Inc. Relating to the Off-Hours Trading Facility and Matched MOC Order Procedures</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>15 U.S.C. 78s(b)(1) (1988).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>17 CFR 240.19b-4 (1991).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See Securities Exchange Act Release No. 29237 (May 31, 1991), 56 FR 24853 (June 3, 1991) (File Nos. SR-NYSE-90-52 and SR-NYSE-90-53 (``OHT Approval Order'').</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>3</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See Securities Exchange Act Release No. 32362 (May 25, 1993), 58 FR 31565 (June 3, 1993) (order granting accelerated approval to File No. SR-NYSE-93-23).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>4</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The Commission initially approved the matched MOC order procedures on a pilot basis in June, 1990. In that order, the Commission also granted an exemption from its short sale rule, Rule 10a-1, for matched MOC orders that are part of a program trading strategy. See Securities Exchange Act Release No. 28167 (June 29, 1990), 55 FR 28117 (order granting temporary approval to File No. SR-NYSE-89-10) and letter from Richard G. Ketchum, Director, Division of Market Regulation, SEC, to James E. Buck, Senior Vice President and Secretary, NYSE, dated July 2, 1990. The original one-year pilot program was temporarily extended by the Commission for an additional six months, until September 30, 1991, in order to give the Exchange the opportunity to contrast the use of matched MOC orders with certain program trading transactions effected in the Exchange's then recently implemented Crossing Session II. See Securities Exchange Act Release No. 29393 (July 1, 1991), 56 FR 30954 (order granting temporary accelerated approval to File No. SR-NYSE-91-22). Subsequently, the Commission granted accelerated approval to an Exchange proposal to extend the pilot period until November 30, 1991. See Securities Exchange Act Release No. 29761 (September 30, 1991), 56 FR 50743 (order granting temporary accelerated approval to File No. SR-NYSE-91-34). Thereafter, the Commission extended the matched MOC order pilot program through May 24, 1993. See Securities Exchange Act Release No. 30004 (November 27, 1991), 56 FR 63533 (order granting temporary approval to File No. SR-NYSE-91-35). On May 25, 1993, the Commission approved extensions of the NYSE pilots until January 31, 1994. See Securities Exchange Act Release No. 32362 (May 25, 1993), 58 FR 31565 (June 3, 1993).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>5</textblock>
  </footname>
</doc>
