<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00167</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-2-00092</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Form (2)</textblock>
    <textblock>Article 1904 Binational Panel Review pursuant to the United States-Canada Free Trade Agreement</textblock>
    <textblock>In the matter of:</textblock>
    <textblock>(Title of Panel Review)</textblock>
    <textblock>Secretariat File No.</textblock>
    <textblock>Request for Panel Review</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Article 1904 of the Canada-United States Free-Trade Agreement, panel review is hereby requested of the final determination referenced below. The following information is provided pursuant to Rule 34 of the</textblock>
    <textblock>Article 1904 Panel Rules:</textblock>
    <textblock>1.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The name of the Party or the interested person filing this request for panel review)</textblock>
    <textblock>2.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The name of counsel for the Party or the interested person, if any)</textblock>
    <textblock>3.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The service address, as defined by Rule 3 of the Article 1904 Panel Rules,</textblock>
    <textblock>including facsimile number, if any)</textblock>
    <textblock>4.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The telephone number of counsel for the Party or the interested person or the telephone number of the interested person, if not represented by counsel)</textblock>
    <textblock>5.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The title of the final determination for which panel review is requested)</textblock>
    <textblock>6.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The investigating authority that issued the final determination)</textblock>
    <textblock>7.</textblock>
    <textblock>(The file number of the investigating authority)</textblock>
    <textblock>8. (a)</textblock>
    <textblock>(The citation and date of publication of the final determination in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>or</textblock>
    <textblock>Canada Gazette</textblock>
    <textblock>); or</textblock>
    <textblock>(b)</textblock>
    <textblock>(If the final determination was not published, the date notice of the final determination was received by the other Party)</textblock>
    <textblock>9. Yes</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>No</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>Non-Applicable</textblock>
    <textblock>XXXX</textblock>
    <textblock>(Where a Notice of Intent to Commence Judicial Review has been served, is the sole reason for requesting review of the final determination to require review by a panel?)</textblock>
    <textblock>10. The Service List, as defined by Rule 3, is attached.</textblock>
    <textblock>Date</textblock>
    <textblock>Signature of Counsel (or interested person, if not represented by counsel)</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
