<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-1-00070</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-1-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Interested persons may participate in this proposed rulemaking by submitting data, views, or arguments in writing to the Bureau of Prisons, 320 First Street NW., HOLC Room 754, Washington, DC 20534. Comments received during the comment period will be considered before final action is taken. All comments received remain on file for public inspection at the above address. The proposed rule may be changed in light of the comments received. No oral hearings are contemplated.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 28 CFR Part 551</textblock>
    <textblock>Prisoners.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Kathleen M. Hawk,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Bureau of Prisons.</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, pursuant to the rulemaking authority vested in the Attorney General in 5 U.S.C. 552(a) and delegated to the Director, Bureau of Prisons in 28 CFR 0.96(p), it is proposed to amend part 551 in subchapter C of 28 CFR, chapter V as set forth below.</textblock>
    <textblock>SUBCHAPTER C_INSTITUTIONAL MANAGEMENT</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 551_MISCELLANEOUS</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for 28 CFR part 551 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>5 U.S.C. 301; 18 U.S.C. 1512, 3621, 3622, 3624, 4001, 4005, 4042, 4081, 4082 (Repealed in part as to offenses committed on or after November 1, 1987), 4161-4166 (Repealed as to offenses committed on or after November 1, 1987), 5006-5024 (Repealed October 12, 1984 as to offenses committed after that date), 5039; 28 U.S.C. 509, 510; Public Law 99-500 (sec. 209); 28 CFR 0.95-0.99.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Subpart N, consisting of §§551.160 through 551.163, is revised to consist of §§551.160 through 551.164 as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart N_Smoking/No Smoking Areas</textblock>
    <textblock>Sec.</textblock>
    <textblock>551.160␣Purpose and scope.</textblock>
    <textblock>551.161␣Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>551.162␣Designated no smoking areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>551.163␣Designated smoking areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>551.164␣Notice of smoking areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>Subpart N_Smoking/No Smoking Areas</textblock>
    <textblock>§551.160</textblock>
    <textblock>Purpose and scope.</textblock>
    <textblock>To advance towards becoming a clean air environment and to protect the health and safety of staff and inmates, the Bureau of Prisons will restrict areas and circumstances where smoking is permitted within its institutions and offices.</textblock>
    <textblock>§551.161</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>For purpose of this subpart, smoking is defined as carrying or inhaling a lighted cigar, cigarette, pipe or other lighted tobacco products.</textblock>
    <textblock>§551.162</textblock>
    <textblock>Designated no smoking areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>All areas of Bureau of Prisons facilities and vehicles are no smoking areas unless specifically designated as a smoking area by the Warden as set forth in §551.163.</textblock>
    <textblock>§551.163</textblock>
    <textblock>Designated smoking areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) At all Medical Referral Centers, including housing units, and at minimum security institutions, including satellite camps and intensive confinement centers, the Warden shall identify ``smoking areas'', ordinarily outside of all buildings and away from all entrances so as not to expose others to second-hand smoke.</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) At all low, medium, high, and administrative institutions other than medical referral centers, the Warden shall identify outdoor smoking areas and may, but is not required to, designate a limited number of indoor smoking areas where the needs of effective operations so require, especially for those who may be employed in, or restricted to, a nonsmoking area for an extended period of time.</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) To the maximum extent practicable nonsmoking inmates shall be housed in nonsmoking living quarters.</textblock>
    <textblock>§551.164</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of smoking areas.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Warden shall ensure that smoking areas are clearly identified by the appropriate placement of signs. The absence of a sign shall be interpreted as indicating a no smoking area. Appropriate disciplinary action shall be taken for failure to observe smoking restrictions.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2851 Filed 2-7-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4410-05-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
