<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00124</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00031</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Authors</textblock>
    <textblock>The primary authors of this rule and its associated CHU maps are Sheryl L. Barrett, Christine Mullen, Mark Maley, Michael Burroughs, and David L. Harlow, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Nevada Field Office (see</textblock>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES</textblock>
    <textblock>section); Ray Bransfield, Kirk Waln, and Tim MacGillvray, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Ventura Field Office; Marilet A. Zablan, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Utah State Office; James Rorabaugh, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Arizona Field Office; Arthur Davenport, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Carlsbad Field Office; Mel Schamberger and Dirk Draper, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, National Ecology Research Center, Ft. Collins, Colorado.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 50 CFR Part 17</textblock>
    <textblock>Endangered and threatened species, Exports, Imports, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements, and Transportation.</textblock>
    <textblock>Regulation Promulgation</textblock>
    <textblock>Accordingly, part 17, subchapter B of chapter I, title 50 of the Code of Federal Regulations is hereby amended as set forth below:</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 17_[AMENDED]</textblock>
    <textblock>1. The authority citation for part 17 continues to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 1361-1407; 16 U.S.C. 1531-1544; 16 U.S.C. 4201-4245; Pub. L. 99-625, 100 Stat. 3500, unless otherwise noted.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Section 17.95(c) is amended by removing the critical habitat of the Beaver Dam Slope population of the desert tortoise and adding the following new critical habitat of the desert tortoise (</textblock>
    <textblock>Gopherus agassizii</textblock>
    <textblock>) in its place to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>§17.95</textblock>
    <textblock>Critical habitat_fish and wildlife.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Desert Tortoise_Mojave Population (</textblock>
    <textblock>Gopherus agassizii</textblock>
    <textblock>)</textblock>
    <textblock>Index map of approximate locations of critical habitat units follows:</textblock>
  </text>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-55-P</textblock>
  </billing>
  <import>
    <textblock>ER08FE94.000</textblock>
  </import>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-55-C</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
