<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00077</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940208-0-00030</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Groundfish of the Gulf of Alaska</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <cfrno>
    <textblock>50 CFR Part 672</textblock>
  </cfrno>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 931199-3299; I.D. 020394A]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>agency:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Services (NMFS), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>action:</textblock>
    <textblock>Closure.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>summary:</textblock>
    <textblock>NMFS is closing the directed fishery for pollock in Statistical Area 61 of the Gulf of Alaska (GOA). This action is necessary to prevent exceeding the interim specification for pollock in this area.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>effective date:</textblock>
    <textblock>12 noon, Alaska local time (A.l.t.), February 4, 1994, until superseded by the final 1994 specifications in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>for further information contact:</textblock>
    <textblock>Andrew N. Smoker, Resource Management Specialist, Fisheries Management Division, NMFS, (907) 586-7228.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>supplementary information:</textblock>
    <textblock>The groundfish fishery in the GOA exclusive economic zone is managed by the Secretary of Commerce according to the Fishery Management Plan for Groundfish of the GOA (FMP) prepared by the North Pacific Fishery Management Council under authority of the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act. Fishing by U.S. vessels is governed by regulations implementing the FMP at 50 CFR parts 620 and 672.</textblock>
    <textblock>The interim specification of pollock total allowable catch in Statistical Area 61 was established by interim specifications (58 FR 60575, November 17, 1993) as 4,232 metric tons (mt), determined in accordance with ยง672.20(c)(1)(ii)(A).</textblock>
    <textblock>The Director of the Alaska Region, NMFS (Regional Director), has determined, in accordance with ยง672.20(c)(2)(ii), that the 1994 interim specification of pollock in Statistical Area 61 soon will be reached. The Regional Director established a directed fishing allowance of 3,832 mt, and has set aside the remaining 400 mt as bycatch to support other anticipated groundfish fisheries. The Regional Director has determined that the directed fishing allowance has been reached. Consequently, NMFS is prohibiting directed fishing for pollock in Statistical Area 61, effective from 12 noon, A.l.t., February 4, 1994, until superseded by the final 1994 specifications in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Directed fishing standards for applicable gear types may be found in the regulations at ยง672.20(g).</textblock>
    <textblock>Classification</textblock>
    <textblock>This action is taken under 50 CFR 672.20.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 50 CFR Part 672</textblock>
    <textblock>Fisheries, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>16 U.S.C. 1801</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: February 3, 1994.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard H. Schaefer,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director of Office of Fisheries Conservation and Management, National Marine Fisheries Service.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-2870 Filed 2-3-94; 2:43 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
