<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00027</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00010</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>December 30, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>COMMITTEE FOR THE IMPLEMENTATION OF TEXTILE AGREEMENTS</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Announcement of Extension of the Visa and Exempt Certification Arrangement Between the United States and India</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements (CITA).</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Announcing the extension of the visa and exempt certification arrangement with India.</textblock>
  </action>
  <date>
    <textblock>EFFECTIVE DATE:</textblock>
    <textblock>January 1, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Jennifer Tallarico, International Trade Specialist, Office of Textiles and Apparel, U.S. Department of Commerce, (202) 482-4212.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Authority:</textblock>
    <textblock>Executive Order 11651 of March 3, 1972, as amended; section 204 of the Agricultural Act of 1956, as amended (7 U.S.C. 1854).</textblock>
    <textblock>The existing export visa and exempt certification arrangement between the Governments of the United States and India has been extended through January 31, 1994, as agreed in an exchange of letters between the two Governments dated December 23 and 27, 1993. This notice is to remind the public that the U.S. Customs Service must continue to require visas and exempt certifications as previously published, for textiles and textile products produced or manufctured in India, and exported to the United States. Any cancellation of those requirements will be announced in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>.</textblock>
    <textblock>See 44 FR 68504 published on November 29, 1979.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Rita D. Hayes,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Chairman, Committee for the Implementation of Textile Agreements.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 93-32116 Filed 12-30-93; 4:35 pm]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DR-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
