<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00069</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00029</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In the Matter of Certain Diltiazem Hydrochloride and Diltiazem Preparations</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Investigation No. 337-TA-349]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Commission Decision Not To Review an Initial Determination Suspending the Investigation</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. International Trade Commission.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the U.S. International Trade Commission has determined not to review an initial determination (ID) issued by the presiding administrative law judge (ALJ) suspending the above-captioned investigation.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Cynthia P. Johnson, Esq., Office of the General Counsel, U.S. International Trade Commission, telephone 202-205-3098.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>On March 31, 1993, the Commission instituted an investigation into allegations by complainants Tanabe Seiyaku Co., Ltd. and Marion Merrell Dow (``complainants'') that respondents Gyma Laboratories of America, Inc.; Mylan Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Mylan Laboratories, Inc. and Profarmaco Norbel SRL (``Mylan respondents'') ; Orion Corporation Fermion, Interchem Corporation, Rhone-Poulenc Rorer, Inc., and Copley Pharmaceuticals, Inc. (``the Fermion Respondents''); and Abic Ltd. (``Abic'') were violating section 337 in the importation and sale of certain diltiazem hydrochloride and diltiazem preparations allegedly manufactured abroad by a process covered by claim 1 of U.S. Letters Patent 4,438,035 (``the</textblock>
    <textblock>’035 patent''). Plantex USA (``Plantex'') was later added as a respondent. On May 3, 1993, respondent Abic requested that the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office (``PTO'') reexamine all claims of the</textblock>
    <textblock>’035 patent. On June 25, 1993, the PTO granted Abic's request and began reexamination proceedings. On November 22, 1993, the PTO issued an office action rejecting claims of the</textblock>
    <textblock>’035 patent as obvious under 35 U.S.C. 103.</textblock>
    <textblock>On November 23, 1993, as a result of the PTO's rejection, complainants moved to suspend the Commission investigation pending the outcome of the PTO reexamination proceedings. Respondents opposed the motion, and the Commission investigative attorney (IA) supported the motion. On November 24, 1993, the presiding ALJ issued an ID suspending the investigation until 30 days after the completion of reexamination proceedings at the PTO or until such time as may be prescribed by the Commission.</textblock>
    <textblock>On December 2, 1993, Abic and Plantex filed a petition for review of the ID. On December 6, 1993, the Fermion respondents filed a response in support of Abic and Plantex's petition for review. On December 9, 1993, complainants and the IA filed oppositions to respondents' petition for review.</textblock>
    <textblock>This action is taken under the authority of section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (19 U.S.C. 1337) and §210.53(h) of the Commission's Interim Rules of Practice and Procedure (19 CFR 210.53(h)).</textblock>
    <textblock>Copies of the ID and all other nonconfidential documents filed in connection with this investigation are available for inspection during official business hours (8:45 to 5:15 p.m. in the Office of the Secretary, U.S. International Trade Commission, 500 E Street, SW., Washington, DC 20436, telephone 202-205-2000. Hearing-impaired persons are advised that information on the matter can be obtained by contacting the Commission's TDD terminal on 202-205-1810.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued: December 28, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>By order of the Commission.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna R. Koehnke,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-152 Filed 1-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7020-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
