<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00060</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00023</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to Public Law 92-463, notice is hereby given of the meeting of the Subcommittee to Evaluate the National Cancer Program, National Cancer Advisory Board, National Cancer Institute, National Institutes of Health on January 20-22, 1994 at the San Diego Hilton, 1175 East Mission Bay Drive, San Diego, California 92109.</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be open to the public from 3 p.m. to recess on January 20; from 9 a.m. to recess January 21, and from 9 a.m. until adjournment on January 22. Attendance by the public will be limited to space available. Discussions will address the evaluation and achievements of the National Cancer Program.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Carole Frank, Committee Management Specialist, National Cancer Institute, National Institutes of Health, Executive Plaza North, room 630M, 9000 Rockville Pike, Bethesda, Maryland 20892 (301/496-5708), will provide a summary of the meeting and a roster of the Subcommittee members upon request.</textblock>
    <textblock>Ms. Cherie Nichols, Executive Secretary, Subcommittee to Evaluate the National Cancer Program, National Cancer Advisory Board, National Cancer Institute, National Institutes of Health, Building 31, room 11A23, Bethesda, Maryland 20892 (301/496-5515), will furnish substantive program information.</textblock>
    <textblock>Individuals who plan to attend and need special assistance, such as sign language interpretation or other reasonable accommodations, should contact Ms. Cherie Nichols on (301/496-5515) in advance of the meeting.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 28, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Institutes of Health</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>National Cancer Institute; Notice of Meeting of the Subcommittee To Evaluate the National Cancer Program, National Cancer Advisory Board</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Susan K. Feldman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Committee Management Officer, NIH.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-153 Filed 1-5-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4140-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
