<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00122</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00059</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 10(A)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Public Law 92-362; 5 U.S.C. App. I), notice is hereby given of a meeting of the Flight Service Technology Subcommittee of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) Research, Engineering and Development (R,E&amp;D) Advisory Committee to be held Friday, January 28, 1994, at 10 a.m. The meeting will take place at the Federal Aviation Administration, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC, in the Round Room on the tenth floor.</textblock>
    <textblock>The agenda for this meeting will include: Review and discussion of the proposed task statement; organization of the effort to develop a report and recommendations; overview of the current and future technology associated with pre-flight weather and flight plan filing services. This subcommittee will attempt to ensure that the FAA's program addresses all the right technology issues.</textblock>
    <textblock>Attendance is open to the interested public but limited to space available. With the approval of the Subcommittee Chairman, members of the public may present oral statements at the meeting. Persons wishing to present oral statements, obtain information, or plan to access the building to attend the meeting should contact Mr. Carl McCullough, ASE-10, at (202) 287-8595 or Ms. Jan Peters, ASD-3, at (202) 287-8543 in the Office of the Associate Administrator for System Engineering and Development, 800 Independence Avenue, SW., Washington, DC 20591.</textblock>
    <textblock>Members of the public may present a written statement to the subcommittee at any time.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued in Washington, DC, on December 27, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Research, Engineering and Development Advisory Committee, Flight Service Technology Subcommittee; Meeting</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Martin T. Pozesky,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Executive Director, Research, Engineering and Development Advisory Committee.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-138 Filed 1-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-13-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
