<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-0-00071</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-0-00015</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Wednesday</textblock>
    <textblock>January 5, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>Part II</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency</textblock>
    <textblock>40 CFR Part 13</textblock>
    <textblock>Referral of Debts to Internal Revenue Service for Tax Refund Offset; Interim Final Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>␣/␣Vol. 59, No. 3␣/␣Wednesday,</textblock>
    <textblock>January 5, 1994␣/␣Rules and Regulations</textblock>
    <textblock>Referral of Debts to the Internal Revenue Service for Tax Refund Offset</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>40 CFR Part 13</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[FRL-4818-2]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Environmental Protection Agency.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interim rule with request for comments.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), as a participant in the Federal Tax Refund Offset Program, is issuing interim regulations to govern the referral of delinquent debts to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) for offset against the income tax refunds of persons owing money to EPA. These regulations allow EPA to collect debts by means of offset from the income tax refunds of persons owing money to EPA provided certain conditions are met. This rule establishes procedures to be followed by EPA in requesting the IRS to offset tax refunds due to taxpayers who have past-due legally enforceable debt obligations to the EPA.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Interim rule is effective on January 5, 1994. Written comments must be received on or before March 7, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Send comments to: Stephen B. Hess, Claims and Property Law Branch (2376), Office of General Counsel, Environmental Protection Agency, 401 M Street, SW., Washington, DC 20460.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Stephen B. Hess, Office of General Counsel. Telephone 202-260-7512.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>This interim rule provides procedures for EPA to refer past-due legally enforceable debts to the IRS for offset against the income tax refunds of persons owing debts to EPA. This rule is authorized by 31 U.S.C. 3720A, the purpose of which is to improve the ability of the government to collect money owed it while adding certain notice requirements and other protections applicable to the government's relationship to the debtor.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule implements 31 U.S.C. 3720A, which directs any Federal agency that is owed a past-due legally enforceable debt by a named person to notify the Secretary of the Treasury in accordance with regulations issued by the Department of the Treasury at 26 CFR 301.6402-6. Before a Federal agency may give such notice, however, it must first:</textblock>
    <textblock>(1) Notify the debtor that the agency proposes to refer the debt for a tax refund deduction;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) Give the debtor 60 days from the date of the notification to present evidence that all or part of the debt is not past-due or legally enforceable;</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) Consider any evidence presented by the debtor and determine whether any amount of such debt is past-due and legally enforceable; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) Satisfy such other conditions as the Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe to ensure that the agency's determination is valid and that the agency has made reasonable efforts to obtain payment of the debt.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rule, in accordance with IRS regulations, provides that before EPA refers a debt to Treasury (through IRS), a notice of intention (Notice of Intent) will be sent to the debtor. This Notice of Intent will inform the debtor of the amount of the debt and that unless the debt is repaid within 60 days from the date of EPA's Notice of Intent, EPA intends to collect the debt by requesting the IRS to offset any tax refund payable to the debtor. In addition, the Notice of Intent will state that the debtor has a right, during such period, to present evidence that all or part of the debt is not past-due or legally enforceable. This rule also establishes procedures for the debtor to present such evidence.</textblock>
  </supplem>
</doc>
