<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-0-00064</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>B. Regulatory Flexibility Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The interim rule may have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities within the meaning of the Regulatory Flexibility Act, 5 U.S.C. 601</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.,</textblock>
    <textblock>because the rule waives the Buy American Act for certain Mexican and Canadian products. An Initial Regulatory Flexibility Analysis (IRFA) has been prepared and will be provided to the Chief Counsel for Advocacy for the Small Business Administration. A copy of the IRFA may be obtained from the FAR Secretariat. Comments are invited. Comments from small entities concerning the affected FAR subpart will be considered in accordance with 5 U.S.C. 610. Such comments must be submitted separately and cite 5 U.S.C. 601,</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>(FAR Case 93-310), in correspondence.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Paperwork Reduction Act</textblock>
    <textblock>The Paperwork Reduction Act (Pub. L. 96-511) is deemed to apply because the new provision at 52.225-20 requires offerors to list the line item number and country of origin for any end product other than a domestic end product. Accordingly, a request for clearance of a new information collection requirement concerning the NAFTA Act is being submitted to the Office of Management and Budget under 44 U.S.C. 3501,</textblock>
    <textblock>et seq.</textblock>
    <textblock>Public comments concerning this requirement are invited through an OMB clearance request appearing in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>at 58 FR 68636, December 28, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Determination To Issue an Interim Rule</textblock>
    <textblock>A determination has been made under the authority of the Secretary of Defense (DOD), the Administrator of General Services (GSA), and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) that compelling reasons exist to promulgate this interim rule without prior opportunity for public comment. This action is necessary because the NAFTA Implementation Act, signed into law on December 8, 1993, becomes effective on January 1, 1994. However, pursuant to Public Law 98-577 and Federal Acquisition Regulation 1.501, public comments received in response to this interim rule will be considered in formulating the final rule.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 48 CFR Parts 5, 14, 15, 17, 25, and 52</textblock>
    <textblock>Government procurement.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 30, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Shirley Scott,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Office of Federal Acquisition Policy.</textblock>
    <textblock>Unless otherwise specified, all Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) and other directive material contained in FAC 90-19 is effective January 1, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 21, 1993.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Eleanor R. Spector,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Director, Defense Procurement, Department of Defense (DOD).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 20, 1993.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Richard H. Hopf, III,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Administrator for Acquisition Policy, General Services Administration.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 21, 1993.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Deidre A. Lee,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Administrator for Procurement, NASA.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
