<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00018</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00006</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Public Comment</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with 19 CFR 353.38, case briefs or other written comments in at least ten copies must be submitted to the Assistant Secretary for Import Administration no later than April 8, 1994, and rebuttal briefs, no later than April 13, 1994. In accordance with 19 CFR 353.38(b), we will hold a public hearing, if requested, to afford interested parties an opportunity to comment on arguments raised in case or rebuttal briefs. Tentatively, the hearing will be held on April 15, 1994, at 10 a.m. at the U.S. Department of Commerce, room 3708, 14th Street and Constitution Avenue, NW., Washington, DC 20230. Parties should confirm by telephone the time, date, and place of the hearing 48 hours before the scheduled time.</textblock>
    <textblock>Interested parties who wish to request a hearing, or to participate if one is requested, must submit a written request to the Assistant Secretary for Import Administration, U.S. Department of Commerce, room B-099, within ten days of the publication of this notice. Requests should contain: (1) The party's name, address, and telephone number; (2) the number of participants; and (3) a list of the issues to be discussed. In addition, an executive summary of no more than two pages on the major issues to be addressed should be submitted with case briefs. Briefs should contain a table of authorities. Citations to the Department's determinations and court decisions should include the page number where the cited information appears. In preparing the briefs, please begin each issue on a separate page. In accordance with 19 CFR 353.38(b), oral presentations will be limited to issues raised in the briefs. If this investigation proceeds normally, we will make our final determination on or about May 23, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>This determination is published pursuant to section 733(f) of the Act and 19 CFR 353.15(a)(4).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 27, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Barbara R. Stafford,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Assistant Secretary for Import Administration.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-160 Filed 1-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-DS-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
