<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00031</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The companies listed in this notice have applied for the Board's approval under section 3 of the Bank Holding Company Act (12 U.S.C. 1842) and  225.14 of the Board's Regulation Y (12 CFR 225.14) to become a bank holding company or to acquire a bank or bank holding company. The factors that are considered in acting on the applications are set forth in section 3(c) of the Act (12 U.S.C. 1842(c)).</textblock>
    <textblock>Each application is available for immediate inspection at the Federal Reserve Bank indicated. Once the application has been accepted for processing, it will also be available for inspection at the offices of the Board of Governors. Interested persons may express their views in writing to the Reserve Bank or to the offices of the Board of Governors. Any comment on an application that requests a hearing must include a statement of why a written presentation would not suffice in lieu of a hearing, identifying specifically any questions of fact that are in dispute and summarizing the evidence that would be presented at a hearing.</textblock>
    <textblock>Unless otherwise noted, comments regarding each of these applications must be received not later than January 28, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>A. Federal Reserve Bank of Cleveland</textblock>
    <textblock>(John J. Wixted, Jr., Vice President) 1455 East Sixth Street, Cleveland, Ohio 44101:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Bridgeville Financial Corp.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Bridgeville, Pennsylvania; to become a bank holding company by acquiring 100 percent of the voting shares of Bridgeville Savings Bank, Bridgeville, Pennsylvania.</textblock>
    <textblock>B. Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta</textblock>
    <textblock>(Zane R. Kelley, Vice President) 104 Marietta Street, N.W., Atlanta, Georgia 30303:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. D/W Bankshares, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Dalton, Georgia; to become a bank holding company by acquiring 100 percent of the voting shares of Dalton/Whitfield Bank &amp; Trust, Dalton, Georgia.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago</textblock>
    <textblock>(James A. Bluemle, Vice President) 230 South LaSalle Street, Chicago, Illinois 60690:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Home Bancorp</textblock>
    <textblock>, Fort Wayne, Indiana; to become a bank holding company by acquiring 100 percent of the voting shares of Home Loan Bank, S.B., Fort Wayne, Indiana.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Orangeville Bancorp, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Orangeville, Illinois; to acquire 100 percent of the voting shares of State Bank of Winslow, Winslow, Illinois.</textblock>
    <textblock>D. Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis</textblock>
    <textblock>(James M. Lyon, Vice President) 250 Marquette Avenue, Minneapolis, Minnesota 55480:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. Community First Bankshares, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Fargo, North Dakota; to acquire 100 percent of the voting shares of Grand National Bank of Colorado, Fraser, Colorado.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Sentry Bancorp, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Edina, Minnesota; to become a bank holding company by acquiring 100 percent of the voting shares of Cannon Valley Bank, Dundas, Minnesota.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Michigan Financial Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>, Marquette, Michigan; to merge with Houghton Financial Inc., Houghton, Michigan, and thereby indirectly acquire Houghton National Bank, Houghton, Michigan.</textblock>
    <textblock>C. Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City</textblock>
    <textblock>(John E. Yorke, Senior Vice President) 925 Grand Avenue, Kansas City, Missouri 64198:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. First Missouri Bancshares, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>, Brookfield, Missouri; to become a bank holding company by acquiring 100 percent of the voting shares of First Missouri National Bank, Brookfield, Missouri.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. Huckabay Enterprises A Limited Partnership</textblock>
    <textblock>, Mustang, Oklahoma; to become a bank holding company by acquiring 48.54 percent of Wichita Bancshares, Inc., Snyder, Oklahoma, and thereby indirectly acquire Bank of the Wichitas, Snyder, Oklahoma; to acquire 50 percent of the voting shares of Southwest State Corporation, Sentinel, Oklahoma, and thereby indirectly acquire Southwest State Bank, Sentinel, Oklahoma; and to acquire 60.70 percent of the voting shares of First Mustang Corporation, Mustang, Oklahoma, and thereby indirectly acquire The First Mustang State Bank, Mustang, Oklahoma.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. Meadows Enterprises A Limited Partnership</textblock>
    <textblock>, Burns Flat, Oklahoma; to become a bank holding company by acquiring 43.92 percent of the voting shares of Wichita Bancshares, Inc., Snyder, Oklahoma, and thereby indirectly acquire Bank of the Wichitas, Snyder, Oklahoma; to acquire 50 percent of the voting shares of Southwest State Corporation, Sentinel, Oklahoma, and thereby indirectly acquire Southwest State Bank, Sentinel, Oklahoma; and to acquire 62.23 percent of the voting shares of Washita Bancshares, Inc., Burns Flat, Oklahoma, and thereby indirectly acquire Washita State Bank, Burns Flat, Oklahoma.</textblock>
    <textblock>4. FIAB Holdings, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>, San Francisco, California; to become a bank holding company by acquiring 100 percent of the voting shares of First Indo-American Bank, San Francisco, California.</textblock>
    <textblock>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, December 30, 1993.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL RESERVE SYSTEM</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Bridgeville Financial Corp., et al.; Formations of; Acquisitions by; and Mergers of Bank Holding Companies</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Jennifer J. Johnson,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Secretary of the Board.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-122 Filed 1-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6210-01-F</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
