<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00065</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00025</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Change in Discount Rate for Water Resources Planning</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Bureau of Reclamation</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>Bureau of Reclamation, Interior.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of change.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice sets forth that the discount rate to be used in Federal water resources planning for fiscal year 1994 is 8 percent. Water Resources Planning Act and Water Resources Development Act of 1974 requires an annual determination of a discount rate. Federal water resources planning for fiscal year 1994 is 8 percent. Discounting is to be used to convert future monetary values to present values.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>This discount rate is to be used for the period October 1, 1993, through and including September 30, 1994.</textblock>
  </date>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. Norbert S. Ries, Special Programs Manager, Investigations and Oversight Branch, U.S. Bureau of Reclamation, Attention: D-5110, Building 67, Denver Federal Center, Denver CO 80225-0007; telephone: (303) 236-9336, extension 233.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice is hereby given that the interest rate to be used by Federal agencies in the formulation and evaluation of plans for water and related land resources is 8 percent for fiscal year 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>This rate has been computed in accordance with section 80(a), Public Law 93-251 (88 Stat. 34) and 18 CFR 704.39, which: (1) Specify that the rate shall be based upon the average yield during the preceding fiscal year on interest-bearing marketable securities of the United States which, at the time the computation is made, have terms of 15 years or more remaining to maturity (average yield is rounded to nearest one-eighth percent); and (2) provide that the rate shall not be raised or lowered more than one-quarter of 1 percent for any year. The Treasury Department calculated the specified average yield to be 7.08 percent. However, application of the above mentioned limitation to the fiscal year 1993 rate of 8.25 percent limits the change in the fiscal year 1994 rate to 8 percent.</textblock>
    <textblock>The rate of 8 percent shall be used by all Federal agencies in the formulation and evaluation of water and related land resources plans for the purpose of discounting future benefits and computing costs, or otherwise converting benefits and costs to a common time basis.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: December 28, 1993.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donald R. Glaser,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Deputy Commissioner.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-109 Filed 1-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4310-94-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
