<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-0-00068</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>(l)(1) For purchases subject to North American Free Trade Agreement or the European Community Agreement, agencies not listed at 25.407;</textblock>
    <textblock>(2) For other purchases under this subpart, agencies not listed at 25.406; or</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>25.405</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>18. Section 25.405 is amended in the introductory text by inserting ``or North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA)'' after ``Act''; in paragraph (d) by removing ``countries'' the first time it appears and inserting ``, NAFTA,'' in its place; and in paragraph (e) by inserting ``or NAFTA'' after ``designated''.</textblock>
    <textblock>19. Section 25.406 is amended by revising the ``General Services Administration'' entry and adding in alphabetical order ``National Archives and Records Administration'' to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>25.406</textblock>
    <textblock>Agencies covered by the Agreement on Government Procurement.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>General Services Administration (except Federal Supply Groups 51 and 52 and Federal Supply Class 7340).</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>National Archives and Records Administration.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>20. Section 25.407 is amended by revising the section heading; removing the introductory paragraph; redesignating paragraphs (a) thru (d) as (b) thru (e), and adding a new paragraph (a); changing ``is'' to ``are'' in newly redesignated (d); and adding paragraphs (f) and (g) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>25.407</textblock>
    <textblock>Agencies covered by the European Community and North American Free Trade Agreements.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) The agencies listed in 25.406.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(f) Federal Housing Finance Board.</textblock>
    <textblock>(g) Office of Thrift Supervision.</textblock>
    <textblock>21. Section 25.408 is amended by removing ``Act'' following ``Agreements'' from paragraph (a)(1) and (a)(2) the first time it appears; by removing ``and'' at the end of paragraph (a)(1); by removing the period at the end of paragraph (a)(2) and inserting a semicolon in its place; by adding new paragraphs (a)(3) and (a)(4); by revising paragraph (c); and in paragraph (d) by inserting ``or NAFTA'' following ``Act'' to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>25.408</textblock>
    <textblock>Solicitation provision and contract clause.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) The provision at 52.225-20, Buy American Act-North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) Implementation Act-Balance of Payments Program Certificate, in solicitations containing the clause at 52.225-21; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(4) The clause at 52.225-21, Buy American Act-North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) Implementation Act-Balance of Payments Program, where the contracting officer has determined that the acquisition is not subject to the Trade Agreements Act but is subject to NAFTA.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) The clause prescriptions at paragraph (a) of this section shall apply where any item under a multiple item solicitation is determined to be subject to the Trade Agreements Act or North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act. If the Acts do not apply to all of the items being solicited, the contracting officer shall indicate, in the schedule, those items that are exempt.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>25.1003</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>22. Section 25.1003 is amended in paragraphs (a)(2) and (b)(2) by revising ``$176,000'' to read ``$182,000''.</textblock>
    <textblock>PART 52_SOLICITATION PROVISIONS AND CONTRACT CLAUSES</textblock>
    <textblock>52.225-3</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>23. Section 52.225-3 is amended by revising the date of the clause to read ``(JAN 1994)''; by removing the last sentence from the definition ``Domestic end product''; and removing the parenthetical following paragraph (b)(4).</textblock>
    <textblock>24. Section 52.225-8 is amended in the section and clause headings by removing ``Act'' following ``Agreements'', and revising the date of the clause heading to read ``(JAN 1994)''; in paragraph (a) by removing ``Act'' following ``Agreements'', and inserting ``a North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) country,'' following ``designated country,''; by revising the introductory text of paragraph (c) and paragraph (c)(1); and in paragraph (c)(2) by removing ``Act'' following ``Agreements''. The revised text reads as follows:</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
