<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-0-00041</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-0-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>E. Gas Industry Standards Board</textblock>
    <textblock>Several of the Working Group reports, and initial comments, endorsed the development of a Gas Industry Standards Board (GISB) which ultimately would replace the Working Groups and continue the development and maintenance of industry-wide standards. In the NOPR, the Commission stated it was interested in this concept and invited submission of a proposal as to how it would operate.</textblock>
    <textblock>Many commenters support an industry standards board in concept as long as all industry segments are represented, but noted the concept is still in the planning phase so any detailed comments would be premature.</textblock>
    <textblock>75</textblock>
    <textblock>A number of commenters emphasized that the GISB concept should not interfere with the on-going efforts of the Working Groups. El Paso did not support an industry standards board unless it was limited to communication format standards, and O&amp;R contended such a board should be an advisory panel only. Con Edison, in contrast, contends the scope of the board should be extended beyond electronic communication to include standardization relating to pipeline operations, imbalances, and nominations.</textblock>
    <textblock>On November 2, 1993, the Commission met with representatives from the Natural Gas Council to hear a report on the progress of GISB. The Commission remains interested in this concept and looks forward to a detailed proposal. When the Commission receives a proposal, it will give close consideration to the effects of such an independent industry standardization effort on all facets of the gas industry, Commission regulation, and state regulation.</textblock>
    <textblock>In the meantime, the Working Group efforts should continue apace. The Working Groups should not defer or delay the development of standards in anticipation of the formation of a standards board. Moreover, they should ensure their proposals can stand alone and should not rely upon the eventual existence of a standards board as the means to administer the standards.</textblock>
    <textblock>VIII. Environmental Analysis</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission is required to prepare an Environmental Assessment or an Environmental Impact Statement for any action that may have a significant adverse effect on the human environment.</textblock>
    <textblock>76</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission has categorically excluded certain actions from these requirements as not having a significant effect on the human environment.</textblock>
    <textblock>77</textblock>
    <textblock>The action taken here falls within the categorical exclusions in the Commission's regulations for rules that are clarifying or procedural and that relate to information gathering, analysis, and dissemination.</textblock>
    <textblock>78</textblock>
    <textblock>Therefore, an environmental assessment is unnecessary and has not been prepared in this rulemaking.</textblock>
    <textblock>IX. Regulatory Flexibility Act Certification</textblock>
    <textblock>The Regulatory Flexibility Act of 1980 (RFA)</textblock>
    <textblock>79</textblock>
    <textblock>generally requires a description and analysis of final rules that will have significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities. Pursuant to section 605(b) of the RFA, the Commission hereby certifies that the regulations proposed herein will not have a significant impact on a substantial number of small entities.</textblock>
    <textblock>X. Information Collection Requirement</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Management and Budget (OMB) regulations require approval of certain information collection requirements imposed by agency rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>80</textblock>
    <textblock>The information/EBB requirements of this final rule are under FERC-549(B), Gas Pipeline Rates: Capacity Release Information, (OMB Control No. 1902-0169).</textblock>
    <textblock>The required information under FERC-549(A) enables the Commission to carry out its legislative mandate under the NGA and NGPA and will ensure a viable capacity release market under Commission Order No. 636. Specifically, the required information allows the Commission to review/monitor capacity release transactions and firm and interruptible capacity made available directly from pipelines and to take appropriate action, where and when necessary.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission is submitting notification of these information/EBB requirements to OMB for its review and approval. Interested persons may send comments regarding the burden estimates or any other aspect of these EBB standards/information requirements, including suggestions for reducing the estimated burden, by contacting the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 941 North Capitol Street, NE., Washington, DC 20426 [Attention: Michael Miller, Information Services Division, (202) 208-1415]. Comments on the requirements of the subject final rule may also be sent to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503 [Attention: Desk Officer for Federal Energy Regulatory Commission].</textblock>
    <textblock>XI. Effective Date</textblock>
    <textblock>This final rule shall take effect February 4, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>List of Subjects in 18 CFR Part 284</textblock>
    <textblock>Continental shelf, Natural gas, Reporting and recordkeeping requirements.</textblock>
    <textblock>By the Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See Power Generators, Northwest, Tenneco, Williston Basin, AGA, AER/MRT, AGD, Brooklyn Union, Columbia Distribution, Columbia Gas, Destec Energy, Exxon, NGSA, Process Gas Consumers Group , IPAA, KGPL, Transco, UDC, Natural, Peoples Gas, et al., Edison, Texaco, PEC Pipeline Group.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>75</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Order No. 486, Regulations Implementing the National Environmental Policy Act, 52 FR 47897 (Dec. 17, 1987), FERC Stats. &amp; Regs. Preambles 1986-1990 ¶ 30 (1987).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>76</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>18 CFR 380.4.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>77</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>See 18 CFR 380.4(a)(2)(ii), 380.4(a)(5).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>78</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>5 U.S.C. 601-612.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>79</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>5 CFR 1320.14.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>80</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Lois D. Cashell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
    <textblock>In consideration of the foregoing, part 284, chapter I, title 18, Code of Federal Regulations, is amended as set forth below.</textblock>
  </signjob>
</doc>
