<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-0-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-0-00014</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>25.305</textblock>
    <textblock>[Amended]</textblock>
    <textblock>13. Section 25.305 is amended in paragraphs (a) and (c) by adding ``or NAFTA'' after ``1979''.</textblock>
    <textblock>14. Section 25.400 is amended by revising paragraph (c) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>25.400</textblock>
    <textblock>Scope of subpart.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) Acquisitions involving offers of Canadian or Mexican end products under the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), as approved by Congress in the NAFTA Implementation Act (Pub. L. 103-182, 107 Stat. 2057);</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>15. Section 25.401 is amended by revising the definitions for ``Canadian end product'' and ``Eligible product''; amending the ``designated country'' list by removing ``Upper Volta'' and adding in alphabetical order ``Burkina Faso'' and ``Portugal''; and adding in alphabetical order the definitions ``Mexican end product'', ``North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) country'', ``NAFTA country construction material'', and ``NAFTA country end product'' to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>25.401</textblock>
    <textblock>Definitions.</textblock>
    <textblock>Canadian end product,</textblock>
    <textblock>as used in this subpart, means an article that (a) is wholly the growth, product, or manufacture of Canada, or (b) in the case of an article which consists in whole or in part of materials from another country or instrumentality, has been substantially transformed in Canada into a new and different article of commerce with a name, character, or use distinct from that of the article or articles from which it was transformed. The term includes services (except transportation services) incidental to its supply;</textblock>
    <textblock>provided,</textblock>
    <textblock>that the value of those incidental services does not exceed that of the product itself. It does not include service contracts as such.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Eligible product,</textblock>
    <textblock>as used in this subpart, means a designated, North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), or Caribbean Basin country end product.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>Mexican end product,</textblock>
    <textblock>as used in this subpart, means an article that (a) is wholly the growth, product, or manufacture of Mexico, or (b) in the case of an article which consists in whole or in part of materials from another country or instrumentality, has been substantially transformed in Mexico into a new and different article of commerce with a name, character, or use distinct from, that of the article or articles from which it was transformed. The term includes services (except transportation services) incidental to its supply;</textblock>
    <textblock>provided,</textblock>
    <textblock>that the value of those incidental services does not exceed that of the product itself. It does not include service contracts as such.</textblock>
    <textblock>North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) country,</textblock>
    <textblock>as used in this subpart, means Canada or Mexico.</textblock>
    <textblock>NAFTA country construction material,</textblock>
    <textblock>means a construction material that (a) is wholly the growth, product, or manufacture of a NAFTA country or (b) in the case of a construction material which consists in whole or in part of materials from another country or instrumentality, has been substantially transformed in a NAFTA country into a new and different construction material distinct form the materials from which it was transformed.</textblock>
    <textblock>NAFTA country end product,</textblock>
    <textblock>as used in this subpart, means a Canadian end product or a Mexican end product.</textblock>
    <textblock>16. Section 25.402 is amended_</textblock>
    <textblock>(a) In paragraph (a)(1) by inserting a new sentence after the first sentence;</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) By revising paragraph (a)(3);</textblock>
    <textblock>(c) In the introductory text of paragraph (a)(4) by inserting ``(European Community Agreement)'' after ``Procurement''; in (a)(4)(i) by revising ``25.406 or'' to read ``25.407''; and in (a)(4)(ii) by revising ``$176,000'' to read ``$182,000'';</textblock>
    <textblock>(d) In paragraphs (a)(5) introductory text and (a)(6) by inserting ``or NAFTA'' after `'Act''; and</textblock>
    <textblock>(e) By removing ``country'' the first time it appears in the introductory text of paragraph (f) and the second time it appears in paragraph (f)(2) and inserting'', North American Free Trade Agreement,'' in their places.</textblock>
    <textblock>The revised text reads as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>25.402</textblock>
    <textblock>Policy.</textblock>
    <textblock>(a)(1) *␣*␣* The current threshold is $182,000. *␣*␣*</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(3) As required by the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) Implementation Act (Pub. L. 103-182, 107 Stat. 2057), agencies shall evaluate offers of the following NAFTA country end products without regard to the restrictions of the Buy American Act (see subpart 25.1) or the Balance of Payments Program (see subpart 25.3):</textblock>
    <textblock>(i) NAFTA country construction materials under construction contracts with an estimated acquisition value of $6,500,000 or more for the agencies in 25.407, except for the Power Marketing Administration segments of the Department of Energy where the estimated acquisition value is $8,000,000 or more.</textblock>
    <textblock>(ii) Canadian end products under supply contracts with an estimated value above $25,000 and Mexican end products under supply contracts with an estimated value of $50,000 or more for the agencies in 25.407, except for the Power Marketing Administrations' segment of the Department of Energy, where the estimated acquisition value is $250,000 or more.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>17. Section 25.403 is amended in paragraph (a) by removing ``Trade Agreements Act''; by revising paragraph (b); in paragraph (e) by inserting ``(3) and'' after ``25.402(a)''; in paragraph (h) by revising ``25.402(a)(4)(ii)'' to read ``25.402(a)(3) and (4)''; and revising paragraph (l) to read as follows:</textblock>
    <textblock>25.403</textblock>
    <textblock>Exceptions.</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
    <textblock>(b) Products of countries (1) not identified in 25.401 as designated, Caribbean Basin, or North American Free Trade Agreement countries, or (2) barred by 25.402(c);</textblock>
    <textblock>* * * * *</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
