<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00029</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00012</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The Chief, Audio Service Division, Mass Media Bureau, has before him the following matter:</textblock>
    <textblock>(Regarding the silent status of Station WCSA (AM))</textblock>
    <textblock>Pursuant to section 312(a)(3) and (4) of the Communications Act of 1934, as amended, Keyboard Broadcasting Communication has been directed to show cause why the license for Station WCSA (AM) should not be revoked, at a proceeding in which the above matter has been designated for hearing concerning the following issues:</textblock>
    <textblock>1. To determine whether Keyboard Broadcasting Communication has the capability and intent to expeditiously resume broadcast operations of WCSA(AM) consistent with the Commission's Rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>2. To determine whether Keyboard Broadcasting Communication has violated §§73.1740 and/or 73.1750 of the Commission's Rules.</textblock>
    <textblock>3. To determine, in light of the evidence adduced pursuant to the foregoing issues, whether Keyboard Broadcasting Communication is qualified to be and remain the licensee of Station WCSA (AM).</textblock>
    <textblock>A copy of the complete Show Cause Order and HDO in this proceeding is available for inspection and copying during normal business hours in the FCC Dockets Branch (room 320), 1919 M Street, NW., Washington, DC. The complete text may also be purchased from the Commission's duplicating contractor, International Transcription Service, 2100 M Street, NW., Suite 140, Washington, DC 20037 (telephone 202-857-3800).</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Communications Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>FEDERAL COMMUNICATIONS COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Licensee Order to Show Cause</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <table>
    <textblock>␣</textblock>
    <textblock>1Licensee</textblock>
    <textblock>1City/state</textblock>
    <textblock>1MM docket No.</textblock>
    <textblock>Keyboard Broadcasting Communication, Licensee of WCSA (AM)</textblock>
    <textblock>Ripley, MS</textblock>
    <textblock>93-317</textblock>
  </table>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Stuart B. Bedell,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Assistant Chief, Audio Services Division, Mass Media Bureau.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-100 Filed 1-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 6712-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
