<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00094</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00046</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>In accordance with the purposes of sections 29 and 182b. of the Atomic Energy Act (42 U.S.C. 2039, 2232b), the Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards will hold a meeting on January 6-8, 1994, in room P-110, 7920 Norfolk Avenue, Bethesda, Maryland. Notice of this meeting was published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on November 24, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>Thursday, January 6, 1994</textblock>
    <textblock>8:30 a.m.-8:45 a.m.: Opening Remarks by ACRS Chairman</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The ACRS Chairman will make opening remarks regarding conduct of the meeting and comment briefly regarding items of current interest. During this session, the Committee will discuss priorities for preparation of ACRS reports.</textblock>
    <textblock>8:45 a.m.-9:45 a.m.: Proposed Final Rule to Revise Emergency Planning Regulations on Exercise Requirements</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The Committee will review and comment on the proposed final rule on emergency planning regulations that is intended to clarify the requirements for the emergency planning exercises.</textblock>
    <textblock>Representatives of the NRC staff will participate.</textblock>
    <textblock>9:45 a.m.-10:45 a.m.: Proposed Resolution of Generic Issue 67.5.1, ``Reassessment of SGTR Radiological Consequences''</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The Committee will review and comment on the proposed resolution of Generic Issue 67.5.1 regarding reassessment of the validity of the present techniques used to calculate radiological consequences resulting from a steam generator tube rupture (SGTR) event. Representatives of the NRC staff will participate.</textblock>
    <textblock>11 a.m.-12:30 a.m.: Results of the Public Workshop on License Renewal</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The Committee will hear a briefing by and hold discussions with representatives of the NRC staff regarding the results of the September 30, 1993 public workshop on license renewal, and a draft Commission paper that includes staff recommendations on the future directions of the license renewal. Representatives of the industry will participate, as appropriate.</textblock>
    <textblock>1:30 p.m.-3 p.m.: BWR Core Power Stability/ATWS</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The Committee will hear briefings by and hold discussions with representatives of the NRC staff regarding the status of the issues associated with the resolution of BWR core power stability combined with an ATWS event, including the issue of liquid poison remixing phenomena, and the development of emergency procedure guidelines. Representatives of the industry will participate.</textblock>
    <textblock>3:15 p.m.-4:15 p.m.: Reliability Assurance Program</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The Committee will hear a briefing by and hold discussions with representatives of the NRC staff regarding the staff position on the Reliability Assurance Program for the Advanced Light Water Reactors.</textblock>
    <textblock>4:15 p.m.-5:15 p.m.: Evaluation of License Feedback on the Impact of NRC Activities on Licensee Operations</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The Committee will hear a briefing by and hold discussions with representatives of the NRC staff regarding SECY-93-236, ``The Staff's Evaluation of Ongoing Licensee Feedback on the Impact of NRC Activities on Licensee Operations.'' Representatives of the industry will participate, as appropriate.</textblock>
    <textblock>5:15 p.m.-6 p.m.: Proposed ACRS Report on Certified Design Material for ABWR</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The Committee will discuss a proposed ACRS report on Certified Design Material in the areas of Human Factors Engineering, Radiation Protection, Piping Design, and Instrumentation and Control.</textblock>
    <textblock>6 p.m.-6:30 p.m.: Preparation of ACRS Reports</textblock>
    <textblock>(Open)_The Committee will discuss proposed ACRS reports regarding items considered during this meeting.</textblock>
  </text>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards; Meeting Agenda</textblock>
  </doctitle>
</doc>
