<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00096</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00047</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>The United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission (the Commission) has granted the request of Northeast Nuclear Energy Company, et al. (the licensee) to withdraw its December 2, 1988 application for proposed amendment to Facility Operating License DPR-21 for the Millstone Nuclear Power Station, Unit 1, located at the licensee's site in New London County, Connecticut.</textblock>
    <textblock>The proposed amendment would have revised the Technical Specifications to reflect the implementation of modifications during the 1989 refueling outage related to degraded grid undervoltage detection. Since the licensee plans to make additional modifications to the undervoltage detection circuitry during the Cycle 15 refueling outage, additional Technical Specification changes will be necessary and will be submitted prior to the outage.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission has previously issued a Notice of Consideration of Issuance of Amendment published in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>on February 1, 1989 (54 FR 5170). However, by letter dated September 10, 1993, the licensee withdrew the proposed change.</textblock>
    <textblock>For further details with respect to this action, see the application for amendment dated December 2, 1988, and the licensee's later dated September 10, 1993, which withdrew the application for license amendment. The above documents are available for public inspection at the Commission's Public Document Room, The Gelman Building, 2120 L Street, NW., Washington, DC 20555, and at the local public document room located at the Learning Resources Center, Three Rivers Community-Technical College, Thames Valley Campus, 574 New London Turnpike, Norwich, Connecticut 06360.</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated at Rockville, Maryland, this 28th day of December 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>For the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Docket No. 50-245]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Northeast Nuclear Energy Co.; Withdrawal of Application for Amendment to Facility Operating License</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <signer>
    <textblock>James W. Andersen,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Project Manager, Project Directorate I-4, Division of Reactor Projects_I/II, Office of Nuclear Reactor Regulation.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-130 Filed 1-4-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7590-01-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
