<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00067</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940105-2-00027</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Certain Cased Pencils From the People's Republic of China and Thailand</textblock>
    <textblock>Determinations</textblock>
    <textblock>On the basis of the record§</textblock>
    <textblock>developed in the subject investigations, the Commission determines, pursuant to section 733(a) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (19 U.S.C. 1673b(a)), that there is a reasonable indication that an industry in the United States is materially injured by reason of imports from the People's Republic of China and Thailand</textblock>
    <textblock>of certain cased pencils, provided for in subheading 9609.10.00 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, that are alleged to be sold in the United States at less than fair value (LTFV).</textblock>
    <textblock>Background</textblock>
    <textblock>On November 10, 1993, a petition was filed with the Commission and the Department of Commerce by the Pencil Makers Association, Inc., Marlton, NJ, alleging that an industry in the United States is materially injured or threatened with material injury by reason of LTFV imports of certain cased pencils from the People's Republic of China and Thailand. Accordingly, effective November 10, 1993, the Commission instituted antidumping investigations Nos. 731-TA-669-670 (Preliminary).</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of the institution of the Commission's investigations and of a public conference to be held in connection therewith was given by posting copies of the notice in the Office of the Secretary, U.S. International Trade Commission, Washington, DC, and by publishing the notice in the</textblock>
    <textblock>Federal Register</textblock>
    <textblock>of November 17, 1993 (58 FR 60670). The conference was held in Washington, DC, on December 1, 1993, and all persons who requested the opportunity were permitted to appear in person or by counsel.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Commission transmitted its determinations in these investigations to the Secretary of Commerce on December 27, 1993. The views of the Commission are contained in USITC Publication 2713 (December 1993), entitled ``Certain Cased Pencils from the People's Republic of China and Thailand: Investigations Nos. 731-TA-669-670 (Preliminary).''</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued: December 29, 1993.</textblock>
    <textblock>By order of the Commission.</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>INTERNATIONAL TRADE COMMISSION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <rindock>
    <textblock>[Investigations Nos. 731-TA-669-670 (Preliminary)]</textblock>
  </rindock>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footcite>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footcite>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>The record is defined in sec. 207.2(f) of the Commission's Rules of Practice and Procedure (19 CFR 207.2(f)).</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>1</textblock>
  </footname>
  <footnote>
    <textblock>Commissioner Brunsdale and Commissioner Crawford determine that there is no reasonable indication that an industry in the United States is materially injured or threatened with material injury by reason of imports of certain cased pencils from Thailand.</textblock>
  </footnote>
  <footname>
    <textblock>2</textblock>
  </footname>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Donna R. Koehnke,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Secretary.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-150 Filed 1-4-93; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 7020-02-P</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
