<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940125-2-00020</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940125-2-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>CAE-12.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. EL93-62-000 and QF92-54-005, Polk Power Partners, L.P.</textblock>
    <textblock>CAE-13.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. EL94-11-000, Ogden Martin Systems of Clark,</textblock>
    <textblock>et al.</textblock>
    <textblock>Consent Agenda_Oil and Gas</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-1.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP93-204-002 and 003, Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-2.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-91-000, Granite State Gas Transmission, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-3.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-98-000, Granite State Gas Transmission, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-4.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-99-000, Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-5.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-101-000, Carnegie Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-6.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-102-000, Carnegie Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-7.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-106-000, Pacific Gas Transmission Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-8.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP94-107-000 and 001, Northwest Pipeline Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-9.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP94-108-000, RP93-161-004 and RP94-1-004, Columbia Gas Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-10.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. TM94-4-16-000, National Fuel Gas Supply Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-11.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. TM94-4-17-000, Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-12.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-13.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-84-000, Viking Gas Transmission Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-14.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-93-000, K N Interstate Gas Transmission Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-15.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-96-000, CNG Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-16.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-100-000, Viking Gas Transmission Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-17.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-104-000, Overthrust Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-18.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-19.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP94-97-000, RS92-87-002, 004 and 012, Transwestern Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-20.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. PR93-14-000, Humble Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-21.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP92-171-003, Texas Eastern Transmission Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-22.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-31-001, CNG Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-23.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. TM93-2-17-001, Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-24.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP91-203-036, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-25.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP93-166-000 and 001, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-26.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP93-167-000, Trunkline Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-27.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-82-000, Florida Gas Transmission Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-28.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP93-175-000, Williston Basin Interstate Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-29.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-33-002, Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-30.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. TM94-2-17-002, Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-31.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP93-161-003, Columbia Gas Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-32.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP94-48-003 and RS92-13-009, Williston Basin Interstate Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-33.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP93-109-009, Williams Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-34.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-43-002, ANR Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-35.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-37-002, Alabama-Tennessee Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-36.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. GP83-11-003 and RI83-9-004, Colorado Interstate Gas Company</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
