<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940125-2-00017</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940125-2-00007</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Announcing the Fifth Meeting of the Motor Vehicle Titling, Registration, and Salvage Advisory Committee</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>National Highway Traffic Safety Administration</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA), DOT.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Meeting announcement.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>This notice announces the fifth meeting of the Motor Vehicle Titling, Registration, and Salvage Advisory Committee. The Committee was established as required by Section 140 of the Anti Car Theft Act of 1992, Public Law 102-519, and in accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act, for the purpose of studying problems related to motor vehicle titling, registration, and controls over motor vehicle salvage which may affect the motor vehicle theft problem. The Committee will develop and submit a report to the President, the Congress, and the chief executive of each State concerning the results of this study, which will include recommendations to solve these problems. At this meeting the Committee will review and approve the final report.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATE AND TIME:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting is scheduled to begin at 10 a.m. on Thursday, February 10, 1994, and conclude at 3 p.m.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>The meeting will be held in room 2230, of the Department of Transportation Building, which is located at 400 Seventh Street SW., Washington, DC.</textblock>
  </address>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>In April 1993, the Motor Vehicle Titling, Registration, and Salvage Advisory Committee was established as required by Section 140 of the Anti Car Theft Act of 1992, Public Law 102-519. The purpose of the Committee is to study problems which relate to motor vehicle titling, registration, and vehicle salvage controls, including the lack of uniformity in State laws, which may contribute to motor vehicle theft and fraud problems.</textblock>
    <textblock>The Committee will prepare a report containing the results of the study, including appropriate recommendations to solve the problems identified. The report shall be submitted to the President, the Congress, and to the chief executive office of each State not later than April 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>This meeting is open to the public; however, participation will be determined by the Committee Chairperson.</textblock>
    <textblock>A public reference file (P.F. 93-001) has been established to contain products of the Committee and will be open to the public during the hours of 9:30 a.m. to 4 p.m. at the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration's Technical Reference Division in room 5108 at 400 Seventh Street SW., Washington, DC 20590, telephone (202) 366-2768.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Richard C. Morse, Odometer Fraud Staff, Office of the Associate Administrator for Enforcement, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, NEF-20, room 5321, 400 Seventh Street SW., Washington, DC 20590, Phone: 202-366-4761.</textblock>
    <textblock>Issued on: January 19, 1994.</textblock>
  </further>
  <signer>
    <textblock>William A. Boehly,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Associate Administrator for Enforcement.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1562 Filed 1-24-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 4910-59-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
