<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940125-2-00021</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940125-2-00009</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>CAG-37.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-39-002, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-38.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-39.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP89-185-007, Panhandle Eastern Pipe Line Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-40.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP93-192-003, Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-41.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP94-18-002, Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-42.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. GP93-7-001, Railroad Commission of Texas, Unit Petroleum Company, Sell No. 2 Well, FERC JD93-13959B</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. GP94-1-000, Snyder Oil Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-43.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP93-174-001, Northwest Pipeline Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP93-168-000, LFC Gas Company v. Northwest Pipeline Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-44.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP94-16-001 and RP85-177-116, Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-45.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-46.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. OR92-8-003 and OR93-5-001, SFPP, L.P.</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-47.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RP93-14-011, Algonquin Gas Transmission Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-48.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-49.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP93-200-001, RP93-150-003 and RP94-8-001, Northern Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-50.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RP94-3-001 and RP94-7-001, Northern Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-51.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. IS94-1-001, Phillips Pipe Line Company</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. OR94-1-000, Sinclair Oil Corporation v. Phillips Pipe Line Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-52.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-53.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. IS93-40-000 and OR93-7-000, ARCO Pipe Line Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-54.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RO89-5-000, Bayport Refining Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-55.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RO92-1-000, Kenco Refining, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-56.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-33-007 and TM94-3-2-000, East Tennessee Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-57.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. RS92-11-016, Texas Eastern Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. CP80-223-003 and CP84-306-003, CNG Transmission Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-58.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. RS92-22-012 and 013, Panhandle Eastern Pipe Line Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-59.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. CP92-580-002, CP92-581-002, CP93-252-001 and CP93-253-001, El Paso Natural Gas Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-60.</textblock>
    <textblock>Omitted</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-61.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP92-182-006, Florida Gas Transmission Company and Florida Gas Transmission Company</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP92-415-004, Transcontinental Gas Pipe Line Corporation</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-62.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP93-41-003, K N Energy, Inc. and K N Interstate Gas Transmission Company</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP93-42-003, K N Gas Gathering, Inc.</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-63.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP93-75-001, Sunrise Energy Company v. Transwestern Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-64.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP93-748-000, Raton Gas Transmission Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-65.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket Nos. CP93-141-000, 001 and 002, Iroquois Gas Transmission System, L.P.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP93-145-000 and 001, Tennessee Gas Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-66.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP93-441-000, Black Marlin Pipeline Company</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-67.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP92-595-000, Great Lakes Gas Transmission Limited Partnership</textblock>
    <textblock>CAG-68.</textblock>
    <textblock>Docket No. CP92-606-000, Great Lakes Gas Transmission Limited Partnership</textblock>
  </text>
</doc>
