<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940125-2-00002</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940125-2-00001</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text/>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <doctitle>
    <textblock>Endangered Species; Permits</textblock>
  </doctitle>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS), NOAA, Commerce.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Notice of receipt of a revision to a modification request for scientific research Permit 747 (P45H).</textblock>
    <textblock>On August 8, 1991 (56 FR 40312), the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) was issued Permit 747 under the authority of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (U.S.C. 1531-1543) and the NMFS regulations governing listed fish and wildlife (50 CFR parts 217-227). Notice was published on August 13, 1992 (57 FR 36386) that the USFWS had applied in due form for a modification to Permit 747. Notice is hereby given that the USFWS has revised their application for a modification to conduct scientific research and enhancement on listed Sacramento River winter chinook salmon.</textblock>
    <textblock>Written data or views, or requests for a public hearing on this application should be submitted to the Director, Office of Protected Resources, National Marine Fisheries Service, 1335 East-West Highway, Silver Spring, MD 20910, within 30 days of the publication of this notice. Those individuals requesting a hearing should set forth the specific reasons why a hearing on this particular application would be appropriate. The holding of such hearing is at the discretion of the Assistant Administrator for Fisheries. All statements and opinions contained in the application and revision request summaries are those of the Applicant and do not necessarily reflect the views of NMFS.</textblock>
    <textblock>Documents submitted in connection with the above application and revision are available for review by interested persons in the following offices by appointment:</textblock>
    <textblock>Office of Protected Resources, National Marine Fisheries Service, NOAA, 1335 East-West Highway, Silver Spring, MD 20910 (301-713-2232); and</textblock>
    <textblock>Director, Southwest Region, National Marine Fisheries Service, NOAA, 501 West Ocean Blvd., suite 4200, Long Beach, CA 90802-4213 (310-908-4016).</textblock>
    <textblock>Dated: January 14, 1994.</textblock>
  </action>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Herbert W. Kaufman,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Acting Director, Office of Protected Resources.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1563 Filed 1-24-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3510-22-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
