<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<doc>
  <docno>
    <textblock>FR940125-2-00003</textblock>
  </docno>
  <parent>
    <textblock>FR940125-2-00002</textblock>
  </parent>
  <text>
    <textblock>Armament Retooling and Manufacturing Support (ARMS) Public/Private Task Force (PPTF)</textblock>
  </text>
  <usdept>
    <textblock>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</textblock>
  </usdept>
  <usbureau>
    <textblock>Department of the Army</textblock>
  </usbureau>
  <agency>
    <textblock>AGENCY:</textblock>
    <textblock>U.S. Army Materiel Command, DOD.</textblock>
  </agency>
  <action>
    <textblock>ACTION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Meeting notice.</textblock>
  </action>
  <summary>
    <textblock>SUMMARY:</textblock>
    <textblock>In accordance with section 10(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (Pub. L. 92-463), announcement is made of the next meeting of the Armament Retooling and Manufacturing Support (ARMS) Public/Private Task Force (PPTF).</textblock>
    <textblock>The PPTF is chartered to develop new and innovative methods to maintain the government-owned, contractor-operated ammunition industrial base and retain critical skills for a national industrial emergency. The purpose of this meeting is to evaluate and offer recommendations regarding the ARMS Program; loan guarantee program; additional ARMS initiative incentives; regulatory waivers, deviations, or changes; and ARMS initiative legislative supplements or changes. This session is open to the public.</textblock>
  </summary>
  <date>
    <textblock>DATES:</textblock>
    <textblock>February 16-18, 1994.</textblock>
    <textblock>PLACE:</textblock>
    <textblock>Holiday Inn, Oakland Park, 4505 Woodson Way, St. Louis, Missouri.</textblock>
  </date>
  <address>
    <textblock>ADDRESSES:</textblock>
    <textblock>Commander, U.S. Army Materiel Command, ARMS Task Force, 5001 Eisenhower Avenue, Alexandria, VA 22333.</textblock>
  </address>
  <further>
    <textblock>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</textblock>
    <textblock>Mr. R. B. Auger, (703) 274-9838.</textblock>
  </further>
  <supplem>
    <textblock>SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</textblock>
    <textblock>Reservations should be made directly with the Holiday Inn; telephone 1-800-426-4700. Please be sure to mention that you will be attending the ARMS meeting to get in the block of rooms set aside for this meeting. Request you contact Donna Ponce in the ARMS Team Office at Rock Island Arsenal; telephone (309) 782-3058/4040, if you will be attending the meeting, so that our roster of attendees is accurate. This number may also be used if other assistance regarding the ARMS meeting is required.</textblock>
  </supplem>
  <signer>
    <textblock>Kenneth L. Denton,</textblock>
  </signer>
  <signjob>
    <textblock>Army Federal Register Liaison Officer.</textblock>
  </signjob>
  <frfiling>
    <textblock>[FR Doc. 94-1596 Filed 1-24-94; 8:45 am]</textblock>
  </frfiling>
  <billing>
    <textblock>BILLING CODE 3710-08-M</textblock>
  </billing>
</doc>
